<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XLIX._MIAMI-DADE_COUNTY_INDIGENT</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-521. Creation and purpose of task force</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created and established the Miami-Dade County Indigent Health Care Task Force. The task force's purpose is to advise and make recommendations to the County Commission on a means whereby private sector physicians, hospitals and other private health care providers and facilities are encouraged to provide health care to the medically indigent residents of Miami-Dade County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-522. Membership; appointment; terms; removal</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Board of County Commissioners shall, by resolution, appoint ten (10) members to the task force in a manner set forth below.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The membership shall consist of a community service agency representative and a representative from each of the following organizations:
Miami-Dade County Public Health Trust
Miami-Dade Legislative Delegation
Miami-Dade County Medical Association
South Florida Hospital Association
Primary Health Care Consortium
Health Council of South Florida
Miami-Dade League of Cities
Miami-Dade County Chapter of the National Medical Association
Miami-Dade County Bar Association
In addition, the County Commission shall appoint an alternate for each member who shall be empowered to vote in the absence of the representative.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Initial appointment and tenure. The ten (10) members and ten (10) alternates representative of the foregoing organizations, presently serving on the task force pursuant to Resolution Nos. 549-91 and 319-92, shall constitute the initial appointment. These members and alternates shall hold office until the task force expires pursuant to Section 2-525 below or until his or her successor is duly appointed and qualified.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Attendance requirements for members shall be in accordance with Section 2-11.39 of this Code. If a member appointed to represent a category listed in subsection (b) above loses such representative status, fails to maintain the qualifications for membership set forth in Section 2-11.38 of this Code, fails to maintain attendance requirements, voluntarily resigns, or for other good cause is removed, the member shall forfeit membership on the task force and the designated alternate shall replace that member and the County Commission shall appoint a new alternate.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The members shall serve without compensation. The County Commission or other sources may provide funds for appropriate and necessary expenses incurred by the task force or any of its members in performance of task force functions, provided that no County funds will be expended without prior approval of the County Commission.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 92-40, § 2, 5-19-92)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-523. Organization of the task force</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The members of the task force shall elect a chairperson and other such officers as may be deemed necessary or desirable, who shall serve at the will of the task force.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A majority of members of the task force shall constitute a quorum necessary to hold a meeting and take any action. A majority vote of the members present shall be necessary to take any action. The chairperson may call meetings of the task force. Meetings may also be called by written notice signed by six (6) members. The task force at any meeting may fix and call a meeting on a future date. Minutes shall be kept of all meetings of the task force and all meetings shall be public. The County Manager, County Attorney and Clerk of the County Commission shall provide appropriate staff support.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The task force may appoint committees to accomplish its tasks, and may include as committee members individuals who are not task force members.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 92-40, § 3, 5-19-92)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-524. Duties and powers of the task force</catch_line>
<text>
The task force shall have the following duties, functions, powers and responsibilities:
<section prefix = "a">
The task force shall prepare recommendations to the County Commission addressing the following issues:
<section prefix = "1">
Reducing or limiting the liability exposure for registered volunteer health care providers that provide services to medically indigent patients whose treatment would otherwise be rendered by the Public Health Trust; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Developing a voucher system, reimbursement program or other financial arrangement that will allow private hospitals to recover the reasonable costs of rendering secondary level support services to those medically indigent patients that would otherwise be treated at Jackson Memorial Hospital. This program or arrangement would be available to registered volunteer physicians and other health care providers and staff physicians of the Public Health Trust.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The task force may review and comment on other indigent health care issues.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
In carrying out the duties and responsibilities set forth above, the task force may utilize a strategic planning process and shall meet with and receive input from other groups and agencies involved in health care planning.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The task force shall, on behalf of the above-referenced groups, present recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners regarding areas of indigent health care where the combined efforts of the public and private health care providers would be appropriate and cost effective.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-525. Reports</catch_line>
<text>
The task force shall submit its recommendations in writing to the County Commission on or before December 31, 1992 at which time the task force's tenure shall expire, unless otherwise extended by the Board of County Commissioners.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-526—2-530. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
</law>
