<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="2">ARTICLE_LXXIA._OFFICE_OF_CITIZEN_ASSISTA</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. Sec. 2-967.11. Established; director as head; appointment; term; operating procedures; compensation of employees</catch_line>
<text>
The Office of the Citizen Assistance and Outreach (hereinafter referred to as "Team Metro") is hereby established as a department of Miami-Dade County. The head of this Department is its Director. The Director shall be appointed by and serve at the will of the Manager. The organization and operating procedures of the Department shall be prescribed by administrative orders and regulations of the Manager. Any changes made to the Office of Citizen Assistance and Outreach ("Team Metro") including any changes to the duties and powers of the Department must occur by amendment to the Code. The Manager shall appoint such employees as may be necessary to operate the Department. The compensation of all personnel, except employees with the classified service, shall be fixed by the Commission upon recommendation of the Manager.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-968. Duties and powers</catch_line>
<text>
The duties and powers of the Director of Team Metro shall include, but not be restricted to, the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Providing assistance to the public in accessing government and its information and services;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Establishing regional offices to increase citizen access to government;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Identifying community concerns and issues and providing information for local civic action and to work with County government to bring to the citizens the available resources to alleviate or eliminate problems to the greatest degree and as effectively as possible;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Providing an integrated system of code enforcement authorized to enforce the provisions of the Code of Miami- Miami-Dade County set forth below, and to collect fines, fees and, penalties,and file liens and foreclosure actions for County Departments as identified in administrative orders of the County Manager.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Performing such additional duties as may be prescribed by ordinance or by administrative orders and regulations of the Manager.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-968.1 Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
Definitions of specific terms used in the enforcement of this chapter are incorporated by reference from Chapter 2,Chapter 8, Chapter 15,Chapter 17, Chapter 17A, Chapter 17B, Chapter 18A, Chapter 19, Chapter 21 Chapter 28, Chapter 30, Chapter 33 of the Code of Miami-Dade County and the South Florida Building Code. In cases where there are two (2) or more definitions in the Code for the same word, the definition in the Code chapter being enforced shall prevail.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-969. Enforcement</catch_line>
<text>
Team Metro shall, through its duly authorized enforcement officers, be authorized to enforce the following provisions of the Code of Miami-Dade County:
<section prefix="1" type="table">
<table class="table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="25%" /> 
  <col width="75%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Code Section</i> </td> 
   <td style="" align="center" valign="top" class="">Description of Violation<br /></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level3/PTIIICOOR_CH2AD_ARTXIVPUWODE.html#PTIIICOOR_CH2AD_ARTXIVPUWODE_S2-100FUPODU">2-100</a>(d) </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Illegal object(s) or vegetation in the right-of-way not approved for use according to the Public Works Manual </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level3/PTIIICOOR_CH2AD_ARTXIVPUWODE.html#PTIIICOOR_CH2AD_ARTXIVPUWODE_S2-103.15SIPURI-WPR">2-103.15</a> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Illegal signs in right-of-way</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="2" valign="top" class="">All other<a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH2AD.html#PTIIICOOR_CH2AD"> Chapter 2</a> violations as identified in administrative order of the County Manager </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH15SOWAMA.html#PTIIICOOR_CH15SOWAMA_S15-2SOWACOSECOUSCOLO">15-2</a> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Having a waste container at curbside, right-of-way, or street edge before or after specified hours of normal collection day </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH15SOWAMA.html#PTIIICOOR_CH15SOWAMA_S15-5DUDISOWAPRAC">15-5</a> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Unauthorized bulky or industrial waste on right-of-way</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH15SOWAMA.html#PTIIICOOR_CH15SOWAMA_S15-5DUDISOWAPRAC">15-5</a> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Uncontainerized refuse, rubbish, or solid waste</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH15SOWAMA.html#PTIIICOOR_CH15SOWAMA_S15-6LIDUUNDEPRDUBUSOWAWIPRAUUNDESOWANETRRECEDEPUNUPR">15-6</a>(b)(1), (3) </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">General littering in an amount not exceeding 100 pounds in weight or 50 cubic feet in volume </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="2" valign="top" class="">All other<a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH15SOWAMA.html#PTIIICOOR_CH15SOWAMA"> Chapter 15</a> violations as identified in administrative order of the County Manager </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="2" valign="top" class="">All<a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH17HO.html#PTIIICOOR_CH17HO"> Chapter 17</a>,<a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH17AVASTSTMI.html#PTIIICOOR_CH17AVASTSTMI"> Chapter 17A</a> and<a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH17BMEMIDECODEUNSTOR.html#PTIIICOOR_CH17BMEMIDECODEUNSTOR"> Chapter 17B</a> violations as identified in administrative order of the County Manager or as necessary to enforce the Minimum Housing Standards. Minimum Standards for Vacant Structures and Demolition of Uninhabitable Structures Ordnance, respectively. </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH19REPROWMEAC.html#PTIIICOOR_CH19REPROWMEAC_S19-3DE">19-3</a> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Allowing public nuisance to exist</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH19REPROWMEAC.html#PTIIICOOR_CH19REPROWMEAC_S19-4RECO">19-4</a>(C) </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Illegal disposal of cuttings, solid waste or junk</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH19REPROWMEAC.html#PTIIICOOR_CH19REPROWMEAC_S19-5COENRECO">19-5</a> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Failure to comply with schedule</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH19REPROWMEAC.html#PTIIICOOR_CH19REPROWMEAC_S19-6TEMEDIENPODU">19-6</a> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Allowing a violative condition to exist</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="2" valign="top" class="">All other<a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH19REPROWMEAC.html#PTIIICOOR_CH19REPROWMEAC"> Chapter 19</a> violations as identified in administrative order of the County Manager </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level3/PTIIICOOR_CH21OFMIPR_ARTIVMI.html#PTIIICOOR_CH21OFMIPR_ARTIVMI_S21-30OFAGPUPRPR">21-30</a>(2) </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Destroying, damaging or vandalizing public property, including public right-of-way</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level3/PTIIICOOR_CH21OFMIPR_ARTIVMI.html#PTIIICOOR_CH21OFMIPR_ARTIVMI_S21-30.01GR">21-30.01</a>(f)(1) </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Sale of spray paint or markers to persons under 18 years of age.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level3/PTIIICOOR_CH21OFMIPR_ARTIVMI.html#PTIIICOOR_CH21OFMIPR_ARTIVMI_S21-30.01GR">21-30.01</a>(d) </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Failure to remove graffiti</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level3/PTIIICOOR_CH21OFMIPR_ARTIVMI.html#PTIIICOOR_CH21OFMIPR_ARTIVMI_S21-30.01GR">21-30.01</a>(f)(1) </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Sale of spray paint or markers to persons under 18</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level3/PTIIICOOR_CH21OFMIPR_ARTIVMI.html#PTIIICOOR_CH21OFMIPR_ARTIVMI_S21-30.01GR">21-30.01</a>(f)(2) </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Failure to display graffiti warning signs or improper storage of spray paint or markers</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level3/PTIIICOOR_CH21OFMIPR_ARTIVMI.html#PTIIICOOR_CH21OFMIPR_ARTIVMI_S21-30.01GR">21-30.01</a>(f)(3) </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Violation of spray paint or marker sale injunction</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" rowspan="0" colspan="2" valign="top" class="">All other<a href="../level3/PTIIICOOR_CH21OFMIPR_ARTIVMI.html#PTIIICOOR_CH21OFMIPR_ARTIVMI_S21-30.01GR"> Chapter 21-30.01</a> violations as identified in administrative order of the County Manager </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" rowspan="0" colspan="2" valign="top" class="">All<a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH30TRMOVE.html#PTIIICOOR_CH30TRMOVE"> Chapter 30</a> violations as identified in Sections<a href="../level3/PTIIICOOR_CH30TRMOVE_ARTIINGE.html#PTIIICOOR_CH30TRMOVE_ARTIINGE_S30-388.32PEVIAR"> 30-388.32</a>,<a href="../level3/PTIIICOOR_CH30TRMOVE_ARTIIPASPDIPE.html#PTIIICOOR_CH30TRMOVE_ARTIIPASPDIPE_S30-447PEMISPMAPASP"> 30-447</a>,<a href="../level3/PTIIICOOR_CH30TRMOVE_ARTIIAPASPPETRYOCHST.html#PTIIICOOR_CH30TRMOVE_ARTIIAPASPPETRYOCHST_S30-449PASPPETRYOCHST"> 30-449</a> and<a href="../level3/PTIIICOOR_CH30TRMOVE_ARTIIAPASPPETRYOCHST.html#PTIIICOOR_CH30TRMOVE_ARTIIAPASPPETRYOCHST_S30-450PEMISPMAPASP"> 30-450</a> of this code </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level3/PTIIICOOR_CH33ZO_ARTIINGE.html#PTIIICOOR_CH33ZO_ARTIINGE_S33-13UNUS">33-13</a>(b) </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Unpermitted use in conflict with prescribed and expected uses therein</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 

Enforce against violations of Chapter 33 of the Code of Miami-Dade County with the exception of Section 33-8 and all work lawfully in progress under an authorized permit.
Issue civil violation notices for work without permits as required under the South Florida Building Code.
Wherever reference is made in any of the provisions cited above to an enforcement officer or agency, such references shall also be understood to refer to Team Metro.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-970. Resisting or obstructing enforcement</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful to resist, obstruct or oppose the Director or the Director's designee or enforcement officer in the discharge of duties under this chapter.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-971. Penalty for violation of chapter</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Any person who shall violate a provision of this chapter, or fails to comply therewith, or with any of the requirements thereof, shall upon conviction thereof in the County Court, be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for not more than sixty (60) days, or by both such fine and imprisonment. At the discretion of the Director, violations of this chapter may be enforced pursuant to Chapter 8CC of the Code of Miami-Dade County. Any person who violates or fails to comply with this chapter shall also be subject to fines in accordance with Chapter 8CC of this Code. Each day of violation or noncompliance shall constitute a separate offense.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Whenever a violation of this chapter occurs or exists, or has occurred or existed, any person individually or otherwise, who has a legal, beneficial or equitable interest in the facility or instrumentality causing or contributing to the violation, or who has a legal, beneficial or equitable interest in the real property upon which such violation occurs or exists, or has occurred or existed, shall be jointly and severally liable for said violation regardless of fault and regardless of knowledge of the violation.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 96-86, § 1, 6-4-96)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-972. Remedies</catch_line>
<text>
In addition to any other remedies provided in this chapter, in Chapter 8CC of the Code of Miami-Dade County, or in any other applicable provision of the County Code, the Director shall have the following judicial remedies available for violations of this chapter or any other lawful rule or regulation promulgated hereunder.
<section prefix = "1">
Any person who violates a provision of this chapter or any lawful rule, regulation or written order promulgated under this chapter is subject to injunction or other equitable relief to enforce compliance with or prohibit the violation of this chapter. Further, such person is liable for any damage to Miami-Dade County caused by such violation, and for the reasonable costs and expenses incurred by Miami-Dade County in enforcing the provisions of this chapter, including but not limited to the costs of enforcement, inspections, preparation of enforcement reports, photographs, title searches, postage and other demonstrable administrative costs for enforcement and collection. All such sums shall become immediately due and payable upon expenditure by the County and shall become delinquent if not paid within thirty (30) days after receipt by the violator of the Department's bill itemizing the enforcement costs incurred in enforcing the provisions of this chapter (the "due date"). All such delinquent sums shall bear interest at the rate of twelve (12) percent per annum.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
In addition to the foregoing, any person who violates a provision of this chapter or any lawful rule, regulation or written order promulgated under this chapter is subject to the judicial imposition of a civil penalty for each offense of an amount not to exceed five thousand dollars ($5,000.00) per day per offense. In assessing the penalty, the court may receive evidence in mitigation. Each day during any portion of which a violation occurs constitutes a separate offense.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Upon the rendition of a judgment or decree by any of the courts of this State against any person and in favor of the Director or the County in any action to enforce compliance with or prohibit the violation of the provisions of this chapter, the court shall adjudge or decree against that person and in favor of the Director or the County a reasonable sum as fees or compensation for the attorney acting on behalf of the Director or the County in the suit in which recovery is had. This provision shall apply to all civil actions filed after the effective date of this ordinance. Cessation of the violation of any of the provisions of this chapter prior rendition of a judgment or prior to execution of a negotiated settlement, but after an action has been filed by the Director or the County to enforce the provisions of this chapter, shall be deemed for the purpose of this section the functional equivalent of a confession of judgment or verdict in favor of the Director or the County, for which attorney's fees shall be awarded as set forth in the Department's Administrative Order.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit or require the Director to bring an action on behalf of any private person.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-973. Consent agreements</catch_line>
<text>
The Director or the Director's designee may, in the discretion of the Director or the Director's designee, terminate an investigation or an action commenced under the provisions of this chapter upon execution of a written consent agreement between the Director or the Director's designee and the persons who are the subject of the investigation or action. The consent agreement shall provide written assurance of voluntary compliance with all the applicable provisions of this chapter by such persons. The consent agreement may in addition provide for the following: Mitigation of injuries accruing on account of the violation investigated or sued upon; compensatory damages, punitive damages; civil penalties; costs and expenses of enforcement; attorney's fees; and remedial or corrective action. Except as expressly and specifically provided in the executed written consent agreement, an executed written consent agreement shall neither be evidence of a prior violation of this chapter nor shall such agreement be deemed to impose any limitation or action by the Director or the County in enforcing any of the provisions of this chapter, nor shall the agreement constitute a waiver of or limitation upon the enforcement of any federal, State or local law or ordinance. Each violation of any of the terms of an executed written consent agreement shall constitute a separate violation under this chapter by the persons who executed the agreement and by their respective officers, directors, agents, servants, employees, attorneys, heirs, successors and assigns, and by any persons in active concert or participation with any of the foregoing persons and who have received actual notice of the consent agreement. Each day during any portion of which each such violation occurs constitutes a separate offense under this chapter.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-974. Enforcement; procedure</catch_line>
<text>
The Director is hereby authorized to institute actions on behalf of the County in any court of competent jurisdiction in this State to seek enforcement of this chapter and all remedies for violation thereof.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-975—2-980. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (91) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 96-86, adopted June 4, 1996, amended the Code by the addition of Art. LXXII, §§ 2-967—2-974, which provisions have been redesignated at the discretion of the editor as Art. LXXIA, §§ 2-967.11—2-974 to avoid duplication of with existing article and section numbering. (Back)
Cross reference— Delegation of public works department enforcement powers and duties to director of Team Metro, §§ 2-100.1, 19-11; delegation of solid waste management department enforcement powers and duties to director of Team Metro, § 2-100.1; delegation of the department of planning, development and regulation enforcement powers and duties to director of Team Metro, § 33-39.2.1. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
