<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 20 MUNICIPALITIES</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_II._INCORPORATION_PROCEDURE</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 20-20. Petition for incorporation initiated by individual or group; Creation of Municipal Advisory Committee related to petition</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
An individual or group of area residents may file a request for approval of the form of a petition and authorization to circulate such petition for incorporation with the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners.
<section prefix = "1">
The petition form shall provide for the following information about the proposed municipality:
<section prefix = "a">
General description and map of area boundaries, and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Statement of the reason for seeking incorporation.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners shall report to the Commission that a request to approve the form of a petition for incorporation and authorize the circulation of such petition has been received. The Board of County Commissioners may approve the form of the petition and may authorize the petitioners to circulate the petition for incorporation and obtain signatures of resident electors within the area.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
In order for the submitted petition to be complete, the petition shall include consent from no less than twenty-five (25) percent of the electors in the area proposed for incorporation.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Signed petitions shall be submitted to the Clerk of the Board within 90 days of the date the County Commission approves the form and authorizes the circulation of the petition in order for the petition to receive any further review or consideration by the County. Petitioners should submit any resolutions of support or opposition, if any exist, from the closest existing municipality within such 90 day period.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
The Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners shall upon receipt of a petition for incorporation transmit a copy to the Office of Strategic Business Management for determination of completeness in accordance with the requirement of subsection (A)(1) and to the Department of Elections for certification as to the sufficiency of signatures on the petition. Upon determining that the petition is complete and that a sufficient number of valid signatures has been obtained, the Office of Strategic Business Management shall notify the Clerk of the Board of such occurrence.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
The Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners shall notify the County Commission that the petition is complete and contains sufficient signatures. Upon notification of the completeness and sufficiency of the petition and upon sponsorship of the County Commissioner whose district comprises the majority of the area proposed to be incorporated by the petition, the Board of County Commissioners may create a Municipal Advisory Committee ("MAC"), which shall carry out the functions set forth in the resolution or ordinance creating the MAC and be subject to the requirements of Section 20-29 of the Code of Miami-Dade County (the "Code"), excluding the requirement of consent of resident electors. Notwithstanding the creation of a MAC, the procedures for consideration of a petition set forth in Section 20-20 et seq. of the Code shall apply. If the boundaries in the completed petition differ from the boundaries of the MAC study area, the boundaries of the MAC study area shall supplant and be substituted for the boundaries included in the petition; provided, however, 25% of the electors residing within the boundaries as revised to conform to the MAC study area shall have signed the completed petition indicating their interest in incorporating the area.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
The requirement of filing a petition for incorporation pursuant to Sec. 20-20 of the Code of Miami-Dade County (the "Code") and the procedures for such filing contained in Sec. 20-21(A) of the Code shall not apply to incorporation proposals by the County Commission or County Manager. It is provided, however, that a Commission or Manager-initiated incorporation proposal shall be deemed a petition for proposed incorporation for purposes of Section 20-21; 20-22, and 20-23 and shall be required to comply therewith. Notwithstanding Section 20-23A herein, the Board of County Commissioners may hold a public hearing on a Commission initiated incorporation proposal during any regular or special meeting of the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 95-78, § 1, 5-2-95; Ord. No. 95-131, § 1, 7-13-95; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-136, § 1, 9-17-96; Ord. No. 98-125, § 13, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 00-124, § 1, 10-3-00; Ord. No. 01-168, § 1, 10-23-01; Ord. No. 01-183, § 1, 11-6-01; Ord. No. 05-140, § 1, 7-7-05)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 20-21. Initial consideration of petition for proposed incorporation</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Upon creation of a MAC pursuant to Section 20-20(C) of the Code and receipt of the final resolution and report of the MAC created to study the issues involved in the incorporation petition (the "Municipal Advisory Committee or MAC report"), the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners shall submit the MAC report to the Board of County Commissioners. Upon receipt of the MAC report and only upon motion of the district commissioner whose district comprises the majority of the area proposed to be incorporated, the Board of County Commissioners, at a regular meeting of the Board of County Commissioners may schedule the petition for consideration by the Planning Advisory Board in accordance with all applicable requirements. The provisions of this section shall apply to petitions filed prior to and subsequent to the effective date of this ordinance. No MAC in existence prior to the effective date of this ordinance shall fulfill the requirements of this Section. No petitions having had their initial public hearing pursuant to Sec. 20-21(C) prior to the effective date of this ordinance shall receive further consideration by the County Commission or any county established board, unless and until the provisions of this section and Section 20-20(C) have been met.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
The Clerk shall advertise in a daily newspaper of general circulation that a petition for incorporation has been received and shall include in the advertisement the following information:
<section prefix = "1">
Map of the area proposed for incorporation,
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Date of hearing for initial consideration by the Board of County Commissioners, and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Contact persons or departments where additional information may be provided.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
The Board of County Commissioners at its initial public hearing for considering a petition for incorporation, after determining the requirements for showing of support set forth in Section 20-20 (A)(2) have been fulfilled, may:
<section prefix = "1">
Establish an overall schedule for consideration of the petition, after receiving the County Manager's recommendation on such matter; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Refer the petition to the Planning Advisory Board for its review and recommendations.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 95-78, § 1, 5-2-95; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 13, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 01-168, § 1, 10-23-01; Ord. No. 05-140, § 2, 7-7-05)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 20-21.1. Exception to filing and consideration of requests for incorporation</catch_line>
<text>
Notwithstanding anything in this article to the contrary, no incorporation request shall be filed, nor shall any filed request be heard, considered, or approved, pursuant to Section 20-23, by the Board of County Commissioners, prior to December 1, 1998, except upon a prior two-thirds (2/3) vote of the membership of the County Commission to allow such filing, hearing consideration or approval.
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 01-218, § 2, adopted Dec. 18, 2001 amended section 20-21.1. Section 6 of said ordinance provided for the repeal of said ordinance 90 days from its effective date.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 20-22. Planning Advisory Board's consideration of petition for incorporation</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
The Director of the Office of Management and Budget, prior to transmittal to the Planning Advisory Board, shall request the directors of all other applicable County departments to review and comment on the incorporation petition with respect to their areas of expertise and responsibility.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
The Director of the Office of Strategic Business Management, upon receipt of comments and information from other departments, shall prepare a report on the petition containing the following information:
<section prefix = "1">
Summary of petition,
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Socio-economic profile of area,
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Development profile of area,
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Any Municipal Advisory Committee Report, and
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Other information outlined in Section 20-23(B)(1),
The report shall be transmitted to the Planning Advisory Board.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
The Planning Advisory Board, upon receipt of a petition and appropriate County department staff review and comment shall:
<section prefix = "1">
Create a five-member committee of the Planning Advisory Board appointed by its chair for the purpose of studying and making a recommendation to the full Board on the petition. The chair of the Planning Advisory board shall designate a chair for such committee. In making its report and recommendation to the full Board the committee shall utilize the guidelines set forth in subsection (4).
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Conduct a properly advertised public hearing within the area proposed for incorporation.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Require additional information from appropriate County departments as needed.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Make written recommendations with respect to the petition and any Municipal Advisory Committee Report which shall include the following:
<section prefix = "a">
An analysis of the issues outlined in Section 20-23(B);
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Whether the proposed incorporation:
<section prefix = "1">
will divide a historically recognized community;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
is compatible, to the degree possible, with existing planned land uses and zoning of the areas surrounding the proposed municipality;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
will, if currently qualified, continue to be eligible for any benefits derived form inclusion in federal or state enterprise zones, or targeted area assistance provided by federal, state and local government agencies;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
will impact public safety response times;
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
creates barriers to municipal traffic circulation due to existing security taxing districts, walled communities and/or private roads;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
if identified by the federal government as a flood zone or by emergency planners as an evacuation zone, has the proposed municipality indicated its preparedness to address any extraordinary needs that may arise;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
to the degree possible, will be contained in one or more school district boundaries governing admission to elementary, middle and high schools.
<section prefix = "c">
Other considerations deemed relevant by the Board
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
The Planning Advisory Board recommendation to the Board of County Commissioners shall be either:
<section prefix = "1">
Approval of the petition;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Approval of the petition on a modified basis;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Deferral of the petition for more information;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Deferral of the petition to permit modification; or
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Denial of the petition.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
The Director of the Office of Strategic Business Management shall forward the petition and recommendations of the Planning Advisory Board as well as the Municipal Advisory Committee Report, to the County Manager for review and recommendation. The County Manager shall transmit the Manager's recommendation, the petition, the recommendation of the Planning Advisory Board, as well as the Municipal Advisory Committee Report, to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
The Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners, upon receipt of the recommendations by the Planning Advisory Board and County Manager, shall set the matter of such proposed incorporation for public hearing at a regular meeting of the County Commission and cause notice of such public hearing to be published in a daily newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County at least once not less than one (1) week prior to the date of such public hearing. Notice of such public hearing shall be furnished to all property owners within the area and within six hundred (600) feet thereof.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 95-78, § 1, 5-2-95; Ord. No. 95-176, § 2, 10-5-95; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 13, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 01-168, § 1, 10-23-01; Ord. No. 05-86, § 3, 5-3-05; Ord. No. 05-140, § 3, 7-7-05)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 20-23. Board of County Commissioners consideration of proposed incorporation petition</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
The Board of County Commissioners shall only hold a public hearing on the petitions for incorporation during the period between September 1 and September 30 inclusive and during the period between March 1 and March 31 inclusive in each year, which shall be conducted as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
Persons requesting incorporation shall make a presentation outlining the merits of their petition,
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The County Commission shall consider and review the recommendations of the Planning Advisory Board and the County Manager, and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The County Commission shall hear from any other interested persons.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
At the conclusion of the public hearing the Board of County Commissioners, in evaluating the appropriateness of a petition for incorporation, shall consider the following guidelines:
<section prefix = "1">
The suitability of the proposed boundaries to provide for a municipal community of interest that is both cohesive and inclusive. Specifically, the area should:
<section prefix = "a">
Not divide a U.S. Census Designated Place, to the extent feasible.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Include adjacent areas of ethnic minority and lower income residents in which a majority of those residents have so petitioned.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Have contiguity and not create any unincorporated enclave area(s). An unincorporated enclave area is defined as an area that would be 1) surrounded on more than eighty (80) percent of its boundary by one (1) or more municipalities and of a size that could not be serviced efficiently or effectively.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Have natural or built barriers as boundaries, to the extent feasible, and
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Include a mixture of residential and non-residential land uses.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Evidence of support of area residents and property owners sufficient to warrant the costs of balloting of electors,
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Existing and projected property tax costs for municipal-level services to average homeowner in the area as currently unincorporated and as incorporated as a comparable Miami-Dade County city with a similar per capita property tax base.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
There are no suitable alternatives to incorporation, including annexation to an existing municipality,
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Is totally contained within the Urban Development Boundary depicted on the future Land Use Plan map of the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan,
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
The impact of the proposal, as updated by the Office of Strategic Business Management prior to the public hearing, on the revenue base of the unincorporated area, and on the ability of the County to efficiently and effectively provide services to adjacent remaining unincorporated areas, including the potential for the area to:
<section prefix = "a">
Continue to participate in the County's Fire-Rescue and Library Districts, and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Contract with the County for other municipal services,
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Potential revenue sources and facilities to be made available to the proposed municipality upon incorporation, and
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
The financial impacts of the proposed incorporation on the remaining unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County. Specifically in order to insure fiscal equity the per capita taxable property value of the area proposed for incorporation should fall between twenty thousand dollars ($20,000.00) and forty-eight thousand dollars ($48,000.00) in order to assure that fiscal viability is maintained in both the potential new municipality and the remaining unincorporated area.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Any other factor that arises by virtue of recommendations of the Planning Advisory Board, pursuant to Section 20-22 of the Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Any other factor that arises by virtue of any special or unique circumstances of a given area.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
The Board of County Commissioners shall at the conclusion of the public hearing take one (1) of the following actions:
<section prefix = "1">
Call for the election of the area electors on the incorporation petition as presented by the applicant(s),
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Call for the election of the area electors on the incorporation petition as modified with respect to boundaries or other aspects,
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Deny the proposed incorporation petition, or
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Defer such petition for further consideration by the applicant(s), Board of County Commissioners, the County Manager or the Planning Advisory Board.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 95-78, § 1, 5-2-95; Ord. No. 95-131, § 1, 7-13-95; Ord. No. 95-176, § 2, 10-5-95; Ord. No. 02-99, § 1, 6-18-02; Ord. No. 05-86, § 3, 5-3-05; Ord. No. 07-177, § 1, 12-4-07)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 20-24. Appointment of Charter Commission</catch_line>
<text>
Upon the affirmative vote approving the requested incorporation by a majority of electors voting and residing in the proposed boundaries, in an election conducted pursuant to Section 20-23(C)(1) or (2), the Board of County Commissioners may approve the incorporation of the municipality. If they so act, the Board of County Commissioners shall appoint a Charter Commission consisting of five (5) electors residing in the proposed boundaries who shall propose a charter be submitted to the electors in the manner provided in Section 5.03 of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 20-25. Retention of garbage and refuse collection and disposal</catch_line>
<text>
The County shall forever retain authority for residential garbage and refuse collection and disposal in all areas which incorporate subsequent to the effective date of this ordinance.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 20-26. Future Municipalities' Obligations to the County</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
As a condition of incorporation approved pursuant to Article I of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, each new municipality shall include a provision in its charter and shall agree to remain a part of the Miami-Dade County Fire-Rescue District and the Miami-Dade County Library System in perpetuity.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
As a condition of incorporation approved pursuant to Article I of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, each new municipality shall include a provision in its charter and shall agree in perpetuity to contract with the Miami-Dade County Police Department ("MDPD") and pay for specialized police services from its municipal millage or other municipal funds. For purposes of this subsection, specialized police services include, but are not limited to, narcotics, criminal intelligence, economic crimes, homicide, robbery, sexual crimes, environmental crimes, domestic crimes, and crime scene investigations; property and evidence efforts; tactical operations activities; and aviation patrol.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
As a condition of incorporation approved pursuant to Article I of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, each new municipality shall include a provision in its charter and shall agree to contract with the Miami Dade County Police Department ("MDPD") and pay for local patrol police services for three years or such longer period of time as may be requested by the municipality.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The fiscal impact of an incorporation on the remainder of the unincorporated area shall be revenue neutral; provided, however, any municipality which does not meet the foregoing requirement, as a condition of incorporation pursuant to Article I of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, shall agree to make an annual mitigation payment to the County's Municipal Services Trust Fund in the Unincorporated Municipal Service Area Budget, the amount of which shall be determined by the Board of County Commissioners, in the event of a negative fiscal impact of the municipality's incorporation on the unincorporated area. For purposes of this subsection, "a revenue neutral municipality" is defined as an area that previously, as part of the unincorporated municipal service area, generated revenues equal to or less than the cost of services provided to the area by the County. Any annual mitigation amount determined by the Board of County Commissioners pursuant to the provisions of this paragraph shall be established so as not to trigger "most-favored-nation-status" clauses which are contained in any municipal charter.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
As a condition of incorporation approved pursuant to Article I of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, each new municipality shall include in its charter that such municipality shall be responsible for (i) its pro-rata share of any County debt outstanding at the time the municipality incorporates and with respect to the Stormwater Utility, outstanding at the time the municipality elects to be separate from the Stormwater Utility through an interlocal agreement or by exemption and (ii) its prorata share of any refunding of such debt. The municipality's annual pro-rata share of debt service shall be determined by multiplying the total debt service in each Fiscal Year by the municipality's percentage share of pledged revenues (revenues pledged by the County to the repayment of the debt). The municipality's percentage share shall be determined by dividing the pledged revenues collected within the municipality during the County's Fiscal Year in which municipality incorporates, and with respect to the Stormwater Utility in the Fiscal Year in which the municipality elects to separate from the Stormwater Utility district; by the total pledged revenues collected in that same Fiscal Year. It is further provided that the municipality's charter shall authorize the County to continue to collect and distribute the pledged revenues in a manner that is consistent with the requirements of the debt and shall recognize the municipality's obligations pursuant to this subsection.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The Board of County Commissioners may by way of resolution allow the distribution of existing unincorporated bond proceeds to municipalities created after September 1, 2000 for the same type of project originally described in the bond documents.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
As a condition of incorporation approved pursuant to Article I of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, each new municipality, as a part of its charter, shall provide for adoption of Miami-Dade County's workforce housing development program established at Chapter 33, Article XIIA of the Code of Miami-Dade County, as amended, provided, however, that any municipality may establish and enforce more stringent regulations as necessary to ensure provision of workforce housing units within its jurisdiction.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
As a condition of incorporation approved pursuant to Article VI of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, each new municipality shall provide, as a part of the charter, that the Board of County Commissioners retains jurisdiction over the modification or deletion of declarations of restrictive covenants accepted by either the Board of County Commissioners or a Community Zoning Appeals Board in connection with a Comprehensive Development Master Plan application or zoning application, regardless of whether such declaration provides for modification or deletion by a successor governmental body. It is provided, however, that the Board of County Commissioners may not exercise such jurisdiction unless the applicable municipality has first approved the modification or deletion.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 02-26, § 2, 2-26-02; Ord. No. 05-97, § 2, 5-17-05; Ord. No. 05-98, § 1, 5-17-05; Ord. No. 05-142, § 2, 7-7-05; Ord. No. 07-05, § 20, 1-25-07; Ord. No. 08-51, § 1, 5-6-08; Ord. No. R-13-06, § 2, 1-23-13)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 20-26A. Process for Amending Pre-agreed Conditions of Incorporation in a Municipal Charter</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Any municipality which is desirous of amending the pre-agreed conditions to incorporation contained in its municipal charter shall request the County's approval of the proposed amended charter language indicating language to be added and deleted and stating the ballot question, prior to calling an election on the question of amending the municipal charter.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The municipality shall submit the proposed amended charter language and ballot question to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners with copies to the County Attorney and County Manager for placement by the Clerk on the agenda of the appropriate committee. Upon review of the municipality's proposed amended charter language and ballot question, the Board of County Commissioners may direct the County Attorney to prepare a resolution approving such amendment for placement on a subsequent County Commission agenda.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
If the County Commission by resolution approves the proposed amended charter language and ballot question by an affirmative vote of two-thirds (2/3) of its members then in office, the municipality may consider and adopt a resolution calling an election on the proposed charter changes, subject to compliance with Section 5.03 of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-201, § 1, 11-30-04)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 20-27. Future Municipalities' Elections</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 20-28.1. Areas and Facilities of Countywide Significance</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
As a condition of incorporation approval pursuant to Article V of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, each new municipality shall conduct its regular election(s) to fill municipal elective offices as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
For those municipalities that elect their officeholders in a single election without a provision for a run-off, elections shall be held on the second Tuesday in March of even numbered years.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
For those municipalities that elect their officeholders by means of a primary election, used to narrow down the list of candidates to appear on the general election ballot, and a general election, primary elections shall be held on the second Tuesday in March of even numbered years and general elections shall be held on the second Tuesday in April of even numbered years. In those election years where it is not necessary to conduct a primary election, the general election shall be held on the second Tuesday in March.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
For those municipalities that elect their office holders by means of a general election and a run-off election held for those races in which no candidate receives a majority of the votes cast in the general election, general elections shall be held on the second Tuesday in March of even numbered years and run-off elections shall be held on the second Tuesday in April of even numbered years.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The election dates specified in (A)(1)-(3) above shall not apply to the election or elections held to fill the municipal elective offices following the vote to approve the charter of a new municipality.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
As a condition of incorporation approval pursuant to Article V of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, each new municipality shall provide a period for candidates for municipal elective office to file such qualifying papers and pay such fees as may be required by law with the applicable city clerk no earlier than noon on the first workday in January and no later than noon on the 14th day following the first weekday in January of the calendar year in which the election is to be held.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
As a condition of incorporation approval pursuant to Article V of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, each new municipality shall provide for all of its elections to be canvassed by a County Canvassing Board as provided under the election laws of this state.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-19, § 2, 1-20-04)</history>
Sec 20-28. Policy Regarding Incorporation and Annexation of Commercial, Business, or Industrial Areas.
<section prefix = "1">
Policy. It is the policy of the Board of County Commissioners that any proposed municipal incorporation which would result in a donor municipality having any Commercial Business or Industrial or "CBI Area" within its boundaries or any municipality that proposes the annexation of any CBI Area in the area it proposes to annex shall as a condition of incorporation or annexation, pay to the County 100% of the net excess of revenues minus expenses attributable to the CBI Area within the boundaries of the proposed municipality or the annexed area. In the case of incorporation, the agreement to pay net excess of revenues minus expenses shall be included in the charter of the proposed municipality. In the case of annexation, the agreement to pay net excess of revenues minus expenses shall be included in an interlocal agreement between the municipality and the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Exceptions: (a) Any annexing municipality having a below average per capita taxable value as compared to all other cities within Miami-Dade County, including UMSA, and an above average tax effort as compared to all other cities in Miami-Dade County, including UMSA, shall be exempt from the application of Section 1 to the extent necessary to achieve an average per capita taxable value. It is provided, however, that if after the annexation, the municipality reduces its tax effort to below the average tax effort as compared to all cities including UMSA, it shall pay a mitigation fee into a municipal services trust fund equal to the revenues generated in the proposed annexed area less the cost of services which the County provided to the area prior to annexation; (b) Any annexing municipality having a below average per capita taxable value as compared to all cities in Miami-Dade County, including UMSA, wherein over ten per cent (10%) of families or individuals are below the poverty level status, as reported by the United States Bureau of the Census, shall be exempt from the application of Section 1, provided they maintain their existing tax effort at the time of the annexation. Provided, however, the County may negotiate the terms of mitigation with such municipality.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Definitions. For purposes of this section, the term:
<section prefix = "a">
"Donor Municipality" is defined as a municipality where the revenue generated from the area as part of UMSA is more than the expenses incurred by the County to serve that area.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
"Commercial, Business or Industrial Area ("CBI Area") is a high-value area used primarily for commercial, business or industrial purposes and each of which is identified and described in Composite Exhibit I hereto, which is incorporated herein by reference.
</section>
</section>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 05-73, § 1, adopted April 19, 2005, amended the Code with the addition of a new section 20-27. In order to avoid duplication of section numbers, the provisions of said ordinance have been included herein as section 20-28 at the discretion of the editor.

Sec. 20-28.1. Areas and Facilities of Countywide Significance.
(a)
Definition. "Areas and Facilities of Countywide Significance" consist of any private or public lands, including surface, subsurface, and appurtenant airspace and improvements thereupon, located in unincorporated Miami-Dade County as of the date of this ordinance that are deemed necessary by the Board of County Commissioners for the coordinated use of lands, development and service delivery within the County to promote the health, safety, order, convenience, prosperity, and welfare of the current and future residents and tourists of this County.
(b)
Designation. The Board of County Commissioners hereby designates each of the following lands listed on Exhibit A, as an "Area or Facility of Countywide Significance". Any future designation of lands as an Area or Facility of Countywide Significance may be made by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners, upon a finding that:
1)
The area or facility is susceptible to substantial change and development that will detrimentally affect the facility or land;
2)
There is a need for the continued, unimpaired functioning of the area or facility by the greater community and;
3)
The service provided at or by the area or facility, or at a combination of areas or facilities, is a significant resource to the greater community.
If the Board of County Commissioners determines that an area or facility no longer meets the definition of an "Area or Facility of Countywide Significance" as defined herein, the Commission, by resolution, may relinquish regulatory control to the municipality in which such area or facilities are located.
(c)
Regulatory Jurisdiction Over Areas or Facilities of Countywide Significance Reserved to the County. Jurisdiction for purposes of comprehensive planning, zoning and building and other development approvals (including but not limited to land use, site plan approvals, issuance of building permits, building inspections, issuance of certificates of occupancy, zoning applications, special exceptions, variances, building or zoning moratoria, and all other types of functions typically performed by the departments responsible for building, planning and/or zoning), water and sewer installations, compliance with environmental regulations, and utility regulation shall be and are hereby vested in Miami-Dade County regardless of any municipal code, charter, or ordinance provision to the contrary. If an "Area or Facility of Countywide Significance" is located in an area which is sought to be annexed to a municipality or incorporated, the County shall not transfer operation, maintenance, or regulatory jurisdiction of such Area or Facility to a municipality, unless expressly permitted herein.
(d)
Applicability. The requirements of this ordinance apply to municipalities created after the effective date of this ordinance.
(e)
Condition of Incorporation. The provisions of this section shall be considered a condition of incorporation for any area incorporated after the effective date of this ordinance and shall be included in the municipal charter of such area.
(Ord. No. 05-141, § 3, 7-7-05)
Editor's note—
Ord. No. 05-141, § 3, adopted July 7, 2005, amended the Code with the addition of a new § 20-28. In order to avoid the duplication of section numbers, the provisions of said ordinance have been included herein as § 20-28.1 at the discretion of the editor.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 20-29. Municipal Advisory Committee—Creation and Limitation of Study Area</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
A Municipal Advisory Committee may only be created by ordinance of the Board in accordance with the provisions of this section to study and give advice to the County Commission regarding the creation of a proposed municipality. However, as of the effective date of this ordinance, no Municipal Advisory Committee shall be created by the County Commission, unless no less than twenty-five (25) percent of the resident electors in the area to be studied consent to the creation of a Municipal Advisory Committee on a consent form which shall be approved by the Office of Strategic Business Management. The signed consent forms shall be submitted to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners. Upon submission of the signed consent forms, the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners shall submit the signed consent forms to the Department of Elections for certification as to the sufficiency of signatures on the consent forms. Upon notification of certification by the Department of Elections, the Clerk of the Board shall forward to the County Commission the signed consent forms of area residents and the certification of the sufficiency of the consent forms. Following public hearing, the County Commission may create a Municipal Advisory Committee by ordinance. It is provided, however, that where a Municipal Advisory Committee has been established, prior to the effective date of this ordinance, no consent of resident electors shall be required for the adoption of an ordinance creating a Municipal Advisory Committee involving the same study area. Upon receipt of the Municipal Advisory Committee report, which shall include findings of fiscal feasibility, evidence of desirability, and a plan for the development of a viable community, and upon motion of the district commissioner whose district comprises the majority of the proposed area to be incorporated, the Board of County Commissioners, at a regular meeting of the Board, may schedule the Municipal Advisory Committee report and resolution for consideration by the Planning Advisory Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
In the event a Municipal Advisory Committee is created where part of the study area is outside the sponsoring Commissioner's district, such area shall automatically be excluded from the Municipal Area Committee's consideration.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
The restriction set forth in Paragraph (B) may be waived by the Commissioner(s) whose district the study area comes within by filing a memorandum with the Clerk of the Board indicating consent to all or part of the study area.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
This section shall apply to existing as well as to all future Municipal Advisory Committee's created after the effective date of the ordinance from which this section derives.
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
The Municipal Advisory Committee shall complete the required feasibility and desirability study within twenty-four (24) months of its initial creation. If the Municipal Advisory Committee does not meet the required deadline, the Municipal Advisory Committee shall automatically sunset. Any Municipal Advisory Committee in existence as of the effective date of this ordinance shall include as part of its report a study of the feasibility and desirability of incorporating and shall be required to complete its study and submit the required report within twenty-four (24) months of the adoption of this ordinance. If a Municipal Advisory Committee in existence as of the effective date of this ordinance does not meet this required deadline it shall automatically sunset. It is provided however, in the event that the Board of County Commissioners adopts an ordinance which suspends the processing of incorporation requests, the calculation of the twenty-four (24) month period of time provided by this section shall be tolled during the pendency of such suspension.
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
Any public hearing held by the Board of County Commissioners to consider a proposed incorporation of an unincorporated area shall required that prior to such hearing the Office of Strategic Business Management provide the Board an updated Impact to the Unincorporated Municipal Service Area Analysis.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 02-130, § 1, 7-23-02; Ord. No. 03-128, § 1, 6-3-03; Ord. No. 05-140, § 4, 7-7-05; Ord. No. 07-177, § 2, 12-4-07)</history>
</law>
