<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="2">ARTICLE_CXVII._7TH_AVENUE_CORRIDOR_COMMU</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1771. Established</catch_line>
<text>
The 7th Avenue Corridor Community Redevelopment and Revitalization Trust Fund (the "Fund") is hereby established. Each taxing authority (as defined in the Act) shall annually pay into the Fund, an amount not less than that increment in the income, proceeds, revenues and funds of each taxing authority derived from or held in connection with the undertaking and carrying out of community redevelopment in accordance with the Act. The increment shall be determined annually and shall be that amount equal to 95 percent of the difference between: (a) the amount of ad valorem taxes levied each year by each taxing authority, exclusive of any amount from any debt service millage, on taxable real property contained within the geographic boundaries of the Redevelopment Area; and (b) the amount of ad valorem taxes which would have been produced by the rate upon which the tax is levied each year by or for each taxing authority, exclusive of any debt service millage, upon the total of the assessed value of the taxable real property in the Redevelopment Area as shown upon the most recent assessment roll used in connection with the taxation of such property by each taxing authority prior to the effective date of this article.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1772. County's obligation to fund</catch_line>
<text>
Except for the purpose of funding the Fund pursuant to Section 2-1773 herein, upon the enactment of this article, each taxing authority shall, by January 1st of each year, appropriate to the Fund for so long as any indebtedness pledging increment revenues to the payment thereof is outstanding (but not to exceed thirty (30) years) a sum that is no less than the increment as defined and determined by Section 2-1771 of this article accruing to such taxing authority. In no year shall the County's obligation to the Fund exceed the amount of that year's tax increment as determined pursuant to Section 2-1771 of this article. Beginning with the twentieth year after the date of sale of the initial bonding or indebtedness pledging tax increment funds, no new sale of bonds or indebtedness supported by the County's tax increment may occur nor may existing indebtedness so supported be refunded without amending this article. The County's increment contribution is to be accounted for as a separate revenue within the Fund but may be combined within other revenues for the purpose of paying debt service. The County must approve the amount, duration of the obligation and the purpose of any bond, note or other form of indebtedness, including advances, pledging or otherwise obligating tax increment funds.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1773. Same—Duration</catch_line>
<text>
Notwithstanding the provisions of Section 2-1772 herein, the County's obligation to fund the Fund annually shall continue until all loans, advances and indebtedness, if any, and interest thereon, of the Agency incurred as a result of redevelopment in the Redevelopment Area have been paid.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1774. Expenditures; purposes</catch_line>
<text>
Moneys in the Fund may be expended from time to time for the following purposes, when directly related to financing or refinancing of redevelopment in the Redevelopment Area pursuant to the Plan:
<section prefix = "a">
Administrative and overhead expenses necessary or incidental to the implementation of the Plan;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Expenses of redevelopment planning, surveys and financial analysis, including the reimbursement to the Board or the Agency for such expenses incurred before the Plan was approved and adopted;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The acquisition of real property in the Redevelopment Area;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The clearance and preparation of any Redevelopment Area for redevelopment and relocation of site occupants as provided in Section 2-177163.370, Florida Statutes;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The repayment of principal and interest or any redemption premium for loans, advances, bonds, bond anticipation notes and any other form of indebtedness;
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
All expenses incidental to or connected with the issuance, sale, redemption, retirement or purchase of agency bonds, bond anticipation notes or other form of indebtedness, including funding of any reserve, redemption or other fund or account provided for in the ordinance or resolution authorizing such bonds, notes or other form of indebtedness;
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
The development of affordable housing within the Redevelopment Area; or
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
The development of community policing innovations.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1775. End of fiscal year; money remaining in fund</catch_line>
<text>
On the last day of the Agency's fiscal year, any money which remains in the Fund after the payment of the expenses listed in Sec. 2-1774 herein for such year shall be:
<section prefix = "a">
Returned to each taxing authority which paid the increment in the proportion that the amount of the payment of such taxing authority bears to the total amount paid into the Fund by all taxing authorities within the Redevelopment Area for that year;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Used to reduce the amount of any indebtedness to which increment revenues are pledged;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Deposited into an escrow account for the purpose of later reducing any indebtedness to which increment revenues are pledged; or
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Appropriated to a specific redevelopment project pursuant to the Plan which project will be completed within three (3) years from the date of such appropriation.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1776. Audit of fund</catch_line>
<text>
The Agency shall provide for an independent financial audit of the Fund each fiscal year and a report of such audit. Such report shall describe the amount and source of deposits into, and the amount and purpose of withdrawals from, the Fund during such fiscal year and the amount of principal and interest paid during such year on any indebtedness to which is pledged increment revenues and the remaining amount of such indebtedness. The Agency shall provide a copy of the report to each taxing authority. All Fund records shall be available for County inspection. The County reserves the right to audit the Fund.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1777. Liberal construction</catch_line>
<text>
This article is hereby declared to be for a public purpose and for the welfare of the citizens of Miami-Dade County, Florida and shall be literally construed to effectuate the purpose thereof.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-1778—2-1780. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (126) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 04-124, §§ 2—8, adopted June 22, 2004, did not specifically amend the Code. Hence, its inclusion herein as article CXVII, sections 2-1771—2-1777, was at the discretion of the editor. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
