<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXII._PERSONAL_INJURY_PROTECTION</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-420. Purpose and Intent</catch_line>
<text>
The purpose and intent of this article is to:
<section prefix = "a">
Promote the health, safety and general welfare of the residents of Miami-Dade County; and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Prevent fraudulent automobile insurance claims which negatively affect both consumers and insurers within Miami-Dade County through the implementation of registration requirements for certain Personal Injury Protection Medical Providers, as defined below, operating in Miami-Dade County, which treat patients allegedly injured in automobile accidents and receive a major portion of the Personal Injury Protection Medical Provider's income from personal injury protection insurance claims.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-421. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Applicant shall mean the owner or a person or persons authorized by the owner to complete a registration application to operate as a PIP Medical Provider in Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Department shall mean the Miami-Dade County Sustainability, Planning and Economic Enhancement Department or its successor department.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Operating as a Personal Injury Protection Medical Provider, or Operation of a Personal Injury Protection Medical Provider or Operate as a Personal Injury Protection Medical Provider shall mean to conduct the affairs of or manage the operations of a Personal Injury Protection Medical Provider including, but not limited to, any one or more of the following:
<section prefix = "1">
Scheduling or accepting appointment(s) for services including, but not limited to, diagnosis, treatment, and/or therapy which are billed for payment to a PIP insurance provider;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Prescribing, dispensing, or administering any medicine, medical or physical treatment, medical or physical therapy, massage treatment or therapy, or acupuncture treatment or therapy;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Accepting payments from one or more PIP Insurance providers for any of the events listed in paragraphs (1) and (2) above; or
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Employing or contracting with any person for compensation to work in connection with the provision of services for a PIP Medical Provider business.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Person shall mean an individual, partnership, corporation, association, or other legal entity.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Personal Injury Protection Medical Provider or PIP Medical Provider shall mean any person, clinic, facility, location, or other business that provides medical or physical therapy treatment to patients or clients claiming an injury from an automobile accident and which derives:
<section prefix = "1">
Ninety (90) percent or more of the PIP Medical Provider's monthly gross income from billing PIP Insurance providers; or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Two hundred thousand dollars ($200,000.00) or more in gross income during a twelve (12) month period from the billing of PIP Insurance providers.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Personal Injury Protection Medical Provider or PIP Medical Provider shall not mean any business or a facility:
<section prefix = "1">
Licensed as a facility pursuant to Chapter 395, Florida Statutes;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Where the majority of the physicians, who provide services in the facility, primarily provide surgical services for the facility;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Owned by a publicly held corporation whose shares are traded on a national exchange or on the over-the-counter market and whose total assets at the end of the corporation's most recent fiscal quarter exceeded fifty million dollars ($50,000,000.00);
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Affiliated with an accredited Florida medical school for the education of physicians licensed under Chapter 458, 459, or 460 of the Florida Statutes, at which training is provided for medical, osteopathic, or chiropractic students, residents, or fellows;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Owned by a corporate entity exempt from federal taxation under U.S.C. 501(c)(3) or (4);
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
That perform only magnetic resonance imaging, static radiographs, computed tomography, or position emission tomography; or
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Accredited by the Joint Commission as an Outpatient/Ambulatory Care clinic.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Physical Therapy shall mean any type of massage therapy provided in response to a doctor's prescription or direction.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
PIP shall mean personal injury protection.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
PIP Insurance shall mean personal injury protection insurance.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 12-08, § 2, 2-21-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-422. Registration Required</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
All PIP Medical Providers operating within the geographic boundaries of Miami-Dade County shall be registered with the Department. Registration shall be renewed annually.
<section prefix = "1">
Proof of current registration with the County shall be prominently displayed in a common public area of all PIP Medical Provider locations.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Each PIP Medical Provider location shall be registered separately, regardless of whether the location is operated under the same business name or management as another PIP Medical Provider location.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 12-08, § 2, 2-21-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-423. Designated Department</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Department shall:
<section prefix = "1">
Conduct the registration process;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Establish a database of PIP Medical Providers operating in Miami-Dade County;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Enforce the provisions of this article; and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Charge a reasonable application and registration fee for processing applications, enforcing this article, and maintaining the database.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Department shall establish policies and procedures necessary to implement the registration process, maintain the database, enforce this article, and through an implementing order, charge reasonable application and registration fees.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Department is authorized to inspect any PIP Medical Provider for proof of registration at any reasonable hour without prior notice. However, in no event shall any inspection violate any medical records privacy requirements, including HIPPA, or involve the inspection of private or confidential medical information without appropriate authorization or permission.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The Department shall provide written notice to the State of Florida of any PIP Medical Provider or any person employed or associated with a PIP Medical Provider who fails to maintain a professional and/or clinic license or registration required by state law or applicable state agency.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 12-08, § 2, 2-21-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-424. Registration Application and Process; Requirements</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Application Required: Any PIP Medical Provider, as defined in Section 8A-421, must complete an application available from the Department, which shall at a minimum require the applicant to provide the following information:
<section prefix = "1">
Proof of applicable professional and/or clinic license or registration required by state law, the Florida Agency for Health Care Administration, and/or the Florida Department of Health;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Designation of the physician who shall be responsible for complying with all requirements related to registration and Operation of the PIP Medical Provider. The designated physician must have a clear and active license under Chapter 458, 459, 460 or 466, Florida Statutes. If that physician ceases to be affiliated with the PIP Medical Provider, another physician must be so designated within fifteen (15) days.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
A list of all persons associated with the management or Operation of the PIP Medical Provider, including persons involved with rendering medical care and/or billing PIP insurance providers, whether paid or unpaid, part-time or full-time, including all contract labor and independent contractors. This list includes, but is not limited to, all owners, operators, employees, and volunteers. For persons listed, the following additional information must be provided:
<section prefix = "a">
The person's title;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A copy of the person's license, if required by state law, issued by the State Department of Health or applicable agency, to engage in the practice of:
<section prefix = "1">
Acupuncture pursuant to Chapter 457, Florida Statutes,
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Medicine pursuant to Chapter 458, Florida Statutes,
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Osteopathic Medicine pursuant to Chapter 459, Florida Statutes,
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Chiropractic Medicine pursuant to Chapter 460, Florida Statutes,
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Dentistry pursuant to Chapter 466, Florida Statutes,
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Massage Therapy pursuant to Chapter 480, Florida Statutes, or
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Physical Therapy pursuant to Chapter 486, Florida Statutes;
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The person's current home address, telephone number, and date of birth;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
A list of all criminal convictions, guilty pleas, or nolo contendere, whether misdemeanor or felony for that person;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
A copy of a current Florida driver's license or a current government issued photo identification card issued to that person; and
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
If that person is an owner, the percentage of ownership for each owner or shareholder.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The property owner's name, address, and telephone number;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
A copy of a current business tax receipt required pursuant to Chapter 205, Florida Statutes;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Whether the PIP Medical Provider dispenses controlled substances;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Any other reasonable information the Department Director deems necessary; and
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
A sworn and notarized statement from both the designated physician and the PIP Medical Provider business owner(s) attesting to the veracity and accuracy of the information provided in the application. The Department may require the designated physician and the PIP Medical Provider business owner(s) to complete an in-person interview to verify the information in the application and/or notarized statement.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Application Process: Within thirty (30) days of submission, the Department shall verify the information in the application and determine whether or not the applicant meets all the criteria established in subsection (a) above.
<section prefix = "1">
If the applicant satisfies all the criteria in subsection (a), the PIP Medical Provider shall be registered.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
If the application is deemed incomplete, the applicant shall be notified in writing of the deficiencies within thirty (30) days of submission. The applicant shall have fifteen (15) days from the date of such notice to correct the deficiencies and complete the application. Failure to respond or make the corrections within the fifteen (15) days shall be considered a withdrawal of the application. The Department shall notify the applicant of the withdrawal upon expiration of the fifteen (15) days. If the applicant corrects the deficiencies within the fifteen (15) days, the Department shall have fifteen (15) additional days to verify that the application is complete and, if complete, register the PIP Medical Provider.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
If the applicant does not satisfy the criteria in subsection (a), the PIP Medical Provider shall not be registered. The applicant shall be notified in writing of the decision to not register the PIP Medical Provider, including the reasons for denying registration, within thirty (30) days of submission of a new or renewal application or fifteen (15) days from the date that the applicant corrects deficiencies. The applicant shall have fifteen (15) days from the date of such notice to request a hearing in writing before a Hearing Officer pursuant to Chapter 8CC of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. The request for a hearing shall be filed with the Department. The Department Director or any PIP Medical Provider regulated by this article who is aggrieved by any decision of the Hearing Officer may appeal a final order of the Hearing Officer by filing a notice of appeal in the Circuit Court in and for Miami-Dade County, Florida, in accordance with the procedures and within the time provided by the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure for review of administrative action.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Failure of the Department to meet any of the time requirements set forth herein shall not constitute an automatic registration of the PIP Medical Provider.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
In the event that any information provided in the application changes, the designated physician and the PIP Medical Provider business owner(s) must file a notarized statement providing the updated information with the Department within fifteen (15) days of the change.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 12-08, § 2, 2-21-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-425. Additional Registration Compliance Requirements</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
PIP Medical Provider registration is nontransferable and cannot be assigned. Whenever ownership or management of a PIP Medical Provider changes, a new application must be filed and all applicable fees paid.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A valid business tax receipt must be maintained by the PIP Medical Provider.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Any Department designee, code enforcement officer, law enforcement officer, or any other persons authorized to enforce County ordinances must be allowed access for inspection of the PIP Medical Provider premises at any reasonable hour without prior notice.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 12-08, § 2, 2-21-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-426. Registration Denial or Revocation of Registration; Grounds</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Department Director may deny or revoke a PIP Medical Provider registration upon the occurrence of one or more of the following:
<section prefix = "1">
An application contains material false information or missing information;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The PIP Medical Provider, as a clinic and/or individual, is not registered or licensed, as applicable, in accordance with state law, or has had its registration and/or license suspended or revoked by the State of Florida;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
A current business tax receipt is not submitted with the application for each PIP Medical Provider;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Failure to allow an inspection for compliance with this article by a Department designee, code enforcement officer, law enforcement officer, or any other person authorized to enforce ordinance violations in Miami-Dade County at any reasonable hour;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Failure of the PIP Medical Provider to notify the Department in writing of a change in the designated physician within fifteen (15) days pursuant to Section 8A-424
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Failure of the PIP Medical Provider to notify the Department in writing of any change in the registration application information within fifteen (15) days pursuant to Section 8A-424
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Failure to abide by any provision of this article; or
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
If the payment for the application fee or registration fee is invalid or uncollectible for any reason.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 12-08, § 2, 2-21-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-427. Revocation of PIP Medical Provider Registration</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Department Director shall provide written notice of the decision to revoke a current registration, specifying in writing the grounds for revoking the registration. The applicant shall have fifteen (15) days from the date of such notice to request a hearing in writing before a Hearing Officer pursuant to Chapter 8CC of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. The request for a hearing shall be filed with the Department. The Department Director or any PIP Medical Provider regulated by this article who is aggrieved by any decision of the Hearing Officer may appeal a final order of the Hearing Officer by filing a notice of appeal in the Circuit Court in and for Miami-Dade County, Florida, in accordance with the procedures and within the time provided by the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure for review of administrative action.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Failure of the Department to meet any of the time requirements set forth herein shall not affect the revocation of a PIP Medical Provider registration.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 12-08, § 2, 2-21-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-428. Registration Renewal</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Registration required for PIP Medical Providers shall be valid for one year from the date of issuance. At least sixty (60) days prior to expiration of the registration, a renewal application must be submitted, along with a nonrefundable renewal application fee. Provided the PIP Medical Provider named in the renewal application and all information on the application are in compliance with this article, a renewal registration shall be issued by the Department, after payment of an annual registration fee. Renewal registration shall only be issued to PIP Medical Providers that were previously registered and who timely file a renewal application.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 12-08, § 2, 2-21-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-429. Violation, Enforcement, and Penalties</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It shall be unlawful for any person to Operate as a PIP Medical Provider without prior registration. Any enforcement action or legal remedy available under controlling state law including, but not limited to, prosecution as a non-criminal infraction with a fine not exceeding five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment for a term not exceeding sixty (60) days or by both fine and imprisonment, may be imposed as a penalty.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Nothing contained herein shall prevent the County from taking such other action in law and equity as may be necessary to remedy any violation of, or refusal to comply with, any part of this article, including, but not limited to:
<section prefix = "1">
Code Enforcement action pursuant to Chapter 8CC of the Miami-Dade County Code;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Seeking any legal or equitable remedy available in a court of law. The Department Director is authorized to file any action in a court of competent jurisdiction to enforce the provisions of this article and to seek appropriate remedies. In any such action the Department shall be entitled to recover its reasonable costs in the enforcement of this article, including reasonable attorney fees.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 12-08, § 2, 2-21-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-430. Service of Notice</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Any notice required by this article shall be in writing and sent by certified mail or by regular mail if notice is returned undelivered or unclaimed, to the mailing address set forth on the application for the PIP Medical Provider registration. The mailing address set forth in the application shall be presumed the correct mailing address.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 12-08, § 2, 2-21-12)</history>
</law>
