<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_CXXXVI._COMPENSATION_AND_BENEFIT</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2070. Authority and purpose</catch_line>
<text>
There is created and established pursuant to the Home Rule Amendment and Charter of Miami-Dade County, as amended, an advisory committee of Miami-Dade County to be known as the Compensation and Benefits Review Committee ("Review Committee"). The Review Committee is established solely for the purpose of advising the Mayor and the Board of County Commissioners ("Commission") regarding the compensation and benefits of County employees. The Review Committee may exercise only those duties specifically granted in this Article or necessary in the exercise of the duties enumerated in this Article.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2071. Review committee</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Membership. The Review Committee shall be comprised of nine (9) members.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Qualifications. Each member shall be a resident of Miami-Dade County; shall possess an outstanding reputation for civic pride, integrity, responsibility and business or professional ability; and shall have no financial interest, direct or indirect, in the compensation paid to County employees. The membership of the Compensation and Benefits Review Committee should be representative of the community at large and should have a demonstrated expertise in human resources, organizational design, public management, or other related topics to be considered.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Term. Members of the Review Committee shall serve for a three-year term. All such members may be reappointed or may continue to serve until resignation or their successors have been appointed.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Appointment of Members. Members of the Review Committee shall be appointed by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners after having been selected by the Commission from persons nominated by a Nominating Council established and described herein. The Nominating Council, hereinafter known as the Compensation and Benefits Review Nominating Council, shall be comprised of the following five (5) voting members: three (3) County Commissioners, the Chair of the Social and Economic Development Council, and one representative of a County Collective Bargaining Union. The Members of the Nominating Council shall be appointed by the Chairman of the Board of County Commissioners, who shall designate a Chairperson of the Nominating Council. The County Manager and the County Attorney shall provide appropriate staff support to the Council. The sole function of the Nominating Council shall be to solicit, screen, interview and recommend for appointment the best qualified candidate for each vacancy on the Compensation and Benefits Review Committee. All meetings of the Nominating Council shall be audio recorded and minutes of the proceedings shall be transcribed and maintained by the Clerk of the Board of the County Commission. The Nominating Council shall submit to the Commission a list of nominees containing a total number of names which is equal to one (1) nominee for each vacancy on the CBR Committee plus one (1) alternate nominee. The Commission shall select and appoint the voting members from the list of nominees submitted by the Nominating Council.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Modified Applicability of Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance. The Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance (the "Conflict of Interest Ordinance"), Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall be applicable to the members of the Review Committee only in the manner and to the extent provided in the next sentence. It is declared to be the intent of the Commission, as expressed in this subsection, to provide that the Conflict of Interest Ordinance shall not operate to preclude individuals from serving as Review Committee members on the basis of interests relating to Miami-Dade County when such interests do not conflict, directly or indirectly, with their responsibilities on the Review Committee.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Organization and Procedure. The members of the Review Committee shall elect a chairperson and a vice-chairperson and both shall serve a term of three (3) years. The chairperson may organize the membership of the Review Committee as deemed necessary to conduct its business. The Review Committee shall hold regular meetings no less than four (4) times a year and such other meetings, as it deems necessary. A majority of the members of the board of directors shall constitute a quorum. All meetings of the Review Committee shall be public and the Review Committee shall maintain written minutes of all proceedings that shall be promptly prepared and recorded. Copies of all minutes and resolutions of the Review Committee shall be forwarded to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners no later than thirty (30) days subsequent to any meeting of the Review Committee.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Compensation. Members of the Review Committee shall serve without compensation.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Any member shall be automatically removed if, in a given calendar year, (i) he/she is absent from three (3) consecutive meetings or, (ii) he/she is absent from more than 50% of all the committee meetings held during a year. A member shall be deemed absent when he/she is not present at the meeting for at least 75% of its duration.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 09-109, ยง 1(2), 12-1-09)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2072. Duties of the review committee</catch_line>
<text>
The Review Committee shall have the following duties, responsibilities, and functions.
<section prefix = "a">
To review and make recommendations concerning County personnel costs. The Review Committee shall conduct a comprehensive study of all employee compensation policies, and provide recommendations regarding salaries, wages and benefits. In making such recommendations, the Review Committee shall consider such factors as:
<section prefix = "1">
The current County pay structure as set forth in the adopted County Pay Plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The obligations and commitments adopted in the County's collective bargaining agreements.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The span-of-control ratios for managers and subordinates within the various service areas.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The preferences and desires of County employees as expressed through their collective bargaining representatives.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Comparison of the compensation paid to County employees with the compensation paid to employees of other public employers in the local area.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Comparison of the compensation paid to County employees with the compensation paid to private sector employees in the local area performing similar duties under similar conditions.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
The County's fiscal condition and capacity to meet future personnel obligations.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
The County's need to attract and retain qualified employees in order to provide efficient service to the public.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Policies governing the hiring of individuals separated pursuant to the Deferred Retirement Option Program.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Salary compression between supervisors and subordinates.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
The County's classified civil service rules and other laws and rules designed to protect the rights of its employees.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Policies that govern continuing employment opportunities for civil service employees during periods of a reduction in force.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
To periodically advise the Mayor and the County Commission regarding the appropriate compensation policies to meet the needs of the County, its employees and the public.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
To submit a report in May 2010 and an annual report in February of each year thereafter to the Mayor and the County Commission recommending the appropriate compensation policies for County employees.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
To promulgate rules consistent with this Ordinance for the conduct of its meetings and the discharge of its responsibilities.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
To comply with all laws and regulations of the United States, the State of Florida, and Miami-Dade County, including, but not limited to, the laws relating to the keeping of records including the preservation of all audit rights.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2073. Modifications and term</catch_line>
<text>
It is the intent of the Board of County Commissioners to create by this article and for the purposes set forth in this article, a Review Committee that may be modified or revoked in whole or in part by duly enacted ordinance of the Commission. This Ordinance shall expire three years from its effective date.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2074. Staff and counsel</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager and the County Attorney shall provide such staff support to the Advisory Committee as may be necessary to accomplish its purpose. The Review Committee shall be provided meeting facilities and pre-approved expense reimbursement as the Commission or the County Manager may deem necessary to accomplish the Committee's purposes.
</text>
</law>
