<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="2">ARTICLE_IIA._PARKING_SPACES_FOR_PERSONS_</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-449. Parking spaces for persons transporting young children and strollers</catch_line>
<text>
Parking spaces specifically designed for persons transporting young children under the age of three (3) and strollers, shall be required for all uses other than single-family, duplex, townhouse or multifamily; provided, however, industrial zoned properties shall not be required to comply with this section. Such baby stroller parking spaces shall be provided as follows:
<section prefix = "a">
Quality of specially designated parking spaces:
<section prefix="1" type="table">
<table class="thead1 table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">Total Parking<br />Spaces in Lot</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">Required Number<br />of Spaces</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Up to 100</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">101 to 500</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">501 to 1,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Over 1,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">One (1) additional space for each 500 parking spaces over 1,000</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Location of parking spaces. Such spaces shall be located as closely as possible to parking spaces designated for the physically handicapped and/or disabled persons; provided however, parking spaces designated for the physically handicapped and/or disabled persons shall take precedence. Where no parking spaces designated for the physically handicapped and/or disabled persons have been provided, parking spaces for persons transporting young children and strollers shall be located on the shortest accessible route of travel from adjacent parking to an accessible entrance.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Signage and markings. All parking spaces reserved for persons transporting young children and strollers shall be prominently outlined with green paint and posted with an approved permanent above-ground sign which shall conform to the figure entitled "Baby Stroller Parking Sign" hereby incorporated in this section. The bottom of the sign must be at least five (5) feet above grade when attached to a building, or seven (7) feet above grade for a detached sign.


</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Parking permit required. Such parking spaces shall only be utilized by parking permit holders as specified in Section 30-450 of this Code and only when the permit holder is transporting a young child and a stroller; provided, however, physically handicapped and/or disabled persons displaying a valid handicapped parking permit shall be permitted to utilize parking spaces designated for persons transporting young children and strollers.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-450. Penalty for misuse of specially marked parking spaces</catch_line>
<text>
It is unlawful for any person to stop, stand, or park a vehicle within any parking space designated for persons transporting young children and strollers, unless such vehicle displays a parking permit decal issued pursuant to administrative order, and such vehicle is transporting a child aged two (2) years or less; provided, however, physically handicapped and/or disabled persons displaying a valid handicapped parking permit shall be permitted to utilize parking spaces designated for persons transporting young children and strollers. Whenever a law enforcement officer or a parking enforcement specialist finds a vehicle in violation of this section, that officer or enforcement specialist shall:
<section prefix = "1">
Have the vehicle in violation removed to any lawful parking space or facility or require the operator or other person in charge of the vehicle immediately to remove the unauthorized vehicle from the parking space. Whenever any vehicle is removed by a law enforcement officer, parking enforcement specialist, or agency to a storage lot, garage, or other safe parking space, the cost of such removal and parking shall be a lien against the vehicle, or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Charge the motor vehicle owner in violation with a noncriminal traffic infraction.
<section prefix = "a">
Whenever evidence shall be presented in any court of the fact that any automobile, truck, or other vehicle was found to be parked in a specially designated parking space in violation of this section, it shall be prima facie evidence that the vehicle was parked and left in the space by the person, firm, or corporation in whose name the vehicle is registered and licensed according to the records of the Division of Motor Vehicles.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Violators of this article shall be punished by the maximum fine for a non-moving violation pursuant to Chapter 318, Florida Statutes.

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 30-451—30-460. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (3) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 94-104, § 2, adopted June 7, 1994, amended the Code by the addition of Art. IIA, §§ 3-449 and 30-450. Section 3 of said ordinance provided that within 90 days after the effective date of this ordinance, the County Manager shall develop an administrative order providing standards for producing and issuing parking permits for persons transporting young children and strollers. The administrative order shall also provide a fee for such permit, one-third () of which shall be distributed to private not-for-profit non-denominational agencies providing services for severely abused or neglected children. The administrative order shall provide procedures for application and distribution of such funds. The administrative order shall become effective upon approval by the Board of County Commissioners. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
