<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XV._CONVENIENCE_STORE_SECURITY</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-301. Definition</catch_line>
<text>
The term "convenience store" means any place of business that is engaged in the retail sale of groceries, including the sale of prepared foods, and gasoline and services, that is regularly open for business at any time between the hours of 10 p.m. and 5 a.m., and that is attended during such hours by one (1) employee. The term "convenience store" does not include a store which is solely or primarily a restaurant. The term "convenience store" does not include any store in which the owner and members of his family work in the store between the hours of 10 p.m. and 5 a.m.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-302. Security requirements</catch_line>
<text>
Each convenience store as defined above shall:
<section prefix = "1">
Be equipped with the following security devices:
<section prefix = "a">
A silent alarm that notifies local law enforcement or a private security agency that a robbery is taking place.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A security camera system capable of retrieving an image to assist in the identification and apprehension of a robber.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
A drop safe or cash management device that provides minimum access to the facility's cash receipts.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Lighted parking lots illuminated at an intensity of two (2) footcandles per square foot with a uniformity ratio of no more than five to one (5:1) at eighteen (18) inches above the surface.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Post a conspicuous sign in the convenience store entrance which states that the cash register contains fifty dollars ($50.00) or less.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Maintain window signage so that there is a clear and unobstructed view of the cash register and transaction area.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Prohibit window tinting on the windows of the establishment if such tinting reduces exterior or interior viewing during the hours of operation to which this act is applicable.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Install height markers at the entrance of the establishment which display height measures from the floor.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Establish a cash management policy to limit the amount of available cash on hand between the hours of 9 p.m. and 6 a.m.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-303. Robbery deterrence and safety training for employees</catch_line>
<text>
No later than June 30, 1991, the owner or principal operator of a convenience store shall provide proper robbery deterrence and safety training to at least its employees who work between the hours of 9 p.m. and 6 a.m. Any proposed program of training shall be submitted in writing to the Attorney General. The Attorney General shall review and approve or disapprove of training programs in writing within sixty (60) days after receipt of a proposal describing the training to be provided. The State shall have no liability for approving or disapproving training programs under this section. Approval shall be given to programs which train and familiarize store employees with the security principles, devices, and measures required by Section 8A-302 above. Decisions of the Attorney General relating to approval of training programs shall be subject to the provisions of Chapter 120, Florida Statutes. No person shall be liable for ordinary negligence due to implementing an approved training program, provided that the training was actually provided.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-304. Penalty</catch_line>
<text>
Violation of the provisions of this article shall be punishable by a fine not to exceed five thousand dollars ($5,000.00) provided, however, if noncompliance with the provisions of this article is corrected within ten (10) days after receipt of written notice, no noncompliance fee shall be assessed. Provided further, however, any owner or principle operator of a convenience store who willfully and deliberately violates the requirements of this article or who deliberately fails initially to implement the requirements of this article shall be required to pay to Miami-Dade County, upon complaint filed by the County, a civil fine not to exceed five thousand dollars ($5,000.00).
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 8A-305—8A-324. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (15) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 90-124, adopted Nov. 27, 1990, amended the Code by the addition of provisions which have been designated at the discretion of the editor as Art. XV, §§ 8A-301—8A-304. (Back)
State Law reference— Convenience store security, F.S. § 812.171 et seq. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
