<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XIX._GENDER_PRICE_DISCRIMINATION</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-400. Intent and scope</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It is hereby declared to be the intent of Miami-Dade County, in the exercise of its police power for the public safety, health, and general welfare, to eliminate and prevent price discrimination based on gender in the provision of goods and services in Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
This article shall be effective in both the incorporate and unincorporated Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The provisions of this article shall be cumulative and in addition to and not in derogation of any and all other provisions or laws prohibiting price discrimination based on gender in the provision of goods and services. In the event of a conflict between any of the provisions of this article and any provision of any county or municipal ordinance, the provision which establishes the most stringent standard shall prevail.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 97-53, § 1, 5-20-97)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-401. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
Customer shall mean an individual who inquires about, makes a request for, or purchases a good or service.
Department shall mean Miami-Dade County's Consumer Services Department or its successor department.
Director shall mean the Director of Miami-Dade County's Consumer Services Department or its successor department.
Seller shall mean any individual, business, company, corporation, partnership, sole proprietorship, association, professional association, firm, store, shop, establishment, service, place or building which offers, sells or otherwise makes available to the public any good or service.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-402. Price discrimination prohibited; exemptions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
No seller of a good or service shall charge a customer a different price for a good or service based solely on the customer's gender or the gender of the beneficiary of the good or service.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Nothing in this section prohibits price differences in goods and services based specifically upon the amount of time, difficulty or cost of providing the good or service.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Nothing in this section prohibits bona fide discount programs based on gender classifications so long as such programs are not designed, intended or used to deny any individual or group access to the premises or the right to patronize the premises and such program is for a limited period of time.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Nothing in this section shall alter or affect the Insurance Code of the State of Florida or any other law or provision of the State, County or municipalities which governs health care service plans or insurer underwriting or rating practices.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 97-53, § 1, 5-20-97)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-403. Procedures for filing a complaint</catch_line>
<text>
Any customer aggrieved by a violation of this article may file a written complaint with the Department. The Department shall act upon the complaint in accordance with the Department's established complaint procedures.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-404. Acceptance of assurances of compliance; enforcement procedures; remedies; attorney's fees; costs</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The procedures for accepting assurances of compliance that are set out in Section 8A-82.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, as amended, are incorporated herein and shall be the procedures for accepting assurances of compliance for this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The enforcement procedures, remedies, attorney's fees and costs, that are set out in Section 8A-124 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, as amended, are incorporated herein and shall be the enforcement procedures, remedies, attorney's fees and costs for this article.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 97-53, § 1, 5-20-97)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-405. Private cause of action</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Any person who suffers a loss as result of a violation of any provision of this article may, in addition to any other available remedy, recover compensatory damages, attorney's fees and court costs from the person committing the violation.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Any person who proves the violation of any provision of this article occurred willfully or in bad faith shall recover from the person committing the violation as compensatory damages threefold the actual damages sustained or two hundred dollars ($200.00), whichever is greater, in addition to any other recovery available under law or this article.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 97-53, § 1, 5-20-97)</history>
<catch_line>Secs. 8A-406—8A-410. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
</law>
