<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_V._PUBLIC_NUISANCES_ON_LEASED_PR</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-81. Legislative findings and intent</catch_line>
<text>
This article is enacted pursuant to the provisions of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter and Florida Statutes, Section 893.138, as it may be renumbered or amended from time to time.
The Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, hereby finds and declares that any places or premises which are used by tenants as the site of the unlawful sale or delivery of controlled substances, prostitution, youth and street gang activity, gambling, illegal sale or consumption of alcoholic beverages, or lewd or lascivious behavior, may be a public nuisance that adversely affects the public health, safety, morals, and welfare and renders that tenant subject to eviction. This Board also finds that it is the responsibility of landlords to take any reasonable measures to evict tenants who engage in such public nuisances on leased property and that imposing such a requirement will improve the quality of life of the residents of Miami-Dade County and safeguard the public health, safety, and welfare.
This article is hereby declared to be remedial and essential to the public interest and it is intended that this article be liberally construed to effect the purposes as stated above. The provisions of this article and the standards set forth herein shall be applicable only to the unincorporated areas of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, Florida.
The provisions of this article shall be cumulative and supplemental to and not in derogation of any provision of the Florida Statutes, the Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, or any other applicable law.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-82. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
[As used in this article the following words and terms shall have the meanings respectively ascribed:]
<section prefix = "1">
Dwelling unit means:
<section prefix = "a">
A structure or part of a structure that is rented for use as a home, residence, or sleeping place by one person or by two or more persons who maintain a common household.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A mobile home rented by a tenant.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
A structure or part of a structure that is furnished, with or without rent, as an incident of employment for use as a home, residence, or sleeping place by one or more persons.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Landlord means the owner or lessor of a dwelling unit.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Tenant means any person entitled to occupy a dwelling unit under a rental agreement.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Premises means a dwelling unit and the structure of which it is a part and a mobile home lot and the appurtenant facilities and grounds, areas, facilities, and property held out for the use of tenants generally.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Public nuisance means any place or premise which within a six-month period has been used on more than two (2) occasions:
<section prefix = "a">
As the site of the unlawful sale or delivery of controlled substances, or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
By a youth and street gang for the purpose of conducting a patter of youth and street gang activity, or
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
For prostitution, or solicitation of prostitution, or
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
For illegal gambling, or
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
For the illegal sale or consumption of alcoholic beverages, or
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
For lewd or lascivious behavior, or
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Any premise or place declared to be a nuisance by Florida Statute, Section 823.05 or Section 823.10 as they may be renumbered or amended from time to time.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Rental agreement means any written agreement, or oral agreement if for less duration than one (1) year, providing for use and occupancy of premises.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-83. Tenant's obligation to maintain dwelling unit</catch_line>
<text>
In addition to those requirements imposed by Section 83.52, Florida Statutes, tenant shall not use the premises or any part thereof for the purposes of engaging in any public nuisance.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-84. Termination</catch_line>
<text>
In addition to the rights and remedies granted by Chapter 83.56, Florida Statutes, if a tenant materially fails to comply with the provisions of Section 17-83 above, the landlord may terminate the rental agreement in the manner provided by Chapter 83, Florida Statutes.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-85. Aiding in the maintenance of a nuisance penalized</catch_line>
<text>
Whoever, by himself, his servant, clerk or agent, knowingly allows or permits premises owned by him or under his control to be used for a public nuisance, or after due notice of any such use fails to take all reasonable measures to either abate the nuisance or terminate the rental agreement and to evict therefrom the persons occupying said premises, shall be punished by fine of not more than five hundred dollars ($500.00) or imprisonment for no more than sixty (60) days. A person will be deemed to have knowledge of such public nuisance if the resident manager, superintendent of the premises, resident agent, or any other person designated by the landlord to manage, control or operate the premises has such knowledge.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-86. Exercise of police power</catch_line>
<text>
It is deemed by the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida, that this article is necessary and lawful exercise of the police power of the County for the protection of the public health, welfare, and safety of the people of Miami-Dade County and shall be liberally construed to accomplish such purposes.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 17-87—17-100. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (6) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 94-113, § 1, adopted June 9, 1994, amended the Code by the addition of Section 17-8, which provisions have been included herein at the discretion of the editor as Art. V, §§ 17-81—17-86. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
