<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_V._FINANCE_DEPARTMENT</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-57. Established; Director of Finance as head; appointment; term; operating procedures; compensation of employees</catch_line>
<text>
A Finance Department is hereby established. The head of this Department is the Director of Finance. The Director shall be appointed by and serve at the will of the Manager. The organization and operating procedures of the Department shall be prescribed by administrative orders and regulations of the Manager. The Manager shall appoint such employees as may be necessary to operate the Department. The compensation of all personnel, except employees with the classified service, shall be fixed by the Commission upon recommendation of the Manager.
</text>
A Finance Department is hereby established. The head of this Department is the Director of Finance. The Director shall be appointed by and serve at the will of the Manager. The organization and operating procedures of the Department shall be prescribed by administrative orders and regulations of the Manager. The Manager shall appoint such employees as may be necessary to operate the Department. The compensation of all personnel, except employees with the classified service, shall be fixed by the Commission upon recommendation of the Manager.
Charter reference— Authority of Manager to issue and place into effect administrative orders, rules and regulations and to prescribe the organization and operating procedure of departments of the County, § 4.02.
<catch_line>Sec. 2-58. Powers and duties</catch_line>
<text>
The Finance Department shall be responsible for the financial affairs of the County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-58.1. Annual leave payments; prepayment authorized; rules and procedures</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Finance Director is authorized to pay any employee or officer whose salary is disbursed by Miami-Dade County for the period of accrued annual leave granted the employee or officer, before the start of the annual leave, upon receipt of an appropriate request.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Finance Director is authorized to establish such rules and procedures as may be necessary to implement this provision.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 67-62, §§ 1, 2, 9-6-67)</history>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (15) ---
Annotations—AO's 3-1, 3-2, 3-3, 3-4, 3-6, 5-4, 8-1, 9-1. AO's of 4-19-83, 2-7-89. (Back)
Charter reference— Financial administration, § 4.03; bids and purchasing procedure, § 4.03(D); assessment and collection of taxes, § 4.04. (Back)
Cross reference— Taxation, Ch. 29. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
