<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_VII._TAX_REVIEW_BOARD</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-68. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
Sec. 2-68. Reserved.
Editor's note—
Section 2-68, pertaining to the short title of Article VII Tax Review Board, has been deleted as obsolete. The section was derived from Ord. No. 67-1, § 1, adopted Jan. 10, 1967.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-69. Election of the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County; Establishing Qualifying Period and Fee and Residency Requirements; Commencement of Term; Compliance with the Ethical Campaign Requirements Ordinance; Restricting Corporate Campaign Contributions; Vacancy in Office</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The duties of the Property Appraiser, previously carried out under the supervision of the Mayor, are transferred to the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County, who shall be elected pursuant to Section 5.04 of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, effective upon the commencement of the term of office of the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Commencing with the general election held on November 4, 2008, the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall be elected by a majority of the qualified electors voting at a countywide election held within Miami-Dade County, Florida. If no candidate receives a majority vote of qualified electors voting at the November 4, 2008 election, the Commission shall call a countywide runoff election to be held prior to January 1, 2009. Every four years thereafter, the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall be elected at a countywide election by a majority of the qualified electors voting at such election held in conjunction with the Miami-Dade County state Primary election. If no candidate receives a majority of the votes cast, there will be a runoff election at the time of the general election following the state primary election between the two (2) candidates receiving the highest number of votes. Should a tie result, the outcome shall be determined by lot.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
For the general election held on November 4, 2008, all candidates seeking election as the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall qualify using the method provided by ordinance no earlier than noon on the 84th day and no later than noon on the 68th day prior to the date of the election at which he or she is a candidate. Every four years thereafter, all candidates seeking election as the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall qualify using the method provided by ordinance with the Clerk of the Circuit Court no earlier than the 84th day and no later than noon on the 70th day prior to the date of the election at which he or she is a candidate. Each candidate for Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall pay a filing fee of five thousand dollars ($5,000.00). All filing fees shall be paid into the general funds of the county. Each candidate for Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall be a qualified elector residing within Miami-Dade County for at least three (3) years before qualifying.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
All candidates seeking election as the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall comply with the Ethical Campaign Practices Ordinance codified at Section 2-11.1.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
It is unlawful for any candidate, political committee, or other person in connection with the election of any candidate for the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County to knowingly accept or receive any contribution from a corporation incorporated under the laws of the State of Florida or any other state or any foreign country or any partnership or any other legal entity other than a natural person ("Contributing Entity") unless: (1) the Contributing Entity discloses to the campaign treasurer of the campaign receiving the contribution all real and personal property assessed for taxes in Miami-Dade County which is owned by the Contributing Entity, or a parent or subsidiary of the Contributing Entity, or any entity which has the same parent entity as the Contributing Entity; and (2) the campaign treasurer reports, on a form provided by the Supervisor of Elections, all real and personal property assessed for taxes in Miami-Dade County which is owned by the Contributing Entity, or a parent or subsidiary of the Contributing Entity, or any entity which has the same parent entity as the Contributing Entity to the Supervisor of Elections at the same time the campaign treasurer reports the contribution. In addition to any other penalties which may be applicable, any person who violates this subsection shall be punishable by a fine up to five hundred dollars ($500.00) or imprisonment not to exceed sixty days, or both. Contributions made prior to the effective date of this ordinance shall be reported in accordance with the requirements of this subsection on or before the next required reporting date. It shall also be unlawful for a candidate for property appraiser to knowingly use or permit the use of campaign material that falsifies, distorts, or misrepresents the property appraiser's ability to appraise property in a manner which is in violation of state law.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The term of office of the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall commence on the first Tuesday after the first Monday in January following his or her election.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
In the event of any vacancy in office of the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County, the person appointed by the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County as his or her deputy or next in authority shall act as the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County. The person serving as the acting Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall meet the eligibility requirements for the office unless waived by the Board of County Commissioners by resolution. The person acting as the Property Appraiser shall serve only until the next countywide election. A person elected at such countywide or runoff election, if necessary, shall serve for the remainder of the unexpired term of office vacated by the Property Appraiser.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 08-62, § 1, 5-20-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-70. Duties and Powers of the Property Appraiser</catch_line>
<text>
The Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall serve as the head of the Office of the Property Appraiser with the following specific powers and responsibilities:
<section prefix = "1">
The Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall perform the duties and functions pertaining to assessing all property in Miami-Dade County as required by and in accordance with the Florida Constitution and Florida Statutes, including but not limited to the following specific responsibilities:
<section prefix = "a">
Annual determination of exempt status, classification and valuation of real and personal property in Miami-Dade County;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Preparation of real and personal property tax rolls.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Delivery of real and personal property tax rolls to the Department of Revenue and taxing authorities within Miami-Dade County;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Certification of value to all taxing authorities for purposes of preparation of budget[s] and adoption of millage[s].
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Mailing of TRIM ("Truth and Responsibility in Millage") notices to all property owners in Miami-Dade County under the mark, brand or seal of the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Certification of the assessment rolls to the Tax Collector.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Completion of any pending or unfinished tasks or duties that were originally begun or undertaken by the Miami-Dade County Property Appraisal Department or the predecessor Property Appraiser.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Property Appraiser may sue and be sued in his or her name and official capacity in cases involving assessment challenges or related issues. Any suit by or against the Property Appraiser may be settled or compromised by the Property Appraiser and the County Attorney or their designees, if the Property Appraiser and County Attorney determine that said settlement or compromise is in the best interests of Miami-Dade County after considering the legal liability, potential litigation expenses, potential financial exposure of the County and the precedential effect of such litigation. The settlement of all such litigation shall be reported quarterly to the County Commission.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Property Appraiser, upon request of the Mayor and/or the County Manager, shall provide the proposed budget for purposes of preparing the budget for the Office which will be considered by the Board of County Commissioners in its adoption of the County's annual budget.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The Property Appraiser may enter into interdepartmental agreements with other County departments as may be necessary to carry out the purposes and provisions of this ordinance.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The Property Appraiser may enter into agreements with third parties, subject to approval by the Board of County Commissioners. Such approval, however, shall not be required if funds for the agreement are within the Property Appraiser's approved budget. Contracts and purchases by the Property Appraiser shall not require competitive bids when the transaction involves funds within the Property Appraiser's approved budget, provided the contract or purchase is made in accordance with the provisions of this section. Contracts and purchases exceeding the Property Appraiser's approved budget may be made by the Board of County Commissioners in accordance with the provisions of the Code. The Property Appraiser shall be authorized to contract for the purchase of goods and services subject only to the requirements of the procurement policy set forth in the implementing order approved by resolution of this Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
The Property Appraiser may submit proposed resolutions, ordinances or reports related to his or her duties to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners and such items shall be placed on the next available agenda of the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
The Property Appraiser may become associated with The Florida Association of Property Appraisers; The Property Appraisers' Association of Florida and/or such other organizations dedicated to supporting and advocating on behalf of Property Appraisers in the State of Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
The Property Appraiser, in order to make a determination regarding the exempt status, classification, or valuation of real and personal property in Miami-Dade County, may request the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners to issue subpoenas to compel the attendance of witnesses and the production of any books, letters, or other documentary evidence required by the Property Appraiser in the performance of such duties. At the request of the Property Appraiser, the Chairperson of the Commission may issue said process on behalf of the Board of County Commissioners. Prior to requesting the issuance of a subpoena, the Property Appraiser shall notify the State Attorney and the U.S. Attorney for the Southern District of Florida. The Property Appraiser shall not request the issuance of a subpoena where the State Attorney, the U.S. Attorney for the Southern District of Florida, or other law enforcement agency notifies the Property Appraiser in writing that the subpoena will interfere with an ongoing criminal investigation. The Property Appraiser may seek enforcement of such process issued under the authority of this section by filing a petition for enforcement in the County Court of Miami-Dade County, Florida, or other appropriate cause of action in any court of competent jurisdiction. Any person who willfully fails or neglects to attend and testify or to answer any lawful inquiry, or to produce records, documents or other evidence, if in his or her power to do so, may be fined by the County Court of Miami-Dade County, Florida or other court of competent jurisdiction, not more than five hundred dollars ($500.00) or imprisoned not more than sixty (60) days, or both. Any person who, with intent thereby to mislead, makes or causes to be made any false entry or statement of fact in any report, account, record or other document submitted pursuant to this section, or who shall willfully neglect or fail to make, or cause to be made, full, true and correct entries in such reports, accounts, records or other documents, or who shall willfully mutilate, alter or by any other means falsify any documentary evidence, may be fined by the County Court of Miami-Dade County, Florida, or other court of competent jurisdiction, not more than five hundred dollars ($500.00) or imprisoned not more than sixty (60) days, or both.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
The Property Appraiser may perform any other lawful acts which the Property Appraiser may consider necessary or desirable in carrying out the purposes and provisions of this ordinance.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-71. Applicability of County Ordinances to the Property Appraiser</catch_line>
<text>
The Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall be subject to the ordinances of Miami-Dade County to the same extent as other department directors of Miami-Dade County, including, but not limited to, the Code of Ethics and Conflict of Interest Ordinance codified at Section 2-11.1 et seq. of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, Section 2-1076 et seq. of the Code relating to the Office of the Inspector General, and Section 2-1795 of the Code relating to the County's annual budget. The Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall devote his or her full time service to the office of Property Appraiser and shall not be otherwise employed.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-72. The Property Appraiser's Salary, Compensation and Benefits</catch_line>
<text>
The salary, compensation and benefits of the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County for 2009 shall be one hundred fifty-three thousand dollars ($153,000.00) and he or she shall receive Class 1 Executive Benefits and thereafter salary, compensation and benefits shall be fixed annually by the Board of County Commissioners.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-73. Employees of the Office of the Property Appraiser; Salary, Compensation and Benefits of Such Employees; Use of County Facilities and Services. County Attorney's Office to Provide Legal Counsel</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Upon the commencement of the term of office of the elected Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County elected in November, 2008, the employees assigned to the Property Appraisal department prior to the election of the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall be assigned to the Office of the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County (the "Office"). From that point forward, the Property Appraiser shall have the authority to select all employees of the Office, in accordance with the provisions of the Code and Personnel Rules. Upon selection by the Property Appraiser of an employee for a position in the County's classified service and compliance with the requirements of the Code and Personnel Rules for the appointment of personnel, the Mayor shall formally appoint the selected employee to the County's classified service. The Property Appraiser shall have the authority to directly appoint employees to all positions in the Office which are exempt from the County's classified service. The elected Property Appraiser shall have the authority to hire, evaluate, promote, demote, discipline or discharge Office employees; provided, however, that employees shall continue to have the right to challenge or appeal such decisions on the same terms as other County employees. The Office of the Property Appraiser shall continue to honor and abide by the terms of any existing collective bargaining agreement and to negotiate any changes in such agreement in accordance with state law.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The salaries, compensation and benefits of all Office employees shall be fixed by the County Commission upon recommendation of the Property Appraiser, subject to the provisions of any applicable collective bargaining agreement. Except for the purpose of transmitting constituent inquiries, budgeting, funding and carrying out other functions required by this ordinance, the Property Appraiser shall perform his or her duties without supervision or interference from the Mayor or the County Manager.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall utilize general County services and facilities, including but not limited to, purchasing, centralized computer services, general services administration, and personnel. Legal services shall be provided by the County Attorney's Office.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 08-62, § 1, 5-20-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-73.1. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Section 2-73.1, pertaining to the deadline for modification of assessments because of errors in judgment, has been deleted as obsolete. The section was derived from Ord. No. 67-1, § 5, adopted Jan. 10, 1967 and Ord. No. 71-3, § 5, adopted Jan. 6, 1971.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-73.2. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Section 2-73.2, pertaining to the extension of deadlines for the performance of duties by the Tax Assessment Department and the Tax Review Board has been deleted as obsolete. The section was derived from Ord. No. 68-24, § 1, adopted May 7, 1968.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-73.3. Publication in Spanish, and Haitian Creole of information about certain countywide tax, special assessment, and fee notices</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It is the official policy of Miami-Dade County that information about certain legal notices regarding taxes, special assessments, and fees that are published or delivered in English also be published or delivered in Spanish and Haitian Creole to the communities that speak Spanish or Haitian Creole.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
This policy applies when:
<section prefix = "1">
There is an increase or creation of a tax, special assessment, or fee;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The tax, special assessment, or fee is countywide;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Notice of such increase or creation is legally required by statute to be published or delivered; and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The legally required notice is published or delivered in English.
In addition, when it is reasonably foreseeable that the creation or increase of a tax, special assessment, or fee that is less than countywide in scope will impact a substantial number of persons who speak Spanish or Haitian Creole, efforts shall be made to provide information in Spanish or Haitian Creole about any legally-required notices which are published or delivered in English.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
This policy does not require a word-for-word translation of the legal notice, but only the publication or delivery of information about such notice. Such information may include a reference to sources such as the 311 call center or the Miami-Dade County Web Pages for more precise information. This policy does not require the publication of the budget book in any language other than English.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The official in charge of providing the legal notice shall have discretion to determine the best and most cost effective method to provide information about the notice in Spanish and Haitian Creole.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
This additional information is intended to supplement and not replace formal legal notice as required by governing law. Any mistakes or failure to provide such supplemental information, therefore, shall not provide a basis to challenge any legal action taken pursuant to the formal legal notice.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 09-51, § 1, 6-30-09)</history>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (17) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 67-1, § 8, adopted Jan. 10, 1967, changed the title of Article VII from "Reassessment Advisory Board" to "Tax Review Board." (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
