<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXX._COMMISSION_FOR_WOMEN</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-264. Short title</catch_line>
<text>
This article enacted under and pursuant to the provisions of the Home Rule Charter of Government for Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall be known and may be cited as the "Miami-Dade County Commission for Women Ordinance".
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-265. Commission for Women</catch_line>
<text>
The Miami-Dade County Commission for Women is hereby created and established. The Commission shall consist of twenty-seven (27) members appointed by the County Commission. The Office of the Chairperson of the County Commission shall provide appropriate support for the Commission for Women. The Chairperson of the County Commission shall have the power to appoint employ, remove and supervise such assistants, employees, and personnel as deemed necessary to provide appropriate support to the Commission for Women, and such assistants, employees, and personnel shall serve at the will of the Chairperson of the County Commission.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-266. Qualifications of members</catch_line>
<text>
Members of the Commission shall be permanent residents of Miami-Dade County. Members, while serving, shall not become candidates for election to any public office. In order to secure representative membership upon the Commission, each of the eight (8) County Commissioners shall appoint three (3) members to the Commission and the Mayor shall appoint three (3) members to the Commission.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-267. Terms of office</catch_line>
<text>
In order that the terms of Office of all members of the Commission shall not expire at the same time, the initial appointments to the Commission shall be as follows: The Mayor and the County Commissioners shall each appoint one (1) member to the Commission for a term of one (1) year, one (1) member to the Commission for a term of two (2) years, and one (1) member to the Commission for a term of three (3) years. The Chairman shall be elected by the members of the Commission for a one (1) year term. Thereafter all appointments shall be made for a term of four (4) years. Appointments to fill any vacancy on the Commission shall be for the remainder of the unexpired term of office. A member may be removed without cause only by three-fourths vote of the entire membership of the County Commission. When any member of the Commission fails to attend three (3) consecutive meetings without due cause, the Chairman shall certify the same to the County Commission. Such member shall then be deemed to have been removed and a vacancy created.
Terms of office, of members of the Commission appointed by the Board of County Commissioners, which would normally expire on or between the dates of January 1 through June 30, or July 1 through December 31 of the termination year, shall be deemed ended and expired as of March 31 or September 30 thereof respectively; and the position thereon vacated may be refilled by the Board of County Commissioners.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-268. Organization of the Commission</catch_line>
<text>
The members of the Commission shall elect such officers other than a Chairman as may be deemed necessary or desirable, who shall serve at the will of the Commission. Fourteen (14) members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum necessary to hold a meeting and take any action. Members shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties, upon approval by the County Commission. The Chairman may call meetings of the Commission, and meetings may be called by written notice signed by fourteen (14) members and the Commission at any meeting may fix and call a meeting on a future date. Minutes shall be kept of all meetings of the Commission. All meetings shall be public.
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 71-51, § 1, amended § 5 of Ord. No. 70-11, codified as § 2-268, by substituting "fourteen (14)" in lieu of "seventeen (17)".
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-269. Duties and powers of the Commission</catch_line>
<text>
The Commission shall have the following duties, functions, powers and responsibilities:
<section prefix = "a">
To serve in an advisory capacity to the County Commission, the County administration, the community, and all agencies and persons in Miami-Dade County, Florida, in respect to all matters pertaining to the status of women, including but not limited to discrimination against women, employment of women, education of women, establishment of day care centers in the community, and attitudes towards women in the community, and to make periodic reports and recommendations to these bodies in respect to such matters.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
To make a continuing study of all existing County institutions, facilities and services, and programs dealing with women or affecting women, and consider the future needs of this metropolitan area in respect to such institutions, facilities, services and programs.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
To serve as liaison between the County Commission and the County administration, and consult with representatives of said bodies from time to time as requested and necessary in order to carry out the Commission's duties and functions.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
To make studies and have studies made of the problems of discrimination against women employees, increasing the availability of part-time employment for women, establishment of day care centers in the community, and attributable changes towards women in the community, and to formulate and recommend plans and programs for the coordination of the activities of all governmental entities and nongovernmental agencies dealing with these problems.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
It is the express purpose of this Commission to serve as a medium for responsible persons to utilize and consult with in attempting to understand and solve the many complex problems involved with dealing with the status of women, and to make findings and recommendations to the County Commission and the County administration regarding such matters as are presented to the Commission.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
To establish the Miami-Dade County Commission for Women Trust Fund (hereinafter referred to as "Trust Fund") in which will be placed all donations, contributions and funds received by the Commission for Women. The funds placed into the Trust Fund shall be used only to fund conferences, projects and special events which further the purposes of the Miami-Dade County Commission for Women.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
To perform such other duties as may from time to time be assigned to it by resolution of the County Commission.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-270. Limitation of powers</catch_line>
<text>
The powers and jurisdiction of the Commission shall be purely advisory, voluntary, and persuasive. The Commission shall not have any power or authority to subpoena or compel the attendance of witnesses. The Commission shall have no power to appoint County officers or employees or to make policy decisions, or to manage, control or administer institutions or programs relating to the status of women in Miami-Dade County.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (51) ---
Editor's note— Article XXX, §§ 2-264—2-270, is derived from Ord. No. 71-11, §§ 1—7, enacted Jan. 19, 1971, which ordinance was codified pursuant to § 9 thereof. Ord. No. 99-35, § 1, adopted April 13, 1999, changed the title of article XXX from "Commission on the Status of Women" to "Commission for Women." (Back)
Cross reference— Discrimination, Ch. 11A. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
