<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="2">ARTICLE_XIV._BACKGROUND_CHECKS_FOR_PERSO</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-281. For whom investigation is required</catch_line>
<text>
All operators and personnel of child care facilities and day care homes, as defined in Section 402.302(4) and (5), Florida Statutes, respectively; and facilities for persons with intellectual disabilities, specifically day facilities for persons with intellectual disabilities as defined in Section 393.063(4), Florida Statutes; developmental training facilities for persons with intellectual disabilities as defined in Section 393.063(7), Florida Statutes; foster care facilities for persons with intellectual disabilities as defined in Section 393.063(12), Florida Statutes; group home facilities for persons with intellectual disabilities as defined in Section 393.063(13), Florida Statutes; intermediate care facilities for persons with intellectual disabilities, as defined in Section 393.063(15), Florida Statutes; major State intellectual disability facilities, as defined in Section 393.063(16), Florida Statutes; and residential habilitation centers for persons with intellectual disabilities as defined in Section 393.063(22), Florida Statutes shall apply to the Miami-Dade Police Department for a criminal background investigation within thirty (30) days from the enactment of Ordinance No. 85-1 or five (5) days from employment at the facility, whichever is later.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-282. Application for and extent of investigation</catch_line>
<text>
The Miami-Dade Police Department shall provide an application form, which will require the submission of identifying information by the applicant, including name, past name, aliases, sex, race, date of birth, place of birth, Social Security number and physical description. The application, which must be sworn to by each applicant, shall contain an authorization to conduct and release, as allowed by law, a background investigation report, showing whether the applicant has a record of any arrests or convictions within the State of Florida, an outstanding warrant for his or her arrest, or is named on a wanted list and the nature of the offense with which the applicant is connected. An applicant must present two (2) forms of identification to the Miami-Dade Police Department at the time of application. Each application shall also be accompanied by an application fee which shall be utilized to defray the cost of conducting the background investigation and enforcing the provisions of this article. The fee to be charged shall be established by administrative order. Upon receipt of a fully completed application, the Miami-Dade Police Department will provide a receipt of application to the applicant and the facility at which the applicant is employed. Upon receipt of a fully completed application form, the Miami-Dade Police Department shall conduct a background investigation, which shall be concluded within sixty (60) days of the date an application is received and shall mail a copy of the report derived from the investigation to the applicant, the facility at which the applicant is employed, and the Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services, State of Florida.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-283. Two-year effective period of investigation</catch_line>
<text>
The applicant shall have his or her application report renewed and a new background investigation performed every two (2) years from the date of the initial report by applying to the Miami-Dade Police Department. The background investigation report may be updated from time to time at the option of the Miami-Dade Police Department. An updated investigation report may be distributed in accordance with the provisions of this article.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-284. Records to be kept by facilities</catch_line>
<text>
Upon receipt of the notice of applications from the Miami-Dade Police Department, the operators of child care facilities or facilities for persons with intellectual disabilities shall maintain the receipts of application for all personnel of such facilities in a file located at the premises of the facility. Upon receipt of the criminal investigation report from the Miami-Dade Police Department, operators of child care facilities, day care homes or facilities for persons with intellectual disabilities, shall maintain the investigation reports on file for all personnel. It shall be unlawful for any operator to operate a child care facility or facility for persons with intellectual disabilities, unless the receipts of application and investigation reports are maintained in accordance with the provisions of this section.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-285. Reports available for inspection—Notice posted in facility</catch_line>
<text>
The operator of a child care facility, day care home or facility for persons with intellectual disabilities shall post a notice that receipts of application and background investigation reports, when available, are open for public inspection. Such notice must be posted in a conspicuous place at the premises of the facility. It shall be unlawful for any operator to operate a child care facility, day care home or facility for persons with intellectual disabilities, unless such notice is posted in accordance with the provisions of this section.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-286. Same—Notice on application for admission</catch_line>
<text>
The operator of a child care facility, day care home or facility for persons with intellectual disabilities shall provide notice on the application for admission to such facility that receipts of applications and criminal investigation reports, when available, are open for public inspection. It shall be unlawful for any operator to operate a child care facility, day care home or facility for persons with intellectual disabilities, unless such notice is provided in accordance with the provisions of this section.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-287. Penalty</catch_line>
<text>
Every person who is convicted for a violation of Sections 8A-284, 8A-285 or 8A-286 shall be punished as provided in Section 1-5.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 8A-288—8A-300. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (14) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 85-1, adopted Jan. 8, 1985, amended the Code but did not specify Code section numbers to be assigned; therefore, codification as Art. XIV of Ch. 8A has been at the editor's discretion. Section 11 of the ordinance, as amended by Ord. No. 85-65, provides for termination of its provisions on December 31, 1985, unless otherwise extended. (Back)
Cross reference— Nonpublic educational and child care facilities, § 33-151.11 et seq. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
