<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_I._CABLE_TELEVISION_REGULATIONS</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-1. Intent and purpose</catch_line>
<text>
It is the intent of the County to promote the public health, safety, and general welfare by providing for the control of cable systems in incorporated and unincorporated Miami-Dade County; to provide for the payment of fees and other valuable consideration by a licensee to the County for the privilege of using public rights-of-way for constructing and operating a cable system; to promote widespread availability of cable service to County residents; to encourage the provision of diverse information to the community over cable; and to establish minimum standards for the regulation and performance of cable systems in Miami-Dade County for all cable television licenses granted or renewed after the effective date of this chapter [Ordinance No. 90-104].
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-1.1. Name and scope</catch_line>
<text>
This chapter shall be known as the "Miami-Dade County 1990 Cable Ordinance." It shall be applicable to all licenses issued on or after the date this chapter is passed. Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to interfere with the rights, if any, vested in a licensed cable operator pursuant to a Miami-Dade County cable license that has not expired or pursuant to federal law. The following provisions are considered quasi-contractual: 8AA-3, 8AA-4, 8AA-7, 8AA-8, 8AA-9, 8AA-10, 8AA-11, 8AA-12, 8AA-13, 8AA-14, 8AA-16, 8AA-18, 8AA-20, 8AA-21, 8AA-22, 8AA-24, 8AA-25, 8AA-26, 8AA-27(1), 8AA-28.1, 8AA-38(b), 8AA-48, 8AA-49, 8AA-50, 8AA-52, 8AA-53, 8AA-54, 8AA-55, 8AA-56, 8AA-63(a)(2), 8AA-68, 8AA-69, 8AA-70, 8AA-71, 8AA-72, 8AA-77, 8AA-78. The remaining provisions are considered quasi-regulatory in nature rather than quasi-contractual and therefore shall apply to all licenses regardless of when they were issued or renewed.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-2. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
Any word or term defined in the Communications Act but not defined below shall have the meaning set forth in the Communications Act.
<section prefix = "a">
Communications Act shall mean the federal Communications Act of 1934, 47 U.S.C. para. 151 et seq. as amended by the Cable Communications Policy Act of 1984, the Cable Television Consumer Protection and Competition Act of 1992, and the Telecommunications Act of 1996, and as those Acts may be hereinafter be amended (collectively the "Communications Act").
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Cable service shall mean the one-way transmission to subscribers of video programming or other programming services, and the subscriber interaction, if any, which is required for the selection or use of such video programming or other programming service.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Cable system shall mean a facility consisting of a set of closed transmission paths and associated signal generation, reception, and control equipment that is designed to provide cable service which includes video programming and which is provided to multiple subscribers within a community, but such term does not include:
<section prefix = "1">
A facility that serves only to retransmit the television signal of one (1) or more television broadcast stations;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
A facility that serves subscribers without using any public right-of-way;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
A facility of a common carrier which is subject, in whole or in part, to the provisions of Title II of the Communications Act, except that such facility shall be considered a cable system (other than for purposes of Section 621(c) of the Communications Act) to the extent such facility is used in the transmission of video programming directly to subscribers unless the extent of such use is solely to provide interactive on demand services;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Any facilities of any electric utility used solely for operating its electric utility systems; or
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
An open video system that complies with Section 653 of the Telecommunications Act, as amended.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Channel or cable channel shall mean those channels engineered at the headend of a cable system for the provision of cable services generally available to subscribers of the cable system, regardless of whether such services are actually provided, including any channels designated for public, educational, or governmental use.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Commission shall mean the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, or its representative.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Reserved.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
County shall mean Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
County Manager shall mean the Miami-Dade County Manager, as appointed by the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County.
(i1)
Director shall mean the Consumer Services Department Director or the Director's designee.
(i2)
Distribution system shall include all means of transmission of all signals.
<section prefix = "j">
