<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="2">ARTICLE_CXIX._BUILDING_BETTER_COMMUNITIE</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1801. Authority and purpose</catch_line>
<text>
There is created and established pursuant to the Home Rule Amendment and Charter of Miami-Dade County, as amended, an advisory committee of Miami-Dade County to be known as the Building Better Communities Citizens' Advisory Committee ("Advisory Committee"). The Advisory Committee is established solely for the purpose of advising the Mayor, the Board of County Commissioners ("Commission") and the County Manager regarding the Building Better Communities General Obligation Bond Program ("Bond Program"). The Advisory Committee may exercise only those duties specifically granted in this Article or necessary in the exercise of the duties enumerated in this Article.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1802. Advisory Committee</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Membership and Appointment. The Advisory Committee shall be comprised of twenty-one (21) members. The Mayor shall appoint three (3) members, each Commissioner shall appoint one member and the remaining five (5) at-large members shall be selected by the County Manager.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Qualifications. Each member shall be a resident of Miami-Dade County; shall possess an outstanding reputation for civic pride, integrity, responsibility and business or professional ability; and shall have no financial interest, direct or indirect, in any of the programs or projects that are part of the Bond Program. The membership of the Advisory Committee should generally reflect the geographic, ethnic, racial and gender make-up of the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Term. Mayoral appointed and District members of the Advisory Committee shall serve until the respective appointing authority, Mayor or Commissioner, leaves office, or until resignation, whichever occurs first. All such members may be reappointed or may continue to serve until resignation or their successors have been appointed.
The five (5) at-large members selected by the County Manager shall hold office for a term of five (5) years, or until resignation, whichever comes first and may be re-appointed for up to two (2) additional five (5) year terms.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Vacancies. The Mayor and each Commissioner shall appoint or re-appoint a member within forty-five (45) days of taking office or in the event of their appointee's resignation. All at-large member vacancies shall be filled by the County Manager within forty-five (45) days of the resignation of the member.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Modified applicability of Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance. The Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance (the "Conflict of Interest Ordinance"), Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall be applicable to the members of the Advisory Committee only in the manner and to the extent provided in the next sentence. It is declared to be the intent of the Commission, as expressed in this subsection, to provide that the Conflict of Interest Ordinance shall not operate to preclude individuals from serving as Advisory Committee members on the basis of interests relating to Miami-Dade County when such interests do not conflict, directly or indirectly, with the Bond Program.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Organization and Procedure. The members shall elect a chairperson and a vice-chairperson and both shall serve a term of two (2) years. The members shall also elect other officers as the members determine to be necessary and such officers shall also serve a term of two (2) years.
The Advisory Committee shall hold regular meetings no less than four (4) times a year and such other meetings, as it deems necessary. A majority of the members of the board of directors shall constitute a quorum. All meetings of the Advisory Committee shall be public and the Advisory Committee shall maintain written minutes of all proceedings that shall be promptly prepared and recorded. Copies of all minutes and resolutions of the Advisory Committee shall be forwarded to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners no later than thirty (30) days subsequent to any meeting of the Advisory Committee.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Compensation. Members of the Advisory Board shall serve without compensation.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 05-70, § 1, 4-5-05)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1803. Duties of the Advisory Committee</catch_line>
<text>
The Advisory Committee shall have the following duties, responsibilities, and functions.
<section prefix = "1">
To review and monitor performance and program achievements related to the Bond Program.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To periodically advise the Mayor, the County Commission and County Manager, and assist in informing the community regarding the Building Better Communities General Obligation Bond Program's accomplishments on projects as approved by the electorate on November 2, 2004.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
To assist in the preparation of quarterly reports to the Mayor and the County Commission, and annual written report to the community describing the progress of the Building Better Communities General Obligation Bond Program. The Advisory Committee may also periodically provide advice, by either a written resolution or oral presentation, as may be requested by the County Commission, at regularly scheduled Commission meetings in accordance with the terms of this Ordinance.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
To advise on the use of any surplus bond project funds or unspent allocations derived from those projects specifically identified in Resolution Numbers R-912-04, R-913-04, R-914-04, R-915-04, R-916-04, R-917-04, R-918-04, and R-919-04, and set forth in informational pamphlets and media releases distributed by the County to the public prior to said election.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
To participate, along with County staff, in citizen outreach efforts relating to the Bond Program.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
To promulgate rules consistent with this Ordinance for the conduct of its meetings and the discharge of its responsibilities.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
To comply with all laws and regulations of the United States, the State of Florida, and Miami-Dade County, including, but not limited to, the laws relating to the keeping of records including the preservation of all audit rights.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Any member shall be automatically removed if, in a given calendar year; (i) he/she is absent from three (3) consecutive meetings or, (ii) he/she is absent from more than 50% of all the committee meetings held during a year. A member shall be deemed absent when he/she is not present at the meeting for at least 75% of its duration.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1804. Modifications and Term</catch_line>
<text>
It is the intent of the Board of County Commissioners to create by this article and for the purposes set forth in this article, an Advisory Committee that may be modified or revoked in whole or in part by duly enacted ordinance of the Commission.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1805. Staff and Counsel</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager and the County Attorney shall provide such staff support to the Advisory Committee as may be necessary to accomplish its purpose. The Advisory Committee shall be provided meeting facilities and pre-approved expense reimbursement as the Commission or the County Manager may deem necessary to accomplish the Committee's purposes.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-1806—2-1820. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (129) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 05-70, § 1, adopted April 5, 2005, did not specifically amend the Code; hence, its inclusion herein as article CXIX, sections 2-1801—2-1805, was at the discretion of the editor. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
