<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XVII._BRANCH_OFFICES_OF_COUNTY_A</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-119. Occupational license, approval by County Manager, prerequisites to operation</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Any person, firm, partnership, professional association or corporation operating a branch auto tag agency office and performing the functions thereof pursuant to law must have (1) authorization from the County Manager, pursuant to the provisions of this article and (2) a valid, current occupational license pursuant to this article. This section shall apply to branch auto tag agency offices in existence prior to July 1, 1994, as well as any office established subsequent thereto; provided, however, that only those branch auto tag agency offices authorized for the first time after July 1, 1994, shall be subject to the bid provisions of Section 2-120.1(a).
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
It is unlawful for any person, firm, partnership or corporation not authorized to operate a branch auto tag agency office pursuant to this article to advertise, name its business, or otherwise hold itself out in such a way as to represent itself as an official state or county office or agent with respect to performing the functions of an auto tag agency. The penalties for violation of this subsection are set forth in Section 2-127(a).
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Automobile and/or truck dealers which are properly licensed by the State of Florida and which are in good standing with the Florida Division of Motor Vehicles may operate a Limited Branch Office solely for the purpose of issuing a vehicle registration renewal, permanent license plat, and/or title transfer only in the course of a sale or lease of a vehicle by said dealer. Prior to issuing a vehicle registration renewal, permanent license plate, and/or title transfer, the automobile and/or truck dealer must:
<section prefix = "1">
Enter into a written agreement with a currently licensed and existing branch auto tag agency, which agreement shall contain, but not be limited to, the proper procedures for issuance of auto tags and decal inventory through the Electronic Filing System. This written agreement shall be approved by and on file with the Tax Collector.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Enter into an agreement with a Valid Certified Service Provider to obtain approved software applications which will enable the dealer (Limited Branch Office) to comply properly with this article and the program standards for the Electronic Filing System as established by the Florida Tax Collectors, Inc.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Obtain written authorization from the Miami-Dade County Tax Collector.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 94-135, § 2, 6-21-94; Ord. No. 97-93, § 1, 6-17-97)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-119.1. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
For the purpose of this article the following definitions shall apply:
<section prefix = "1">
The term "applicant" shall refer to any person, firm, partnership or corporation which meets the requirements for placement in the eligibility pool described in Section 2-120. As set forth in Section 2-120(f), a designated person shall represent a corporate applicant.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The term "authorization" shall refer to the authority granted an operator by the County Manager in accordance with this article, and after compliance with all applicable requirements, to operate a branch auto tag agency office.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The term "Board" shall refer to the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The term "branch office" shall refer to a private business operating pursuant to the provisions of this article and on behalf of the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency providing auto tag agency services to the public.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The term "corporate," when used in this ordinance, shall refer to and encompass, in addition to a corporation, any firm, partnership or other business entity other than a sole proprietorship.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
The term "eligibility pool" shall refer to the pool established pursuant to Section 2-120 containing the names of applicants eligible to bid for award of authorizations to operate new branch offices and to otherwise acquire existing branch offices.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
The term "operator" shall refer to any person, firm, partnership or corporation which is authorized to operate a branch auto tag agency or a Limited Branch Office and the name for which the authorization is granted. With respect to a branch auto tag agency, as set forth in Section 2-120(f), and subject to the requirements therein, a designated person shall represent a corporate operator.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
The term "qualified employee" shall refer to a person who has satisfactorily passed a written examination given under the direction and supervision of the Tax Collector or his designees, which tests the person's knowledge of applicable laws, rules, regulations and procedures.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
The term "automobile and/or truck dealer" shall refer to those entities properly licensed by the State of Florida to engage in the business of selling motor vehicles to the general public.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
The term "Electronic Filing System" (EFS) shall refer to the system by which permanent auto tags are assigned and issued to buyers of cars or trucks when the transaction occurs at a licensed automobile and/or truck dealer with Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
The term "limited branch office" shall refer to an automobile and/or truck dealer who is licensed by and is in good standing with the State of Florida, has been authorized by the Tax Collector, and has a current written agreement with a private branch auto tag agency, which agreement has been approved by and is on file with the Tax Collector, for the purpose of fulfilling obligations relating to the EFS. A limited branch office shall not mean and shall not be interpreted to mean a privately owned auto tag agency as described in this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
The term "valid certified service provider" shall refer to a provider of software and other computer services to a limited branch office which has contracted with the Florida Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles for the applicable access agreements, contracted with the Florida Tax Collectors, Inc. for compliance with the program standards of the EFS, and agreed with Miami-Dade County to adhere to appropriate local laws, standards, administrative orders, and other appropriate procedures.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-119.2. Creation and operation authorized; limitation on transfers</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The County Manager is hereby authorized and empowered to create one branch office of the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency for each seventy-five thousand (75,000) population, according to the last official federal census, at such location as he may determine is necessary to properly serve the needs, convenience and interest of the public; however, new branch offices will be phased in ratably during the ten-year periods between each census. Only members of the eligibility pool may be appointed to operate all branch offices in existence as of the effective date of this article or created pursuant to the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
There shall be no branch office created except as provided in subsection (a) of this section, unless the County Manager, upon finding that a special need exists within a specified geographical area of the County, recommends to the Board that a branch office of the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency operate within said area and the Board, by separate resolution, authorizes the creation of such branch office. Said branch office shall be in addition to those authorized in subsection (a) of this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Authorization to operate a branch office shall be conditioned upon the faithful compliance by the operator with all rules, regulations, laws and public needs as determined by the manager. Whenever the County Manager has determined that an operator has not faithfully complied with all rules, regulations, laws and the provisions of this article, he may revoke, suspend or otherwise condition his authorization to continue operation subject to the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Except for those operators who, prior to April 6, 1982, were authorized to operate more than one branch auto tag agency, no operator shall own, in whole or in part, operate, or control more than one branch auto tag agency. Members of the immediate family of a non-corporate operator, as defined in subsection (f) of this section, shall be limited to owning no more than two (2) branch agencies.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The rights and privileges granted any operator or qualified employee under the provisions of this article are personal in nature and cannot be sold, transferred or assigned, except as provided for in Section 2-120.1, or subsection (f) of this section. In the event of any voluntary or involuntary dissolution of a corporate operator, the authorization shall be deemed revoked. For purposes of this subsection, a change of voting control within a corporation shall be treated as a transfer for purposes of Section 2-120(c).
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
When an existing branch office ceases operation for any reason, including but not limited to the death of a non-corporate operator, a sustained revocation or voluntary cessation, such office shall not be transferred, sold or otherwise replaced unless replacement is specifically authorized by the County Manager in accordance with the provisions of this article. Any transfer of authorization allowed hereunder shall be only to qualified operators on the eligibility list established pursuant to this article. Any such transfer shall be in accordance with the provisions of this article:
<section prefix = "1">
Transfer of authorization in event of death of non-corporate operator. A non-corporate operator may transfer by testamentary disposition the existing authorization to operate an existing office to a family member or authorized co-operator who is qualified or qualifies as an applicant pursuant to Section 2-120 within six (6) months from the time of death of the operator, unless an extension, not to exceed six (6) months, is authorized by the Tax Collector for good cause shown, and whose name has been submitted for inclusion on a succession list maintained by the Tax Collector. A family member is defined as a spouse, child, son/daughter-in-law, parent, grandparent, brother, sister, or upon proof, any person whose ties customarily would be considered immediate family. In the absence of testamentary disposition, the branch office may be sold by the estate of the operator to an applicant in the authorized eligibility pool established by the county in accordance with the provisions of Section 2-120. Such sale must take place within one (1) year from the date of the operator's death, unless an extension, not to exceed six (6) months, is authorized by the Tax Collector for good cause shown. Prior to any sale or transfer hereunder, the administrator of the operator's estate shall be responsible for all moneys, decal paper stock, license tags, computer equipment and all accountable forms and items belonging to the State of Florida and Miami-Dade County. If there is no sale within the time limitation set forth herein, the authorization to operate the branch office shall be deemed revoked.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Transfer of authorization in event of bankruptcy of a corporate operator. Upon the filing of a petition for bankruptcy by an operator, no transaction affecting ownership or operation of the branch office shall occur without notice to and the consent of the County Manager and in accordance with the provisions of this article.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 94-135, § 2, 6-21-94; Ord. No. 01-25, § 1, 2-13-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-120. Eligibility to apply to operate a branch office; qualifications, examination of applicants; conditions for transfer of branch office; reporting responsibilities of applicants and operators</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Effective July 1, 1994, authorization for operation of a new branch office shall be awarded to the highest bidder. Only applicants in the eligibility pool established and maintained by the Tax Collector shall be eligible to bid. The eligibility list in existence as of the effective date of this ordinance shall expire July 1, 1994. However, applicants on said list can be placed in the eligibility pool by notifying the Tax Collector by certified mail no later than thirty (30) days from the effective date of this ordinance.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The eligibility pool shall contain only the names of applicants whose written applications have been approved, who have qualified by written examination and who have paid an application fee established by administrative order. A grade of seventy (70) in the written examination shall qualify the applicant for purposes of passing the examination and the names of those qualified shall appear in the eligibility pool. A qualified applicant shall remain eligible to bid for newly established branch offices or on those existing offices offered for sale provided that the Tax Collector is notified via certified mail every three (3) years that the applicant wishes to remain in the eligibility pool. The Tax Collector shall open the eligibility pool each October 1, or whenever he deems appropriate. An advertisement shall appear in a newspaper of daily circulation at least forty-five (45) days prior to the opening of any eligibility pool. The advertisement shall be in substantially the following form:
"Notice for acceptance of applications for authorizations to operate branch auto tag agency offices of the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency in Miami-Dade County, Florida."
"Pursuant to the provisions of Section 2-120, Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, notice is hereby given that applications will be accepted for eligibility to bid for an award of authorization to operate a new or existing branch auto tag agency of the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency. Application forms may be obtained from the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency, 140 West Flagler Street, Miami, beginning at ____________. Completed applications may be filed with the Miami-Dade County Tax Collector at any time following the above time and date along with a ____________ application fee. All persons submitting a completed application prior to ____________ shall submit to a written examination to be given at ____________ on ____________. An application list will be established based upon a qualifying score on the written examination. All future authorizations for new agencies will be offered to the highest bidder in the eligibility pool maintained by the Tax Collector. The sale or transfer of existing agencies will be allowable only to those applicants in said eligibility pool. No person shall be appointed to simultaneously operate more than one branch auto tag agency office. Only legal residents of the United States who reside in Miami-Dade County or corporations authorized to operate within the State of Florida shall be authorized to operate branch auto tag agency offices."
"MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA   By "
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
As established by administrative order, a fee shall be paid to the County for the transfer by sale or gift of any authorization granted hereunder. The fee owed to the County will be paid in full upon consummation of the sale or transfer. No fee shall be paid for transfer by gift to family, as defined in Section 2-119.2(f)(1), or by testamentary devise pursuant to Section 2-119.2(f)(1).
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
At the time of application, each applicant shall provide complete information about any prior violation of any provision of this article, any prior charge or conviction of any felony or of any offense involving moral turpitude or the mishandling of funds or properties, the nature and extent of his business or professional experience, character, employment and business references and such other information as may be required by applicable law or that the Tax Collector may in his discretion deem appropriate.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Each applicant and operator is required to keep on file with the Tax Collector complete and current copies of all documents requested by the Tax Collector consistent with State and County disclosure requirements and necessary to the Tax Collector for implementation of this article, including the name of the designee required in subsection (f) of this section. The Tax Collector shall be notified of all changes to the applicant's or operator's corporate charter, officers and directors and of individuals having a financial interest in the branch agency. Additionally, a copy of any contract executed in the event of a transfer or sale of existing agency shall be submitted to the Tax Collector.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Corporate applicants and operators shall be represented by one qualified officer or employee who will be responsible for fulfilling all requirements of this article that pertain to applicants and operators. A person so designated can act only on behalf of one applicant or operator. In the event that the designated person's affiliation or employment with the applicant or operator ends, there must be designated within thirty (30) days a successor who must qualify by written examination as provided in subsection (b) herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Only legal residents of the United States who reside in Miami-Dade County or corporations authorized to operate within the State of Florida shall be authorized by the County to operate branch auto tag agency offices.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 94-135, § 2, 6-21-94)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-120.1. Awards of authorizations to operate branch offices</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Effective July 1, 1994, all new authorizations granted pursuant to Section 2-120 shall be accomplished through a bidding process to be administered by the Tax Collector pursuant to established County procedures. In the event of a transfer of an existing agency pursuant to Section 2-119.2(f), the Tax Collector shall determine that the transfer was bona fide. In addition to all requirements placed upon operators by this article, the Tax Collector may include such additional requirements as may be needed to ensure efficient operation of the branch office and accountability to the State and the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The award of authorization hereunder shall be conditioned upon the operator's written acknowledgement agreeing to abide by all applicable laws, rules, regulations and requirements relating to the terms and conditions under which branch offices must operate.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 94-135, § 2, 6-21-94)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-120.2. Qualified personnel required</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Each branch office shall have on its premises during all working hours a minimum of one qualified employee handling ongoing business transactions within the branch office. Any branch office which does not have on its premises such qualified employee to conduct business shall immediately cease from operating as a branch office of the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency until this section is complied with.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Unless the operator and the qualified employee are the same person, each operator must designate at least one individual, who shall be a qualified employee, to be involved on a continual basis in on-site management of the branch office. This individual shall be in addition to the qualified employee referred to in subsection (a) of this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Each qualified employee must satisfactorily complete the examination as provided in this article.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 94-135, § 2, 6-21-94)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-120.3. Business hours</catch_line>
<text>
Each branch office shall be open to the public from 9:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m. on all days when County government offices are normally open unless otherwise required or authorized by the Tax Collector. Branch offices have the option to open their offices on other days and to maintain longer office hours. Operating hours must be prominently displayed at each public entrance to the branch office.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-120.4. Full service to be provided</catch_line>
<text>
Each branch office shall provide the same full services to the public as given at the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-121. Bond and insurance; amount, terms, conditions; computers</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Before being authorized or reauthorized, each potential or current operator shall give bond with good and sufficient sureties, or part cash collateral with the Tax Collector. The amount and type of said bond will be set forth in Administrative Order 4-83. Such bond shall be conditioned upon the branch office and its officers, directors, agents and employees' faithful compliance with all laws, correctly accounting for all moneys coming into its hands, and using ordinary care in correctly informing persons with whom it deals concerning any taxes or fees levied against them or their property. Such bond shall be payable to the County for any damages suffered by the County by reason of any unlawful act, fraud, neglect or embezzlement by such branch office, its owners, employees, officers or agents. It is further provided that any person who shall be damaged by reason of any unlawful act, fraud, neglect or embezzlement of said branch office shall have as his sole recourse an action on said bond in his name against the principal and sureties thereon. In no event shall such person claiming to have been damaged have any right, remedy, action or course of action against the County or its agents or employees.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Each branch office shall furnish evidence of liability insurance in an amount and type to be determined by the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The bond and insurance shall be carried with solvent and responsible insurers authorized to transact business in the State of Florida. Such bond and insurance shall be subject to the approval of the County risk manager prior to acceptance by the Tax Collector. Failure of the operator to maintain the required bond and insurance shall result in suspension of all auto tag activities during the period when the bond and insurance are not in effect.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Computer equipment providing access to Division of Motor Vehicle (DMV) Florida Real Time Information System (FRTIS) will be supplied and maintained by DMV. Operators shall be required to execute a use agreement with the State and maintain such insurance thereon as required by the State. Failure to execute and comply with said agreement may result in the removal of the agency's computer equipment.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 94-135, § 2, 6-21-94; Ord. No. 01-25, § 2, 2-13-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-121.1. Payment of occupational license taxes; duration of licenses; address of licensee</catch_line>
<text>
Every branch office shall pay a County occupational license tax as set forth in Sections 8A-223.1 and 8A-247.1. No license shall be issued for more than one year and all licenses shall expire on the thirtieth day of September of each year. All licenses shall be issued in the name of the operator and shall state the address of the branch office.
Prior to the issuance of a license renewal, the Tax Collector shall ascertain the operator's compliance with all applicable laws, rules, regulations, procedures and agreements. In his discretion, and with respect to minor acts of non-compliance, the Tax Collector may in writing notify the operator of such acts and extend a thirty-day period within which to come into compliance. If the Tax Collector declines to renew a license, he shall notify the County Manager so that the manager may take action pursuant to Section 2-119.2(c). No license shall be issued to a branch office if its authorization has been revoked by the County Manager.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-122. Grant, revocation of decal paper stock and/or tag consignment privileges; inventory of decals and/or tags</catch_line>
<text>
Upon the issuance of the bond required by Section 2-121 and the payment of the occupational license tax required by Section 2-121.1, each branch office may secure decal paper stock and/or tags from the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency.
Each branch office may be granted decal paper stock and/or tag distribution privileges at quantities for automobiles and vessels and classes to be determined by the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency. The Tax Collector shall prescribe rules and regulations upon which the distribution privileges are predicated.
All reports shall be accompanied by remittances in full and reports for tags sold shall be returned to the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency on the basis of first in-first out, according to each series.
Each branch office shall furnish the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency with a letter setting forth the names and signatures of that branch office's qualified employees who can receive and sign for decal paper stock, tags and other accountable items.
The failure of any operator or its employees or agents to comply with any rules, regulations or the provisions of this article shall constitute adequate and sufficient grounds for the revocation of prepayment and/or decal paper stock and/or tag distribution privileges in the discretion of the Tax Collector.
Each branch office shall, upon request of the Tax Collector or his representative, return all unused decal paper stock, tags, and other accountable documents, licenses and items supplied by the Tax Collector to the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency for inventory purposes, and all decal paper stock, tags and other accountable documents, located within the branch office's place of business, shall be subject to physical inventory by the Tax Collector or his representative at any time.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-123. Fees, amounts, collection, disposition</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Any and all fees and payments, whether payable to the County by an applicant or operator or payable to an operator in the course of branch office transactions or for services otherwise rendered, shall be established by and set forth in an administrative order submitted by the County Manager and approved by the Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The operator shall collect the service fees specified in Chapters 319, 320, 327 and 328, Florida Statutes. These amounts shall be remitted with each motor vehicle transaction report delivered to the Tax Collector.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Each operator shall be entitled to fees for services rendered. Fees so authorized are the only lawful fees allowable for such services which the operator performs or renders on behalf of Miami-Dade County. Any branch office charging fees in excess [of] those set forth in the applicable administrative order shall return such overcharges to the customer and submit to the Tax Collector proof of refund. Charging fees in excess of that set forth may constitute adequate and sufficient grounds for the revocation or suspension of the authorization to operate a branch office.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
To compensate for inflation and other changes in operating conditions, at the request of the Tax Collector or the majority of operators, fees may be subject to review and adjustment, but not more frequently than at two-year intervals unless the Tax Collector in his discretion determines that special circumstances exist necessitating review. The adjustments are intended to compensate for such factors as inflation, changes in the law which affect the costs of operation and other changes in operating conditions. In no event shall the initial obligations or start-up costs of new or transferred branch offices be considered as grounds for fee adjustments.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Whenever any operator shall receive any moneys from any person for a transaction pertaining to a motor vehicle or vessel decal, tag, title, title transfer, registration, or other application, the customer shall be given a receipt for all moneys collected, showing all details of the transaction, upon a receipt form approved by the Tax Collector, and shall report such transaction upon a form supplied by the Tax Collector, and pay over such moneys together with the respective documents and a copy of the customer's receipt to the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency within the time prescribed by the tax collector in Administrative Order 4-83.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
It shall be unlawful for any branch office to accept payments and/or documents on any application and hold such payments and/or documents in abeyance for any reason.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Whenever any operator fails to report any transaction to the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency within the prescribed period, the said operator will be assessed a penalty on the total remittance due and in arrears at a rate of 12 percent per year or 0.0329 percent per day. This penalty shall be in addition to any suspension or revocation of the branch office's authorization.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
The failure of any operator of a private branch agency or limited branch office or employee or agent thereof to comply with all rules and regulations as established by the County Manager, Tax Collector or other governmental agency shall constitute adequate and sufficient grounds for the suspension and/or revocation of the operator's authorization to act on behalf of Miami-Dade County. In such event, each operator shall, upon request of the Tax Collector, return all unsold decals, tags, unreported registrations, title applications, all other documents the Tax Collector deems appropriate, and all unused forms to the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
After approval by the Tax Collector, a copy of the fee schedule shall be posted in a conspicuous place in the branch office where it may be readily observed by customers without inquiry as to its place of posting. The fee schedule shall include the following notice:
"This is a privately owned business under contract with Miami-Dade County as a branch office of the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency. The fees shown on this schedule are the maximum fees authorized and approved by Miami-Dade County. Any complaint concerning this branch office may be directed to the Miami-Dade County Tax Collector, 140 West Flagler Street, (375-4677)."
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Limited branch offices must deposit funds in a bank designated by Miami-Dade County using procedures outlined in the program standards of the EFS and those included in the administrative order regarding the EFS when the transaction is completed, but in no event more than thirty (30) days after the transaction was commenced.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 94-135, § 2, 6-21-94; Ord. No. 97-93, § 3, 6-17-97; Ord. No. 01-25, §§ 4, 5, 2-13-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-124. Books and records of operator</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Each branch office and limited branch office shall maintain a complete set of accounting records, including a permanent set of ledgers, journals, and supporting source documents, posted up to date, reflecting all business transactions regarding the issuance of vehicle or vessel titles, registrations of same, and any and all transactions relating to the EFS or this article. All such records shall be held for a period of not less than three (3) years or until all applicable audits have been satisfied, whichever period is longer.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The director of the Miami-Dade County Audit and Management Services Department may establish a standard uniform accounting system to be used by all branch offices and limited branch offices and may require the use of such accounting system. All books and records of the operators pertaining to transactions under this article and the EFS shall be available during all business hours for the inspection and/or audit by the Miami-Dade County Internal Auditor, the Tax Collector, or their designee(s).
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Each operator shall complete each of the prescribed forms as required by the Tax Collector and submit completed forms to the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency at the time specified.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 94-135, § 2, 6-21-94; Ord. No. 97-93, § 4, 6-17-97)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-125. Compliance with applicable rules, regulations, required; supervision or revocation of agency authorization, review of suspension or revocation</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
In addition to complying with the laws, rules and regulations of the United States, Florida and Miami-Dade County, the operator of private branch agencies and limited branch offices shall fully comply with all rules and regulations of the Florida Division of Motor Vehicles, Florida Department of Revenue, the County Manager, and the Tax Collector.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Tax Collector shall have authority to prescribe rules and regulations relating to the operation of all branch offices and limited branch offices and standards of service.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Failure to comply with any applicable laws, rules or regulations of the United States, Florida and Miami-Dade County, including those promulgated by the County Manager and Tax Collector, shall constitute adequate and sufficient grounds for suspension or revocation by the County Manager of the operator's authorization. In the event of such action, the County Manager shall serve a notice of suspension or revocation upon the operator. Conditions of suspension or revocation may include, in the County Manager's discretion, immediate suspension of operations until such time as a review, if requested, is concluded. If three (3) violations of this ordinance which result in a letter of reprimand and/or suspension occur within an eighteen-month period, it will be grounds for revocation of authorization to operate the branch office. The Tax Collector may in his discretion continue branch office operations with his own personnel during the period in which a suspension is in effect or during which operations have been suspended pending review.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The operator may seek review by the Board of County Commissioners of the County Manager's notice of suspension or revocation by filing a written request for review with the clerk of the board within fifteen (15) days from the date of service of the County Manager's notice. If requested, said review shall be scheduled on the next available Board agenda. The operator shall have the right to present its position and all supporting evidence to the Board as part of the Board's review. Witnesses shall be sworn and the rules of evidence applicable to quasi-judicial proceedings shall govern. The Board shall hear and consider all facts material to the review and may affirm, modify or reverse the action taken. The decision of the Board shall be final unless overturned by a court of competent jurisdiction.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Nothing herein is to be deemed to vest in any third party the right to require the Tax Collector or the County Manager to take any course of action with respect to the activities of branch offices.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Any violations by a limited branch office of this article and/or administrative orders shall constitute an irreparable injury and grounds for suspension or revocation of the privilege of utilizing the EFS system in Miami-Dade County.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 94-135, § 2, 6-21-94; Ord. No. 97-93, § 5, 6-17-97)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-126. Violations by operators and employees</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Any person, whether as an individual or as an officer, manager, agent or employee of a private branch office or a limited branch office who shall receive or collect any money from any person upon the representation, promise or for the purpose of payment of any taxes or fees imposed on any motor vehicle or boat for which a fee, commission or any other compensation is collected or expected and who shall convert or embezzle said money to his/her own use or benefit or to the use or benefit of some person other than the taxpayer or who shall fail to pay over said money to the Tax Collector within the time prescribed by this article and applicable administrative orders or to the person paying same upon demand, shall be guilty of embezzlement and shall upon conviction be punished as if he/she had been guilty of larceny.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
An operator shall not knowingly aid or abet any person or firm in an unlawful transaction relating to a motor vehicle, boat or any other vehicle. It shall be unlawful for any branch office or limited branch office to knowingly give false information to persons with whom it deals concerning official agency or limited branch office transactions.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Private auto tag agencies shall not conduct business in such a manner as to restrict the choice of certified service providers by a licensed branch office.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Certified service providers shall not conduct business in such a manner as to restrict the choice of private auto tag agencies by a licensed branch office.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Limited branch offices shall not conduct business in such a manner as to restrict the choice of certified service providers and/or private auto tag agencies by a licensed branch office.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Violations of any of the provisions of this section shall constitute an irreparable injury and grounds for suspension or revocation of authorization to operate the branch office or limited branch office.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 94-135, § 2, 6-21-94; Ord. No. 97-93, § 6, 6-17-97)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-127. Penalties for violation</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
In addition to any penalties or sanctions provided elsewhere in this article, any operator who fails to obtain the required occupational license or any person, firm, partnership or corporation which violates the provisions of Section 2-119(b) shall be subject to penalties in accordance with Chapter 8CC of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
No operator shall be eligible to operate a branch office under this chapter if the designee required in Section 2-120(f), any qualified employee or any person otherwise involved on behalf of the operator in the operations on the branch office has been convicted of any crime involving misuse of funds or of a felony. Upon conviction, the authorization and occupational license shall be automatically cancelled or nullified.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Nothing herein shall prohibit the County or any affected operator from seeking injunctive relief for violations of Section 2-119(b).
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 94-135, § 2, 6-21-94)</history>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (32) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 94-135, § 1, adopted June 21, 1994, deleted former Art. XVII, §§ 2-119—2-127, relative to branch auto tag agencies, and § 2 of said ordinance enacted a new Art. XVII to read as herein set out. The provisions of former Art. XVII derived from Ord. No. 65-75, 11-23-65; Ord. No. 67-58, 8-8-67; Ord. No. 67-93, 12-5-67; Ord. No. 68-12, 2-21-68; Ord. No. 70-59, 7-21-70; Ord. No. 76-47, 5-18-76; Ord. No. 79-36, 6-5-79; Ord. No. 82-24, 4-6-82; Ord. No. 87-17, 4-7-87. (Back)
Cross reference— State vehicle license required for operation of the vehicle on County roads, highways, etc., § 30-367. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
