<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXIV._INDUSTRIAL_DEVELOPMENT_AUT</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-215. Determination of need for Industrial Development Authority to function</catch_line>
<text>
There is found a need for the development and financing of industry in Miami-Dade County, and therefore, there is declared a need for an Industrial Development Authority in Miami-Dade County.
</text>
There is found a need for the development and financing of industry in Miami-Dade County, and therefore, there is declared a need for an Industrial Development Authority in Miami-Dade County.
State law reference— Creation of industrial development authorities, limitation of authority to transact business until the County Commission declares, by proper resolution, the need for such an authority to function in the County, composition of authority, terms of membership, etc., § 159-45, Fla. Stats.
<catch_line>Sec. 2-216. Powers</catch_line>
<text>
The Miami-Dade County Industrial Development Authority shall have all the powers from time to time:
<section prefix = "1">
Conferred by, and incorporated by reference into, the enabling act, Part III of Chapter 159, Sections 159.44 through 159.53, Florida Statutes, as the same shall be amended from time to time; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Otherwise granted under the laws of the State of Florida.

</section>
</text>
The Miami-Dade County Industrial Development Authority shall have all the powers from time to time:
<section prefix = "1">
Conferred by, and incorporated by reference into, the enabling act, Part III of Chapter 159, Sections 159.44 through 159.53, Florida Statutes, as the same shall be amended from time to time; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Otherwise granted under the laws of the State of Florida.

State law reference— Powers of industrial development authority generally, § 195.47, Fla. Stats.
</section>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-217. Membership; terms</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Initial members. Five (5) persons who are residents and electors of Miami-Dade County are designated as the initial members of the Authority.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Additional members. Additional members may be appointed by motion of the Board of County Commissioners; provided, however, that the membership of the Authority shall not exceed thirteen (13) persons. Any member appointed pursuant to this subsection (b) shall serve for a term of four (4) years. Section 6 of Ordinance No. 93-114 shall not apply.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 86-57, § 3, 7-15-86; Ord. No. 94-32, 2-1-94)</history>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-218—2-220. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (41) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 78-19, § 1, adopted March 21,1978, repealed Ord. No. 77-44, which ordinance provided for an industrial development council to function as the Industrial Development Authority for Miami-Dade County; said ordinance was formerly codified herein as Art. XXIV of Ch. 2, §§ 2-215—2-221. In lieu of said former provisions, the editor has included herein at his discretion the provisions of Ord. No. 78-19, §§ 1, 2, adopted March 21, 1978, likewise providing for an Industrial Development Authority for Miami-Dade County, as a new Art. XXIV of Ch. 2 (Back)
Annotations—AO 9-1; CAO 81-16. (Back)
State Law reference— Industrial development authorities, F.S. § 159.44 et seq. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
