<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XVII._THE_LAUREN_BOOK_CHILD_SAFE</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-277. Title</catch_line>
<text>
Article XVII shall be known and may be cited as "The Lauren Book Child Safety Ordinance."
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-278. Findings and Intent</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Repeat sexual offenders, sexual offenders who use physical violence and sexual offenders who prey on children are sexual predators who present an extreme threat to the public safety. Sexual offenders are extremely likely to use physical violence and to repeat their offenses. Most sexual offenders commit many offenses, have many more victims than are ever reported, and are prosecuted for only a fraction of their crimes. This makes the cost of sexual offender victimization to society at large, while incalculable, clearly exorbitant.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The intent of this article is to serve the County's compelling interest to promote, protect and improve the health, safety and welfare of the citizens of the County, particularly children, by prohibiting sexual offenders and sexual predators from establishing temporary or permanent residence in certain areas where children are known to regularly congregate, to prohibit renting or leasing certain property to sexual offenders or sexual predators if such property is located where children are known to regularly congregate and to restrict sexual offenders' and sexual predators' access to parks and child care facilities.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 05-206, § 2, 11-15-05)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-279. Applicability</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
This article shall be applicable to the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
This article shall be applicable in all municipalities in Miami-Dade County on the effective date of this ordinance. All municipal ordinances in Miami-Dade County establishing sexual offender or predator residency restrictions are hereby preempted and shall stand repealed.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 05-206, § 2, 11-15-05; Ord. No. 10-01, § 2, 1-21-10)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-280. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
The following terms and phrases when used in this article shall have the meanings ascribed to them in this section unless the context otherwise requires:
<section prefix = "1">
"Child" or "children" means any person(s) less than sixteen (16) years of age.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
"Child care facility" means day nurseries, and family day care homes, licensed by the Department of Children and Families, and as defined in Section 33-151.11 of the Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
"Child safety zone" means an area three hundred (300) feet extending from schools, child care facilities, parks, and school bus stops measured in a manner similar to the measurement of the residency restriction area provided in this ordinance.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
"Convicted" or "conviction" means a determination of guilt which is the result of a trial or the entry of a plea of guilty or nolo contendere, regardless of whether adjudication is withheld. A conviction for a similar offense includes, but is not limited to: a conviction by a federal or military tribunal, including courts-martial conducted by the Armed Forces of the United States, and includes a conviction or entry of a plea of guilty or nolo contendere resulting in a sanction in any state of the United States or other jurisdiction. A sanction includes, but is not limited to, a fine, probation, community control, parole, conditional release, control release, or incarceration in a state prison, federal prison, private correctional facility, or local detention facility.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
"Legal guardian" or "guardian" shall mean biological or adoptive parent of a child registered at a child care facility or a person who is responsible for the care and maintenance of said child pursuant to Florida Statutes or similar laws of another jurisdiction.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
"Park" means a County or municipal park excluding a park that includes a shooting range.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
"Permanent residence" means a place where a person abides, lodges, or resides for fourteen (14) or more consecutive days.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
"Reside" or "residence" means to have a place of permanent residence or temporary residence.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
"School" means a public or private kindergarten, elementary, middle or secondary (high) school.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
"Sexual offender" shall have the meaning ascribed to such term in Section 943.0435, Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
"Sexual offense" means a conviction under Section 794.011, 800.04, 827.071, 847.0135(5) or 847.0145, Florida Statutes, or a similar law of another jurisdiction in which the victim or apparent victim of the sexual offense was less than sixteen (16) years of age, excluding Section 794.011(10), Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
"Sexual predator" shall have the meaning ascribed to such term in Section 775.21, Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
"Temporary residence" means a place where the person abides, lodges, or resides for a period of fourteen (14) or more days in the aggregate during any calendar year and which is not the person's permanent address, or a place where the person routinely abides, lodges, or resides for a period of four (4) or more consecutive or nonconsecutive days in any month and which is not the person's permanent residence.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-281. Sexual Offender and Sexual Predator Residence Prohibition; Penalties</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It is unlawful for any person who has been convicted of a violation of Section 794.011 (sexual battery), 800.04 (lewd and lascivious acts on/in presence of persons under age 16), 827.071 (sexual performance by a child), 847.0135(5) (sexual acts transmitted over computer) or 847.0145 (selling or buying of minors for portrayal in sexually explicit conduct), Florida Statutes, or a similar law of another jurisdiction, in which the victim or apparent victim of the offense was less than sixteen (16) years of age, to reside within 2,500 feet of any school.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The 2,500-foot distance shall be measured in a straight line from the outer boundary of the real property that comprises a sexual offender's or sexual predator's residence to the nearest boundary line of the real property that comprises a school. The distance may not be measured by a pedestrian route or automobile route, but instead as the shortest straight line distance between the two points.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Penalties. A person who violates section 21-281(a) herein shall be punished by a fine not to exceed $1,000.00 or imprisonment in the County jail for not more than 364 days or by both such fine and imprisonment.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 05-206, § 2, 11-15-05; Ord. No. 10-01, § 2, 1-21-10)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-282. Exceptions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
A sexual offender or sexual predator residing within 2,500 feet of any school does not commit a violation of this section if any of the following apply:
<section prefix = "a">
The sexual offender or sexual predator established a residence prior to the effective date of this ordinance. The sexual offender or sexual predator shall not be deemed to have established a residence or registered said residence for purposes of this section, if the residence is an illegal multifamily apartment unit within a neighborhood zoned for single-family residential use.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The sexual offender or sexual predator was a minor when he or she committed the sexual offense and was not convicted as an adult.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The school was opened after the sexual offender or sexual predator established the residence.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Section 21-282(1)(a) and (1)(c) herein shall not apply to a sexual offender or sexual predator who is convicted of a subsequent sexual offense as an adult after residing at a registered residence within 2,500 feet of a school.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 05-206, § 2, 11-15-05; Ord. No. 10-01, § 2, 1-21-10)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-283. Property Owners or Lessors Prohibited from Renting Real Property to Certain Sexual Offenders or Sexual Predators; Penalties</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It is unlawful to let or rent any place, structure, or part thereof, trailer or other conveyance, with knowledge that it will be used as a permanent or temporary residence by any person prohibited from establishing such permanent or temporary residence pursuant to this Article of the Code, if such place, structure, or part thereof, trailer or other conveyance, is located within 2,500 feet of a school. Knowingly renting to a sexual offender or predator shall include, but shall not be limited to, renting or leasing a residence after being notified that the prospective renter, lessee or adult resident is a sexual offender or predator as defined in this ordinance.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Prior to letting, renting or leasing any place, structure, or part thereof, trailer or other conveyance for use as a permanent or temporary residence that is located within 2,500 feet of a school, and annually thereafter if a rental agreement is entered into, the owner or lessor shall obtain confirmation of a nationwide search from the Miami-Dade County Police Department or other law enforcement agency that the prospective renter, lessee or adult resident is not a registered sexual offender or sexual predator as a result of a conviction of a sexual offense as defined in section 21-280 herein. A person may call the Miami-Dade County Answer Center (311) to obtain assistance or referrals to determine whether a prospective renter, lessee or adult resident is a sexual offender or predator and to determine whether a residence is 2,500 feet, from a particular school.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Penalties.
<section prefix = "1">
A person who violates section 21-283(a) herein shall be punished by a fine not to exceed $500.00 or imprisonment in the County jail for not more than 60 days, or both such fine and imprisonment. A person who is convicted of a second or subsequent violation of section 21-283(a) herein shall be punished by a fine not to exceed $1,000.00 or imprisonment in the County jail for not more than 364 days, or by both such fine and imprisonment.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
A person who violates section 21-283(b) herein shall be punished by a civil penalty of five hundred dollars ($500.00) in the manner established by Chapter 8CC of this Code. Each day of violation or noncompliance shall constitute a separate offense.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 05-206, § 2, 11-15-05; Ord. No. 10-67, § 2, 10-5-10)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-284. Sexual Offender and Sexual Predator Access to Parks and Child Care Facilities Restricted; Penalties</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It is unlawful for a sexual offender or sexual predator convicted of a sexual offense, as defined in section 21-280, to knowingly be present in a County or municipal park, when a child under the age of sixteen (16) years is present, unless the sexual offender or sexual predator is the parent or legal guardian of a child present in the park.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Signage at the entrance of County and municipal parks shall include notification that a person convicted of a sexual offense, as defined in section 21-280 herein, shall not be present in a park when a child under the age of sixteen (16) years is present, unless the sexual offender or sexual predator is the parent or guardian of a child present in the park.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
It is unlawful for a sexual offender or sexual predator convicted of a sexual offense, as defined in section 21-280, to knowingly enter or remain in a child care facility ("facility") or on its premises unless the sexual offender or sexual predator:
<section prefix = "1">
Is dropping off or picking up a child registered at the facility and is the parent or legal guardian of said child; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Remains under the supervision of a facility supervisor or his or her designee while on the facility premises.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Penalties. A person who violates section 21-284(a) or (c) herein shall be punished by a fine not to exceed $500.00 or imprisonment in the County jail for not more than 60 days, or by both such fine and imprisonment. A person who is convicted of a second or subsequent violation of section 21-284(a) or (c) herein shall be punished by a fine not to exceed $1,000.00 or imprisonment in the County jail for not more than 364 days, or by both such fine and imprisonment.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 05-206, § 2, 11-15-05; Ord. No. 10-67, § 2, 10-5-10)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-285. Loitering or prowling in child safety zone; penalties</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It is unlawful for any sexual offender or sexual predator:
<section prefix = "1">
To loiter or prowl with the intent to commit a sexual offense as listed in Section 21-280 of this article;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
While knowingly within a child safety zone when children are present; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
To engage in overt conduct that, under the circumstances, manifests an intent to commit a sexual offense as listed in Section 21-280 of this article.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Conduct which may, under the circumstances, be deemed adequate to manifest an intent to commit a sexual offense as listed in Section 21-280 of this article includes, but is not limited to, conduct such as the following:
<section prefix = "1">
Making sexual conversation or sexual remarks to a child;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Making lewd or sexual gestures to a child, or exposing sexual organs to a child;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Giving gifts of candy, money, music, or other items to a child to which he or she is not related or acquainted.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Unless flight by the sexual offender or sexual predator or other circumstance makes it impracticable, a law enforcement officer shall, prior to any arrest for an offense under this section, afford the sexual offender or predator an opportunity to explain his or her presence and conduct. No sexual offender or predator shall be convicted of an offense under this section if the law enforcement officer did not comply with this procedure or if it is proven at trial that the explanation given by the sexual offender or predator is true, and that the sexual offender or predator had no intent to commit a sexual offense.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
As used in this section a sexual offender or predator is related to a child if he or she is the father, mother, step-father, step-mother, grandparent, sibling, cousin, aunt, uncle or resides with the child. As used in this section a sexual offender or predator is acquainted with a child if he or she has been introduced to the child in the presence of an adult with legal authority to supervise the child.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Penalties. A person who violates Section 21-285(a) herein shall be punished by a fine not to exceed $500.00 or imprisonment in the County jail for not more than 60 days or by both fine and such imprisonment.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
This provision is not intended to limit or affect the applicability of any general loitering and prowling statutes to sexual offenders or predators, including, but not limited to, F.S. § 856.021.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 10-01, § 3, 1-21-10; Ord. No. 10-67, § 2, 10-5-10)</history>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (12) ---
Editor's note— Section 2 of Ord. No. 10-67, adopted Oct. 5, 2010, retitled Art. XVII, The Miami-Dade County Sexual Offender and Sexual Predator Ordinance, to read as herein set out. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
