<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXXIIIE._OFFICE_PARK_DISTRICT_(O</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.29. Legislative purposes</catch_line>
<text>
The Office Park District (OPD) incorporates a concept which delineates an open space character for buildings whose principal uses are administrative, professional or research. The major objectives to be achieved by this district are to provide office complexes in an open space environment, to provide freedom for the designer to take a creative approach to the development of an office park and thereby to enhance the visual quality of Miami-Dade County, to encourage developers to seek professional design expertise in the design of office parks, to promote the use of energy saving techniques, to provide a variety of office uses with associated service facilities, and to encourage the efficient use of land with reduction of street and utility networks.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.30. Uses permitted</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
No land, body of water and/or structures shall be used or permitted to be used, and no structure shall be hereafter erected, constructed, moved, reconstructed, or structurally altered or maintained in any OPD District, which is designed, arranged or intended to be used or occupied for any purpose, unless otherwise herein provided, excepting for one (1) or more of the following uses:
<section prefix = "1">
Principal uses. Principal uses are those permitted uses that will form the major use concentration within the office park complex and include the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Office buildings for business, professional and secretarial uses that cater to the provision of services. Retail and industrial activities are not permitted as principal uses.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Laboratories for scientific and industrial research and development, including the use of scientific laboratory equipment and devices, shall be permitted. Assembly of precision instruments requiring a clinical environment in conjunction with scientific and medical research and development is also permitted upon approval of the Director. Any dust, fumes, gases, noises, odors and vibrations resulting from industrial or scientific research shall be completely contained within an enclosed building. It shall be the applicant's responsibility to provide sufficient data demonstrating that all potential impacts as listed above are so contained.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Commuter colleges/universities.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Accessory uses. Accessory uses are those uses that are associated with the principal use(s) and which provide service primarily to employees and patrons of the office park. The accumulative total of all accessory uses shall be limited to a maximum of fifteen (15) percent of the total gross interior square footage of the buildings proposed for the site. Such uses shall have no outside advertising. Areas devoted to structure parking shall not be included in the above calculations. Service facilities shall constitute the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Auditorium(s).
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Eating establishments such as a cafeteria, coffee shop, food carry-out, restaurant and sandwich shop. Liquor, beer and wine, if associated with normal restaurant operation, shall be permitted under the terms specified in the BU-1 District. Drive-in facilities are prohibited.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Office and stationery supplies.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Personal services such as:
<section prefix = "i">
Banks and savings and loans;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Barbershop;
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Beauty shop;
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
Chapel;
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
Day care center, nursery and kindergarten, subject to compliance with the requirements of sections 33-151.11 through 33-151.22 of this code;
</section>
<section prefix = "vi">
Dry cleaning and laundry (pickup only, no cleaning or washing on premises);
</section>
<section prefix = "vii">
Newsstands;
</section>
<section prefix = "viii">
Shoe repair shop and shoeshine parlor;
</section>
<section prefix = "ix">
Tobacco shops;
</section>
<section prefix = "x">
Adult day care center.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Pharmacies restricted to the preparation and sale of drugs and medicines and other pharmaceutical supplies.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Print shops.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Private clubs.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Recreational facilities within enclosed structures:
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Court games;
<section prefix = "ii">
Putting greens;
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Saunas;
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
Swimming pool.
<section prefix = "i">
Other similar uses as approved by the Director, provided such uses are primarily accessory uses to the principal office park use(s).
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
All uses shall be within enclosed building(s) except for approved passive and active recreational uses.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 77-64, § 1, 9-20-77; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 02-46, § 8, 4-9-02; Ord. No. 09-102, § 6, 11-17-09; Ord. No. 11-04, § 8, 2-1-11)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.31. Unity of ownership</catch_line>
<text>
In order to preserve the integrity of the plan and ensure its execution, the Office Park District shall be maintained under one (1) ownership or so designed and planned that it can logically be developed in sections or units, each complying independently with all district regulations.
A unity of title agreement, suitable for recording, shall be submitted to and meet with the approval of the Director at the time of the filing of the application for rezoning, unless the application is filed in the name of the Director, in which case the agreement shall be submitted with the application for permit. In those cases where the project is designed and planned to be developed in sections, the agreement shall permit the severance of the property into sections or units providing that the sections or units are placed under a unity of ownership and further provided that the section or unit complies with minimum lot width and area requirements.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.32. Minimum site size and frontage requirements</catch_line>
<text>
The minimum frontage requirements shall be one hundred (100) feet, with a minimum lot area of three (3) net acres including right-of-way dedications.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.33. Floor area ratio</catch_line>
<text>
The floor area ratio shall be thirty one-hundredths (0.30) at one (1) story and shall be increased by eight one-hundredths (0.08) for each additional story. Structure parking shall not count as part of the floor area, but shall be counted in computing building height and number of stories.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.34. Height</catch_line>
<text>
The maximum permitted height for any structure shall be eight (8) stories or one hundred (100) feet above finished grade, whichever is less.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.35. Landscaped open space; trees; landscape maintenance</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
[Landscaped open space.] Landscaped open space, unencumbered with any structure or off-street parking, ingress or egress drives or private drives, shall be provided in accordance with the requirements herein established. Areas to be credited toward the landscaped open space requirements are categorized as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
Not less than eighty (80) percent of the required landscaped open space shall be provided at ground level, outside of any structure and such area shall be well maintained with grass, trees and shrubbery, and may include water bodies which are completely enclosed within the office park development, provided, however, that such water areas shall not exceed fifty (50) percent of the required landscaped open space. Entrance features, passive recreational uses, pedestrian walks, permanent outdoor art displays, sitting areas and putting greens may also be included in the required landscaped open space.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Specific areas within the enclosed or nonenclosed malls which are landscaped with grass, trees and/or shrubbery, water areas therein, and areas therein with permanent art displays.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Roof decks and other above-grade surfaces.
The minimum landscaped open space shall be in accordance with the following:
<section prefix="1" type="table">
<table class="table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Net Acreage</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Minimum Percentage</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Up to 10.0</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">25%</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10.1 to 20.0</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">30%</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">20.1 to 30.0</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">35%</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Above 30</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">40%</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 

The minimum landscaped open space shall be increased by three (3) percent for each additional story or part thereof above two (2) stories, based on the tallest structure on the property. Each parking level within the structure shall be calculated as one story.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Trees. Landscaping and trees shall be provided in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Landscape maintenance. Sprinkler systems shall be provided that are adequately sized to provide water for landscaped areas. All plant material shall be maintained in a healthy condition.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 77-64, § 1, 9-20-77; Ord. No. 95-223, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 03-130, § 1, 6-3-03)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.36. Setbacks</catch_line>
<text>
All structures shall be setback a minimum of thirty (30) feet from property lines abutting any residential zoning districts in which only single-family, duplex or townhouse uses are permitted. Setbacks from front street property lines shall be a minimum of fifty (50) feet for structures and twenty-five (25) feet for paved parking areas. All other setbacks shall not be less than fifteen (15) feet.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.37. Parking</catch_line>
<text>
Parking shall meet the applicable requirements provided elsewhere in the Miami-Dade County Zoning Code.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.38. Site plan review</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
[Generally.] The Department shall review plans for compliance with zoning regulations and for compliance with the site plan review criteria. The purpose of the site plan review is to encourage logic, imagination, innovation and variety in the design process and ensure the congruity of the proposed development and its compatibility with the surrounding area. If plan(s) are denied, the applicant may appeal to the appropriate Community Zoning Appeals Board for action.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Required exhibits. The following exhibits shall be prepared by design professionals such as architects and landscape architects and submitted to the Department of Planning and Zoning:
<section prefix = "1">
The overall site plan shall indicate existing zoning on the site and adjacent areas.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
[As to] the use, height, bulk and location of all buildings and other structures, study models may be required when needed for adequate review.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Three-dimensional drawings such as isometric or perspective sketches of major design elements.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Pedestrian and vehicular circulation systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Landscape development plan, including plant names, quantities and sizes of major plant masses; location and size of sprinkler system shall also be indicated in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Demonstration of specific methods used to conserve energy.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Demonstration of the design graphics and permanent advertising features and outdoor furniture.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Indication of permanent outdoor art features.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Parking layouts and drives.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Figures indicating the following:
<section prefix="2" type="table">
<table class="thead0 table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="43.99999999999999px" /> 
  <col width="36px" /> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
  <col width="48px" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">(a)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Gross land area</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">____________ </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">s.f.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Less lakes, canals</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">____________ </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">s.f.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">(b)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Net land area</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> ____________ </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">s.f.</td> 
   <td style="" align="center" valign="top" class="">  <cite class="ulsingle">&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;100%&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;</cite>  <br /> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Building lot coverage</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">____________ </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">s.f.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> ____________% </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Paved areas</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> ____________ </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">s.f.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> ____________ %<br /> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Landscaped open space in category 1*</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">____________ </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">s.f.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> ____________% </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">(c)</td> 
   <td style="" colspan="4" valign="top" class="">Percentages of landscaped open space.<br /></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Category 1*</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> ____________ </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">s.f.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> ____________%<br /> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Category 2*</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> ____________ </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">s.f.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> ____________%<br /> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Category 3*</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> ____________ </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">s.f.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> ____________%<br /> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Category 4*</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> ____________ </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">s.f.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> ____________%<br /> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">(d)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Floor area ratio.<br /></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Floor 1</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> ____________ </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">s.f.<br /></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Floor 2</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> ____________ </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">s.f.<br /></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Etc.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> ____________ </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">s.f.<br /></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">(e)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Maximum height</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> ____________ </td> 
   <td style="" colspan="2" valign="top" class="">stories _____ft.</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 
 
Editor's note—The categories referred to herein are presumably those categories delineated in § 33-284.35(A).
In addition the method(s) used to determine all the above shall be clearly demonstrated.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Name of water and sewer utilities.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Other material and data which may be required for an adequate plan review by the Department.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Plan review standards. The following criteria shall be utilized in the plan review process:
<section prefix = "1">
Purpose and intent: The proposed development fulfills the objectives of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Planning studies: Design, planning studies or neighborhood area studies accepted or approved by the Board of County Commissioners that include development patterns or environmental design criteria which would apply to the development proposal under review shall be utilized in the plan review process.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Exterior spatial relationships: The three-dimensional air space created by the arrangement of structures and landscape shall produce spatial relationships that function with the intended use and occupancy of the project and are compatible with the development or zoning in the adjoining area. Spacing between buildings shall provide ample access for emergency equipment.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Landscape: Landscape shall be preserved in its natural state insofar as is practicable by minimizing tree removal. Landscape shall be used to shade and cool, direct wind movements, enhance architectural features, relate structure design to site, visually screen noncompatible uses and block noise generated by the major roadways and intense-use areas.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Buffers: Buffering elements in the form of architectural design and landscape design that provide a logical transition to adjoining existing or permitted uses shall be provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Scale: Scale of proposed structures shall be compatible with surrounding proposed or existing uses or shall be made compatible by the use of buffering elements.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Circulation: Pedestrian and auto circulation shall be separated insofar as is practicable, and all circulation systems shall adequately serve the needs of the development and be compatible and functional with circulation systems outside the development.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Energy conservation: Design methods to reduce energy consumption shall be encouraged. Energy conservation methods may include, but not be limited to, natural ventilation of structures, siting of structures in relation to prevailing breezes and sun angles, insulation of structures, use of landscape materials for shade and transpiration, and orientation of breezes.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Parking areas: Parking areas shall be provided that are screened and so located as not to adversely impact the development, its environs, and adjacent properties. On-site parking shall be screened so that it is not visible from any abutting property zoned under the AU, GU, RU or EU Districts, unless found unnecessary at time of site plan review because of existing conditions in the area.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Open space: Open space shall relate to any natural characteristics in such a way as to preserve and enhance their scenic and functional qualities to the fullest extent possible.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Subtropic architectural characteristics: Architecture and site development should incorporate consideration of the subtropical characteristics of the area. The provision of sun control devices, shaded areas, vegetation, roof terraces and similar features characteristic of subtropical design shall be encouraged.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Outdoor furniture and graphics: All outdoor furniture and graphics shall be designed as an integral part of the overall design of the project.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Art display: Permanent interior and exterior art displays and water features should be encouraged in the overall design of the project.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
Visual screening for decorative walls: In an effort to prevent graffiti vandalism, the following options shall be utilized for walls abutting zoned or dedicated rights-of-way:
<section prefix = "a">
Wall with landscaping. The wall shall be setback two and one-half (2½) feet from the right-of-way line and the resulting setback area shall contain a continuous extensively landscaped buffer which must be maintained in a good healthy condition by the property owner, or where applicable, by the condominium, homeowners or similar association. The landscape buffer shall contain one (1) or more of the following planting materials:
<section prefix = "1">
Shrubs. Shrubs shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Hedges. Hedges shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Vines. Climbing vines shall be a minimum of thirty-six (36) inches in height immediately after planting.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Metal picket fence. Where a metal picket fence abutting a zoned or dedicated right-of-way is constructed in lieu of a decorative wall, landscaping shall not be required.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 77-64, § 1, 9-20-77; Ord. No. 95-19, § 20, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 95-223, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-127, § 28, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 98-125, § 21, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 99-38, § 21, 4-27-99)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.39. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Section 1 of Ord. No. 85-59, adopted July 18, 1985, repealed § 33-284.39, concerning signs, as derived from § 1 of Ord. No. 83-66, adopted July 19, 1983.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.40. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (48) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 77-64, § 1, adopted Sept. 20, 1977, added provisions to the zoning code relative to Office Park District; inclusion herein as Art. XXXIIIE. of Ch. 33, §§ 33-284.29—33-284.38, is at the discretion of the editor, no section numbers having been designated by the County. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
