<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="2">ARTICLE_XXXVIII._IMPOSITION_OF_MORATORIU</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-350. Issuance of administrative order by County Manager prohibiting execution of new water contract commitments</catch_line>
<text>
Whenever it shall be made to appear to the County Manager that it is in the public interest and necessary to the public health, safety and welfare to make a comprehensive determination as to whether existing water resources are adequate and sufficient to meet the needs of the County or any portion thereof, and it is further made to appear to the County Manager that the existing allocation or supply of water resources jeopardizes present and future use of same to the detriment of the residents of the County or any part thereof should the present allocations and contractual commitments be continued, then the County Manager shall immediately issue his administrative order to the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority and/or any private or public utility within Miami-Dade County prohibiting the execution of new water contract commitments that represent new requests for gallonage allotments not filed with the Authority or the utility prior to the date of the administrative order.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-351. Compliance with administrative order required</catch_line>
<text>
Any administrative order issued pursuant to Section 2-350 shall be complied with by all Miami-Dade County departments, Boards, agencies, authorities, personnel and said utilities, and shall be effective until reversed, modified or superseded by order of the Board of County Commissioners.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-352. Duty of County Manager to notify Clerk of Board of County Commissioners upon issuance of administrative order; placement of matter before Board for consideration and review after public hearing</catch_line>
<text>
Immediately upon issuance of any administrative order pursuant to Section 2-350, the County Manager shall notify the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners, whose duty it shall be to place the matter before the Board of County Commissioners for consideration and review following a public hearing as soon as is reasonably practicable.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-353. Notice of public hearing</catch_line>
<text>
The aforesaid Clerk shall give reasonable notice by publication in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County of the public hearing which has been scheduled before the Board of County Commissioners.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-354. Authority of Board to reverse, modify or supersede moratorium order</catch_line>
<text>
At the public hearing the Board of County Commissioners shall inquire into the propriety of the water contract moratorium or any part thereof and may reverse, modify or supersede any moratorium order previously issued. The Board's determination shall be predicated upon the reasonable necessity for a detailed comprehensive analysis of the water resource problem and the probability of detriment to the County or any part thereof by the continued execution of water resource contract commitments.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-355. Determination by Board of necessity of water contract moratorium; recommendations relating to allocation plant, etc.; period of moratorium</catch_line>
<text>
Should the Board of County Commissioners determine that a water contract moratorium is reasonably necessary, it shall order the same and direct that no further water contracts be entered into by either the public or private utility involved or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority. The Board's order shall fix a time within which the County Manager shall report back to the Board with his recommendations relating to an allocation plan for existing water resources and/or a plan to provide more water to the affected area consistent with the Comprehensive Development Plan for Miami-Dade County, Florida. The said time limitation shall be a reasonable one, predicated upon the time needed for a comprehensive analysis of the affected area. The initial Commission moratorium shall be for a period not to exceed one hundred twenty (120) days. The Commission on its own motion or otherwise may continue any moratorium for a longer period of time if reasonably necessary. This provision is supplemental to Section 2-356 hereof.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-356. Extension of time limitation for County Manager's report back to Board</catch_line>
<text>
Should the County Manager be unable to report back to the Board within the time prescribed by its moratorium order, upon timely request by the County Manager and after public hearing on the need therefor, the Board may reasonably extend the time limitation.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-357. Public hearing upon submission of County Manager's report and recommendations; determination and action of Board</catch_line>
<text>
Upon the submission of the County Manager's report and recommendations to the Clerk of the Board, the Clerk shall call a public hearing thereon before the Board at the earliest practicable time, after reasonable notice by publication in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County. After said public hearing the Board shall make its determination as to whether existing allocations of water resources shall remain the same or shall be changed and/or what actions, if any, can and should be taken to increase these water resources. Should the Board determine that the allocation of water resources shall remain the same, it shall immediately issue its order terminating the water contract moratorium or any part thereof. Should the Board determine that the allocation of existing and future water resources should be changed, or new sources of supply created therefor, it shall issue its order continuing the water contract moratorium or any part thereof and shall immediately take the actions required elsewhere within the Miami-Dade County Code or Charter for such changes.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-358. Completion of recommendations; issuance of Board order terminating water contract moratorium in whole or in part</catch_line>
<text>
Upon the completion of all recommendations relating to the affected area or the completion of a part thereof that are effective on a short-term basis, the Board shall issue its order terminating the water contract moratorium in whole or in part depending upon the nature of the completed recommendation.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-359. Application to County Manager for issuance of administrative order; denial of order or failure of Manager to act on application; application to Board of County Commissioners; determination as to necessity of public hearing</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Any person, as defined herein, shall be entitled to make written application to the County Manager for issuance of an administrative order provided for by Section 2-350 herein. Should such an application be made and denied by the County Manager or should the Manager fail to take action thereon within thirty (30) days, such person may make written application to the Board of County Commissioners for the issuance of a water contract moratorium by that Board. Such application to the Board shall be filed with the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners, whose duty it shall be to place the matter before the Board of County Commissioners as soon as is reasonably practicable for the Board's determination as to whether a public hearing shall be called thereon. The County Manager shall be notified by the Clerk that the matter is to be considered by the Board. The word "person" as used in this section includes, but is not limited to, any individual, firm, corporation, governmental or private entity, including any County department, Board, agency or authority.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Should the Board determine that a public hearing should be held as to whether a water contract moratorium is appropriate, it shall call the same for the earliest practicable date and give reasonable notice thereof by publication in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County. Pending the public hearing, the Board may issue an order prohibiting the execution of water contracts in the affected area.
The procedure to be followed for the purposes of this section after the completion of the steps provided in Sections 2-359 and 2-360 above, is that set forth in Sections 2-354 through 2-358 of this article.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 75-31, §§ 10, 11, 5-7-75; Ord. No. 83-92, § 4, 10-4-83)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-360. Authority of County Manager to grant exceptions to article provisions; guidelines for determination of public interest</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager or his designated agent is hereby authorized to grant such exceptions to or variances from the terms of this article as he deems consistent with the public health, safety and general welfare of the residents of the County. In determining which applicants, if any, should be granted exceptions or variances from the terms of any order issued pursuant to this article, the County Manager or his designated agent shall be guided by the standard of public interest. In determining the public interest the County Manager or his designated agent may consider the following guidelines in descending order of importance:
<section prefix = "a">
The amount of water requested and its relationship, if any, to the supply of water available, if any, and the causes calling the order or orders issued pursuant to this article;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Domestic use normally has the highest priority. For purposes of this section "domestic use" means any use of water for individual personal needs or for household purposes such as drinking, bathing, heating, cooking or sanitation;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Proposed uses that supply essential services to the public are to be preferred over proposed uses not supplying such essential services. For purposes of this section "essential services" include, but are not limited to, fire departments, hospitals or other emergency services;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Proposed public use or quasi-public uses are to be preferred over proposed private uses;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Proposed water uses that do not require extensions of existing water mains are to be preferred over those requiring such extensions;
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Proposed uses that will diminish reliance on private water supply wells are to be preferred over proposed uses calling for new supplies of water to areas not relying on private water supply wells;
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Proposed uses that will diminish serious economic hardships or loss of invested capital if not granted are to be preferred over proposed uses not subject to such losses or hardships;
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Economically more productive uses should be preferred over less productive uses.

The listing of the above guidelines is nonexclusive and should establish a priority ranking between prospective users.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-361. Appeals from decision of County Manager as to grant or denial of exception</catch_line>
<text>
Any person aggrieved with a decision of the County Manager or his designated agent as to the grant or denial of such an exception or variance may apply to the Environmental Quality Control Board in the manner and mode provided for by Section 24-6 of this Code for a review of that decision. Further review of the Board's decision affirming, reversing or modifying the decision sought to be reviewed shall be to the Board of County Commissioners. Any person aggrieved by the decision of the Board of County Commissioners shall be entitled to apply to the Circuit Court of Miami-Dade County for a review thereof by writ of certiorari in accordance with the applicable court rules.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (63) ---
Editor's note— The Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority, as referred to in this article, is now the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority Department. (Back)
Cross reference— Water and sanitary sewer connections, § 32-76 et seq. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
