<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXXIII(T)._PALMER_LAKE_METROPOLI</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.99.55. Purpose and intent</catch_line>
<text>
This Article applies to the area bounded by the Miami River on the northeast, the Seaboard Air Line Railroad on the west, and the Tamiami Canal on the south, hereinafter referred to as the Palmer Lake Metropolitan Urban Center District (PLMUC). A more detailed legal description of this boundary is provided in Section 33-284.99.66 below. The intention of this Article is to permit the development of a Metropolitan Urban Center that fulfills the goals, objectives and policies of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan by:
<section prefix = "A">
Coordinating development intensity within the district by the proximity to mass transit.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Organizing an interconnected network of streets to improve pedestrian access to transit.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Creating attractive and usable public space by shaping the way buildings front onto streets and open spaces.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
Maintaining and promoting marine activity on the Miami River by encouraging the retention of water dependent and/or water related uses consistent with the Port of Miami River Sub-element of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan.

The Illustrative Plan (Figure 1), illustrates the vision and may be used to better interpret this Article. Where there is conflict between the illustrative plan and the text of this Article, the text shall govern.

Figure 1. Illustrative Plan.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.99.56. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
Terms used throughout this Article shall take their commonly accepted meaning unless otherwise defined in Chapter 33 or Chapter 28 of the Code of Miami-Dade County. Terms requiring interpretation specific to this Article are as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
Block: A combination of contiguous building lots, the perimeter of which abuts one or more public streets, private streets, easements or designated open spaces.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Building Frontage: The portion of a building required to adjoin or be located within the frontage zone.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Building Frontage Zone: The portion of a lot adjoining a street or right-of-way. The width of the building frontage zone is established by the applicable street type and/or Sub-district.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Elevated Pedestrian Walkway: An enclosed structure located above private property and/or the public right-of-way allowing pedestrian access between and through buildings.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Floorplate: The total indoor and outdoor area of any given story of a building, measured to the exterior of the wall.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Forecourt: an open area where the building pedestal is recessed outside of the building frontage zone.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Frontage: The property line or lines of a lot which coincide with a right-of-way or other public open space line as shown on a Regulating Plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Habitable Space: Building space whose use involves human presence with direct view of the adjoining streets or open space, excluding parking garages, self-service storage facilities, and warehouses.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Mixed-use building: A building that includes a combination of two or more vertically integrated uses, such as, but not limited to retail and/or office uses on the ground story, with residential uses above.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Pedestal: The lower portion of the building including the ground story located adjoining or within the building frontage zone..
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Retail Use: Premises used for the exchange of services or goods.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Storefront: Retail or office use areas, lobby areas or other habitable space located at the building frontage.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Story: A floor level within a building as described in this Article's General Requirements.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
Street: A thoroughfare for the movement of pedestrians and vehicles, as provided in this Article.
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
Tower: The upper portion of a building above the pedestal.
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
Water-dependent Use: Activities that can be carried out only on, in, or adjacent to water areas because the use requires access to a water body, including without limitation: waterborne transportation hubs such as ports or marinas; or marine recreation.
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
Water-related Use: Activities that are not directly dependent upon access to a water body, but that provide goods and services that are directly associated with water-dependent uses.
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
Weather Protection Features: Architectural features that provide protection from the sun and rain, including without limitation, colonnades, awnings, or projecting roofs.
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
Work-force Housing Unit or WHU: A dwelling unit, the sale, rental or pricing which is restricted to households whose income is up to one-hundred forty (140) percent of the most recent median family income for the County reported by the U.S. HUD as maintained by the Department of Planning and Zoning.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.99.57. Organization of this article</catch_line>
<text>
This Article is organized into three (3) primary sections:
<section prefix = "1">
The Regulating Plans allocate Sub-Districts and Street Types, which serve as the controlling plans for the district.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Uses section provides for the various uses permitted by Sub-District.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The General Requirements are the instructions for implementing the Regulating Plans.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.99.58. Regulating plans</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
The Regulating Plans establish three (3) Sub-Districts, five (5) street types, and bicycle and greenway facilities, as set forth below:
<section prefix = "1">
The Sub-District Plan delineates three sub-districts, the MIC Core, the Center, and the Riverside. These Sub-Districts control land use and intensity of development in accordance with the County's Comprehensive Development Master Plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Street Frontage Plan establishes a hierarchy of street types in existing and future locations, which shall be provided in all future development. The five (5) street types, in descending order of pedestrian activity, are lettered "A" through "E". An "A" street is the most important street to accommodate pedestrian activity.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Greenway and Bicycle Plan establishes the location of bicycle and greenway facilities within the PLMUC.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Sub-District Plan

</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Street Frontage Plan

</section>
<section prefix = "D">
Greenway and Bicycle Plan

</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 13-43, ยง 4, 5-7-13)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.99.59. Uses</catch_line>
<text>
No land, body of water and/or structure shall be used or permitted to be used, and no structure shall be hereafter erected, constructed, reconstructed, moved, occupied, or maintained for any purpose in Palmer Lake Metropolitan Urban Center District except for one (1) or more of the following uses. All uses are subject to the airport safety uses and height restrictions provided in Section 33-336 of this chapter. The uses delineated herein shall be permitted only in compliance with the development parameters provided in Section 33-284.99.60 of this article. Water-dependent uses delineated herein shall be subject to the permit requirements of Chapter 24 of this code and be consistent with the Coastal Management Element of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan.
<section prefix = "A">
Permitted uses in the MIC Core and Center Sub-Districts shall be as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
All uses permitted in the IU-1, IU-2, and BU-2 Districts.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The following BU-3 uses:
<section prefix = "i">
Bakeries, retail and wholesale.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Secondhand stores.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Television and broadcasting stations.
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
Upholstery and furniture repairs.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Residential uses shall be permitted up to two hundred fifty (250) units per acre. Developments having more than four (4) residential units shall provide a minimum of twelve and one-half (12.5) percent of their units as work-force housing units.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Hotels, motels, and apartment hotels developed for transient residential usage shall be permitted up to three hundred seventy five (375) units per acre.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Mobile food sales and services, including but not limited to outdoor dining, cart vendors, and merchandise displays, shall be permitted in accordance with Section 33-13(h) of this code.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Commercial parking garages shall be permitted either alone or in conjunction with other permitted uses and shall comply with the storefront and screening requirements of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Drive-through services, provided that they shall be concealed from "A", "B" and "C" streets by buildings or walls.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Alcoholic beverage uses shall be permitted in accordance with Article X of this chapter, except that such uses shall not be subject to the spacing/distance requirements set forth in Section 33-150(A) and (B) therein.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Permitted uses in the Riverside Sub-District shall be as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
All uses permitted in the IU-1 and IU-2 Districts.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The following water-dependent uses:
<section prefix = "i">
Storage of recreational boats, including rack storage facilities. A masonry wall at least ninety-six (96) inches in height shall enclose the boat storage area except along an adjoining lake, canal, or river.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Marinas, non-live aboard, marine commercial. No permanent occupancy of private watercraft shall be permitted, except as required for a watchman's quarters. The following accessory uses shall be permitted at a commercial marina: Bait and tackle shop; Charter boat service; Dock master's office; Dry stack boat storage facility; Pleasure craft fueling facility; Pleasure craft rentals; Restaurants including therein any accessory outdoor dining area(s). Marinas shall provide electrical, water, and sewage disposal connections to each vessel berth.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Other water-dependent uses not specifically enumerated in this section or in the IU-1 and IU-2 districts as approved by resolution of the County Commission.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The following water-related uses:
<section prefix = "i">
Fish market and accessory seafood restaurant.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Seafood products and by-products collection, cooking, processing, and wholesale distribution, including accessory eating and drinking establishments related to such operations.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Vessel sales, wholesale or retail, and the following accessory uses: Marine supplies and equipment, retail and or wholesale distribution; Marine sporting goods and supplies, retail and or wholesale distribution.
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
Other water-related uses not specifically enumerated in this section or in the IU-1 and IU-2 districts as approved by resolution of the County Commission.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The additional uses listed below shall be permitted only in conjunction with one or more of the following water-dependent uses occurring on the same lot: marinas; marine terminals, passenger, freight; boat slips for the purpose of repair; boat and yacht repair, overhaul, manufacturing; shipyards. An annual certificate of use shall be required for the water dependent use when built as part of a mixed-use development that includes one of the uses listed in paragraphs (i) through (iii) below. Development shall comply with the waterfront setback and access requirements set forth in Section 33-284.99.60(B)(4)(b). The following additional uses shall be permitted only when the Director determines that such use: will not have an adverse impact on operation of the Port of the Miami River; will not substantially reduce or inhibit existing public access to marine or tidal waters; and will not interfere with the activities or operation of adjacent water-dependent uses or significantly impede access to vessel berthing or other access to the water by water-dependent uses.
<section prefix = "i">
Hotels, motels, and apartment hotels developed for transient residential use shall be allowed up to one hundred eighty-seven (187) units per acre, provided that such uses shall be constructed so that the Day Night Noise Level (DNL) within guest rooms are no greater than forty-five (45) decibels (db). Submitted plans for such uses shall include an acoustical analysis demonstrating that the proposed construction complies with the noise limit indicated, including documentation of noise levels at the development site, noise insulation measures to be utilized in building construction, and the predicted performance of the proposed measures. An annual certificate of use shall be required for these uses.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Retail uses shall be allowed, provided that such use is limited to less than fifty (50) percent of the building gross floor area on the same lot, except that retail uses provided as accessory to permitted hotel uses shall not be subject to this limitation.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
On lots adjoining the Tamiami Canal, residential uses shall be permitted above the ground story and limited to less than fifty (50) percent of the building gross floor area on the same lot, except that hotels, motels, and apartment hotels shall not be subject to this limitation.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
In all sub-districts, public recreation buildings, playgrounds, and parks or reservations owned and operated by a municipality, County, State or the United States Government shall be permitted. No minimum building frontage shall be required for such recreation building.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.99.60. Development parameters</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Building Standards.
<section prefix = "1">
The below diagram illustrates the building placement standards for all Sub-districts:

</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The below table provides minimum requirements for building and site development by Street Type:
<section prefix="1" type="table">
<table class="thead1 table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="28.571428571428573%" /> 
  <col width="14.285714285714286%" /> 
  <col width="14.285714285714286%" /> 
  <col width="14.285714285714286%" /> 
  <col width="14.285714285714286%" /> 
  <col width="14.285714285714286%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">Building/Site Element</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">&quot;A&quot; Street</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">&quot;B&quot; Street</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">&quot;C&quot; Street</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">&quot;D&quot; Street</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">&quot;E&quot; Street</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Minimum Sidewalk Width</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">18 ft.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10 ft.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6 ft.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6 ft.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6 ft.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Building Frontage Zone Width</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">25 ft.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">15 ft.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6 ft.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6 ft.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">12 ft.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Minimum Building Frontage</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">80 percent</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">50 percent</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">None</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">None</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">None</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Minimum Storefront within the Building Frontage</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">75 percent</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">50 percent</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">None</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">None</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">None</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
ย
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The minimum sidewalk width may be provided in the right-of-way and building frontage zone in combination. The building pedestal shall be located adjoining or within the building frontage zone for the minimum linear distance required by the above table.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The building pedestal shall be permitted to encroach into the building frontage zone such that the minimum sidewalk width is provided.


</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
General Requirements. All new development and redevelopment shall comply with the following parameters, irrespective of Sub-District and frontage categories:
<section prefix = "1">
Lots and Buildings.
<section prefix = "a">
Minimum lot size is two thousand (2,000) square feet, with a minimum frontage of twenty (20) feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
All lots shall share a frontage with a street.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The maximum height of buildings shall be as provided in Article XXXVII - Miami International Airport (Wilcox Field) Zoning of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Minimum front and side street building setbacks shall be determined by the table in paragraph (A) above. Minimum building interior side and rear setbacks shall be zero (0) feet. Lot coverage and floor area of buildings shall not be limited.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
All buildings shall have their main pedestrian entrance opening to the street of highest pedestrian activity. Where storefronts are required, pedestrian entrances shall be provided at maximum intervals of seventy-five (75) feet. Where ground story uses have entries from more than one street frontage, the primary entrance shall be from the street of highest pedestrian activity.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Building design shall use energy conservation measures, including but not limited to self-shading, natural lighting, natural ventilation, outdoor circulation, and reduced dependence on artificial lighting and air conditioning. Porches, balconies, breezeways, pergolas, deep eaves, eyebrows, and other elements promoting natural ventilation and shading are encouraged. Each building shall dedicate a specific location for recycling separation, storage, and access.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Vehicular entry gates at garage entries shall be positioned a minimum of twenty (20) feet behind the front wall of the building. At colonnaded frontages, this distance is measured from the interior/rear wall of the colonnade. To increase safety during off-hours, the setback area between the entry gate and the public sidewalk may be gated at the sidewalk edge during times when the garage is closed.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Glazing, Transparency and Storefront Requirements:
<section prefix = "1">
Portions of buildings facing or adjoining the building frontage zone shall be glazed as follows: office, hotel, and residential, minimum thirty (30) percent; retail, minimum twenty (20) percent; industrial and marine, minimum ten (10) percent. Storefronts shall be glazed as provided below and may count toward the overall building glazed area. Glazing shall be clear or tinted, except where used for screening garages, where it may be translucent.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Where required, storefronts shall occupy the ground story and be directly accessible from the building frontage zone and/or sidewalk. Storefronts shall be a minimum of sixty (60) percent clear-glazed for the height of the ground story.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Storefront security screens, if any, shall be of the mesh type that pedestrians can see through and shall be located behind storefront displays. Storefronts shall remain open to view and be lit from within at night.
<section prefix = "i">
