<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXXIIIB._CENTER_FOR_THE_FINE_ART</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-301. Preamble</catch_line>
<text>
This Board of County Commissioners owns and has constructed the Center for the Fine Arts building as an integral part of the Miami-Dade Cultural Center in Miami. It is the intention of the Board of County Commissioners that the County support the operation and maintenance of the facilities of the Center, and that the programming policies and expenses for the center be determined and borne by a private nonprofit corporation.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-302. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Association: The Center for the Fine Arts Association, Inc., a private, nonprofit corporation, with membership open to the general public and with reasonable annual membership fees. The Association is not an agency or instrumentality of Miami-Dade County. Its articles, bylaws and regulations shall be promulgated by its Board of Trustees.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Center for the Fine Arts: That building located within the Miami-Dade Cultural Center in Miami that houses fine arts exhibitions.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Center for the Fine Arts Department: A department of Miami-Dade County established by this article [Ordinance Number 87-1] to operate and maintain the facilities of the Center for the Fine Arts.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Director: The head of the Center for the Fine Arts Department and, at the discretion of the Association, may also be the Chief Administrative Officer of the Association.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Trustees: The Board of Trustees of the Center for Fine Arts Association, Inc.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 87-1, § 1, 1-20-87)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-303. Department established</catch_line>
<text>
The Center for the Fine Arts Department is hereby established, which shall be responsible for the operation and maintenance of the Center for the Fine Arts. The head of this Department is the Director of the Center for the Fine Arts. The Director shall carry out the policies and programs established by the Association and shall be in charge of the day to day operations of the Center for the Fine Arts. The Association trustees may nominate candidates for the position of Director to the County Manager; and may recommend to the County Manager that the Director be discharged, but the Director shall be appointed by and serve at the will of the County Manager. The organization and operating procedures of the Department shall be prescribed by administrative orders and regulations of the Manager. The Director shall appoint such employees as may be necessary to operate the Department.
The compensation of all personnel, except employees with the classified service, shall be fixed by the County Manager. The Director may receive supplemental compensation and expenses, payable from the association, in addition to the compensation paid by the County Commission, as shall be determined from time to time jointly by the Association and the County Manager.
Annotation—AO 9-1
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-304. Department; powers and duties</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Contracts. No contract executed by the Director, shall be binding upon Miami-Dade County, unless specifically approved by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Maintenance. The Department shall operate and maintain the Center for the Fine Arts in accordance with appropriate museum practices and shall provide all water, sewer, electrical, repair, security services as the Center may reasonably require.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Rules and regulations. Except as to admission charges, the Department may promulgate rules and regulations regarding the use of the center.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 87-1, § 1, 1-20-87)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-305. Association</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Association, shall support the Center for the Fine Arts and shall foster community involvement in the Center for the Fine Arts' activities. The Association shall fund exhibitions and other programs at the Center for the Fine Arts for the advancement of public knowledge and appreciation of art and design. The Association shall actively interact with other components of the Miami-Dade Cultural Center to advance the cultural life and experience of the residents of and visitors to Miami-Dade County. With respect to the display of works and collections of art, the primary objective of the Association shall be the attraction to the Center of major art exhibitions loaned by other institutions and individuals. No permanent exhibition is contemplated. With respect to its other objectives, the Association shall conduct lectures, seminars and any other functions or operations appropriate for the dissemination of public knowledge and appreciation of art and shall promote the exchange of artists' aesthetic expressions, concepts and practices among the various academic, cultural, ethnic, religious and social groups within Miami-Dade County.
These objectives may be revised or restated by the Association trustees.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Neither the Board of Trustees nor any of its members shall direct the appointment of any person to, or his removal from, office by the Director or any of his subordinates. Except for the purpose of inquiry, the Board and its members shall deal with the Department employees solely through the Director, and neither the Board nor any of its members shall give orders to any Department employees either publicly or privately.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The bylaws of the Association shall provide that the Association shall hold the County and any individuals serving or employed by the County entirely harmless from and against any and all liabilities, damages, costs, expenses, causes of action, suits, claims, demands or judgments of any nature which arise from the negligent or deliberate acts or omissions of the Association, its officers, trustees, employees or agents; provided however, that this provision shall not apply to actions of or directed by any County employee.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The Association is intended to reflect and be responsive to the cultural needs of the community. The Association should provide a broad source of community support for the Center for the Fine Arts, coordinating its private fund-raising activities and service of volunteers. To these ends, the bylaws and regulations of the Association shall encourage the membership of, and participation in the activities of the Association by, citizens of the diverse cultural, ethnic and artistic backgrounds in Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The Association shall establish a fiscal year which coincides with that of Miami-Dade County. Its budget in connection with the operations of the Center for the Fine Arts shall be balanced.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 87-1, § 1, 1-20-87)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-306. Association; rights and obligations</catch_line>
<text>
The Association shall be responsible for funding all programming of the Center for the Fine Arts. The Board of County Commissioners may from time to time budget or grant funding support to the Association.
<section prefix = "a">
Admissions and charges. The Association may set and collect admissions rates and charges for entrance to the Center for the Fine Arts or any part thereof and may use the funds so collected as it may designate; provided, however, that at least one (1) day each week, admissions shall be free or on a voluntary donation basis and further provided, that the Board of County Commissioners shall approve the schedule of admissions charges as may be in effect from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Gift store. The Association shall have the exclusive right to sell merchandise inside the Center for the Fine Arts and to determine the identity and nature of items offered for sale. No partial assignment, concession, license, or sublease agreement for the gift shop may be entered into without the prior consent of the County regarding selection criteria and the identity of the assignee.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Annual report. The Association shall report to the Board of County Commissioners, no less frequently than once each year, the Association budget and programming at the Center for the Fine Arts.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Books and records. The Association shall maintain books and records in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles. The Association shall furnish an audited accounting to the County within one hundred twenty (120) days after the close of each fiscal year. The County shall have the right to examine and to audit all Association books and records until three (3) years after such time as the Association may cease to exist.

</section>
</text>
The Association shall be responsible for funding all programming of the Center for the Fine Arts. The Board of County Commissioners may from time to time budget or grant funding support to the Association.
<section prefix = "a">
Admissions and charges. The Association may set and collect admissions rates and charges for entrance to the Center for the Fine Arts or any part thereof and may use the funds so collected as it may designate; provided, however, that at least one (1) day each week, admissions shall be free or on a voluntary donation basis and further provided, that the Board of County Commissioners shall approve the schedule of admissions charges as may be in effect from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Gift store. The Association shall have the exclusive right to sell merchandise inside the Center for the Fine Arts and to determine the identity and nature of items offered for sale. No partial assignment, concession, license, or sublease agreement for the gift shop may be entered into without the prior consent of the County regarding selection criteria and the identity of the assignee.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Annual report. The Association shall report to the Board of County Commissioners, no less frequently than once each year, the Association budget and programming at the Center for the Fine Arts.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Books and records. The Association shall maintain books and records in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles. The Association shall furnish an audited accounting to the County within one hundred twenty (120) days after the close of each fiscal year. The County shall have the right to examine and to audit all Association books and records until three (3) years after such time as the Association may cease to exist.

Annotation—CAO 79-40.

FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (56) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 87-1, § 1, adopted Jan. 20, 1987, amended Art. XXXIIIB, relative to the Center for the Fine Arts to read as herein set out in §§ 2-301—2-306. Prior to this amendment, Art. XXXIIIB, §§ 2-301—2-307, derived from Ord. No. 78-46, § 1, adopted July 18, 1978; Ord. No. 79-65, § 1, adopted July 17, 1979; Ord. No. 79-108, §§ 1, 2, enacted Dec. 4, 1979; Ord. No. 81-39, § 1, adopted April 21, 1981; and Ord. No. 82-77, § 1, enacted Sept. 7, 1982. (Back)
Annotation—AO 9-1 (Back)

</section>
</law>
