<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_CXLI._SCRAP_METAL_AND_COPPER_WIR</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2106. Created</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created the Miami-Dade County Task Force on Scrap Metal and Copper Wire Theft ("Task Force").
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2107. Membership; Appointments; Vacancies; and Qualifications</catch_line>
<text>
The Task Force shall be comprised of twenty-six (26) members from the following categories of representatives:
<section prefix = "1">
One (1) member of the Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners appointed by the Chair;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
One (1) selected by each of the following municipalities:
<section prefix = "a">
City of Miami,
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
City of Hialeah,
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
City of Miami Gardens,
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
City of North Miami,
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
City of Miami Beach,
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
City of Medley, and
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
City of Homestead;
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
One (1) selected by the League of Cities;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
One (1) from the Miami-Dade Office of the State Attorney selected by the Miami-Dade Office of the State Attorney;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
One (1) selected by the Miami-Dade County Inspector General's Office;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
One (1) from Florida Power and Light selected by Florida Power and Light;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
One (1) from the Miami-Dade Schools Police Department selected by the Miami-Dade Schools Police Department; and
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
One (1) representative from each of the following County departments appointed by the Mayor or the Mayor's designee:
<section prefix = "a">
Miami-Dade County Police Department, and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Miami-Dade County Public Works Department.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
The following representatives shall be appointed by majority vote of the Board of County Commissioners:
<section prefix = "a">
Six (6) representatives from the scrap metals industry each possessing at least five (5) years experience in the scrap metals industry; and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Five (5) representatives from the community with an understanding of the impact of copper wire and scrap metal theft on neighborhoods.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Vacancies. Vacancies shall be filled in the same manner by which the original members were appointed.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Qualifications of Members. Each member of the Task Force shall be a permanent resident and duly qualified elector of Miami-Dade County, unless the Board of County Commissioners waives this requirement by a two-thirds (2/3) vote of its membership. No applicant shall be selected for the Task Force if he or she has ever had in any jurisdiction any prior charge, indictment, citation, prosecution, plea of guilty or nolo contendere of a felony, misdemeanor, or ordinance violation, for larceny, theft, possession of or dealing in stolen goods or any crime related to scrap metal processors or junk dealers, regardless of whether adjudication was withheld. The members of the Task Force shall serve without compensation but shall be entitled to reimbursement for necessary expenses incurred in the discharge of their duties.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2108. Organization</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
The Task Force may establish, adopt, and amend bylaws, rules, and regulations for its own governance.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
A chairperson and a vice chairperson shall be selected by the Task Force at its first meeting. The chairperson and vice chairperson shall serve at the will of the Task Force.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The chairperson shall preside at all meetings at which he or she is present. The vice chairperson shall act as chairperson in the absence or inability of the chairperson.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
In order to transact any business or to exercise any power vested in the Task Force, a quorum consisting of a majority of those persons duly appointed to the Task Force shall be present, provided that at least one-half (½) of the full Task Force membership has been appointed.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The Task Force may appoint committees to accomplish its tasks. Members of a committee may consist of members of the Task Force and/or other persons with specialized knowledge that would benefit the committee.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
The Mayor or the Mayor's designee shall supply such support staff to the Task Force as may be necessary to fulfill its purpose. The staff shall maintain and keep the records of the Task Force; prepare in cooperation with the chairperson, the agenda for each meeting; be responsible for the preparation of such reports, minutes, documents, or correspondence as the Task Force may direct; and generally administer the business and affairs of the Task Force, subject to budgetary limitations.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
The County Attorney's Office shall provide legal counsel, as needed, to the Task Force.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 11-76, § 3, 10-4-11)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2109. Meetings</catch_line>
<text>
The Task Force shall meet no less than every 90 days. Additional meetings may be held at the discretion of the Task Force.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2110. Powers and duties</catch_line>
<text>
The purpose of the Task Force is to provide non-binding written recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners on:
<section prefix = "1">
Enforcement of ordinances regulating junk dealers and scrap metal processors, including Sections 8A-203, 8A-237, and 8A-9 through 8A-9.6 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Proposed amendments to ordinances regulating junk dealers and scrap metal processors;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Methods of educating local businesses and the community on the effect of ordinances regulating junk dealers and scrap metal processors; and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Methods of preventing the illegal sale of regulated metals and restricted regulated metals as defined in Sections 8A-9.1 and 8A-9.4 of the Code of Miami- Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The Task Force is advisory only and shall not have the power or authority to commit Miami-Dade County or any of its agencies or instrumentalities to any policies, incur any financial obligations or to create any liability, contractual or otherwise, on behalf of Miami-Dade County or any of its agencies or instrumentalities.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2111. Reports</catch_line>
<text>
The Task Force shall submit its first written recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners no later than 180 days from the effective date of this ordinance and shall submit written recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners every 180 days thereafter.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2112. Applicability of County rules and procedures</catch_line>
<text>
The Task Force shall at all times operate under the Florida Open Government laws, including the "Sunshine Law," public meeting laws and public records laws and shall be governed by all State and County conflict of interest laws, as applicable, including the Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance, Section 2-11.1 [of] the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</text>
</law>
