<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_LXXVII._AFRICAN-AMERICAN_TOURIST</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1051. Creation; purpose; duties</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created and established as a task force of Miami-Dade County, the African-American Tourist Site Task Force Board (the Task Force Board"). The Task Force Board is created for the specific purpose of identifying a location and developing business opportunities for a tourist attraction within the African-American community. To that end, the Task Force Board shall submit a final report to the Board of County Commissioners on its findings and recommendations. Prior to submission of the final report, the Task Force Board is directed to appear, as needed, at regular meetings of the Housing, Community and Economic Development and the Maritime Trade and Tourism Committees of the Board of County Commissioners to report on its progress.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1052. Membership, appointment and term office</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Task Force Board shall be composed of twenty-three (23) voting members, appointed as described below. Each member may designate a single alternate to serve and vote on his or her behalf. Members shall serve without compensation.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Task Force Board shall be appointed by the Board with representatives from the following:
<section prefix = "1">
One (1) representative of each member of the Board of County Commissioners for a total of thirteen (13) representatives, to be chosen initially from the membership of the original African-American Tourist Site Task Force.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The County Manager of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Two (2) representatives from the Miami-Dade Chamber of Commerce.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
One (1) representative from the Miami-Dade County Public Schools.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
One (1) representative from the Greater Miami Chamber of Commerce.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Two (2) representatives from the Greater Miami Convention and Visitors Bureau.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
One (1) representative from the Beacon Council.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
One (1) representative from the Tools for Change.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Mayor or City Manager of the City of Miami.
Vacancies on the Task Force Board shall be filled in the same manner by which the original members were appointed, with a special emphasis on choosing persons representative of the gender, racial and ethnic composition of the entire community, and the segments of the community necessary to achieving the goals of the Task Force Board.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All voting members shall serve terms of three (3) years each.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
No member, with the exception of ex officio members, shall be permitted to serve more that two (2) consecutive and complete terms of three (3) years each unless so authorized by two-thirds (2/3) vote of the full membership of the Board of County Commissioners. Members may be removed in accordance with provisions of Section 2-11.38 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The Board of County Commissioners may, from time to time, appoint ex officio non-voting members, by resolution or motion.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Each member shall comply with the requirements of Section 2-11.38 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 96-169, § 1, 11-12-96)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1053. Organizations and procedures</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Task Force Board shall organize after the members thereof have qualified to serve and shall select one (1) of its members as a chairperson and such other officers as the Task Force Board may determine to be necessary. In addition, the Task Force Board shall make, adopt and amend bylaws, rules and regulations for its own governance. The Task Force Board shall create any committees it deems necessary.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Task Force Board shall hold regular meetings and such other meetings as it deems necessary. A majority of the members of the Task Force Board shall constitute a quorum. Minutes shall be kept of all meetings and all meetings shall be public. The Clerk of the Board shall keep minutes of all meetings.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All Task Force Board members shall comply with the Florida Open Government Laws, including the "Sunshine Law," Public Meeting Laws and Public Records Laws and shall be governed by all state and county conflict of interest laws, as applicable, including Miami-Dade County's Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance, Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 96-169, § 1, 11-12-96)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1054. Powers and functions of the Task Force Board</catch_line>
<text>
The members shall have the following powers, duties, functions and responsibilities:
<section prefix = "a">
To serve in an advisory capacity to the Board of County Commissioners with respect to all issues affecting or relating to the designation, development and implementation of the Site.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
To recommend to the Board of County Commissioners an annual budget and plan for use of the federal grant and other funds allocated to carry out plans for the Site.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
To recommend to the Board of County Commissioners the allocations of funds to public agencies, the award of contracts and grants to organizations, entities and agencies, including independent not-for-profit corporations organized under Section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
To review the Site recommendations on a regular basis and at least annually to assure that the Site's implementation is achieving Site goals and addressing the needs of the Community.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
To evaluate performance and recommend to the Board of County Commissioners any needed amendments or modifications.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
To submit annually of the Board of County Commissioners a report summarizing and evaluating the performance of all programs and activities in the Site Selection, including the timetable for performance. The report shall include an audit and accounting, in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, of all funds received and expended.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1055. Staff support</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager shall provide to the Task Force Board adequate staff and support services to enable the Task Force Board to carry out its duties and responsibilities.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-1056—2-1065. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
</law>
