<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">Chapter 30A URBAN RENEWAL</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="2">ARTICLE_IV._HOMESTEAD_COMMUNITY_REDEVELO</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 30A-101. Incorporation of ordinance recitations</catch_line>
<text>
The recitations set out in Ordinance No. 94-125 are hereby deemed true and correct and are hereby incorporated as a part of this article by reference.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30A-102. Establishment of redevelopment trust fund; appropriations of funds; calculation of increment</catch_line>
<text>
A Homestead Community Redevelopment and Revitalization Trust Fund (the "fund") is hereby established. Each taxing authority (as defined in Part III Chapter 163, Florida Statutes, as amended) shall annually pay into the fund, a sum not less than that increment in the income, proceeds, revenues and funds of each taxing authority derived from or held in connection with the community redevelopment project area, and the city's undertaking and implementing of its community redevelopment and revitalization plan. The increment shall be determined annually and shall be that amount equal to ninety-five (95) percent of the difference between:
<section prefix = "a">
The amount of ad valorem taxes levied each year by each taxing authority, exclusive of any amount from any debt service mileage, on taxable real property contained within the geographic boundaries of the redevelopment area; and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The amount of ad valorem taxes which would have been produced by the rate upon which the tax is levied each year by or for each taxing authority, exclusive of any debt service mileage, upon the total of the assessed value of the taxable real property in the redevelopment area as shown upon the most recent assessment roll used in connection with the taxation of such property by each taxing authority prior to the effective date of this article [Ordinance No. 94-125].

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30A-103. Obligation to appropriate; duration of obligation; limitations on obligation, bond sales and refundings; accounting requirements for County increment</catch_line>
<text>
Each taxing authority shall by January 1st of each year appropriate to the fund for so long as any indebtedness pledging the tax increment due the fund is outstanding (but not to exceed thirty (30) years), a sum not less than the increment as defined and determined by Section 30A-102. In no year shall the County's obligation to the fund exceed the amount of that year's tax increment as determined in Section 30A-102. Beginning with the twentieth year after the date of sale of the initial bonding or indebtedness pledging tax increment funds, no new sale of bonds or indebtedness supported by the County's tax increment may occur nor may existing indebtedness so supported be refunded without amending this article [Ordinance No. 94-125]. The County's obligation to fund the fund annually shall continue until all loans, advances, and indebtedness, if any, and interest thereon, of the community redevelopment agency incurred as a result of redevelopment in the redevelopment area have been paid. The County's increment contribution is to be accounted for as a separate revenue within the fund but may be combined with other revenues for the purpose of paying debt service. The County must approve the amount, duration of the obligation and the purpose of any bond, note or other form of indebtedness, including advances, pledging or otherwise obligating tax increment funds.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30A-104. Review of financial records; right of audit</catch_line>
<text>
The financial records for the redevelopment trust fund shall be prepared pursuant to Section 163.387(8), Florida Statutes, as amended and shall be available for County inspection. The County reserves the right of audit of the fund.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30A-105. Public purpose</catch_line>
<text>
This article [Ordinance No. 94-125] is hereby declared to be for a public purpose and for the welfare of the citizens of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and shall be liberally construed to effectuate the purpose thereof.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30A-106. Severability</catch_line>
<text>
If any section, subsection, sentence, clause or provision of this article is held invalid, the remainder of this article shall not be affected by such invalidity.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 30A-107—30A-120. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (3) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 94-125, adopted June 21, 1994, amended the Code by the addition of provisions which have been included herein at the discretion of the editor as Art. IV, §§ 30A-101—30A-106. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
