<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_CX._BEACON_LAKES_COMMUNITY_DEVEL</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1661. Findings</catch_line>
<text>
The foregoing findings, which are expressly set forth herein, are hereby adopted and made a part hereof.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1662. Petition</catch_line>
<text>
The Petition to establish the Beacon Lakes Community Development District over the real property described in Exhibit A attached to the ordinance from which this article derives, which was filed by AMB Codina Beacon Lakes L.L.C., on January 17, 2003 and which Petition as supplemented is on file at the Office of the Clerk of the Board, is hereby granted. A copy of the Petition is attached in its entirety and incorporated herein (Exhibit B).
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1663. District boundaries</catch_line>
<text>
The external boundaries of the District shall be as depicted on the location map attached to the ordinance from which this article derives and incorporated herein as Exhibit C.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1664. District name</catch_line>
<text>
The name of the District shall be the "Beacon Lakes Community Development District."
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1665. Purpose</catch_line>
<text>
The Beacon Lakes Community Development District is created for the purposes set forth in Chapter 190, Florida Statutes, pursuant to the authority granted by Section 1.01(A)(21) of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1666. District charter</catch_line>
<text>
Pursuant to Section 190.005(2)(d), Florida Statutes, the charter for the Beacon Lakes Community Development District shall be Sections 190.006 through 190.041, Florida Statutes.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1667. Grant of general powers</catch_line>
<text>
The Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners hereby grants to the Beacon Lakes Community Development District all general powers authorized pursuant to Section 190.011, Florida Statutes, and hereby finds that it is in the public interest of all citizens of Miami-Dade County to grant such general powers.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1668. Grant of special powers</catch_line>
<text>
The Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners hereby grants to the Beacon Lakes Community Development District the special powers authorized pursuant to Section 190.012(1), Florida Statutes and Sections 190.012(2)(d) and (f), (except for powers regarding waste disposal), Florida Statutes and Section 190.012(3), Florida Statutes, and hereby finds that it is in the public interest of all citizens of Miami-Dade County to grant such special powers.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1669. Bond validation</catch_line>
<text>
All bonds issued by the Beacon Lakes Community Development District pursuant to the powers granted by this article shall be validated pursuant to Chapter 75, Florida Statutes.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1670. No district bonds or debts to constitute debts or obligations of the county</catch_line>
<text>
No bond, debt or other obligation of the Beacon Lakes Community Development District, nor any default thereon, shall constitute a debt or obligation of Miami-Dade County, except upon the express approval and agreement of the Miami-Dade Board of County Commissioners.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1671. County rates, fees and charges applicable to district</catch_line>
<text>
Notwithstanding any power granted to the Beacon Lakes Community Development District pursuant to this article, neither the District nor any real or personal property or revenue in the district shall, solely by reason of the District's creation and existence, be exempted from any requirement for the payment of any and all rates, fees, charges, permitting fees, impact fees, connection fees, or similar County rates, fees or charges, special taxing districts special assessments which are required by law, ordinance or County rule or regulation to be imposed within or upon any local government within the County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1672. Power of eminent domain</catch_line>
<text>
Notwithstanding any power granted to the Beacon Lakes Community Development District pursuant to this article, the District may exercise the power of eminent domain outside the District's existing boundaries only with the prior specific and express approval of the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1673. District regulations</catch_line>
<text>
This article shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of enactment unless vetoed by the Mayor, and if vetoed, shall become effective only upon an override by this Board. It is provided, however, that this article shall not become effective, in whole or in part, unless on or before 5:00 p.m. on the 10th day after the date of enactment, a proposed Interlocal Agreement has been submitted and received by the County Manager, in a form acceptable to the County Attorney, and executed by each member of the Board of Supervisor designates named in Section 4 of the ordinance from which this article derives, having provisions in substantially the following form:
<section prefix = "a">
Except upon the prior written consent of Miami-Dade County, which shall not be unreasonably withheld, the District shall not apply for or use grants or loans of money or other property from the United States, the State of Florida, any other unit of local government in Florida, or any other person or entity (except in connection with any financings of the District, and any loans made to the District by the developers, their affiliates and/or lenders in connection with the land development orders for property that is the subject of the Petition approved hereby, as they may be amended from time to time) for any District purpose. Any and all such requests by the District for authorization to apply for or use such grants or loans shall be made to Miami-Dade County, which shall have the sole discretion to decide whether to allow application for any such loans or grants. Should the County apply for any such loans or grants on behalf of the District, the District shall pay all costs to the County in connection with any such applications;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Miami-Dade County Water and Sewer Department shall provide all water and wastewater service to the District and all lands within the District boundaries.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Beacon Lakes Community Development District shall, to the best of its ability, fully utilize economic development enhancement resource agencies and programs designed to involve small and minority businesses in the development and expansion of permanent job opportunities within the District. The proposed Interlocal Agreement containing this provisions shall contain examples of such agencies and programs. The Beacon Lakes Community Development District will attempt to access the range of job skills available in the region and promote greater labor force enhancement. At a minimum, the Beacon Lakes Community Development District shall encourage all landowners in the District to provide potential commercial tenants with information about employment and training agencies that maintain a database of trained/skilled workers to consider in meeting the District's employment needs.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The Beacon Lakes Community Development District shall adopt and utilize specific measures designed to involve small and minority businesses in the development and expansion of permanent job opportunities. Such measures shall be in substantially the forms employed by Miami-Dade County, specifically, the Miami-Dade County Community Small Business Enterprise Program; the Black, Women and Hispanic Enterprise Programs; fair subcontracting measures; nondiscrimination in bidding and contracting measures; and prompt payment measures.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The Beacon Lakes Community Development District shall provide for the election of a member to its Board of Supervisors who is deemed by the Board of County Commissioners to represent the voice of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
In addition to notice required under Section 190.048, Florida Statutes, the Beacon Lakes Community Development District shall provide a separate notice to each prospective purchaser of residential property in the District, prior to execution of any contract for sale, describing the type and amount of all projected taxes and assessments on the property in the District, including a good-faith estimate of the taxes and assessments on the individual parcel being considered for prospective purchase.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
The Beacon Lakes Community Development District shall adopt and utilize measures providing for employment of welfare recipients by entities contracting with the District. Such measures shall be in substantially the form of Miami-Dade County Resolution R-1206-97, as the same shall be amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
The Beacon Lakes Community Development District agrees to apply for the creation of a multipurpose special taxing district to maintain the development's infrastructure such as roadways, storm drainage, water, sewer and landscape should the CDD be dissolved or fail to fulfill its maintenance obligations. Any and all plats of property within the CDD shall contain a conveyance clause to Miami-Dade County to be exercised at its discretion should the CDD be dissolved or fail to perform.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-1673—2-1680. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (119) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 03-105, §§ 1—3, 5—13, 15, adopted May 6, 2003 did not specifically amend the Code. Hence, its inclusion herein as article CX, sections 2-1661—2-1673, was at the discretion of the editor. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
