<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 29 TAXATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_VI._CONVENTION_DEVELOPMENT_TAX</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-60. Levy and imposition of convention development tax</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
There shall be levied and imposed throughout Miami-Dade County, except within any municipality which adopts a resolution prohibiting the levy of this tax pursuant to clause (d) of this section, a convention development tax at a rate of three (3) percent on the amount of any payment made by any person or entity for the rental, lease, or use for a period of six (6) months or less of any living quarters or accommodations in a hotel, apartment hotel, motel, resort motels, apartment, apartment motel, rooming house, tourist or trailer camp, mobile home park, recreational vehicle park, or condominium. When receipt of consideration is by way of property other than money, the tax shall be levied and imposed on the fair market value of such nonmonetary consideration. Payments under an oral lease due weekly, monthly, or otherwise, shall not be subject to the tax where the tenant occupies a residential unit located in a facility in which residential units are leased primarily as permanent residences. Any payment made by a person to rent, lease or use any living quarters or accommodations which are exempt from the tax imposed under Section 212.03, Florida Statutes, shall likewise be exempt from any tax imposed under this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
This convention development tax shall be in addition to any other tax imposed pursuant to Chapter 212 and Section 125.0104, Florida Statutes, and in addition to all other taxes, fees and the consideration for the rental or lease.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The convention development tax shall be charged by the person or entity receiving the consideration for the lease or rental and it shall be collected by the lessor from the lessee, tenant or customer at the time of payment of the consideration for such lease or rental.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The governing body of each municipality in Miami-Dade County in which a municipal tourist tax is levied pursuant to Chapter 67-930, Laws of Florida, may adopt a resolution prohibiting the levy of the convention development tax within such municipality. No funds collected pursuant to this article may be expended in a municipality which has adopted such a resolution.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Where rentals are received by way of property, goods, wares, merchandise, services or other things of value, the tax shall be at the rate of three (3) percent of the value of said property, services or other things of value.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Any person taxable under this section who, either by himself or through his agents or employees, fails or refuses to charge and collect the taxes herein provided from the person paying any rental or lease is, in addition to being personally liable for the payment of the tax, guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in Section 775.082, Section 775.083, or Section 775.084, Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
No person shall advertise or hold out to the public in any manner, directly or indirectly, that he will absorb all or any part of the tax; that he will relieve the person paying the rental of the payment of all or any part of the tax; or that the tax will not be added to the rental or lease consideration or, if added, that the tax or any part thereof will be refunded or refused, either directly or indirectly, by any method whatsoever. Any person who willfully violates any provision of this paragraph is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in Section 775.082, Section 775.083, or Section 775.084, Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
The rental of living accommodations in migrant labor camps is not taxable under this section. "Migrant labor camps" are defined as one or more buildings or structures, tents, trailers, or vehicles, or any portion thereof, together with the land appertaining thereto, established, operated, or used as living quarters for seasonal, temporary, or migrant workers.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Full-time students enrolled in an institution offering postsecondary education and military personnel currently on active duty who reside in the facilities described in subsection (a) shall be exempt from the tax imposed by this article. The County shall be empowered to determine what shall be deemed acceptable proof of full-time enrollment.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 83-91, § 2, 10-4-83; Ord. No. 84-43, §§ 1, 2, 6-5-84; Ord. No. 87-80, §§ 6—8, 11-17-87)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-61. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 87-80, § 1, adopted Nov. 17, 1987, amended § 29-61, relative to the collection and disbursement of the convention development tax, in its entirety and redesignated said provisions as § 29-61.1. The history notations of former § 29-61 have been included in § 29-61.1 for reference purposes.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-61.1. Collection and disbursement</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The person or entity receiving the consideration for such rental or lease shall receive, account for, and remit the tax to the Miami-Dade County Tax Collector in accordance with the following procedures:
<section prefix = "1">
The taxes levied hereunder shall be due and payable monthly on the first day of each month, and for the purpose of ascertaining the amount of tax payable under this article, it shall be the duty of all lessors to make a return, on or before the twentieth day of the month, to the County Tax Collector, upon forms prepared and furnished by the County, showing all rentals during the preceding calendar month; however, the County may authorize a quarterly return and payment when the tax remitted by the lessor for the preceding quarter did not exceed twenty-five dollars ($25.00). The County or its designated agent shall accept returns if postmarked on or before the twentieth day of the month; if the twentieth day falls on a Saturday, Sunday, or federal or State legal holiday, returns shall be accepted if postmarked on the next succeeding work day. Each lessor shall file a return for each tax period even though no tax is due for such period.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The same duties, privileges, enforcement procedures and penalties imposed by Chapter 212, Florida Statutes upon dealers in tangible property respecting the remission and collection of tax, the making of returns, the keeping of books, records and accounts, and compliance with the rules of the Florida Department of Revenue in the administration of said chapter, to the extent that such provisions of said Florida Statutes and Department of Revenue regulations are not in conflict with the provisions of this article, shall apply to and be binding upon all persons and entities who are subject to the provisions of this Ordinance Number 87-80.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The tax imposed by this article shall constitute a lien on the property of the lessee or rentee of any sleeping accommodations in the same manner as and shall be collectible as are, liens authorized and imposed by Sections 713.67, 713.68 and 713.69, Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
(i) Every lessor upon whose premises the tax is levied hereunder shall have the duty to maintain adequate records to show gross collections from all rentals and the amount of tax due and paid hereunder. It shall be the duty of every such person so charged with such duty, moreover, to keep and preserve, for a period of three (3) years, all invoices and other records of leases and rentals under this article, and all such books, invoices, and other records shall be open to examination at all reasonable hours to the County or its designated agent.
<section prefix = "ii">
For the purpose of this subsection, if a lessor does not have adequate records of his rentals the County or its designated agent, may, upon the basis of a test or sampling of the lessor's available records or other information relating to the rentals made by such lessor, for a representative period, determine the proportion that taxable rentals bear to total rentals. This subsection does not affect the duty of the lessor to collect, or the liability of any tenant to pay, any tax imposed by or pursuant to this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
If the records of a lessor are adequate but voluminous in nature and substance, the County or its designated agent may statistically sample such records and project the audit finding derived therefrom over the entire audit period to determine the proportion that taxable rental amounts be to total rental amounts, provided, the lessor and the County have entered into an agreement which provides for the use of statistical sampling and projections and the means and methods to be used. The agreement shall be binding on the lessor and the County.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
(i) The County is authorized to audit or inspect the records and accounts of such lessors and correct by credit any overpayment of tax; and, in the event of a deficiency, an assessment shall be made and collected. No administrative finding of fact is necessary prior to the assessment of any tax deficiency.
<section prefix = "ii">
In the event any lessor charged herein fails or refuses to make his records available for inspection so that no audit or examination has been made of the books and records of such dealer or person, fails or refuses to register as a lessor, or fails to make a report and pay the tax as provided by this article, or makes a grossly incorrect report, or makes a report that is false or fraudulent, then, in such event, it shall be the duty of the County to make an assessment from an estimate based upon the best information then available to it for the taxable period of retail sales of such lessor, the gross proceeds from rentals, together with interest, plus penalty, if such have accrued, as the case may be. Then the County shall proceed to collect such taxes, interest, and penalty on the basis of such assessment, which shall be considered prima facie correct; and the burden to show the contrary shall rest upon the lessor.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Collections received by the Tax Collector from the convention development tax, less costs of administration, are to be deposited into the Miami-Dade County Convention Development Tax Trust Fund hereby established.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Moneys in the Miami-Dade County Convention Development Tax Trust Fund shall be divided and paid on a monthly basis to the County for distribution pursuant to Section 212.0305, Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. Ord. No. 83-91, § 2, 10-4-83; Ord. No. 84-43, § 3, 6-5-84; Ord. No. 87-80, § 1, 11-17-87; Ord. No. 96-91, § 1, 6-18-96)</history>
Note—See the editor's note to § 29-61
<catch_line>Sec. 29-61.2. Tax Collector's powers and duties</catch_line>
<text>
The Tax Collector shall maintain accurate books, records and accounts reflecting the collection, administration and disbursement of the tax. The Tax Collector shall prescribe and publish such forms as may be necessary to effectuate the local collection of the Miami-Dade County Convention Development Tax. For the purpose of collecting the convention development tax, the Tax Collector shall have the same duties and powers as those vested in the Florida Department of Revenue under Chapter 212, Florida Statutes.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-61.3. Costs of administration</catch_line>
<text>
The Tax Collector may retain a portion of the tax collected for costs of administration in an amount not to exceed two (2) percent of collections.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-61.4. Dealer's credit</catch_line>
<text>
The same duties and privileges imposed upon dealers by Chapter 212, Florida Statutes apply under this article. To compensate dealers for keeping of prescribed records and the proper accounting and remitting of taxes by them, dealers shall be allowed three (3) percent of the first one thousand dollars ($1,000.000) of the amount of tax due and accounted for and remitted to the Tax Collector and one (1) percent of all amounts in excess of one thousand dollars ($1,000.00) on each tax return to the Tax Collector. The collection allowance may not be granted nor may any deduction be permitted, if the tax is delinquent at the time of payment. The Tax Collector may reduce the collection allowance by ten (10) percent or fifty dollars ($50.00), whichever is less, if the taxpayer files an incomplete return.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-61.5. Procedures for confidentiality</catch_line>
<text>
All information contained in returns, reports, accounts or declarations received from dealers, and from the Department of Revenue, including investigative reports and information, is confidential except for official purposes and subject to the provisions of Section 213.053, Florida Statutes. Miami-Dade County, its officers and employees having access to convention development tax information shall accord such information, documents, names, and addresses the same confidentiality as required by said statute. All Miami-Dade County officers and employees having access shall be made aware of those requirements and the penalties for their violation.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-62. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 84-43, § 4, adopted June 5, 1984, repealed § 29-62, "Disbursement," as derived from § 2 of Ord. No. 83-91, adopted Oct. 4, 1983.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-63. Application of revenues</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
All tax revenues and any interest accrued thereon received pursuant to this section shall be used as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
The portion received by the authority designated by the City of Miami Beach shall be used to extend, enlarge, and improve the Miami Beach Convention Center;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The portion received by the authority designated by the City of Miami shall be used to construct a new multipurpose convention/coliseum/exhibition center or the maximum components thereof as funds permit within the City of Miami;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
After the completion of any project under subparagraph (1) or (2), tax revenues and interest accrued may be used to acquire, construct, extend, enlarge, remodel, repair, improve, operate, manage, or maintain one (1) or more convention centers, stadiums, exhibition halls, arenas, coliseums, or auditoriums; and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
For the purposes of completion of any project pursuant to this section, tax revenues and interest accrued may be used:
<section prefix = "a">
As collateral, pledged or hypothecated, for projects authorized by this section, including bonds issued in connection therewith; or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
As a pledge or capital contribution in conjunction with a partnership, joint venture, or other business arrangement between a municipality and one (1) or more business entities for projects authorized by this section.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 83-91, § 2, 10-4-83; Ord. No. 11-02, § 1, 1-20-11)</history>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (6) ---
State Law reference— Convention development tax, F.S. § 212.0305. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
