<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_CXXXVIII._VOLUNTARY_ENERGY_EFFIC</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2079. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
Administrator means the County or any qualified firm selected by the County through a competitive process to administer the Energy Savings Program.
Agreement means a written agreement between the County and an Eligible Participant setting forth the terms and conditions of the Energy Savings Program.
Contractor means a contractor properly certified or registered pursuant to part I or part II of chapter 489, Florida Statutes.
Eligible Participant means any residential or commercial Property owner who voluntarily participates in this Energy Savings Program and satisfies the eligibility requirements set forth below.
Energy Audit shall mean an energy audit performed by qualified energy auditor or a certified building energy rater approved by the County pursuant to Section 2-2086.
Energy Savings Program means the Voluntary Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy Program authorized by this Article.
Notice means the notice that an Eligible Participant is required to provide to a purchaser of the Property prior to its sale.
Property means a property, residential or commercial, located within the boundaries of the County which is being improved pursuant to the Energy Savings Program.
Qualifying Improvement includes any:
<section prefix = "1">
Energy conservation and efficiency improvement, which is a measure to reduce consumption through conservation or a more efficient use of electricity, natural gas, propane or other forms of energy on the property, including, but not limited to, air sealing; installation of insulation; installation of energy-efficient heating, cooling, or ventilation systems; building modifications to increase the use of daylight; replacement of window(s); installation of energy controls or energy recovery systems; installation of electric vehicle charging equipment; and installation of efficient lighting equipment; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Renewable energy improvement, which is the installation of any system in which the electrical, mechanical, or thermal energy is produced from a method that uses one or more of the following fuels or energy sources: hydrogen, solar energy, geothermal energy, bioenergy, and wind energy; provided, such energy conservation and efficiency improvement and renewable energy improvement shall be made, and affixed, to an existing residential or commercial Property and not to new construction and shall not include a household appliance such as a washing machine or refrigerator that is not permanently fixed to real property.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2080. Eligible participants</catch_line>
<text>
In order to be an Eligible Participant, a Property owner (or Property) must meet the following criteria:
<section prefix = "1">
Be the legal owner of the Property and provide proof of ownership in the application for the Energy Savings Program.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Property must be located within Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
All Property taxes and any other assessments levied on the same bill as Property taxes are paid and have not been delinquent for the preceding three (3) years or the Property owner's period of ownership, whichever is less;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Property owner must be current on any mortgage.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Property owner cannot be in bankruptcy nor can the Property be an asset in any bankruptcy proceeding.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Property cannot have any federal income tax lien, judgment lien or similar involuntary lien, including construction liens, encumbering it.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
No notices of default or other evidence of Property-based debt delinquency have been recorded during the preceding 3 years or the Property owner's period of ownership, whichever is less.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2081. Application</catch_line>
<text>
An Eligible Participant shall submit a complete application to the Administrator for approval. A complete application shall include the following information:
<section prefix = "1">
Proof of ownership and location of the Property. Organizational documents if the Property owner is not on the title as an individual.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Documentation showing the structure or building, subject of the application, is an existing structure or building on the date of application.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
A cost estimate for the installation of the Qualifying Improvements completed by a Contractor (including the name and license number of the Contractor). This estimate shall include all construction costs, equipment, permitting fees, recording fees for the assessment of liens, energy audit costs, and contingency fees. Estimated costs shall be reasonable for the scope of the proposed project and in relation to the property value.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Written documentation indicating that the Property owner meets all of the criteria set forth in Section 2-2080(3)—(7) above.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Statement that the Eligible Participant will agree to a non-ad valorem assessment being collected pursuant to Section 197.3632, Florida Statutes to secure any loans entered into by the Eligible Participant related to the Energy Savings Program.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Proof that notice was provided to any lender of the Eligible Participant's intent to enter into written agreement with the County with respect to the Energy Savings Program and in the event of a loan, the maximum principal amount to be financed and the maximum annual assessment necessary to repay that amount.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2083. Agreement terms</catch_line>
<text>
The County shall enter into a voluntary written agreement with each Eligible Participant. The written agreement shall provide, among other matters, for the following:
<section prefix = "1">
All work requiring a license under any applicable law to make a qualifying improvement shall be performed by a Contractor.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The source and amount of funding to be provided to the Eligible Participant.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The maximum limit of the financing for the Energy Savings Program shall not exceed 10 percent of the just value of the Property as determined by the County's Property Appraiser on the latest available tax roll unless:
•
A higher financing amount is consented to by the mortgage holder on the Property, if one exists; or
•
The Energy Audit demonstrates that the annual energy savings from the Qualified Improvement equals or exceeds the annual repayment amount of the non-ad valorem assessment.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Express voluntary consent by the Eligible Participant to accept the non-ad valorem assessment collection process pursuant to Section 197.3632, Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The length of time for the Eligible Participant to repay the non-ad valorem assessment, provided, that it shall not exceed 20 years.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
The Eligible Participant shall be responsible for assuring the Qualifying Improvements are completed as reflected in the approved application documents. The Eligible Participant also consents to providing access to the Property to the County to verify that the Qualifying Improvements have been completed as proposed in the application.
At the time of a transfer of Property ownership except a transfer resulting from foreclosure, the past due balances of any non-ad valorem assessment under this Subsection shall be due for payment, but future payments shall continue as a lien on the property. At or before the execution of a contract for the sale and purchase of any property for which a non-ad valorem assessment for the Energy Savings Program has been levied and has an unpaid balance due, the seller shall give the prospective purchaser a Notice.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
The risks associated with participating in the Energy Savings Program shall be disclosed in the written Agreement, including risks related to the failure of the Eligible Participant to make payments and the risk of issuance of a tax certificate and loss of the property pursuant to Chapter 197, Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
The cost of an energy savings audit or the cost to complete an estimate of information on energy saving measures, estimated energy savings for each measure, estimated greenhouse gas reductions and estimated cost savings from the projects will be subject to reimbursement upon execution of the written agreement to accept the non-ad valorem assessment.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Description of the Qualifying Improvements, their cost, estimated completion date and estimated savings.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
A copy of the Energy Audit shall be included as an Exhibit.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
The Eligible Participant shall agree to apply any rebates provided by an entity other than the County, received for the Qualifying Improvements, towards the repayment of any non-ad valorem assessment.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
The Eligible Participant shall provide all copies of final permits and inspections to the County upon completion of the Qualifying Improvements.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2084. Administration</catch_line>
<text>
The Energy Savings Program may be administered by the County Mayor or County Mayor's designee or by a qualified energy firm selected by the County through a competitive selection process. The Energy Savings Program shall be administered in accordance with this Article and any additional regulations and orders adopted by the Board of Miami-Dade County Commission from time to time.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2085. Funding</catch_line>
<text>
The County may issue bonds or notes secured solely from non-ad valorem special assessments collected pursuant to Chapter 197, Florida Statutes and is authorized by this Article to provide funds to Eligible Participants to make Qualifying Improvements. The County may also make available to the Energy Savings Program, federal or state grant funds, private loans from a financial institution or not-for-profit sources of funds.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2086. Energy audit</catch_line>
<text>
At a minimum, an Energy Audit for the Energy Savings Program shall include the following information:
<section prefix = "1">
Recommendations for energy savings measures;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Estimated energy savings and a priority ranking for each measure;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Estimated renewable energy to be produced;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Estimated greenhouse gas reductions; and
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Estimated cost savings resulting from the implementation of the recommendations and use of funds made available by the County.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2087. Non-ad valorem assessments</catch_line>
<text>
The County is authorized to impose non-ad valorem assessments on Property to secure the repayment of any loan by an Eligible Participant to pay for Qualified Improvement(s). The non-ad valorem assessments shall be collected pursuant to Section 197.3632, Florida Statutes or any successor Section and, notwithstanding Section 197.3632(8)(a), shall not be subject to discount for early payment. The notice and adoption requirements of Section 197.3632(4), Florida Statutes are not applicable if the non-ad valorem assessments are collected pursuant to and in compliance with Section 163.08, Florida Statutes and this Article. The intent resolution, publication of notice, and mailed notices to the property appraiser, tax collector, and Department of Revenue required by Section 197.3632(3)(a), Florida Statutes may be provided on or before August 15 in conjunction with any non-ad valorem assessment authorized by this Article, if the property appraiser, tax collector, and local government agree.
Pursuant to Chapter 197, Florida Statutes, non-ad valorem assessments levied pursuant to this Article shall remain liens, coequal with the lien of all state, County, district, and municipal taxes, superior in dignity to all other liens, titles, and claims, until paid.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2088. Recordation</catch_line>
<text>
The Agreement shall be recorded in the public records of the County within five (5) days after execution of the Agreement. The recorded Agreement shall provide constructive notice that the assessment to be levied on the property constitutes a lien of equal dignity to County taxes and assessments from the date of recordation. Failure to record the Agreement within such five (5) day period shall not invalidate the terms of the Agreement.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2089. Mortgagees</catch_line>
<text>
A provision in any agreement between a mortgagee or other lien holder and an Eligible Participant, or otherwise now or hereafter binding upon the Property or the Eligible Participant, which allows for acceleration of payment of the mortgage, note, or lien or other unilateral modification solely as a result of entering into a Agreement as provided for in the Energy Savings Program regarding the collection of non-ad valorem assessments is not enforceable. This subsection does not limit the authority of the holder or loan servicer to increase the required monthly escrow by an amount necessary to annually pay the Qualifying Improvement non-ad valorem special assessment.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2090. Notice to purchaser</catch_line>
<text>
At or before the execution of a contract for the sale and purchase of any property for which a non-ad valorem assessment for the Energy Savings Program has been levied and has an unpaid balance due, the seller shall give the prospective purchaser the following notice in writing:
The property being purchased is located within the jurisdiction of Miami-Dade County that has placed an assessment on the property pursuant to Section 163.08, Florida Statutes. The assessment is for a qualifying improvement to the property relating to energy efficiency, renewable energy, or wind resistance, and is not based on the value of property. You are encouraged to contact the county property appraiser's office to learn more about this and other assessments that may be provided by law.

</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2091. Limitations</catch_line>
<text>
A provision in any agreement between the County and a public or private power or energy provider or other utility provider is not enforceable if it limits or prohibits the County from exercising its authority under this Article. A provision in any agreement between a mortgagee or other lienholder and an Eligible Participant, or otherwise now or hereafter binding upon an Eligible Participant, which allows for acceleration of payment of the mortgage, note, or lien or other unilateral modification solely as a result of entering into an Agreement as provided in this Article is not enforceable.
</text>
</law>
