<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_CXXIX._EMPOWERMENT_ZONE_STRATEGI</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2024. [Created.</catch_line>
<text>
The Empowerment Zone Strategies Alliance is hereby created. The Empowerment Zone Strategies Alliance (hereinafter "EZSA") shall consist of fourteen (14) members. The Mayors of Miami-Dade County and the cities of Miami, Florida City and Homestead shall each appoint one member to the EZSA (the "general appointments"). In addition to their general appointments, the Mayor or Miami-Dade County shall also appoint one member representing the Miami International Airport area and the Mayor of the City of Miami shall appoint one member representing the Central Business District/Seaport area. Each of the currently existing eight (8) Empowerment Zone Neighborhood Assemblies—1) Melrose; 2) Allapatah/Civic Center; 3) Overtown; 4) East Little Havana; 5) Wynwood; 6) Liberty City/Model City; 7) Homestead; and 8) Florida City—shall appoint one of its members to the EZSA.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2025. [Implementation.</catch_line>
<text>
The Mayor or his designee is authorized to place the responsibility for the implementation of the County's Empowerment Zone designation with the Office of Community and Economic Development (OCED). The EZSA shall review OCED staff funding recommendations and make final recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners on the funding of all projects and programs funded with federal Empowerment Zone funds and any program income derived from local, and federal Empowerment Zone funds invested in Empowerment Zone assisted activities that are within the established EZ funding criteria, County procurement and fiscal guidelines, and benchmarks approved by the U.S. HUD. The funding recommendations made by OCED staff to the EZSA shall be based on proposals that comport with carrying out the Empowerment Zone Strategic Plan. Prior to OCED's funding recommendations to the EZSA, OCED shall receive input during the review of proposals through the currently existing Neighborhood Assembly process. Implementation and award of funds as recommended by EZSA shall require review by and approval of the Board of County Commissioners. OCED shall implement the final funding decisions as determined by the Board of County Commissioners. EZSA shall operate through the end of the County's designation as an Empowerment Zone.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2026. [Neighborhood assemblies.</catch_line>
<text>
Neighborhood Assemblies shall [be] re-established and convened for each of the neighborhoods in the Empowerment Zone. The role of the Neighborhood Assemblies shall be:
<section prefix = "1">
To guide the implementation of the Empowerment Zone Strategic Plan and to make recommendations on projects to OCED;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To advise and recommend to OCED when appropriate, amendments and revisions to the Strategic Plan, and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
To name representatives to the EZSA.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2027. [Reports.</catch_line>
<text>
OCED shall report quarterly to the BCC on all funding decisions made by the EZSA. These reports shall also be provided to the cities of Miami, Florida City and Homestead.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2028. [Termination of implementing arm.</catch_line>
<text>
The designation of OCED as the implementing arm of the Empowerment Zone shall terminate upon the expiration of the County's designation as an Empowerment Zone.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2029. [Authority.</catch_line>
<text>
The Mayor or his designee is authorized to take all actions necessary to carry out the purposes of this ordinance, including but not limited to, amending agreements with each of the Empowerment Zone Partners and U.S. HUD, including amending the Empowerment Zone Strategic Plan and the Memorandum of Agreement between the County and U.S. HUD, and executing any necessary interlocal agreements with the cities of Miami, Florida City, and Homestead. The Mayor or his designee is further authorized to execute and amend all contracts, grant agreements, and other documents for the award of Empowerment Zone funds as approved by the Board of County Commissioners.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2030. Sunset provision</catch_line>
<text>
This article shall sunset three (3) years after its creation.
</text>
</law>
