<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXIB._HOUSING_FINANCE_AUTHORITY</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-191.1. Legislative authority</catch_line>
<text>
This article is enacted pursuant to the Florida Housing Finance Authority Law, Chapter 78-89, Laws of Florida, a copy of which is attached hereto and incorporated herein by reference.
</text>
<EditorsNote>
The "Florida Housing Finance Authority Law," Chapter 78-89, Laws of Florida, is included in the Florida Statutes at § 159.601 et seq.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-191.2. Legislative findings</catch_line>
<text>
It is hereby ascertained and found that there are shortages of housing and of capital for investment in housing in Miami-Dade County, Florida (the "County"), and declared that there is a need for a Housing Finance Authority in the County to alleviate and remedy the aforementioned housing and investment capital shortages.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-191.3. Creation; powers generally</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created a separate public body corporate and politic to be known as the "Housing Finance Authority of Miami-Dade County, Florida," referred to as the "Authority", which is directed to carry out and exercise, without limitation except as is herein expressly stated, all powers and public and governmental functions set forth in and contemplated by the act [Chapter 78-89, Laws of Florida]. The Authority shall have the power to make and issue such regulations, bylaws and rules as it deems necessary to implement its powers and functions.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-191.4. Countywide authority; authority outside County</catch_line>
<text>
The Authority shall have the power and is hereby directed to operate within the territorial boundaries of the County, and within any area outside the territorial boundaries of the County if the Governing Body of the County within which such outside area is located so approves, either generally or only for specified qualifying housing developments or only for a specified number of qualifying housing developments.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-191.5. Composition; terms of members; vacancies; evidence of appointment, compensation of members</catch_line>
<text>
The Authority shall be composed of five (5) members, one (1) of whom shall be designated Chairperson. Not less than three (3) of the members shall be knowledgeable in one (1) of the following fields: labor, finance or commerce. The terms of the members shall be four (4) years each, except that the terms of the initial members shall be as follows: two (2) members shall serve a term of one (1) year; one (1) member shall serve a term of two (2) years; one (1) member shall serve a term of three (3) years, and one (1) member shall serve a term of four (4) years. A member shall hold office until his successor has been appointed and has qualified. Each vacancy shall be filled for the remainder of the unexpired term. A certificate of the appointment or reappointment of any member shall be filed with the Clerk of the Circuit Court, and the certificate shall be conclusive evidence of the due and proper appointment of the member. A member shall receive no compensation for his services, but shall be entitled to necessary expenses, including traveling expenses, incurred in the discharge of his duties.
</text>
The Authority shall be composed of five (5) members, one (1) of whom shall be designated Chairperson. Not less than three (3) of the members shall be knowledgeable in one (1) of the following fields: labor, finance or commerce. The terms of the members shall be four (4) years each, except that the terms of the initial members shall be as follows: two (2) members shall serve a term of one (1) year; one (1) member shall serve a term of two (2) years; one (1) member shall serve a term of three (3) years, and one (1) member shall serve a term of four (4) years. A member shall hold office until his successor has been appointed and has qualified. Each vacancy shall be filled for the remainder of the unexpired term. A certificate of the appointment or reappointment of any member shall be filed with the Clerk of the Circuit Court, and the certificate shall be conclusive evidence of the due and proper appointment of the member. A member shall receive no compensation for his services, but shall be entitled to necessary expenses, including traveling expenses, incurred in the discharge of his duties.
Annotations—CAO's 79-12, 80-31, 82-10.
<catch_line>Sec. 2-191.6. Authority to act; employees</catch_line>
<text>
The powers of the Authority granted by the act [Chapter 78-89, Laws of Florida], subject to the limitations contained herein, shall be vested in the members of the Authority in office from time to time. Three (3) members shall constitute a quorum, and action may be taken by the Authority upon a vote of a majority of the members present. The Authority may employ such agents and employees. The Authority may delegate to an agent or employee such powers or duties as it may deem proper and may employ its own legal counsel.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-191.7. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Section 1 of Ord. No. 11-99, adopted Dec. 6, 2011, deleted § 2-191.7, which pertained to approval of certain actions by the Board of County Commissioners, and derived from Ord. No. 78-89, adopted Dec. 12, 1978.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-191.8. Amendments to structure, programs, etc.; termination</catch_line>
<text>
The County may, at its sole discretion, and at any time, alter or change the structure, organization, programs or activities of the Authority, [such power] including the power to terminate the Authority, subject to any limitation on the impairment of contracts entered into by the Authority and subject to the limitations or requirements of the act [Chapter 78-89, Laws of Florida].
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-191.9. Miami-Dade County Housing Finance Authority Savings Bank</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
The preamble clauses of this Ordinance No. 90-125 containing the findings of the Board (including the exhibit thereto) are incorporated herein by reference.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Housing Finance Authority of Miami-Dade County, Florida, is hereby expressly empowered to purchase and own the stock of and vote to capitalize the association in accordance with this ordinance. The policy of the association shall be to originate and make low-cost loans and provide related services to eligible persons to allow them to obtain affordable housing in accordance with the purposes of the Florida Housing Finance Authority Law. Such association may accept deposits which must be federally insured and may sell mortgages originated by it in the secondary market and issue mortgage-backed securities. The policy of the association shall be to reinvest the proceeds of the loans and sale of mortgage-backed securities in mortgage loans as provided in the Florida Housing Finance Authority Law or as reserves for the association. The association shall comply with all State and federal banking and regulatory requirements.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 90-125, § 1, 11-27-90)</history>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (38) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 78-89, §§ 1—10, adopted Dec. 12, 1978, did not specifically amend the Code; hence, inclusion herein as Art. XXIB of Ch. 2, §§ 2-191.1—2-191.8, is at the discretion of the editor. (Back)
Annotation—AO 9-1 (Back)
Cross reference— County employees transacting business with housing finance authority, § 2-11.1(c)(5); housing Ch. 17. (Back)
State Law reference— Housing finance authorities, F.S. § 159.601 et seq. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
