<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_II._MINORS</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-6. Purchase or sale of certain articles by</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
When unlawful. It shall be unlawful for any person to buy any used or secondhand article from a person under seventeen (17) years of age unless accompanied by a parent or legal guardian, and it shall likewise be unlawful for any person under seventeen (17) years of age to offer for sale any such articles.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Exception. Persons under seventeen (17) years of age lawfully employed as a sales person in any established place of business shall be exempt herefrom.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 58-5, § 23, 2-18-58)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-7. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
At the direction of the County Attorney as authorized by Ord. No. 11-80, § 21-7, sale of firearms to minors, has been preempted and declared null and void by F.S. § 790.33, which is titled "Field of Regulation of Firearms and Ammunition Preempted." Former § 21-7 derived from Ord. No. 58-5, adopted Feb. 18, 1958.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-7.1. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
At the direction of the County Attorney as authorized by Ord. No. 11-80, § 21-7.1, use of B-B guns and rifles by child under 16, limitation; trial in court of appropriate jurisdiction; penalty for violation, has been preempted and declared null and void by F.S. § 790.33, which is titled "Field of Regulation of Firearms and Ammunition Preempted." Former § 21-7.1 derived from Ord. No. 66-32, adopted July 26, 1966.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-8. Lodginghouse to report presence of</catch_line>
<text>
Each owner, agent, manager or keeper of a hotel, boardinghouse, tenement house or apartment house shall immediately report to the Miami-Dade Police Department the presence there (except for purely temporary purposes in the daytime) of all minors under the age of eighteen (18) years, unless such minors are accompanied by the parent, guardian or other person having the care and custody of such minors. The report shall include the name, age, last-known place of abode of the minors and the names and residences of the parents, guardian or other custodian of such minors, so far as such information can be ascertained from the minors or otherwise.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-9. Tattooing</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful for any person to tattoo any minor in the County unless the parent, guardian, or other person having charge and custody of the minor shall first have given his or her written consent to the tattooing.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-10. False statement or credentials for gaining admission to prohibited places</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful for any minor to make statements, or to furnish, present, or exhibit any fictitious or false registration card, identification card, or note or other document, or to furnish, present or exhibit such document or documents issued to a person other than the one (1) presenting the same, for the purpose of gaining admission to prohibited places or for the purpose of procuring the sale, gift or delivery of prohibited articles, including, but not limited to, beer, liquor, wine, cigarettes, and tobacco.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-11. Minors engaging others for unlawful purpose</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful for any minor to engage or utilize the services of any other person, and it shall be unlawful for any person, whether for remuneration or not, to procure for such minor any article which the minor himself is forbidden by law to purchase.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-12. Trial in Juvenile and Domestic Relations Court</catch_line>
<text>
Where offenses set forth involve violation by minors, the same shall be tried in the Miami-Dade County Juvenile and Domestic Relations Court when so required by the laws of the State of Florida.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-13. Construction of provisions</catch_line>
<text>
The grouping in this chapter of certain sections specifically relating to minors shall in no wise, or under any circumstances, be construed as excluding minors from the penal provisions of other sections of this Code where the plain language of any such section embraces and includes minors.
</text>
</law>
