<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 18 IMPROVEMENT AND SPECIAL-PURPOSE DISTRICTS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_II._MIAMI-DADE_FIRE_AND_RESCUE_S</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 18-24. Creation and Continuance of District</catch_line>
<text>
The special district known and designated as the Metro Dade Fire and Rescue Service District (hereinafter referred to as "the District") created and established in Dade County, Florida by Ordinance No. 80-86 shall continue in existence, as modified by the remainder of this article. The District shall be known henceforth as the Miami-Dade Fire and Rescue Service District.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 18-25. Boundaries</catch_line>
<text>
The initial boundaries of the District shall be the geographic boundaries of Miami-Dade County, excluding any municipality which opted out of the Metro-Dade Fire and Rescue Service District created by Ordinance No. 80-86 prior to the date this article was adopted.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 18-26. Service Provided</catch_line>
<text>
The service provided by the District shall include a uniform level of fire and rescue service throughout the District and to those governmental entities which may from time to time contract with the District. The District shall begin the provision of such service within its boundaries on the date this article becomes effective, and shall from that date forth be ready, willing and able to provide a uniform level of fire and rescue service on a countywide basis to all properties and residents within the County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 18-27. Revocation of Transfer of Property in Trust</catch_line>
<text>
The trust created by Ordinance No. 96-28 is dissolved. The County, as the successor in interest, shall have sole possession of all real property, equipment, facilities and resources previously transferred to the District in trust.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 18-28. Governing Body</catch_line>
<text>
The Board of County Commissioners shall be the governing body of the District.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 18-29. District Budget and Ad Valorem Tax</catch_line>
<text>
The annual budget for the District shall be adopted by the Board of County Commissioners in such manner as may be provided by law. The County shall levy an annual ad valorem tax not to exceed three (3) mills upon all taxable property within the District. The tax shall be assessed, levied and collected, in the manner provided by law.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 18-29.1. Municipal Option to Join District</catch_line>
<text>
Any municipality may join the District through the enactment of an ordinance passed by a majority of its governing body and a resolution passed by a majority of the Board of County Commissioners. If any municipality chooses to join the District, the boundaries of the District shall be automatically adjusted accordingly; provided, however, that property within any municipality exercising such option shall continue to be subject to any outstanding indebtedness or obligations of the municipality until such indebtedness or obligations are no longer outstanding with respect to such property.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 18-30. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Section 2 of Ord. No. 07-107, adopted July 24, 2007, deleted § 18-30, which pertained to municipal option to provide alternative service, and derived from Ord. No. 03-69, adopted April 8, 2003; and Ord. No. 06-82, adopted June 6, 2006.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 18-31. Municipalities Contracting with District for Additional Services</catch_line>
<text>
Any municipality may contract with the District for the delivery of additional fire and rescue services. Any services provided by the District in accordance with any such contract shall be in addition to the fire and rescue services provided under Section 18-26.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 18-32. Existing Indebtedness</catch_line>
<text>
Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, any indebtedness incurred by the District or by the County on the District's behalf prior to the enactment of this article shall continue to be an obligation of the property within the District at the time the indebtedness was incurred; provided, however, that such obligation shall cease when the indebtedness is no longer outstanding or adequate provisions are made for its repayment.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 18-33. Other Chapter Provisions not Applicable</catch_line>
<text>
Notwithstanding any other provision of Chapter 18, the District shall be governed solely by this Article II and Chapter 2, Article XXI of the Code.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 18-34. General Provisions of the District</catch_line>
<text>
It is the intent of the Board of County Commissioners to set forth in this chapter the functions and responsibilities of the Miami-Dade Fire and Rescue Service District created by Ordinance No. 80-86. The District described herein shall continue to be subject to modification or abolishment in whole or in part by duly enacted ordinance of the Commission.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 18-35—18-40. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (2) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 03-69, § 2, adopted April 8, 2003, repealed article II, sections 18-24—18-39, in its entirety and replaced it with a new article II, sections 18-24—18-34. Former article II pertained to similar material and derived from Ord. No. 96-28, § 2, adopted Feb. 6, 1996; Ord. No. 98-115, § 2, adopted July 21, 1998; Ord. No. 02-45, § 1, April 9, 2002; Ord. No. 02-54, § 1, adopted April 23, 2002; Ord. No. 02-125, § 1, adopted July 9, 2002. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
