<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_IIIA._CONSUMER_ADVOCATE</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-25.1. Miami-Dade County Consumer Advocate—Position established; appointment; term; exempt from classified service</catch_line>
<text>
The position of Miami-Dade County Consumer Advocate is hereby created and established. The Con
sumer Advocate shall be appointed by and serve at the will of the County Manager. The Consumer Advocate shall be a duly licensed practicing attorney of the State of Florida. The Consumer Advocate shall serve under the supervision of the County Manager and shall be exempt from the classified service.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-25.2. Same—Duties and powers</catch_line>
<text>
The duties and powers of the Consumer Advocate shall include, but not be restricted to, the following:
<section prefix = "a">
To represent and protect the public interest in proceedings or hearings of any nature, by appearance, intervention or institution of proceedings, before the legislature, courts, commissions, agencies, boards, authorities, or any other such bodies charged with the regulation or control of any business, industry or utility affecting the citizens of this County.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
To represent the public interest in proceedings of any nature, by appearance, intervention, or institution of proceedings in court or any other manner in matters other than those set forth hereinbefore as the Consumer Advocate deems shall best serve the public interest.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
In providing such legal representation for the people of Miami-Dade County before rate making bodies of this County or of the State of Florida, the Consumer Advocate shall have such powers as set forth in subsection (a) as are necessary to carry out the duties of his office, including but not limited to the following specific powers:
<section prefix = "1">
To recommend by petition the commencement of any proceeding or action, or appear in any proceeding or action before any such body in the name of the County or its citizens and to urge therein any position which he deems to be in the public interest, whether consistent or inconsistent with positions previously adopted by such body, and to utilize therein all forms of discovery available to attorneys in civil actions generally.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To have access to and use of all files, records, and data of any such body.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Consumer Advocate may in any such proceeding in which he has participated seek review of any determination, finding or order, in the name of the County or its citizens.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
To prepare and issue reports, recommendations and proposed orders to any such body, or to the County Commission on any matter or subject within the jurisdiction of such body, and to make such recommendations as he deems appropriate for legislation relative to procedures, rules, jurisdiction, personnel and functions.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
To conduct public hearings in areas of widespread consumer interest at such time and places and upon such notice that he may deem necessary and adequate to fulfill his duties.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-25.3. "Public interest" defined</catch_line>
<text>
Defined as used in this article, "public interest" shall mean an interest or right arising from the Constitution, decisions of courts, common law or other laws, rules and regulations of the United States, or of this State or County, inhering in the citizens of this County or in a broad class of such citizens.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-25.4. Decision to represent particular public interest</catch_line>
<text>
The Consumer Advocate shall have sole discretion to represent or refrain from representing the public interest in any proceeding. He shall consider in exercising his discretion the importance and the extent of the public interest involved, whether that interest would be adequately represented without his presence, and the recommendations of the County Manager, the Board of County Commissioners, and the Director of the Consumer Protection Division of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (8) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 75-23, enacted April 2, 1975, provided that said ordinance be included in this Code, but did not specify the manner of inclusion. Codification of §§ 1—4 of said Ord. No. 75-23 as Art. IIIA, §§ 2-25.1—2-25.4, was at the discretion of the editors. (Back)
Annotation—AO 9-1 (Back)
Cross reference— Business regulations generally, Ch. 8A. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
