<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_III._CITY_OF_MIAMI_MINIMUM_HOUSI</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-41. Short title</catch_line>
<text>
This article, enacted under and pursuant to the provisions of the Home Rule Charter of Government for Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall be known and may be cited as the "Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Minimum Housing Standards Ordinance for the City of Miami."
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-42. Legislative findings</catch_line>
<text>
The County Commission hereby finds and declares that there presently exist in the City of Miami, Florida, structures used for human habitation which are, or may become in the future, substandard with respect to structure, equipment or maintenance. Further, that such conditions, together with inadequate provisions for light and air, insufficient protection against fire hazards, lack of proper ventilation for heating and cooling, unsanitary conditions, and overcrowding, constitute a menace to the health, safety, morals, welfare, and reasonable comfort of the citizens and visitors of this municipality. It is further found and declared that the existence of such conditions, factors, or characteristics, if not remedied, will create slum areas requiring large scale clearance, and further that, in the absence of corrective measures, such areas will experience a deterioration of social values, a curtailment of investment and tax revenues, and impairment of economic values. It is further found and declared that the establishment and maintenance of minimum housing standards are essential to the prevention of blight and decay, and the safeguarding of public health, safety, morals and welfare.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-43. Legislative intent</catch_line>
<text>
The intent and purpose of this article is to protect the public health, safety, morals and welfare of all the people of the City of Miami, Florida, by establishing minimum standards governing the condition, occupancy, and maintenance of dwellings, dwelling units, rooming houses, rooming units and premises; establishing minimum standards governing utilities, facilities, and other physical components and conditions essential to make dwellings, dwelling units, rooming houses, rooming units, and premises safe, sanitary, and fit for human habitation; fixing certain responsibilities and duties of owners, operators, agents, and occupants of dwellings, and dwelling units, rooming houses, and rooming units; authorizing and establishing procedures for the inspection of dwellings, dwelling units, rooming houses, and rooming units, and the condemnation and vacation of those dwellings, dwelling units, rooming houses, and rooming units unfit for human habitation; and fixing penalties for the violations of the provisions of this article, and to set forth a procedure for the granting of variances to the enforcement of the provisions of this chapter in cases of extreme hardship, where the health, safety, welfare and morals of the occupants of a given unit, or the public at large, will not be detrimentally affected, and where literal enforcement of the code would offer no meaningful advantage to the occupants of a unit or to the public at large. The article is hereby declared to be remedial and essential to the public interest, and it is intended that this article be liberally construed to effectuate the purposes as stated above.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-44. Construction and applicability</catch_line>
<text>
The provisions of this article shall be applicable solely within the territorial limits of the City of Miami, Florida. Every portion of a building or premises used or intended to be used for any dwelling purpose, except temporary housing in times of local emergency, disaster or necessity, shall comply with the provisions of this article, irrespective of when such building shall have been constructed, altered or repaired; and irrespective of any permits or licenses which shall have been issued for the use or occupancy of the building or premises, for the construction or repair of the building, or for the installation or repair of equipment or facilities, prior to the effective date of this article. This article is intended and shall be construed as establishing minimum standards for the initial and continued occupancy of all buildings. It is not intended to replace, modify, supersede or diminish the standards established for the construction, repair, alteration or use of buildings, equipment or facilities by the South Florida Building Code (Ordinance No. 57-22, as amended). In any case where any provision of this article is found to be in conflict with a material and controlling provision of zoning regulations, the South Florida Building Code, or any other County or municipal ordinance, code or regulation, or any rules or regulations of the Florida State Board of Health, the provision which establishes the highest standard shall prevail. All County and municipal departments, officials and employees who have the duty, responsibility or authority to issue permits or licenses in regard to the use and occupancy of dwellings, dwelling units, rooming houses, or rooming units, or similar facilities, shall conform to the provisions of this article, as a minimum standard.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-45. Existing remedies preserved</catch_line>
<text>
Nothing in this article shall be deemed to abolish or impair any existing remedies relating to the removal or demolition of any buildings which are deemed to be dangerous, unsafe or unsanitary. This article shall not affect violations of any other County or municipal ordinance, code or regulation existing prior to the effective date of this article, and such violations shall be governed and shall continue to be punished to the full extent of the law under the provisions of those ordinances, codes or regulations in effect at the time the violation was committed.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-46. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
In construing the provisions of this article, where the context will permit and no definition is provided herein, the definitions provided in Chapter 4 of the South Florida Building Code shall apply. The following words and phrases when used in this article shall have the meanings ascribed to them in this section:
<section prefix = "1">
Approval shall mean approved by the head of the enforcement agency or his authorized representatives.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Basement shall mean that portion of a building having less than one-half its clear floor-to-ceiling height below the average finished grade of the ground adjoining the building and its ceiling not more than six (6) feet above said grade.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Cellar shall mean that portion of a building having one-half or more than one-half of its clear floor-to-ceiling height below the average finished grade of the ground adjoining the building.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Dwelling shall mean any building which is wholly or partly used or intended to be used for living, sleeping, cooking and eating, provided that temporary housing as hereinafter defined shall not be regarded as a dwelling.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Dwelling unit shall mean any room or group of rooms located within a dwelling and forming a single habitable unit with facilities used or intended to be used for living, sleeping, cooking and eating.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Enforcing agency shall mean the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Enforcing officer shall mean any employee of the enforcing agency charged with the responsibility of making inspections of buildings and premises and issuing violation notices when necessary. The term shall be synonymous with inspecting officer.
(7.1)
Extreme hardship shall describe a condition existing in a case before the Hearing Officer when a dwelling or dwelling unit does not fully comply with the provisions of the minimum housing code but is structurally sound and does not have safety deficiencies, and when the repair of such structure, in order to assure compliance with the code, would result in great economic hardship to the owner or the occupant of said unit, with commensurately little benefit to the owner or occupant and to the public at large.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Garbage shall mean the animal and vegetable waste resulting from the handling, preparation, cooking and consumption of food.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Habitable area shall mean two (2) or more habitable rooms.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Habitable room shall mean a room or enclosed floor space used or intended to be used for living, sleeping, cooking, or eating purposes, excluding bathrooms, shower rooms, water closet compartments, laundries, pantries, foyers, connecting corridors, closets and storage spaces.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Head of enforcement agency shall mean the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Hotel shall mean any dwelling or commercial building, or any part of any dwelling or commercial building, containing one (1) or more hotel units in which space is let by the owner or operator on a predominantly temporary basis to three (3) or more persons who are not husband or wife, son or daughter, mother or father, sister or brother of the owner or operator. Motels and buildings offering dormitory-type sleeping accommodations shall be included in this category.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Hotel unit shall mean any room or group of hotel rooms forming a single habitable unit used or intended to be used for living and sleeping, but not for cooking and eating purposes. Motel units and dormitory-type sleeping accommodations shall be included in this category.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
Infestation shall mean the presence of any insects, rodents, vermin, or other pests.
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
Inspecting officer shall be synonymous with the term enforcing officer as previously defined.
(15.1)
Means of egress shall mean a continuous path of travel from any point in a building or structure to the open air outside at ground level and consists of three (3) separate and distinct parts:
<section prefix = "a">
The way of exit access,
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The exit, and
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The means of discharge from the exit.
A means of egress comprises the vertical and horizontal means of travel and may include the room, space, doorway, corridor, hallway, passageway, stairs, ramps, lobby, escalator, and other paths of travel.
<section prefix = "a">
Exit access shall mean that portion of a means of egress which leads to an entrance to an exit.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Exit shall mean that portion of a means of egress which is separated from the area of the building from which escape is to be made by walls, floors, doors or other means which provide the protected path necessary for the occupants to proceed with reasonable safety to the exterior of the building. Note: An interior aisle, corridor, hallway or other means of travel used to reach an exit or doorway is not an exit, except where the maximum allowable distance of travel to an exit is exceeded, at which point the aisle or corridor shall be treated as part of an exit or [it] is so located, arranged, and enclosed as to constitute an integral part of an exit facility.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Exit discharge shall mean that portion of a means of egress between the termination of the exit at the exterior of the building and ground level.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
Occupant shall mean any person over one (1) year of age living, sleeping, cooking, eating in, or having actual possession of a dwelling, dwelling unit, hotel unit, or rooming unit.
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
Operator shall mean any person who has charge, care, or control of a building, or part thereof, in which dwelling units, hotel units, rooming units, or dormitory-type sleeping accommodations are let.
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
Owner or record owner shall mean any person, firm, corporation or other legal entity, who individually or jointly or severally with others, holds the legal or beneficial title to any dwelling, dwelling unit, rooming house, rooming unit, facilities, equipment or premises subject to the provisions of this chapter. The term shall include the owner's duly authorized agent, a purchaser, devisee, fiduciary, property holder or any other person, firm, corporation, or legal entity having a vested or contingent interest, the holder of record of each mortgage or other lien, except judgment liens, or a taxpayer as defined in Florida Statutes, Section 192.001(13), as may be amended from time to time. It is intended that this term shall be construed as applicable to the person, firm, corporation or legal entity responsible for the construction, maintenance and operation of the building, facilities or premises involved.
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
Premises shall mean any occupied or unoccupied building, accessory structure, lot, parcel of land, or any part thereof, used or intended to be used for residential purposes.
</section>
<section prefix = "20">
Rooming house shall mean any dwelling, or part of any dwelling, containing one (1) or more rooming units in which space is let by the owner or operator on a predominantly permanent basis to three (3) or more persons who are not husband or wife, son or daughter, mother or father, sister or brother of the owner or operator. For the purpose of this article, Boarding houses are included in this category.
</section>
<section prefix = "21">
Rooming unit shall mean any room or group of rooms, forming a single habitable unit, used or intended to be used for living and sleeping but not for cooking or eating purposes.
</section>
<section prefix = "22">
Rubbish shall mean all combustible and noncombustible waste materials except garbage. The term shall include residue from the burning of wood, coal, coke, and other combustible materials, paper, rags, cartons, boxes, wood, excelsior, rubber, leather, tree branches, yard trimmings, tin cans, metal, mineral matter, glass and crockery.
</section>
<section prefix = "23">
Supplied shall mean paid for, furnished, or provided by or under control of the owner or operator.
</section>
<section prefix = "24">
Temporary housing shall mean any tent, trailer, or other structure used for human shelter which is designed to be transportable and which is not attached to the ground, to another structure, or in a permanent manner to any utilities system. For the purpose of this article, living quarters for migratory agricultural workers shall be defined as temporary housing.
</section>
<section prefix = "25">
Meaning of certain words. Whenever the words "dwelling," "dwelling unit," "hotel," "hotel unit," "rooming house," "rooming unit" and "premises" are used in this article they shall be construed as though they were followed by the words "or any part thereof."
</section>
<section prefix = "26">
Any reference in this article to the words "approved," "adequate," "adequately," "properly installed," "properly connected" or "properly constructed," shall have reference to those standards set out in the South Florida Building Code, the Rules of the State Board of Health, Chapters 5, 15 and 26A of the Metropolitan Code, and any other enactment of law applicable to the structure or particular portion or system of the structure under inspection by the enforcing agency.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-47. Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer—Appointment; term; exempt from classified service; salary</catch_line>
<text>
The Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer shall be appointed by and serve at the will of the County Manager. Such officer shall be chosen by the County Manager on the basis of his qualifications and experience in the field of building and housing. The office shall constitute a position exempt from the classified service of the County. The salary for such position shall be fixed by the County Manager and shall be included in the County budget. The Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer shall serve under the administrative supervision of the Director of Team Metro. The County Manager may appoint such assistants to the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer as may be necessary in order that his duties may be properly performed, subject to budget limitations.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-48. Same—Duties and powers</catch_line>
<text>
The powers of the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer shall include the following:
<section prefix = "1">
The enforcement of the provisions of this article and rules and regulations promulgated hereunder, and all County ordinances, codes, rules and regulations pertaining to housing and the use and occupancy of dwellings, and all rules and regulations of the Florida State Board of Health and the Florida Hotel and Restaurant Commission, in cooperation with such state agencies, in the City of Miami.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Investigate complaints and institute enforcement actions necessary to abate all violations of County regulations governing the use and occupancy of housing facilities. In addition to inspections resulting from complaints, inspections may be made at the request of the owner of the subject property provided such requested inspections are for the purpose of qualifying for participation in a governmental program. The Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer shall have the power and authority to charge and collect fees for making inspections. The fees charged shall be as set forth in the Team Metro fee schedule, as established by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida, as amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Make appropriate surveys and inspections to determine whether the provisions of this article are being complied with, and whether minimum housing standards are being maintained within the City of Miami.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Make inspections of housing premises, facilities and equipment in accordance with procedures prescribed by this article to determine whether the provisions of this article are being complied with, and make recommendations for methods by which minimum housing standards may be more effectively maintained.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Render all possible assistance and technical advice to persons operating and maintaining housing facilities, premises and equipment.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Establish, operate and maintain a continuous program for monitoring and inspection of housing facilities in the City of Miami designed to provide accurate data and information as to whether the minimum standards established by this article are being complied with and whether the level of adequate housing facilities is increasing or decreasing in the City of Miami.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Publish and disseminate information to the public concerning all matters relating to minimum housing standards and the advantages of adequate housing facilities.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Render all possible assistance and cooperation to federal, State and local agencies and officials in the accomplishment of effective minimum housing standards and controls.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
The Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer shall have the power and authority to charge and collect fees as described in Section 17-48(2) herein for rendering inspection assistance in accordance with the Team Metro fee schedule, as established by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida, as amended from time to time and to recover the costs of enforcement as provided for in this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Make periodic reports concerning the status of minimum housing standards and the enforcement of the provisions of this article, and recommendations concerning the improvement of minimum housing standards and controls.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Perform such other administrative duties as may be assigned by the County Manager.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-49. Same—Identification of Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer; conflict of interest</catch_line>
<text>
The Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer and all assistants shall be furnished with official identification cards signed by the County Manager, which identification cards shall contain the name of the officer, his photograph, and pertinent descriptive identifying information, and such other matters designed to facilitate recognition by the public of the status of such official. Upon request, the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer and assistants shall exhibit such identification when entering any dwelling, dwelling unit, rooming house, rooming unit, hotel, hotel unit, or premises. The requirements of this section shall not in any wise be construed as relieving the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or assistants from compliance with the procedures prescribed in this article for making inspections.
No official, Hearing Officer or employee charged with the enforcement of this law shall have any financial interest, directly or indirectly, in any repairs, corrections, construction or demolition which may be required.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-50. Authorized inspections</catch_line>
<text>
The Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer and enforcing officers shall be authorized to make inspections to determine the condition of dwellings, dwelling units, rooming houses, rooming units, hotels, hotel units, and premises in order to safeguard the health, safety, morals and welfare of the public. The Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer and enforcing officers shall be authorized to enter any dwelling, dwelling unit, rooming house, rooming unit, hotel, hotel unit, or premises at any reasonable time, or at such other time as may be necessary in an emergency, for the purpose of performing the duties of such office under this article, in accordance with the procedures herein prescribed. Except in emergencies endangering the public health, safety and welfare, the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer and enforcing officers shall enter a dwelling, dwelling unit, rooming house, rooming unit, hotel, hotel unit, or premises only upon the prior consent of the person lawfully in occupancy thereof or the person having legal right of possession thereof, or in accordance with the provisions of this section. When the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or any enforcing officer has reason to believe that any dwelling, dwelling unit, rooming house, rooming unit, hotel, hotel unit, or premises is in violation of the provisions of this article, or when such officer deems it necessary to make an inspection to determine whether a facility is in violation of the minimum housing standards established by this article, such officer shall request permission to make an inspection from the person lawfully in occupancy thereof or from the person having the legal right of possession thereof. In the event that such person refuses to consent to the inspection, the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or enforcing officer may apply to the County Court or Circuit Court for the issuance of an inspection warrant to be served by an officer duly authorized by law to serve inspection warrants and make arrests for violations of this article. The inspection warrant shall issue in accordance with the requirements of the United States Supreme Court case of Camara v. Municipal Court of the City and County of San Francisco, 18 L. Ed. 2d 930, 87 S. Ct. 1727 (1967) and Florida Statutes, Sections 933.20—933.30 and shall authorize entry into and inspection of the premises described therein. Refusal to permit an inspection pursuant to an inspection warrant authorized by this section shall constitute a violation of this article and shall subject the violator to the penalties prescribed herein.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-51. Notice of violations</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Whenever the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or his assistant finds and determines that there has been a violation of the minimum housing standards established by this article he shall give notice of such violation to the owner. Such notice shall be in writing, shall specify the violations, and shall specify the time for compliance.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Such notice shall specify that permits, if necessary, for the work required to correct the violations must be obtained from the Building Official of the City of Miami within the time specified in the notice and that the violation must be corrected within the time specified in the notice, and that final compliance must conform with the requirements of the South Florida Building Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Such notice shall contain an outline of the remedial action which, if taken, will constitute compliance with the requirements of this article. Such notice shall inform the owner of the right to apply to the Hearing Officer for a hearing and review of matters within this notice as provided in Sections 17-57 and 17-58. Such notice may also inform the person or persons to whom it is directed that failure to comply may result in enforcement action as provided for in Section 17-55 or Chapter 8CC of this Code. Such notice shall be served upon the owner. Such notice shall be deemed to be properly served and binding upon the property involved if a copy is served by certified mail return receipt requested, addressed to the owner's last known address, or if the owner cannot be served by certified mail, a copy of the notice shall be posted in a conspicuous place on the facilities or premises involved. Such notice shall state the date of posting.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 68-14, § 12, 3-5-68; Ord. No. 69-87, § 1, 12-3-69; Ord. No. 88-15, § 1, 3-15-88; Ord. No. 07-148, § 12, 10-2-07)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-52. Notice as final order</catch_line>
<text>
Any notice of violation provided for in Section 17-51 hereof shall automatically become a final order in the event that no written appeal from the notice of violation is filed with the Hearing Officer within twenty (20) days after the date of service of the notice of violation.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-53. Recording of final order</catch_line>
<text>
Whenever a notice of violation becomes a final order, or whenever the violations specified in the notice have not been corrected within the time specified in the notice, the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer shall file a copy of such final order or other appropriate instrument indicating that violations of the minimum housing standards established by this article exist upon the property involved, in the office of the Clerk of the Circuit Court of Miami-Dade County, Florida, who shall cause the same to be recorded among the public records of Miami-Dade County, in an appropriate book provided for such purpose. The recordation of such final order or other appropriate instrument as herein provided shall constitute constructive notice to any subsequent purchasers, transferees, grantees, mortgagors, mortgagees, lessees, lienors, and all persons having, claiming or acquiring any interest in the property described therein, or affected thereby. When the violations specified in the said final order shall have been corrected, and all costs of enforcement as provided hereinafter are paid, the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer shall have recorded a certificate certifying that the violations have been corrected and cancelling the final order. All such final orders shall contain the proper legal description of the property involved. The cost of recording the original final order and the certificate of cancellation shall also be recoverable as costs from the owner of record of the property prior to recording the certificate of cancellation. Any person acquiring any interest in or to property described in a final order after recordation thereof shall be bound by the provisions thereof, and shall take the property subject to the requirements set forth in the final order. All such persons acquiring an interest in or to property for which a final order has been recorded under this section shall comply with the requirements thereof, and shall be subject to all of the other provisions of this chapter. Provided, however, that if the time for appeal from the final order as provided in Sections 17-52 and 17-57 has not run as of the time of conveyance, the new owner or transferee of an interest in or to property shall have ten (10) days from the date upon which the transfer of property interest is effective as to him within which to appeal the final order to the Hearing Officer. If an appeal of the final order has been perfected but a final decision of the Hearing Officer has not been rendered, the new owner or transferee may exercise all of the rights of appeal which would have been accorded to the prior owner or transferor.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-54. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 88-15, § 1, adopted March 15, 1988, repealed § 17-54, which pertained to records and searches, as derived from Ord. No. 68-14, § 15, adopted March 15, 1968.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-55. Remedies for enforcement consent agreements; hindering or obstructing Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It shall be unlawful for any person to fail to comply with the minimum housing standards established by this article, or to fail or refuse to comply with the requirements of any final order issued in accordance with the provisions of this article. Each day of continued violation shall be considered as a separate offense.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
If any person shall knowingly fail or refuse to obey or comply with, or wilfully violates, any of the provisions of this article, or any lawful final order issued hereunder, such person, upon conviction of such offense, shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment not to exceed sixty (60) days in the County Jail, or both, in the discretion of the court.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The provisions of this article and final orders issued in accordance with the provisions of this article may be enforced by mandatory injunction, or other appropriate civil action. The Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to impose and recover a civil penalty for each violation in an amount of not more than five thousand dollars ($5,000.00) per offense. Each day during any portion of which such violation occurs constitutes a separate offense.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or his assistant, may, in the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer's or his assistant's discretion, terminate an investigation or an action commenced under the provisions of this chapter upon execution of a written consent agreement between the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or his assistant and the record owner of the land which is the subject of the investigation or action. The consent agreement shall provide written assurance of voluntary compliance with all the applicable provisions of this chapter by the record owner. The consent agreement shall provide the following: Repayment of costs of the County for investigation, enforcement, and litigation including attorneys' fees; and remedial or corrective action. The consent agreement may, in the discretion of the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer upon agreement of the owner, provide for compensatory damages, punitive damages and civil penalties. An executed written consent agreement shall neither be evidence of a violation of this chapter nor shall such agreement be deemed to impose any limitations upon any investigation or action by the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or his assistant, in the enforcement of this chapter. The consent agreement shall not constitute a waiver of or limitation upon the enforcement of any federal, State or local laws and ordinances. Executed written consent agreements are hereby deemed to be lawful orders of the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or his assistant. Each violation of any of the terms and conditions of an executed written consent agreement shall constitute a separate offense under this chapter by the owner who executed the consent agreement, his respective officers, directors, agents, servants, employees and attorneys; and by those persons in active concert or participation with any of the foregoing persons and who receive actual notice of the consent agreement punishable in accordance with the provisions of Section 17-55 of this chapter and Chapter 8CC of this Code. Each day during any portion of which each such violation occurs constitutes a separate offense under this chapter. Decisions and action of the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or his assistant, pursuant to Section 17-55(c) of this Code and written consent agreements executed thereunder, shall not be subject to appeal to or review by the Hearing Officer pursuant to Section 17-57 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Any person who hinders, obstructs or resists the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or his assistant in the discharge of his duty as provided in this chapter, upon conviction thereof in the County Court, shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for not more than sixty (60) days, or by both such fine and imprisonment.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 68-14, § 16, 3-5-68; Ord. No. 88-15, § 1, 3-15-88; Ord. No. 07-148, § 15, 10-2-07)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-56. Power to act in emergencies</catch_line>
<text>
Whenever the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer finds that a violation of the provisions of this article exists which requires immediate action to abate a direct and continuing hazard, or immediate danger to the health, safety or welfare of the occupants or the public, such officer may, without prior notice, issue an order or civil violation notice pursuant to Chapter 8CC of this Code citing the violation and directing that such action be taken as may be necessary to remove or abate the hazard or danger. Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, such emergency order shall be effective immediately upon service and shall be complied with immediately, or as otherwise provided.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-57. Appeals from actions or decisions of Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Any person aggrieved by any action or decision of the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer may appeal to the Clerk of the Courts by filing with the Clerk of the Courts within twenty (20) days after the date of the action or decision complained of, a written notice of appeals which shall set forth concisely the action or decision appealed from and the reasons or grounds for the appeal. This appeal provision shall not apply to any citation issued in accordance with Chapter 8CC. The Clerk shall set such appeal for hearing at the earliest possible date, and cause notice thereof to be given to the appellant and the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The administrative hearing shall be open to the public. The proceedings at the hearing shall be recorded and may be transcribed at the expense of the person requesting the transcript.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Any person who has been served with notice of violation shall elect either to pay the enforcement costs in the manner indicated on the notice, and correct the violation within the time specified on the notice (if applicable); or
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Request an administrative hearing before a Hearing Officer to appeal the decision of the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer which resulted in the issuance of the notice of violation.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Appeal by administrative hearing of the notice of violation shall be accomplished by filing a request in writing to the address indicated on the notice, no later than twenty (20) calendar days after the service of the notice, whichever is earlier.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Upon receipt of a named property owner's timely request for an administrative hearing, the Clerk of the Court shall set the matter down for hearing on the next regularly scheduled hearing date or as soon thereafter as possible or as mandated in the specified Code Section which is enforced pursuant to this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
The Clerk of the Court shall send a notice of hearing by first class mail to the property owner at his last known address. The notice of hearing shall include but not be limited to the following:
<section prefix = "1">
Name of the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer who issued the notice.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Factual description of alleged violation.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Date of alleged violation.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Section of the Code allegedly violated.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Place, date and time of the hearing.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Right of the property owner to be represented by a lawyer.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Right of property owner to present witnesses and evidence.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Notice that failure of property owner to attend hearing shall result in enforcement costs and administrative costs being assessed against him.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Notice that requests for continuances will not be considered if not received by the Hearing Officer at least fifteen (15) calendar days prior to the date set for hearing.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
The Clerk of the Court shall schedule hearings upon the request of the appellant. No hearing shall be set sooner than twenty (20) calendar days from the date of service of the notice of violation.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
All testimony shall be under oath. Assuming proper notice, a hearing may proceed in the absence of the property owner.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
The Clerk of the Court shall provide clerical and administrative personnel as may be reasonably required by each Hearing Officer for the proper performance of his duties.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Each case before a Hearing Officer shall be presented by the head of the enforcing agency or his designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
The hearing need not be conducted in accordance with the formal rules relating to evidence and witnesses. Any relevant evidence shall be admitted if the Hearing Officer finds it competent and reliable, regardless of the existence of any common law or statutory rule to the contrary.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
Each party shall have the right to call and examine witnesses; to introduce exhibits; to cross-examine opposing witnesses on any matter relevant to the issues even though that matter was not covered in the direct examination; to impeach any witness regardless of which party first called him to testify; and to rebut the evidence against him.
</section>
<section prefix = "n">
The Hearing Officer shall make findings of fact based on evidence of record. The Hearing Officer shall make findings of fact immediately upon conclusion of the hearing. Once commenced, no hearing shall be deferred, however, the property owner shall have the option to request a reschedule of the hearing. A request to reschedule the hearing shall only be considered prior to the commencement of the testimony and presentation of evidence. In order to make a finding upholding the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer's decision, the Hearing Officer must find that a preponderance of the evidence indicates that the property owner was responsible for the violation of the relevant Section of the Code as charged.
</section>
<section prefix = "o">
If the property owner is found guilty of the violation, he shall pay the reasonable costs of the administrative hearing and the costs and expenses of the enforcing agency for investigation, enforcement, testing, or monitoring. The costs and expenses of the enforcing agency for investigation, enforcement, testing, or monitoring shall be calculated and submitted to the Hearing Officer, to be attached to the final order for amount owed, in standard format as prescribed by departmental administrative orders approved and amended from time to time by the Board of County Commissioners or the local municipal governing board. All costs of enforcement shall be paid within thirty (30) days of the date of the administrative hearing unless an alternate timeframe is established by the enforcing agency.
</section>
<section prefix = "p">
The fact-finding determination of the Hearing Officer shall be limited to whether the violation alleged did occur and, if so, whether the person named in the civil violation notice can be held responsible for that violation. Based upon this fact-finding determination, the Hearing Officer shall either affirm or reverse the decision of the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer as to the responsibility of the named property owner for the Code violation. If the Hearing Officer affirms the decision of the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer, the Hearing Officer shall determine a reasonable time period within which correction of the violation must be made, provided however, that such time period shall be no more than thirty (30) days. If the Hearing Officer reverses the decision of the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer and finds the named property owner not responsible for the Code violation alleged in the civil violation notice, the named property owner shall not be liable for the payment of any administrative costs, absent reversal of the Hearing Officer's findings. If the decision of the Hearing Officer is to affirm, then the following elements shall be included:
<section prefix = "1">
Amount of enforcement costs of the enforcing agency.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Administrative costs of hearing.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Date by which the violation must be corrected to prevent imposition of continuing violation penalties (if applicable).
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "q">
The Hearing Officer shall have the power to:
<section prefix = "1">
Adopt procedures for the conduct of hearings.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Subpoena property owners and witnesses for hearings; subpoenas may be served by the Miami-Dade County Police Department or by the staff of the Hearing Officer.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Subpoena evidence.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Take testimony under oath.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "r">
<section prefix = "1">
A Hearing Officer shall postpone and shall not conduct a hearing if the named property owner, prior to the scheduled hearing date, files with a duly authorized County board of appropriate jurisdiction, an administrative appeal concerning the interpretation or application of any technical provisions of the Code Section allegedly violated. However, once an issue has been determined by a Hearing Officer in a specific case, that issue may not be further reviewed by a County board in that specific case. A named property owner waives his right to administrative appeal to other County boards if the property owner does not apply for such appeal prior to the property owner's administrative appeal hearing before the Hearing Officer.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Upon exhaustion of a timely filed administrative appeal and finalization of the administrative order by such board, the Hearing Officer may exercise all powers given to him by this chapter. The Hearing Officer shall not, however, exercise any jurisdiction over such alleged Code violations until the time allowed for court appeal of the ruling of such board has lapsed or until such further appeal has been exhausted.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Hearing Officer shall be bound by the interpretations and decisions of duly authorized County boards concerning the provisions of the codes within their respective jurisdictions. In the event such a board decides that an alleged violation of the Code is not in accordance with such board's interpretation of the Code provision on which the violation is based, the Hearing Officer shall not be empowered to proceed with the enforcement of the violation.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "s">
Any person aggrieved by any decision of the Hearing Officer on appeal taken to it, including, but not limited to, the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer, may apply to the Circuit Court of Miami-Dade County for review by writ of certiorari in accordance with the applicable Florida Appellate Rules. For such purposes, the Clerk of the Court shall make available for public inspection and copying the record of each such decision to be reviewed; provided, such Clerk may make a reasonable charge commensurate with the costs, in the event he/she is able to and does furnish copies of all or portions of such records. Prior to certifying a copy of any record or any portion thereof, the clerk, or designee, shall make all necessary corrections in order that the copy is a true and correct copy of the record, or those portions thereof requested, and shall make a charge of not more than actual copying costs per page, instrument, or exhibit; provided the charges here authorized are not intended to repeal or amend any fee or scheduled fees otherwise established.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 68-14, § 18, 3-5-68; Ord. No. 73-48, § 3, 5-1-73; Ord. No. 07-148, § 16, 10-2-07)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-58. Hearing Officer's additional duties in City of Miami</catch_line>
<text>
The Hearing Officer established by Section 17-17 of the Code of Miami-Dade County shall have the following additional duties in the City of Miami:
<section prefix = "1">
Hear and determine appeals from actions and decisions of the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer in accordance with the provisions of Sections 17-57 and 17A-15
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Hearing Officer shall have the power and authority to hear and pass upon all appeals from the enforcement officer's refusal to grant extension of time for compliance with the provisions of this article and Chapter 17A and notices issued by the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer. Applications for extensions of time for compliance shall be considered and determined on the basis of the public interest and welfare and not merely on economic benefit to the applicant. Applications shall be granted only when it is established that the requested extension of time for compliance will not be detrimental to the occupants or to the public health, safety and welfare of the public at large.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
<section prefix = "a">
The Hearing Officer shall not have the power or authority to grant applications for variances to this code, except under the following circumstances:
<section prefix = "1">
When the Hearing Officer specifically finds, upon a showing by the applicant, that an extreme hardship as defined in Section 17-46 or 17A-5 exists; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
When the Hearing Officer finds that such hardship circumstance is one in which the granting of a variance will not detrimentally affect the health, safety, morals or welfare of the occupants or the public.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
When the Hearing Officer finds that the application for variance meets the requirements of subsection (a) above, the Hearing Officer may determine that such variance is necessary for a period of one (1) year or less and in that event the Hearing Officer shall recite the exact date on which the variance shall terminate and by which compliance shall be effected.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
When the Hearing Officer finds that the application for variance meets the requirements of subsection (a) above, and further finds that such hardship variance should be granted for a period of greater than one (1) year, the Hearing Officer shall grant a "continuing variance." Such variance shall apply only to the code violations specifically considered and approved by the Hearing Officer. Such continuing variance shall remain in effect for only so long as those conditions which the Hearing Officer shall attach to each such variance are complied with. The conditions which shall attach to such continuing variance shall include, but not be limited to:
<section prefix = "1">
That ownership of the particular unit involved shall remain unchanged; or, in the alternative, the Hearing Officer may grant a continuing variance which shall run with and attach to the property so long as the usage thereof remains unchanged;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
That the occupancy and usage of said unit shall remain unchanged;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
That no structural modification or alteration affecting that portion or portions of the unit which is the subject of this variance shall be made except such modification or alteration which is necessary to accomplish compliance with this chapter or Chapter 17A
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
That failure to comply with the conditions upon which said variance has been granted shall require the enforcement officer to file a notice of violation in accordance with the provisions of subsection (d) hereof, which shall cause the existence of any such continuing variance to be reviewed for a determination of whether such variance should be revoked by the Hearing Officer;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Other such conditions deemed necessary by the Hearing Officer based upon its consideration of the facts and circumstances of each case; and
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
That said unit shall be annually inspected by the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer to determine the compliance with the conditions of the variance and to determine that changes have not taken place which shall cause a dangerous threat to the health, safety, morals, or welfare of the occupant of said unit or to the public at large.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
If the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer shall, after the annual or periodic inspection provided for in subsection (c)6 above, determine that the conditions attached to any continuing variance have not been complied with, the officer shall file a notice of violation of the terms of said variance in accordance with the notice provisions of Section 17-51 of this chapter or Section 17A-9 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and the officer shall schedule the matter for hearing before the Hearing Officer. The person served with the notice of violation shall have the burden of showing the Hearing Officer why such variance should not be terminated.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Notwithstanding the provisions of Section 17-53 or Section 17A-11, any variance granted by the Hearing Officer for extreme hardship shall be recorded as a final order. The recording of any such variance shall include a list of all conditions which the Hearing Officer shall have attached and a list of the specific violations for which the Hearing Officer has granted the variance. Any other variance granted by the Hearing Officer shall continue to be recorded as provided by Section 17-53 or Section 17A-11

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-58.1. Recovery of enforcement costs</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The entire costs incurred by the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer in enforcing the provisions of this chapter shall be paid by the owner, including but not limited to, the cost of enforcement inspections, preparation of enforcement, reports, photographs, title searches, postage and other administrative costs for enforcement and collection. The owner of any multi-unit dwelling containing four (4) or more dwelling units, rooming units, or hotel/motel units or combination thereof which is subject to the registration certificate requirements of Section 17-20 of the Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County shall only be liable for enforcement costs levied and imposed pursuant to this section, if such enforcement costs collectible hereunder exceed the annual registration certificate fee special assessments collected for the building in which such dwelling is contained. The costs of enforcement shall be paid within thirty (30) days of the owner's receipt of the Team Metro's bill itemizing the enforcement costs incurred in enforcing this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer shall file among his records a fair and accurate statement of each item of expense with the date of execution of any action authorized by this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Team Metro may institute a civil suit to recover such expenses against the property or may cause such expenses to be charged against the real property as a lien, upon recordation of an enforcement lien in the public records of Miami-Dade County, Florida. A lien will remain on the real property after recordation as provided herein until such costs are fully paid and discharged, or barred by law.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Liens created pursuant to Section 17-58.1(c) may be discharged and satisfied by payment to Team Metro of the amount specified in the notice of lien, together with interest thereon from the date of the filing of the lien computed at the rate of eighteen (18) percent per annum, together with the administrative costs, filing and recording fees and fees paid to file a satisfaction of the lien in the public records. When any such lien has been discharged, the Department of Team Metro shall promptly cause evidence of the satisfaction and discharge of such lien to be recorded in the public records. Any person, firm, corporation or legal entity, other than the present owner of the property involved, who pays any such unsatisfied lien shall be entitled to receive an assignment of the lien held by the County and shall be subrogated to the rights of the County in respect to the enforcement of such lien, as permitted by law.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 88-15, § 1, 3-15-88; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 10, 9-3-98)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-59. Minimum standards for basic equipment and facilities</catch_line>
<text>
No person shall occupy, or let to another for occupancy, any dwelling or dwelling unit, for the purpose of living, sleeping, cooking, or eating therein, which does not comply with the following requirements:
<section prefix = "1">
Every dwelling unit shall contain not less than a kitchen sink, lavatory, tub or shower and water closet, all in good working condition and installed in accordance with the South Florida Building Code. Sink, lavatory, tub or shower shall be supplied with adequate hot and cold water.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Every dwelling unit shall contain a room which affords privacy to a person within said room and which is equipped with a flush water closet and a lavatory basin in good working condition and properly connected to an approved water system and sewer system or an approved septic tank installation including an approved absorption bed. No privy shall be constructed or continued in operation after the effective date of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Every dwelling unit shall contain a room which affords privacy to a person within said room and which is equipped with a bathtub or shower in good working condition and properly connected to an approved water system and sewer system or an approved septic tank installation including an approved absorption bed.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Every kitchen sink, lavatory basin, and bathtub or shower required under the provisions of this section shall be properly connected with both hot and cold water lines.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Every dwelling shall have water heating facilities which are properly installed, maintained in safe and good working condition, and properly connected with the hot water lines required under the provisions of the preceding paragraphs. Such water heating facilities shall be capable of supplying on demand to all the required fixtures a continuous supply of hot water, as spelled out below. The following shall be used as a minimum guide:

   WHERE CENTRAL HOT WATER IS    SUPPLIED FOR MULTI-FAMILY    HOUSING UNITS:
<section prefix="1" type="table">
<table class="table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
  <col width="25%" /> 
  <col width="25%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i> Type of</i> <br /><i>Apartments</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Minimum</i> <br />Heater<br />Input* </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Minimum<br />Storage<br /><i>Capacity</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Efficiencies and<br />1-bedroom apartments</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3,825 Btu<br />per hour<br />per apt.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">8 gal.<br />per apt.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2-bedroom apartments</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6,680 Btu<br />per hour<br />per apt.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10 gal.<br />per apt.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3-bedroom apartments</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">9,545 Btu<br />per hour<br />per apt.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">12 gal.<br />per apt.</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 
 
*Based on 70% fuel efficiency. If other than oil or gas is used an adjustment for fuel efficiency may be used.
Where dwelling units have individual water heaters, there shall be provided a system capable of supplying one hundred forty (140) degree water in an amount of sixteen (16) gallons per bedroom per three (3) hours.
An adequately designed solar system is acceptable if there is incorporated in the design a thermostatically controlled booster with Btu input equivalent to that specified above.
Instantaneous or tankless systems are acceptable if they are designed to raise the required volume of water seventy (70) degrees Fahrenheit. The required volume of water shall be determined by the fixture unit method as set forth in the National Bureau of Standards BMS 66.
All such facilities shall be of an approved type, connected and maintained all as provided in the South Florida Building Code and any fire regulations or ordinances now in existence or adopted subsequent hereto.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Every occupied dwelling unit shall be provided with an installed nonportable cooking facility which shall not be capable of being carried easily by one (1) person, and shall have at least two (2) top burners. Vacant dwelling units shall be provided with utility connections for such facility.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Every dwelling unit shall have adequate garbage disposal facilities or garbage storage containers.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Every dwelling structure and dwelling unit of types of construction I, II, III, IV and V as defined by Chapters 17, 18, 19, 20, 21 and 22 respectively of the South Florida Building Code shall have means of egress which conform to the standards of Chapter 31 of the South Florida Building Code and any applicable fire codes, fire regulations or ordinances now in existence or adopted subsequent hereto. Every dwelling structure of type of construction V, built before December 31, 1957, where the structural and other elements of the building consist primarily of wood, having one (1) or two (2) dwelling units above the ground floor, shall have a minimum of two (2) separate means of egress which are remote from each other or at least one (1) means of egress with stairs that are constructed of either noncombustible materials or made safe by approved fire resistive modifications as may be required. Each such means of egress shall be easily accessible for every dwelling unit on the specified floor without passing through any other dwelling unit. Every dwelling structure of type of construction V, where the structural and other elements consist primarily of wood having three (3) or more dwelling units, shall have means of egress which conform with the provisions of the South Florida Building Code and any applicable fire codes, fire regulations or ordinances now in existence or adopted subsequent hereto.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
In every owner-occupied dwelling unit not intended to be let for occupancy containing space heating facilities, such facilities shall be properly installed and maintained in safe and good working conditions as provided in the South Florida Building Code and any applicable fire regulations or ordinances now in existence or adopted subsequent hereto.
Every dwelling and dwelling unit which is let or intended to be let for occupancy shall have adequate space heating facilities which are properly installed and maintained in safe and good working condition as provided in the South Florida Building Code and any applicable fire regulations or ordinances now in existence or adopted subsequent hereto. Adequate heating facilities are hereby defined as follows:
<section prefix = "a">
Permanent space heating equipment capable of heating two-thirds of the habitable rooms to a minimum air temperature of seventy (70) degrees Fahrenheit to be measured three (3) feet above floor when outside temperature is forty-five (45) degrees Fahrenheit, or permanent space heating equipment with capacity of five (5) Btu's per hour of input per cubic foot of habitable room space within two-thirds of the habitable rooms.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The five (5) Btu's per hour input standard is based on a heating unit with seventy (70) percent rating of input-to-output efficiency; an appropriate correction factor will be applied when the proposed heating unit exceeds an input-to-output efficiency rating of seventy (70) percent. Heating units supplied on the basis of this calculation will otherwise comply with the standards described elsewhere in this subsection.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Permanent heating equipment is defined as heating equipment properly connected to a flue or vent or, if electric, properly installed and permanently connected to an adequately wired and sized branch circuit.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Habitable room shall mean a room or enclosed floor space used or intended to be used for living, sleeping, cooking or eating purposes, excluding bathrooms, shower rooms, water closet compartments, laundries, pantries, foyers, connecting corridors, closets and storage spaces.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Heating equipment shall be installed and maintained in accordance with the provisions of the South Florida Building Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Any calculations necessary for the installation of permanent heating equipment to assure adequate heating capacity as defined in this section, shall be made in accordance with the standards established in the current edition of the "Heating, Ventilating, Air-Conditioning Guide," published by the American Society of Heating and Air-Conditioning Engineers, Inc.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Oil heaters, gas heaters, and wood-stoves must be connected to a properly installed vent, said vent conforming to the provisions of the South Florida Building Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Electric heaters will be of a type readily fixed into position and must be properly installed and permanently connected to an adequately wired and sized branch circuit.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Any portable heating device approved by the Underwriters' Laboratories, Inc., or a properly installed fireplace may be used as an accessory heating unit.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Accessory heating units will be deemed to be supplementary to the permanent heating equipment and shall not be considered when calculating the adequacy of the permanently installed heating equipment except as specified in subsection (9)(m).
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Only those accessory heating units which are acceptable under the provisions of the City of Miami and Miami-Dade County Fire Code, the Florida State Hotel and Restaurant Commission regulations, and other regularly adopted regulations will be used.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
The use of unsafe heaters or cooking stoves and the use of cooking stoves, including ovens, for heating purposes is hereby prohibited.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
The requirements of subsection (9) shall not apply to dwelling units in existence on March 17, 1969, provided that either a gas pipe outlet or an electrical outlet and circuit are present for the use of gas space heaters or portable electrical space heaters.

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-60. Minimum standards for light and ventilation</catch_line>
<text>
No person shall occupy or let to another for occupancy, any dwelling or dwelling unit for the purpose of living, sleeping, cooking, or eating therein, which does not comply with the following requirements:
<section prefix = "1">
(a) Every habitable room shall have at least one (1) window or skylight facing directly to the outdoors. The minimum total window area which provides light to each habitable room shall be not less than ten (10) percent of the floor area of such room. Whenever exterior walls or other light-obstructing structures are located less than three (3) feet from the window and extend above the ceiling of the room, such a window shall not be deemed to face directly to the outdoors and shall not be included in the required minimum total window area. Whenever the only window in a room is a skylight-type window located in the top of such room, the minimum total window area of such skylight shall not be less than fifteen (15) percent of the total floor area of the room. Skylights shall not be a substitute for the window requirement in sleeping rooms.

(b) Kitchens and dining rooms will be exempt from the requirements of subsection (1)(a) of this section, providing they meet the requirements in subsections (2) and (6) of this section.
(c) If any two (2) habitable rooms, excluding sleeping rooms, are separated by a common wall and either room lacks the required window area, but meets all three (3) exceptions listed below, such rooms shall be considered in compliance with this subsection.
<section prefix = "i">
The common wall separating the two (2) rooms must provide an opening equal to twenty-five (25) percent of the total wall area.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
If the opening so provided is a doorway, it must be unobstructed and have a minimum width of thirty (30) inches.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
One (1) of the two (2) rooms must provide the required light and ventilation for the total combined floor area of the two (2) rooms.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Every habitable room shall be ventilated by openable areas equal to fifty (50) percent of the required minimum window area, as set forth in subsection (1) of this section or by equivalent mechanical ventilation as approved by the inspecting officer.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Every bathroom, shower room and water closet compartment shall comply with the light and ventilation requirements for habitable rooms contained in subsections (1) and (2) of this section, except that no window or skylight shall be required in adequately ventilated bathrooms, shower rooms and water closet compartments equipped with an approved mechanical ventilating system which automatically becomes operational when the bathroom switch is turned on.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Every door, window or other device opening to outdoor space and used or intended to be used for ventilation shall be provided with an approved type of screen for protection against mosquitoes, flies and other insects.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Every opening beneath a dwelling, including basement or cellar windows and crawl space, shall be equipped with an approved type of screening or lattice work to keep out large animals.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Every habitable room of such a dwelling shall contain at least two (2) separate floor or wall-type electrical convenience outlets, or one (1) such convenience outlet and one (1) ceiling-type electric light fixture. Every bathroom, shower room, water closet, compartment and laundry room shall contain at least one (1) properly installed ceiling or wall-type electric light fixture. The switches shall be so located and installed as to avoid the danger of electrical shock.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Every hall and stairway located in a structure used for human habitation shall be provided with not less than one (1) footcandle of natural light throughout or with properly installed electric lighting facilities which provide not less than one (1) footcandle of illumination throughout and which are controlled by the occupants of the structure and available at all times.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-61. Requirements relating to the safe and sanitary maintenance of dwellings and dwelling units</catch_line>
<text>
No person shall occupy, or let to another for occupancy, any dwelling or dwelling unit, for the purpose of living, sleeping, cooking, or eating therein, which does not comply with the following requirements:
<section prefix = "1">
All foundation walls shall be structurally sound, reasonably rodentproof, and maintained in good repair. Foundation walls shall be considered to be sound if they are capable of bearing imposed loads and are not deteriorated.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Every dwelling unit shall be reasonably weathertight, watertight and rodentproof. Floors, walls, ceilings and roofs shall be capable of affording adequate shelter and privacy and shall be kept in good repair. Windows and exterior doors shall be reasonably weathertight, watertight and rodentproof, and shall be maintained in good working condition. All parts of the structure that show evidence of rot or other deterioration shall be repaired or replaced.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Every inside and outside stairway, porch, and every appurtenance thereto, shall be maintained in a safe condition and be capable of supporting loads which normal use may impose.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Every chimney and smoke pipe, and all flue and vent attachments thereto, shall be maintained in such condition that there will be no leakage or backing up of smoke and noxious gases into the dwelling.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
All exterior surfaces subject to deterioration shall be properly maintained and protected from the elements by paint or other approved protective coating applied in a workmanlike fashion.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Every plumbing fixture, water pipe, waste pipe and drain shall be maintained in good sanitary working condition, free from defects, leaks and obstructions.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
The floor surface of every water closet compartment, bathroom and shower room shall be maintained so as to be reasonably impervious to water and so as to permit such floor to be easily kept in a clean and sanitary condition.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Every supplied facility, piece of equipment, or utility required in this article shall be maintained in a safe and satisfactory working condition. No owner or occupant shall cause any service, facility, equipment, or utility required in this article to be removed from or discontinued for any occupied dwelling or dwelling unit except for such temporary interruption as may be necessary while actual repairs, replacement, or alterations are in process.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
For these purposes, every owner of a building containing three (3) or more dwelling units shall provide the continuing service of a person or persons solely to assure that the minimum requirements of maintenance and sanitation, as provided by this article, are maintained on the premises at all times. The landlord shall provide the tenant with the name, address, and phone number of the person or persons providing the continuing service. Said notice shall be given to the tenant by either posting the notice in a conspicuous place at the building site or by supplying the tenant with the information at the inception of the lease. The landlord is further charged with informing the tenant of any change of name, address, or phone number of the person or persons providing the continuing service.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-62. Minimum space, use and location requirements</catch_line>
<text>
No person shall occupy, or let to another for occupancy, any dwelling or dwelling unit for the purpose of living therein, which does not comply with the following requirements:
<section prefix = "1">
Every dwelling unit shall contain a minimum gross floor area of at least one hundred fifty (150) square feet for the first occupant, one hundred (100) square feet for each of the next two (2) occupants, and at least seventy-five (75) square feet for each occupant thereafter. Floor space shall be calculated on the basis of total habitable room area.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
In every dwelling unit of two (2) or more habitable rooms, every room occupied for sleeping purposes by one (1) occupant shall have a minimum gross floor area of at least eighty (80) square feet. Every room occupied for sleeping purposes by more than one (1) occupant shall have a minimum gross floor area of fifty (50) square feet per occupant. Every room used for sleeping purposes shall have a minimum width of eight (8) feet. Kitchens shall not be used for sleeping purposes. Porches shall not be used as permanent sleeping quarters.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
At last one-half of the floor area of every habitable room shall have a ceiling height of at least seven (7) feet. Any portion of a room having a ceiling height of less than five (5) feet shall not be considered in computing the total floor area of such room.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
No dwelling or dwelling unit containing two (2) or more sleeping rooms shall be so arranged that access to a bathroom, shower room, or water closet compartment intended for use by occupants of more than one (1) sleeping room can be had only by going through another sleeping room or outside the structure, nor shall room arrangements be such that access to a sleeping room can be had only by going through another sleeping room, bathroom, shower room, or water closet compartment.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
No cellar or basement space shall be used as a habitable room or dwelling unit.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-63. Responsibilities of owners and occupants</catch_line>
<text>
No person shall occupy, or let to another for occupancy, any dwelling or dwelling unit for the purpose of living therein, which does not comply with the following requirements:
<section prefix = "1">
Every dwelling unit shall be clean, sanitary and fit for human habitation.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Every occupant of a dwelling or dwelling unit shall keep in a clean and sanitary condition that part of the dwelling, dwelling unit and premises thereof which he occupies and controls, including yards, lawns, courts and driveways. The provisions of this subsection shall also apply to vacant lots and to premises of business establishments located in proximity to dwellings and dwelling units.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Every owner of a building containing three (3) or more dwelling units shall be responsible for maintaining in a clean and sanitary condition the shared or public areas of the dwelling and premises thereof. For this purpose, every owner of a building containing three (3) or more dwelling units shall provide the continuing services of a person or persons solely to assure that minimum requirements of maintenance and sanitation as provided by this article are maintained on the premises at all times.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Exterior premises shall be kept free from the excessive growth of weeds, grass and other flora. The term "excessive" shall be interpreted as detrimental to the health, safety, or welfare of the occupants or the public. The provisions of this subsection shall also apply to vacant lots and to the premises of building establishments located in proximity to dwellings and dwelling units.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Every occupant of a dwelling unit shall keep all plumbing fixtures, sanitary facilities, appliances and equipment therein in a clean and sanitary condition and shall exercise reasonable care in the proper use and operation thereof.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Every occupant of a dwelling or dwelling unit shall dispose of rubbish, garbage and other waste materials in an approved sanitary manner. Garbage shall be placed in the garbage disposal facilities or storage containers required by this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Every occupant of a dwelling containing a single dwelling unit shall be responsible for the extermination of any insects, rodents, vermin, or other pests therein or on the premises. Every occupant of a dwelling unit in a building containing more than one (1) dwelling unit shall be responsible for such extermination whenever his dwelling unit is the only one infested, except that whenever such infestation is caused by the failure of the owner to carry out the provisions of this article, extermination shall be the responsibility of the owner. In every dwelling containing one (1) or more units, the owner shall exterminate all infestations of any insects, rodents, vermin or other pests therein or on the premises except where such pests are the responsibility of the occupant as provided in the preceding sentence.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Every owner of a dwelling or dwelling unit shall, before renting or subletting to another occupant, provide approved door and window screens whenever such screens are required under the provisions of this article and shall repair or replace them when necessary.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Upon commencement of each occupancy, the owner of every dwelling unit which is let for occupancy, furnished, shall initially deliver to the occupant personal property constituting housekeeping equipment, which is operable, clean, safe and sanitary.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Every owner of a dwelling shall grade and maintain the exterior premises so as to prevent the accumulation of stagnant water thereon.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Animals and pets shall not be kept in any dwelling or dwelling unit or on any premises in such a manner as to create insanitary conditions or constitute a nuisance.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
No owner shall let for occupancy any dwelling unit that is not provided with adequate heating facilities of an approved type properly installed and maintained in safe and good working condition as provided in the South Florida Building Code and any applicable fire regulations or ordinances now in existence or adopted subsequent hereto.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-64. Maintenance of nondwelling structures and fences</catch_line>
<text>
Every accessory structure used for nondwelling purposes such as a garage, carport, cabana, storage building, etc., and every fence shall comply with the following requirements:
<section prefix = "1">
Every foundation, exterior and interior wall, roof, floor, ceiling window and exterior door shall be structurally sound and maintained in good repair.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Every accessory structure shall be kept in a reasonably clean and sanitary condition free from rodents, insects, and vermin.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The roof of every accessory structure shall be well drained of rainwater.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
All exterior surfaces subject to deterioration shall be properly maintained and protected from the elements by paint or other approved protective coating, applied in a workmanlike fashion.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Every plumbing fixture, water pipe, waste pipe and drain shall be maintained in good sanitary working condition, free from defects, leaks and obstructions.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-65. Minimum standards for hotels and rooming houses</catch_line>
<text>
No person shall operate a hotel or rooming house, or shall occupy or let to another for occupancy, any hotel unit or rooming unit which does not meet with all of the other standards of this article, except as provided by the following requirements:
<section prefix = "1">
No person shall operate a hotel or rooming house unless he has complied with all applicable licensing and permit requirements.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Every room occupied for sleeping purposes by one (1) person shall contain at least seventy (70) square feet of floor space and every room occupied for sleeping purposes by more than one (1) person shall contain at least fifty (50) square feet of floor space for each occupant thereof. Every room occupied for sleeping purposes shall have a minimum width of eight (8) feet and an average floor to ceiling height of seven (7) feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
At least one (1) flush water closet, lavatory basin and bathtub or shower, properly connected to an approved water system and sewer system or an approved septic tank installation and absorption bed, and in good working condition, shall be supplied for each six (6) persons or fraction thereof residing within a hotel or rooming house, including members of the operator's family whenever they share the use of said facilities. In a hotel or rooming house where rooms are let only to males, flush urinals may be substituted for not more than one-half the required number of water closets. All water closets, urinals, bathtubs, or showers shall be located within a room or rooms which afford privacy to the user and are not more than one (1) story removed from the hotel or rooming unit of any occupant intended to share the facilities. All such facilities shall be so located within the hotel or rooming house as to be accessible to the occupants of each hotel or rooming unit sharing such facilities without going outside of the building or without going through a dwelling, hotel, or rooming unit of another occupant. Every lavatory basin, bathtub or shower shall be supplied with hot and cold water at all times.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
No cellar or basement space shall be used as a habitable room or as a hotel or rooming unit.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The operator of every hotel or rooming house shall change supplied bed linen and towels at least once each week and prior to the letting of any room to any occupant. The operator shall be responsible for maintaining all supplied bedding in a clean and sanitary manner.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
The operator of every hotel or rooming house shall be responsible for the sanitary maintenance of all walls, floors, ceilings and other parts and further he shall be responsible for the sanitary maintenance of the entire premises where all of the building is under the control of such operator.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Every window of every hotel or rooming unit shall be supplied with shades, draw drapes, or other devices or materials which, when properly used, will afford privacy to the occupant of the hotel or rooming unit. No cooking shall be permitted in hotel and rooming units which are not equipped with approved kitchen facilities and do not meet minimum dwelling unit standards.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Every hotel or rooming structure and hotel or rooming unit of types of construction I, II, III, IV and V as defined by Chapter 17, 18, 19, 20, 21 and 22 respectively of the South Florida Building Code shall have means of egress which conform to the standards of Chapter 31 of the South Florida Building Code and any applicable fire codes, fire regulations or ordinances now in existence or adopted subsequent hereto. Every hotel or rooming structure of type of construction V, built before December 31, 1957, where the structural and other elements of the building consist primarily of wood, having one (1) or two (2) hotel or rooming units above the ground floor, shall have a minimum of two (2) separate means of egress which are remote from each other or at least one (1) means of egress with stairs that are constructed of either noncombustible materials or made safe by approved fire resistive modifications as may be required. Each such means of egress shall be easily accessible from every hotel or rooming unit on the specified floor without passing through any other hotel, rooming, or dwelling unit. Every hotel or rooming structure of type of construction V, where the structural and other elements consist primarily of wood having three (3) or more hotel, rooming or dwelling units, shall have means of egress which conform with the provisions of the South Florida Building Code and any applicable fire regulations or ordinances now in existence or adopted subsequent hereto.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
The operator of every hotel or rooming house shall be responsible for keeping the premises free from the accumulation of rubbish at all times.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
The operator of every hotel or rooming house shall be responsible for the prompt and sanitary disposal of all garbage through the use of approved mechanical equipment or by placing it in the required containers.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
The operator of every hotel or rooming house shall be responsible for providing and hanging all window and door screens.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
The operator of every hotel or rooming house shall be responsible for the extermination of any insects, rodents, vermin, or other pests therein and shall be further responsible for such extermination on the entire premises where all of the building within which the hotel or rooming house is contained is leased or rented by the operator. Whenever infestation is caused by failure of the owner to maintain the building in a reasonably insectproof or ratproof condition, extermination shall be the responsibility of the owner.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
It shall be the duty of the operator of every hotel or rooming house to report to the Miami-Dade County Health Department within twenty-four (24) hours the name of any person living in the hotel or rooming house who is believed to be afflicted with any communicable disease.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
No owner shall let for occupancy any rooming unit or hotel unit that is not provided with adequate heating facilities of an approved type properly installed and maintained in safe and good working condition as provided in the South Florida Building Code and any applicable fire regulations or ordinances now in existence or adopted subsequent hereto. Adequate heating facilities are hereby defined as follows:
<section prefix = "a">
Permanent space heating equipment capable of heating two-thirds of the habitable rooms to a minimum air temperature of seventy (70) degrees Fahrenheit to be measured three (3) feet above floor when outside temperature is forty-five (45) degrees Fahrenheit, or permanent space heating equipment with capacity of five (5) Btu's per hour of input per cubic foot of habitable room space within two-thirds of the habitable rooms.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The five (5) Btu's per hour input standard is based on a heating unit with seventy (70) percent rating of input-to-output efficiency, an appropriate correction factor will be applied when the proposed heating unit exceeds an input-to-output efficiency rating of seventy (70) percent. Heating units supplied on the basis of this calculation will otherwise comply with the standards described elsewhere in this subsection.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Permanent heating equipment is defined as heat-equipment properly connected to a flue or vent or, if electric, properly installed and permanently connected to an adequately wired and sized branch circuit.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Habitable room shall mean a room or enclosed floor space used or intended to be used for living or sleeping purposes, excluding bathrooms, shower rooms, water closet compartments, laundries, pantries, foyers, connecting corridors, closets and storage spaces.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Heating equipment shall be installed and maintained in accordance with the provisions of the South Florida Building Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Any calculations necessary for the installation of permanent heating equipment to assure adequate heating capacity as defined in this section, shall be made in accordance with the standards established in the current edition of the "Heating, Ventilating, Air-Conditioning Guide," published by the American Society of Heating and Air-Conditioning Engineers, Inc.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Oil heaters, gas heaters, and wood-stoves must be connected to a properly installed vent, said vent conforming to the provisions of the South Florida Building Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Electric heaters will be of a type readily fixed into position and must be properly installed and permanently connected to an adequately wired and sized branch circuit.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Any portable heating device approved by the Underwriters' Laboratories, Inc., or a properly installed fireplace may be used as an accessory heating unit.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Accessory heating units will be deemed to be supplementary to the permanent heating equipment and shall not be considered when calculating the adequacy of the permanently installed heating equipment except as specified in subsection (14)(m).
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Only those accessory heating units which are acceptable under the provisions of the City of Miami and Miami-Dade County Fire Code, the Florida State Hotel and Restaurant Commission regulations, and other regularly adopted regulations will be used.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
The use of unsafe heaters or cooking stoves and the use of cooking stoves, including ovens, for heating purposes is hereby prohibited.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
The requirements of subsection (14) shall not apply to units or hotel units in existence on March 17, 1969, provided that either a gas pipe outlet or an electrical outlet and circuit are present for the use of gas space heaters or portable electrical space heaters.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
The use of unsafe heaters or cooking stoves is prohibited. All such facilities shall be of an approved type properly installed and maintained in safe and good working condition as provided in the South Florida Building Code and any applicable fire regulations or ordinances now in existence or adopted subsequent hereto.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-66. Designation of dwellings, hotels and rooming houses as unfit for human habitation and procedures for placarding</catch_line>
<text>
The designation of dwellings, dwelling units, hotels and rooming houses as unfit for human habitation and the procedure for placarding as unfit for human habitation of such unfit dwellings, dwelling units, hotels and rooming houses shall be carried out in compliance with the following requirements: Any dwelling, dwelling unit, hotel, hotel unit, rooming house or rooming unit which shall be found to have any of the following defects shall be designated by the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or his assistant as unfit for human habitation and shall be so placarded.
<section prefix = "1">
One which is so damaged, decayed, dilapidated, unsanitary, unsafe, or vermin infested that it creates a serious hazard to the health or safety of the occupants or of the public.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
One which lacks illumination, ventilation or sanitation facilities adequate to protect the health or safety of the occupants or of the public.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
One which, because of its general condition or location, is unsanitary or otherwise dangerous to the health or safety of the occupants or of the public.

Any dwelling, dwelling unit, hotel, hotel unit, rooming house or rooming unit declared unfit for human habitation by the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or his assistant shall be so designated by posting a placard in a conspicuous place on the structure.
A dwelling, dwelling unit, hotel, hotel unit, rooming house or rooming unit deemed to be unfit for human habitation and placarded as such by the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or his assistant shall be vacated within thirty (30) days of placarding as ordered by Team Metro and shall not be used for human habitation again until written approval is secured from, and the placard removed by, Team Metro. Team Metro shall order the removal of the placard whenever the defect or defects upon which the placarding actions were based have been eliminated.
No person shall deface or remove the placard from any dwelling, dwelling unit, hotel, hotel unit, rooming house or rooming unit which has been deemed to be unfit for human habitation and placarded as such, by the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or his assistant except as provided in the foregoing subsection.
Any person whose property has been placarded as unfit for human habitation may request and shall be granted a hearing on the matter before the Hearing Officer.
Where the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or his assistant determines that a building is an unsafe building within the provisions of Section 202 of the South Florida Building Code, he shall immediately report the matter to the Building Official.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-67. Exceptions</catch_line>
<text>
The provisions of this article shall not be applicable to migrant labor camps, as defined by Section 381.422, Florida Statutes, nor to tourist or trailer camps, as defined by Section 513.01, Florida Statutes, which hold valid, current licenses issued by the Florida State Board of Health. The provisions of this article shall not be applicable to temporary housing as defined in Section 17-46 of this article nor to temporary housing utilized for dwelling purposes in times of local emergency, disaster, or urgent necessity, as determined by the Unsafe Structures and Hearing Officer. The provisions of this article shall be applicable to all other dwellings, housing and buildings and buildings used or intended for use for human habitation.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-68. Judicial review</catch_line>
<text>
Any person or persons, jointly or severally, aggrieved by any final action taken or final decision rendered pursuant to the provisions of this article, may seek to have such action or decisions reviewed by the Circuit Court of Miami-Dade County by petition for certiorari in the manner prescribed by the rules of court, provided such person or persons shall have first exhausted the administrative remedies provided for herein.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-69. Repeal clause</catch_line>
<text>
This article is intended and shall be construed as constituting minimum standards for the City of Miami. To the extent of the minimum housing standards herein provided, all County and municipal ordinances, County and municipal resolutions, municipal charters, special laws applying only to Miami-Dade County or any general law which the County Commission is authorized by the Constitution to supersede, nullify or amend, and any part of any such ordinance, resolution, charter, or law in conflict with or inconsistent with the minimum housing standards herein established, are hereby repealed and superseded except as authorized by Section 17-44 of this article.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 17-70. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (4) ---
Editor's note— Article III is derived from Ord. No. 68-14, §§ 2—30, adopted March 5, 1968, effective ten (10) days after enactment. This ordinance was originally codified as Article II pursuant to the authority of § 31 thereof, which authorized its inclusion as a part of this Code. Subsequently, the article was redesignated Art. III in order to facilitate inclusion of § 2 of Ord. No. 80-87 as § 17-01 of a new Art. I of this chapter. The history note following each section indicates the ordinance source and the Code Comparative Table lists all ordinance sections codified and the Code disposition thereof. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
