<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXI._EU-1_SINGLE-FAMILY_ONE_ACRE</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-226. Uses permitted</catch_line>
<text>
No land, body of water and/or structure shall be used or permitted to be used and no structure shall be hereafter erected, constructed, moved, reconstructed or structurally altered or maintained in any district of EU-1 classification, which is designed, arranged or intended to be used or occupied for any purpose, unless otherwise provided herein, excepting for one (1) or more of the following uses:
<section prefix = "1">
Every use as one (1)family residence, including every customary use not conflicting therewith.
(1.1)
Workforce housing units in compliance with the provisions of Article XIIA of this code.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Guest house and/or servants quarters (incidental to principal residence only).
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Raising of poultry and fowl provided same are not kept within one hundred (100) feet of a residential building on adjoining property nor within fifty (50) feet of a side or rear property line and provided further that in no case shall the size of a flock of poultry or fowl exceed twenty-five (25) in number (incidental to existing residential use).
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
It shall be permissible to keep and maintain any combination of the following animals, not to exceed two (2) in number; horses and cows, provided (1) such use is incidental to an existing residential use, (2) the area used to keep and maintain such animals is part of the residential site, and (3) that such animals are fenced at least fifty (50) feet from property under different ownership. One (1) additional animal may likewise be kept and maintained for each acre in excess of the first acre that is part of the residential site on those estates which are five (5) acres or less in size. On those estates which are between five (5) and nine (9) acres in size, one (1) additional animal may likewise be kept and maintained for each additional two (2) acres that forms part of the residential site larger than five (5) acres. On those estates which are larger than nine (9) acres in size, one (1) additional animal may likewise be kept and maintained for each additional five (5) acres that forms part of the residential site larger than nine (9) acres. The total of all such animals shall not exceed ten (10). In no event shall the property be used for the keeping of such animals owned by others than those residing on the property. The Director may waive the set back requirements between any portion or all of the subject property and the abutting properties, provided the abutting property owner or owners consent thereto in writing to the Director, and the Director finds the public health, safety or welfare would not be detrimentally affected; provided however that the Director may revoke the said waiver if he finds that the conditions pertinent thereto have changed. All animals so kept and maintained shall be housed in properly constructed stalls, stables, or places of shelter approved as to location and construction by the Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Boat piers or slips for the docking of privately owned watercraft, except houseboats without power, provided no remuneration is charged for the use of either such motor craft or docking space. Such use shall be limited to the owner of the premises and/or occupant of a residential building on the premises or guest of such occupant.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Limited truck gardening, incidental to an existing residential use, and fruit growing, provided no signs are displayed regarding the sale of products so raised. Such use shall be confined to an area no closer than ten (10) feet to an official highway right-of-way line. No trees shall be planted within thirty-five (35) feet of the intersection of official right-of-way lines or the official highway right-of-way lines projected to an intersection.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Beekeeping not to exceed five (5) hives, provided the same are located no closer than one hundred fifty (150) feet to a highway line nor closer than one hundred fifty (150) feet to a residential structure.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
A group home shall be permitted in a dwelling unit provided:
<section prefix = "a">
That the total number of resident clients on the premises not exceed six (6) in number.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
That the operation of the facility be licensed by the State of Florida Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services and that said Department or sponsoring agency promptly notify the Director of said licensure no later than the time of home occupancy.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
That the structure used for a group home shall be located at least one thousand (1,000) feet from another existing, unabandoned legally established group home. The 1,000-foot distance requirements shall be measured by following a straight line from the nearest portion of the structure of the proposed use to the nearest portion of the structure of the existing use.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Reserved.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-227. Lot area</catch_line>
<text>
Lots for any use in EU-1 District shall contain minimum of one (1) acre in area. Credit shall be given in area for right-of-way dedicated from site.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-228. Lot coverage; minimum lot width; minimum lot depth</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The maximum area covered by the main structure on lots in EU-1, Single-family one (1) acre Estate Districts shall be fifteen (15) percent of total lot area; provided, however, that where the main structure is no higher than one (1) story, then such maximum area covered by the main structure shall be twenty (20) percent.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The minimum lot width shall be one hundred twenty-five (125) feet. The minimum lot width requirement shall not be retroactive, i.e., lots with a smaller width can be used if before April 17, 1951 said lot:
<section prefix = "1">
Was platted or recorded in compliance with old EU-1, EU-1A or EU-1B standards, or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Was purchased under a contract for deed arrangement and meets the old EU-1, EU-1A or EU-1B standards.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The minimum lot depth measured from the center line of the abutting front right-of-way shall be two hundred (200) feet; provided that said minimum depth shall not apply to property that has been lawfully subdivided prior to the effective date of this subsection into lots with less than the said minimum depth.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 57-19, § 15(C), (D), 10-22-57; Ord. No. 71-21, § 1, 3-2-71; Ord. No. 04-123, § 1, 6-8-04)</history>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 04-123, § 1, adopted June 8, 2004, amended Section 33-328 of the Code. As Section 33-328 of the Code does not exist and hence is reserved, the provisions of said ordinance have been interpreted by the editor as amending Section 33-228
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-229. Height of buildings</catch_line>
<text>
The principal residence and/or accessory buildings in EU-1 Districts may be two (2) stories or thirty-five (35) feet in height.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (26) ---
Cross reference— Height of fences, walls and hedges in EU District, § 33-11(h). (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
