<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XVII._MIAMI-DADE_COUNTY_LOCKSMIT</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-350. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Apprentice locksmith shall mean a person who desires to learn the locksmithing trade through on-the-job training under the direct supervision of a licensed locksmith and has obtained a permit from the director pursuant to this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Article shall mean Article XVII of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and any rules, regulations and standards promulgated pursuant to this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Reserved.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Licensed locksmith shall mean an individual who has been an apprentice locksmith for a minimum of one (1) year and who has obtained a license from the Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Reserved.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Commission shall mean the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Compensation shall mean money, fee, emolument, quid pro quo, barter, remuneration, pay, reward, indemnification or satisfaction.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Customer shall mean a person who inquires about, makes a request for or purchases locksmith goods or services from a locksmith business.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Director shall mean the Director of the Consumer Services Department or the Director's designee. This definition shall apply to Section 8A-82.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, when utilizing the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Employer shall mean a person who legally employs an individual for wages or salary, lists the individual on the employer's payroll records, and withholds and transmits all legally required deductions and contributions.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Employee shall mean an individual who legally works for an employer, is listed on the employer's payroll records, and is under the employer's direction and control. An independent contractor is not an employee pursuant to this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Key shall mean a properly combinated device which is or most closely resembles the device specifically intended by a lock manufacturer to operate the corresponding lock.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
Key duplication machine shall mean any device that is capable of copying or reproducing keys.
</section>
<section prefix = "n">
License shall mean the authorization by the Director required by this article for a licensed locksmith to perform locksmith work.
</section>
<section prefix = "o">
Locksmith shall mean any individual who for compensation, wages or salary engages in locksmith work and who has received a license under this article. This definition shall not include any person whose activities are limited to making a duplicate key from an existing key.
</section>
<section prefix = "p">
Locksmith business shall mean any person advertising, offering to perform or performing locksmith work for compensation, including but not limited to locksmith contractors, mobile locksmith business operators, locksmith shops and sole proprietors.
</section>
<section prefix = "q">
Locksmith work or locksmith services shall mean the installing, repairing, rebuilding, rekeying, repinning, recoding, servicing, adjusting, opening or modifying locks, mechanical and electronic security locking devices and peripherals, safes, vaults, safe deposit boxes and closed circuit television systems. It shall also mean originating keys for locks and the operation of mechanical or electronic security locking devices and peripherals, safes, vaults or safe deposit boxes by any means other than the means which is intended by the manufacturer.
</section>
<section prefix = "r">
Locksmithing tool shall mean any tool which is designed or used to open a mechanical or electronic locking device by any means other than the means which is intended by the manufacturer.
</section>
<section prefix = "s">
Permit shall mean the authorization by the Director required by this article for a person to become an apprentice locksmith by learning through on-the-job training under the supervision of a licensed locksmith.
</section>
<section prefix = "t">
Person shall mean any natural person, individual, public, or private corporation, trust, firm, association, joint venture, partnership, municipality, governmental agency, political subdivision, public officer, or any other entity whatsoever, or any combination of the foregoing, jointly or severally.
</section>
<section prefix = "u">
Registration or registration certificate shall mean the authorization by the Director required by this article for the operation of a locksmith business in Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
Safe-opening tools shall mean any tool which is designed or used to open a safe, vault, safe deposit box, or similar object by means other than the means which is intended by the manufacturer.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 95-23, § 1, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 95-137, § 7, 7-25-95; Ord. No. 97-69, § 4, 6-3-97; Ord. No. 97-110, § 1, 7-8-97; Ord. No. 98-110, § 1, 7-21-98; Ord. No. 01-03, § 1, 1-23-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-351. Intent and application</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It is the intent of this article to seek to secure the satisfaction and confidence of customers and members of the public when utilizing a locksmith by regulating locksmiths and locksmith businesses. It is further the intent of this article to protect customers and the members of the public from unscrupulous locksmiths, persons purporting to be locksmiths, and persons who would use locksmiths to gain unauthorized access into residences, motor vehicles, and commercial establishments belonging to members of the public. In a time when home invasion and car theft are a common occurrence, it is the intent of this article to assure that persons possessing locksmithing tools have legitimate purposes for possessing such tools and that locksmiths use their knowledge and skills, whether knowingly or unknowingly, for only lawful business purposes. This article shall be effective in the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County and shall be liberally construed to effectuate the purposes set forth herein and to protect the public. This article shall be known and cited as the "Miami-Dade County Locksmith Ordinance."
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The provisions of this article shall be deemed supplemental to all county and municipal ordinances. In the event of a conflict between any of the provisions of this article and any provision of any county or municipal ordinance, the provision which establishes the most stringent standard shall prevail.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 95-23, § 1, 2-7-95)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-352. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 95-137, § 3, adopted July 25, 1995, repealed former § 8A-352, relative to the locksmith consumer services board, which derived from Ord. No. 95-23, § 1, adopted Feb. 7, 1995.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-353. Director's duties, functions and powers</catch_line>
<text>
The duties, functions, powers and responsibilities of the Director shall include the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Enforce all of the provisions of this article and any rules, regulations and standards promulgated thereunder.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Investigate, upon the Director's initiative, any locksmith or locksmith business.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Deny, revoke, and suspend business registrations, locksmith licenses and apprentice locksmith permits and impose conditions, limitations, and restrictions upon same in accordance with Sections 8A-362, 8A-366, 8A-368 and 8A-370 of this Code. Notwithstanding the foregoing, no revocation or suspension of a business registration, locksmith license or apprentice locksmith permit by the Director shall be effective until the rendition of an appeal, if any, of such revocation or suspension pursuant to Section 8A-357 of this Code, or until the time period for filing such appeal has expired, which ever is later.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Issue cease and desist orders, notices to correct violations, and any other lawful orders of the Director which shall briefly set forth the general nature of the violation of article and specify the time within which the violation shall be rectified or stopped. If an order to cease and desist or notice to correct violations or any other lawful order of the Director is not obeyed the Director shall have the power and authority to revoke or suspend the business registration, locksmith license or apprentice locksmith permit, if any has been issued, or deny the issuance of a business registration, locksmith license or apprentice locksmith permit, and take such other action authorized by this article. Notwithstanding the foregoing, no revocation or suspension of a business registration, locksmith license or apprentice locksmith permit by the Director shall be effective until the rendition of the appeal, if any, of such revocation or suspension pursuant to Section 8A-357 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, or until the time period for filing such appeal has expired, which ever is later. Orders to cease and desist, notices to correct violations, and any other lawful orders of the Director hereunder may be enforced by the Director by the institution of civil actions for mandatory and prohibitory injunctions, civil penalties, restitution and other remedies and attorney's fees as set forth in Section 8A-356 of the Code of Miami-Dade County in a court of competent jurisdiction.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Institute civil actions or proceedings to enforce all the provisions of this article and subpoenae issued by the Director, including seeking mandatory and prohibitory injunctions, the imposition and recovery of civil penalties, restitution and such other remedies and attorney's fees as set forth in Section 8A-356 of this Code. Such civil actions or proceedings may be instituted by the Director whether or not a cease and desist order or notice to correct the violation or other lawful order of the Director has been issued or other administrative proceeding is pending.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Prosecute through the State Attorney in the criminal courts for violations of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Issue subpoenae to compel the presence of any person or document or thing at any hearing, conference or proceeding authorized herein upon information or belief by the Director that a violation of any provision of this article has occurred or may occur.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Upon receipt of complaints or upon the Director's initiative, investigate, inspect, sample, and test any matters regulated hereunder.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Inquire into the practices, functions and policies of any and all locksmiths and locksmith businesses and make such recommendations to the Commission as the Director may deem necessary.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Administer oaths and certify official acts of the Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Apply to any judge of the circuit or county court, criminal or civil division, for the issuance of an administrative search warrant.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Conduct a program for monitoring consumer satisfaction levels in the field of locksmiths and make such monitoring information available to the Commission and the public.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
Publish and disseminate information to the public concerning locksmiths and locksmith businesses.
</section>
<section prefix = "n">
Provide locksmiths and locksmith businesses at least annually with information concerning the rules, regulations, and standards enacted during the immediate past year.
</section>
<section prefix = "o">
Institute informal conferences for discussing and resolving any matter covered by this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "p">
Enter into written assurances of compliance pursuant to Sections 8A-82.1 and 8A-374 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, with respect to the matters regulated under this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "q">
Submit to the Commission proposed rules, regulations and standards to effectuate the purposes of this article. No such proposed rules, regulations and standards shall become effective until approved by the Commission.
</section>
<section prefix = "r">
The powers of the Director enumerated in this article shall be in addition to and not a limitation of any other powers of the Director pursuant to any other provisions of this article or any other provisions of law or ordinance.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-354. Civil penalties</catch_line>
<text>
In addition to any other judicial or administrative remedies or penalties provided by law, rule, regulation or ordinance, any person who violates any of the provisions of this article, any cease and desist order of the Director, any notice to correct a violation or any assurance of compliance entered into pursuant to Section 8A-82.1 of the Code and this article with respect to matters regulated under this article or any other lawful order of the Director or any condition, limitation, or restriction of a registration, license or permit issued by the Director, shall be subject to the judicial imposition and recovery of a civil penalty in an amount of not more than ten thousand dollars ($10,000.00) per offense. Each day during any portion of which such violation occurs or continues to occur constitutes a separate offense. Such monies recovered by the Director shall be deposited in a separate county fund to be used exclusively for enforcement of this article.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-355. Criminal penalties</catch_line>
<text>
In addition to any other judicial or administrative remedies or penalties provided by law, rule, regulation or ordinance, if any person intentionally violates or fails or refuses to obey or comply with any of the provisions of this article or any lawful order of the Director or any cease and desist order of the Director or any notice to correct a violation of the Director or any assurance of compliance entered into pursuant to Section 8A-82.1 of the Code and this article, or any condition, limitation, or restriction of a business registration, locksmith license, or apprentice locksmith permit, issued by the Director, such person, upon conviction of any such offense, shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00), or by imprisonment not to exceed sixty (60) days in the county jail, or both, in the discretion of the court. Each day or portion thereof of continuing violation shall be deemed a separate offense.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-356. Enforcement procedure; remedies; attorney's fees; costs</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It shall be unlawful for any person to violate any of the provisions of this article. In addition to any other judicial or administrative remedies provided by law, rule, regulation, ordinance, or this article, the Director shall have the following judicial remedies available to enforce the provisions of this article:
<section prefix = "1">
The Director may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to seek temporary or permanent, prohibitory or mandatory injunctive relief to enforce compliance with or prohibit the violation of any of the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Director may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to impose and recover a civil penalty in an amount of not more than ten thousand dollars ($10,000.00) for each violation of any of the provisions of this article. Each day during any portion of which such violation occurs or continues to occur constitutes a separate violation. The right of trial by jury shall be available in any court to determine both liability for and the amount of the civil penalties to be imposed and recovered hereunder.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Director may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to seek restitution and other equitable relief:
<section prefix = "i">
To recover any sums and costs expended by the Director for tracing, investigating, preventing, controlling, abating or remedying any violation of any of the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
To provide restitution to any customers injured by any violation of any of the provisions of this article.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Upon the rendition of a judgment or decree by any of the courts of this state against any person and in favor of the Director under any of the provisions of this article, the trial court, or, in the event of an appeal in which the Director prevails, the appellate court, shall adjudge or decree against said person and in favor of the Director a reasonable sum as fees or compensation for the Director's attorney prosecuting the suit in which the recovery is had. Where so awarded, compensation or fees of the attorney shall be included in the judgment or decree rendered in the case. This provision shall apply to all civil actions, legal or equitable, filed after the effective date of this article by the Director. Cessation of any violation of any of the provisions of this article whatsoever, prior to rendition of a judgment or entry of a temporary or final decree, or prior to execution of a negotiated settlement, but after an action is filed by the Director under any of the provisions of this article, shall be deemed the functional equivalent of a confession of judgment or verdict in favor of the Director, for which attorney's fees shall be awarded by the trial court as set forth hereinabove.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All the judicial and administrative remedies in this article are independent and cumulative.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 95-23, § 1, 2-7-95)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-357. Appeals from actions, decisions or determinations of the Director; judicial review</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Any person regulated by this article who is aggrieved by any action, decision or determination of the Director pursuant to this article may request an administrative hearing before a Hearing Officer to appeal the action, decision or determination of the Director which resulted in the grievance. Appeal by administrative hearing of the action, decision or determination complained of shall be accomplished by filing a written request with the Director within fifteen (15) days after the date of the action, decision or determination complained of, a written notice of appeal which shall set forth the nature of the action, decision or determination to be reviewed and the basis for the administrative hearing. A timely request for administrative hearing shall be scheduled and heard by a Hearing Officer pursuant to Section 8CC of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. Customers shall not be deemed to be persons regulated by this article for the purposes of this section. The Hearing Officer shall set the matter for hearing on the earliest practicable regularly scheduled hearing date or as soon as possible, but no sooner than ten (10) days after the request has been filed and shall cause notice of the hearing to be served upon the aggrieved party by first class mail. The notice may include, but not be limited to, the applicable Sections of 8CC-6(b)(2) through (9) of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. The Hearing Officer shall hear and consider all relevant facts in accordance with the procedures set forth in Sections 8CC-6(e), (f), (g), (i), (j), (k), (l), (m)(2) and (n) of the Code of Miami-Dade County (any reference in these sections to Inspector shall mean "Director" and to violator shall mean "the person filing the appeal", and may affirm, modify or reverse the action, decision or determination appealed from. The decision of the Hearing Officer shall constitute final administrative review and no rehearing shall be permitted. Nothing herein shall be construed to prevent or prohibit the Director from instituting any civil or criminal action or proceeding authorized by this article at any time.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Director, the Miami-Dade County Consumer Advocate, or any person regulated by this article who is aggrieved by any decision of the Hearing Officer may appeal a final order of the Hearing Officer by filing a notice of appeal in the Circuit Court in and for Miami-Dade County, Florida, in accordance with procedures and within the time provided by the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure for review of administrative action. The words "action," "decision" and "determination" as used herein shall not include the filing or institution of any action, conference or proceeding by the Director in any court or otherwise. Customers shall not be deemed to be persons regulated by this article for the purposes of this section.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 95-23, § 1, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 97-69, § 4, 6-3-97)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-358. Private cause of action</catch_line>
<text>
Any person who suffers a loss as a result of a violation of any of the provisions of this article, any lawful order of the Director, any cease and desist order or notice to correct a violation issued by the Director or any assurance of compliance entered into pursuant to Section 8A-82.1 of the Code and this article, may recover compensatory damages, punitive damages, restitution, attorney's fees, and court costs from the person committing such violation. Nothing herein shall be construed to require the Director to bring any such action on behalf of a private person.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-359. Exemptions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
This article shall not apply to the following persons as long as these persons do not hold themselves out to the public as locksmiths:
<section prefix = "1">
Any person or his or her agent or employee who is the manufacturer of a product other than locks and keys and who installs, repairs, opens or modifies locks for that product or who makes keys for the locks of that product as a normal incident to that product's marketing.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Tow truck operators or repossessors who do not originate keys for locks and whose locksmith services are limited to gaining access to motor vehicles in the normal course of their duties, except that tow truck operators shall comply with Section 8A-369(b). Tow truck operators and repossessors may possess tools exclusively designed to open motor vehicles.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Any person or his or her agent or employee whose activities are limited to making a duplicate key from an existing key with a key duplication machine, except that such person or his or her agent or employee shall comply with the provisions in Section 8A-369(p), (q), and (r).
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Members of law enforcement, fire rescue and other emergency government service agencies who provide life threatening opening services in their official line of duty.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Sales representatives of key and lock manufacturers who make bona fide sales demonstrations to locksmiths.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Members of the building trades such as carpenters, construction workers and contractors who install or remove complete locks, locking devices or access control devices during the normal course of residential or commercial new construction.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Any person or his or her agent or employee whose activities are limited to installing, maintaining, repairing, altering, adding or changing any system electrically energized, in whole or in part, for the detection, prevention or control of burglary, fire, noxious gases, liquid or atomic radiation as set forth in Section 10-2(II)(B)(3) and (4) in the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
An individual who performs locksmith services for himself or herself or for his or her immediate family members without compensation.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Any person who performs locksmith work or services on nonresidential public facilities, equipment or vehicles arising out of his/her job duties as a public employee for a public employer.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Any retail establishment for which the only locksmith services provided are re-keying or re-combination services or both provided that:
<section prefix = "i">
The services provided by the retail establishment are limited to re-keying and re-combination of locks.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
All re-keying, re-combination, and installation of locks take place on the premises of the retail establishment.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
All re-keying, re-combination, and installation services provided by the retail establishment are limited to locks purchased on the retail establishment premises.
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
All agents and employees of the retail establishment performing these services are trained by the manufacturer of the locks to perform these services, and the manufacturer issues written evidence to the retail establishment demonstrating that said agent or employee has been adequately trained.
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
No agent or employee of the retail establishment shall advertise or represent himself or herself to be a locksmith under this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "vi">
No agent or employee of the retail establishment shall design or implement a master key system.
</section>
<section prefix = "vii">
No agent or employee of the retail establishment shall re-key, change the combination of, alter, or install any automotive locks;
</section>
<section prefix = "viii">
The retail establishment carries minimum combined liability insurance of one million dollars ($1,000,000.00).
</section>
<section prefix = "ix">
The retail establishment, in the ordinary course of business, performs criminal background investigations of all employees performing services, and does not employ any person who does not meet the requirements set forth in Sections 8A-362(a)(3) and (4) and Sections 8A-366(a)(4) and (5) of this Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "x">
The retail establishment does not have on its premises any locksmith tool as defined in Section 8A-350(q) other than key duplication machines, key blanks, and pin kits; and
</section>
<section prefix = "xi">
All documentation referenced above regarding evidence of training, and results of criminal background investigations are kept on the premises of the retail establishment and are available for inspection and copying to authorized County employees and agents as well as to all law enforcement personnel during normal business hours.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
This article shall apply to all locksmith and locksmith businesses including locksmiths and locksmith businesses that perform work on motor vehicles. However, this article shall not apply to motor vehicle repair shops, mechanics and technicians who service, install, repair, or rebuild automotive locks, provided that they do not hold themselves out to the public as locksmiths and they comply with the provisions of Article VIIA, Miami-Dade County Motor Vehicle Repair Ordinance.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code, locksmiths who are registered, licensed or authorized pursuant to this article shall be exempt from Article VIIA, Chapter 8A and Article VI, Section 10-2 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 95-23, § 1, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 97-110, § 1, 7-8-97; Ord. No. 97-159, § 1, 9-23-97; Ord. No. 98-110, § 1, 7-21-98; Ord. No. 01-03, § 1, 1-23-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-360. Registration of locksmith business</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Unless otherwise exempt pursuant to provisions of this article, no person shall operate a locksmith business in Miami-Dade County, Florida without first obtaining a registration from the Director pursuant to this article and maintaining such registration as required herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Any person who operates a locksmith business in Miami-Dade County shall obtain registration annually or biannually from the Director.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 95-23, § 1, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 01-03, § 1, 1-23-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-361. Application for registration of locksmith business; renewal registration; and replacement registration</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Each application for registration, renewal registration and duplicate registration shall be on a form prescribed by the Director and shall be accompanied by a fee in such amount as shall be established by administrative order of the county manager. Said fee shall be effective upon approval by the Commission. All fees collected shall be deposited in a separate county fund to be utilized solely for the administration and enforcement of this article. No part of said fund shall be used for purposes other than the aforesaid.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Each application for registration shall contain the following information:
<section prefix = "1">
Legal business and trade name;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Current telephone number and mailing address from which the locksmith business operates a main office and, if applicable, branch office(s);
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Proof of registration of fictitious name;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Proof of occupational license(s);
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Federal tax identification number;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
If the application for registration is by an individual, then the applicant's full name, current address, telephone number, and the full name, current address and telephone number of the individual to be actively in charge of the locksmith business for which registration is sought;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
If the application for registration is by a partnership, then the full names, current addresses, and telephone numbers of all general partners, the Florida registered agent if a limited partnership, and the full name, current address and telephone number of the individual to be actively in charge of the locksmith business for which the registration is sought;
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
If the application for registration is by a corporation, then the full names, addresses, and phone numbers of its owners or corporate officers and directors, the federal tax identification number of the corporation, the Florida registered agent of the corporation, the date and place of incorporation, a statement listing the names of any other corporations, entities or trades names through which any owner, director or officer of the registrant was known or did business as a locksmith within five (5) calendar years preceding the date upon which the corporation is submitting the application for registration, and the full name, current address and telephone number of the individual to be actively in charge of the locksmith business for which the registration is sought;
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
The full name, current address and license number of all locksmiths who are currently employed with the locksmith business for which registration is sought;
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
The full name, current address and permit number of all apprentices in the employ of the locksmith business.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Minimum of twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000.00) in combined liability insurance;
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Worker's compensation insurance as required by Chapter 440 of the Florida Statutes, a State certificate of exemption, or a letter from the registrant affirming that such coverage is not required by law;
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
One set of fingerprints and two (2) photographs taken by Miami-Dade Police Department for the individual applicant, for each general partner of a partnership, or for each owner, officer or director of a corporation;
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
List of all convictions, in any jurisdiction, whither or not adjudication has been withheld, for felonies, misdemeanors or ordinance violations (excluding traffic violations), for robbery, burglary, larceny, theft, possession of stolen goods, possession of a stolen car, breaking and entering, or any other crime related to locksmithing for the past five (5) years for the individual applicant, for each general partner of a partnership or for each owner, officer or director of a corporation;
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
List of all convictions, in any jurisdiction, whether or not adjudication has been withheld, of any felony involving moral turpitude relating to sex, the use of a deadly weapon, homicide, violence against a law enforcement officer, or as a habitual violent felony offender.
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
Such other relevant items or information as may be required by the Director which are consistent with the provisions of this article.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The application shall be subscribed, verified and signed by the individual applicant, all general partners of a partnership, or any authorized officer or director of the corporation.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
A person operating a locksmith business at more than one (1) location in Miami-Dade County, Florida shall file a single application for registration annually, which together with the other information required by this article, shall clearly indicate the location of and the individual in charge of each locksmith business location. Application fees shall be required for each locksmith business location.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Renewal of locksmith business registration.
<section prefix = "1">
Renewal of registration may be staggered by the Director to facilitate the workload.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The renewal registration application shall be accompanied by a fee as prescribed in Section 8A-361(a).
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
A locksmith business may continue to operate after the expiration date of the registration, pending approval of the renewal application by the Director, if the completed renewal application with applicable fees has been received by the Director on or before the expiration date. If a completed renewal application with applicable fees is filed after the expiration date, the locksmith business may operate from and after the date on which the completed application with applicable fees is received by the Director, pending approval of the renewal application by the Director. A late renewal fee in such amount as established by administrative order of the County Manager shall be required by the Director if the application for renewal registration is received by the Director after the expiration date of the registration.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
A locksmith's suspended registration is subject to expiration and shall be renewed as provided in this article. Application for renewal of the registration does not entitle the locksmith to engage in locksmith work and the Director shall not issue a renewal registration until the period of suspension is terminated.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Any person who operates a locksmith business who desires to change any material aspect of the locksmith business shall provide the Director with written notice and proof of the change accompanied by the required fee, if a replacement registration is required. No registration shall be valid for any locksmith business under any other name or at any place other than that designated in the registration unless the Director is notified in writing no later than thirty (30) days after occurrence of the change.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Change of ownership.
<section prefix = "1">
In the event of a change in ownership of a locksmith business, a new registration and payment of new registration fees shall be required. The locksmith business may continue to operate provided the locksmith business has filed a completed application for registration with the Director and paid all applicable fees. For purposes of this subsection "change of ownership" shall mean a change in the ownership or operators of a locksmith business which is individually owned or a partnership.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Corporations owning or operating a locksmith business which has a change of ten (10) percent or more of the ownership of the corporation shall notify the Director of the change no later than thirty (30) days after the date of the change.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 95-23, § 1, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 97-110, § 1, 7-8-97; Ord. No. 01-03, § 1, 1-23-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-362. Criteria for issuance of locksmith business registration; issuance of registration</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The criteria for issuance of registration by the Director shall be:
<section prefix = "1">
Compliance by the applicant with all the applicable provisions of this article and any rules, regulations and standards promulgated thereunder;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Timely submission to the Director of a completed application and applicable fees by the filing date as prescribed by the Director; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Absence of any plea of nolo contendere, plea of guilt, finding of guilt or conviction within the past five (5) years, in any jurisdiction, of a felony, misdemeanor, or ordinance violation for robbery, burglary, larceny, theft, possession of stolen goods, possession of stolen car, breaking and entering, or any other crime related to locksmithing, whether or not adjudication has been withheld. Effective October 1, 2000, any plea of nolo contendere, plea of guilt, finding of guilt or withhold of adjudication shall only be considered if the applicant files an application for the first time or has not filed timely and successive renewal applications.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Absence of any plea of nolo contendere, plea of guilt, finding of guilt, or conviction, in any jurisdiction, whether or not adjudication has been withheld, of any felony involving moral turpitude relating to sex, the use of a deadly weapon, homicide, violence against a law enforcement officer, or is a habitual violent felony offender.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
At least one (1) licensed locksmith in the employ of the locksmith business.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
An incomplete application shall be considered to be abandoned if an applicant fails to complete his or her application within sixty days from the date that the application was filed with the Consumer Services Department. An application submitted subsequent to the abandonment of a former application shall be treated as a new application. Registration certificates may be issued by the Director subject to such conditions, limitations, and restrictions necessary to protect customers provided said conditions, restrictions and limitations are consistent with the provisions of this article. Violation of such a condition, limitation, or restriction of a registration certificate shall be a violation of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Upon determining that the applicant has qualified for registration pursuant to this article, the Director shall issue a registration certificate in the form and size prescribed by the Director. Such registration certificate shall be prominently displayed to the public in the primary location of the locksmith's business. The registration number appearing on the registration certificate shall appear on all advertisements, forms, commercial motor vehicles and uniforms of the locksmith business.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 95-23, § 1, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 01-03, § 1, 1-23-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-363. Prohibition on publication of written advertisements without registration number</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
No person may knowingly publish an advertisement in any publication which is primarily circulated, displayed, distributed or marketed within Miami-Dade County, Florida, which advertisement identifies a business offering locksmith work regulated by this article, unless the advertisement includes the registration number issued by the Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
For the purposes of this section, any advertisement shall be defined to include any announcement, listing, display, entry or other written statement of whatever nature or kind, and specifically to include a name and address or telephone number placed under a heading, where the heading describes or encompasses any kind of work regulated under this article.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 95-23, § 1, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 97-110, § 1, 7-8-97; Ord. No. 01-03, § 1, 1-23-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-363.1. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 01-03, § 1, adopted Jan. 23, 2001, repealed section 8A-363.1 in its entirety. Former section 8A-363.1 pertained to limited authorization required, and derived from Ord. No. 97-110, § 1, adopted July 8, 1997.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-364. Locksmith license</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Unless otherwise exempt pursuant to provisions of this article, no individual shall perform work as a locksmith in Miami-Dade County, Florida, without first obtaining a locksmith license from the Director pursuant to this article and maintaining such license as required herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Any individual who performs work as a locksmith in Miami-Dade County, Florida shall obtain a license annually or biannually from the Director.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 95-23, § 1, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 01-03, § 1, 1-23-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-365. Application for locksmith license; renewal license</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Each application for a license, renewal license, and replacement license shall be on a form prescribed by the Director and shall be accompanied by a fee in such amount as shall be established by administrative order of the county manager. Said fee shall be effective upon approval by the Commission. All fees collected shall be deposited in a separate county fund to be utilized solely for the administration and enforcement of this article. No part of said fund shall be used for purposes other than the aforesaid. An owner of a locksmith business registered under Section 8A-360 and who is a locksmith may obtain a license without having to pay the individual license fee or resubmit the items in Section (b)(7) and (8) of this Section.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Each application for a license shall contain the following information:
<section prefix = "1">
Full name, current residence address, telephone number, date of birth, and social security number or federal tax identification of the individual applying for a license;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Reserved;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The number of years the individual applicant has performed locksmith work for compensation;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Reserved;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Reserved;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
The name, address, telephone number and registration number of the locksmith business that the individual operates or is employed by;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
List of applicant's convictions, in any jurisdiction, whether or not adjudication has been withheld, for felonies, misdemeanors and ordinance violations (excluding traffic violations), for robbery, burglary, larceny, theft, possession of stolen goods, possession of a stolen car, breaking and entering, or any other crime related to locksmithing for the past five (5) years;
(7.5)
List of all convictions, in any jurisdiction, whether or not adjudication has been withheld, of any felony involving moral turpitude relating to sex, the use of a deadly weapon, homicide, violence against a law enforcement officer, or as a habitual violent felony offender.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Set of fingerprints and two (2) photographs taken by the Miami-Dade Police Department for the individual applicant;
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Other such relevant items or information as may be required by the Director which are consistent with the provisions of this article.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The application shall be subscribed, verified and signed by the applicant.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Renewal of locksmith license.
<section prefix = "1">
Renewal of the license may be staggered by the Director to facilitate the workload.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The renewal license application shall be accompanied by a fee as prescribed in Section 8A-365(a).
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Reserved.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
A locksmith may continue to perform locksmithing services after the expiration date of the license, pending approval of the renewal application by the Director, if the completed renewal application with applicable fees has been received by the Director on or before the expiration date. If a completed renewal application with applicable fees is filed after the expiration date, the locksmith may operate from and after the date on which the completed application with applicable fees is received by the Director, pending approval of the renewal application by the Director. A late renewal fee in such amount as established by administrative order of the County Manager shall be required by the Director if the application for renewal license is received by the Director after the expiration date of the license.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
A locksmith's suspended license is subject to expiration and renewal shall be sought by the suspended locksmith as provided in this article. Application for renewal of the license does not entitle the locksmith to engage in locksmith work and the Director shall not issue a renewal license until the period of suspension is terminated.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Any individual who is licensed as a locksmith and who desires to change any material aspect of his or her license including but not limited to address, telephone number, shall provide the Director with written notice and proof of the change accompanied by the required fee, no later than thirty (30) days after the date of the change.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 95-23, § 1, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 97-110, § 1, 7-8-97; Ord. No. 98-110, § 1, 7-21-98; Ord. No. 01-03, § 1, 1-23-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-366. Criteria for issuance of locksmith license; issuance of locksmith license</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The criteria for issuance of a license by the Director shall be:
<section prefix = "1">
Compliance by the applicant with all the applicable provisions of this article and any rules, regulations and standards promulgated thereunder;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Timely submission to the Director of a completed application and applicable fees;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Reserved.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Absence of any plea of nolo contendere, plea of guilt, finding of guilt, conviction or withhold of adjudication within the past five (5) years, in any jurisdiction, of a felony, misdemeanor or ordinance violation for robbery, burglary, larceny, theft, possession of stolen goods, possession of stolen car, breaking and entering, or any crime relating to locksmithing. Effective with applications submitted on or after October 1, 2000, any plea of nolo contendere, plea of guilt, finding of guilt or withhold of adjudication shall only be considered if the applicant files an application for the first time or has not filed timely and successive renewal applications.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Absence of any plea of nolo contendere, plea of guilt, finding of guilt, or conviction, in any jurisdiction, whether or not adjudication has been withheld, of any felony involving moral turpitude relating to sex, the use of a deadly weapon, homicide, violence against a law enforcement officer, or as a habitual violent felony offender.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Incomplete applications shall be considered to be abandoned if an applicant fails to complete his or her application within sixty days from the date that the application was filed with the Consumer Services Department. An application submitted subsequent to the abandonment of a former application shall be treated as a new application. Licenses may be issued by the Director subject to such conditions, limitations, and restrictions necessary to protect customers, provided said conditions, restrictions and limitations are consistent with the provisions of this article. Violations of such a condition, limitation, or restriction of a license shall be a violation of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Upon determining that the applicant has qualified for a license pursuant to this article, the Director shall issue a license card in the form and size as prescribed by the Director. Such license card shall be prominently displayed on the individual at all times when performing locksmith work whether on or off the premises of the individual's primary place of work.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 95-23, § 1, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 98-110, § 1, 7-21-98; Ord. No. 01-03, § 1, 1-23-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-367. Apprenticeship required</catch_line>
<text>
An individual may apply for a locksmith license if that individual has been an apprentice locksmith for a minimum of one (1) year. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the one (1) year apprentice locksmith requirement shall be waived if the individual submits documentary proof, on a form provided by the Director, of being actively engaged as a locksmith or as a locksmith supervisor for one (1) year out of the ten (10) years preceding the application for a locksmith license.
Verification of employment or experience or both shall be completed by the individual's supervisor or submission of at least three (3) affidavits from persons affiliated with the locksmith industry attesting to at least one (1) year of locksmith experience of the individual.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-368. Apprentice locksmith permit; criteria for issuance</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Any person unable to obtain a license as a locksmith as provided in this article who desires on-the-job training to learn to become a licensed locksmith shall apply to the Director for an apprentice locksmith permit on a form prescribed by the Director. The criteria for issuance of an apprentice locksmith permit by the Director shall be compliance by the applicant with all of the applicable requirements set forth in this article and any rules, regulations and standards promulgated thereunder, submission to the Director of a completed application for a permit and applicable fees, and meeting the requirements of Sections 8A-366(a)(4) and (5). A permit may be renewed annually or biannually upon payment of the required renewal fee and submission of a completed renewal application as prescribed by the Director. Renewal of permits may be staggered by the Director to facilitate the workload. A late renewal fee in such amount as established by administrative order of the County Manager shall be required if the application is filed with the Director after the expiration of the permit. Permits may be issued by the Director subject to such conditions, limitations, and restrictions necessary to protect customers provided said conditions, limitations, and restrictions are consistent with the provisions of this article. Violation of such a condition, limitation or restriction of a permit shall be a violation of this article. An apprentice locksmith shall be employed by a locksmith business which has obtained a registration and shall be required to work under the supervision of a licensed locksmith during the entire time of the apprentice locksmith's employment as an apprentice locksmith; provided, however, the apprentice locksmith shall be under direct supervision of a licensed locksmith for the initial 120 days of employment.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Upon determining that the applicant has qualified for a permit, pursuant to this article, the Director shall issue a permit card in the form and size as prescribed by the Director. Such permit card shall be prominently displayed on the individual at all times when performing locksmith work whether on or off the premises of the individual's primary place of work.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 95-23, § 1, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 97-110, § 1, 7-8-97; Ord. No. 01-03, § 1, 1-23-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-369. Prohibited practices</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be a prohibited practice for a locksmith or locksmith business to:
<section prefix = "a">
Perform opening services for any person on a residential, commercial, industrial or agricultural structure or safe, vault, safe deposit box or other safeguarding device, without first obtaining the address of the residential, commercial, industrial or agricultural structure or the address where the safe, vault, safe deposit box or other safeguarding device is located, and the signature of the person for whom the locksmith work is performed. The following information regarding the person requesting locksmith work on the residence, commercial, industrial or agricultural structure or the safe, vault, safe deposit box or other safeguarding device shall be recorded on a work order form: name, address, telephone number, driver's license number or other identification, and date service was performed. A copy of each work order form shall be retained for two (2) years, shall include the name and license number of the locksmith performing the service, and shall be open for inspection by the Director during business hours and in no event less than between the hours of 9:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m., Monday through Friday or submitted to the Director upon request.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Perform opening services on a motor vehicle for any person, without first obtaining the name and driver's license number or other identification of the person requesting entrance, and the registration number, license plate number or identification number of the motor vehicle upon which locksmith work is to be performed. This information together with the date the service was performed and the signature of the person requesting the locksmith work shall be set forth on a work order. A copy of each work order form shall be retained for two (2) years, shall include the license number of the locksmith performing the service, and shall be open for inspection by the Director during business hours and in no event less than between the hours of 9:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m., Monday through Friday, or submitted to the Director upon request.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Fail to complete an invoice for the sale of any good or service valued at fifty dollars ($50.00) or greater. The invoice shall include: invoice number; the name, address, registration number and telephone number of the locksmith business; the name and identification number of the locksmith business employee who completed the sales transaction; the locksmith license number of the locksmith who performed the service if applicable; the name, address, telephone number, and signature of the customer; amount of good or service and amount of tax; the date of the sales transaction; brief description of the good or service; and any terms and conditions if applicable. A copy of each invoice completed shall be retained for two (2) years and shall be open to inspection by the Director during business hours and in no event less than between the hours of 9:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m., Monday through Friday or submitted to the Director upon request.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Operate a locksmith business without at least one (1) licensed locksmith in its employ.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Employ a locksmith unless the locksmith is an apprentice locksmith with a valid permit or locksmith with a valid license.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Engage in locksmith work without possessing a valid apprentice locksmith permit or valid locksmith license.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Aid or abet a person who is not registered as a locksmith business or who is not licensed as a locksmith.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Conduct a locksmith business as an individual, partnership, or corporation unless the locksmith business holds a valid registration issued to the same individual, partnership or corporation and that registration is not revoked, suspended or expired.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Fail to maintain a file or record containing the name, address, commencing date of employment, position of each employee, proof of apprentice permit or locksmith license and the date of termination of employment if an employee is terminated. The files and records, together with usual payroll records, shall be available for inspection by the Director and copies thereof and information pertaining thereto or contained therein shall be submitted to the Director upon written request.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Fail to include in all advertisements the name and registration number of the locksmith business as this information appears in the Director's records.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Make or authorize any written or oral statements which are deceptive, fraudulent, misleading or false as to quality, quantity, characteristics, workmanship, nature, origin or source of any goods or services in order to influence, persuade or induce patronage of a customer or perform any other act which constitutes fraud or misrepresentation.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Represent that services have been rendered when they have not been rendered or bill for services that have not been rendered.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
make or charge for services which have not been expressly or impliedly authorized by the customer or represent that certain parts or services are necessary when such parts or services are not necessary.
</section>
<section prefix = "n">
Obtain ownership or possession of locksmithing tools, safe-opening tools, locksmith manuals or codebooks, without obtaining a valid apprentice permit or valid locksmith license.
</section>
<section prefix = "o">
Operate a locksmith business without a minimum combined liability insurance of twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000.00).
</section>
<section prefix = "p">
Duplicate a key that is a restricted key or a key that states specifically it is not to be duplicated, unless the locksmith business obtains written authorization to duplicate said key for each transaction and maintains said authorization on file. The written authorization issued shall include the following information: Name, address, telephone number, driver's license, or other identification issued by a government, and the signature of the person authorized to request the duplication; the date of the request; description of the key; and specific quantity of keys to be duplicated.
</section>
<section prefix = "q">
Fail to provide a customer with all duplicated keys, including keys made in error and keys with duplicating errors.
</section>
<section prefix = "r">
Fail to post in a conspicuous place near the key duplication machine, a sign that is written in a legible manner, is in English, Spanish and Creole and informs the customer that under the Miami-Dade County Locksmith Ordinance that the customer is entitled to all duplicated keys including keys made in error and keys with duplicating errors.
</section>
<section prefix = "s">
Make use of the title "licensed locksmith," "certified locksmith" or "certified master locksmith" or any words, letters or abbreviations that would denote such certification or licensure when the individual has not obtained this certification or licensure.
</section>
<section prefix = "t">
Dispatch any employee who does not meet the requirements of Sections 8A-366(a)(4) and (5), including an employee that does not perform locksmith work, to a customer's residence or place of business.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-370. Denial, revocation and suspension of business registration, locksmith license or apprentice permits</catch_line>
<text>
The Director may deny, revoke, or suspend a business registration, locksmith license, or apprentice permit issued pursuant to the provisions of this article if the Director determines that the applicant has:
<section prefix = "a">
Violated any provision of this article;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Engaged in a prohibited practice as prescribed in Section 8A-369
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Aided or abetted a person who has not obtained a registration, license or permit to evade or avoid provisions of this article;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Misrepresented or concealed a fact on the application, renewal application or replacement application for registration, license or permit;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Violated any condition, limitation, or restriction of a registration, license or permit imposed by the Director;
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Was enjoined by a court of competent jurisdiction from engaging in the trade or business of locksmithing or was enjoined by a court of competent jurisdiction with respect to any of the requirements of this article;
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Failed to comply with the terms of a cease and desist order, notice to correct a violation, written assurance of compliance, or any other lawful order of the Director;
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Was convicted of a violation of this article;
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Pled nolo contendere, pled guilty, has been found guilty, has been convicted or has obtained a withhold of adjudication within the past five (5) years, in any jurisdiction, of robbery, burglary, larceny, theft, possession of stolen goods, possession of stolen car, breaking and entering or any crime related to locksmithing.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Pled nolo contendere, pled guilty, has been found guilty, or has been convicted, in any jurisdiction, whether or not adjudication has been withheld, of any felony involving moral turpitude relating to sex, the use of a deadly weapon, homicide, violence against a law enforcement officer, or as a habitual violent felony offender.

Notwithstanding the foregoing, no revocation or suspension of a license, registration or permit by the Director shall be effective until the rendition of the appeal, if any, of such revocation or suspension pursuant to Section 8A-357 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, or until the time period for filing such appeal has expired, whichever is later.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-371. Loss, destruction, or mutilation of registration, license or permit; replacement</catch_line>
<text>
In the event of loss, destruction, or mutilation of a registration, license, or permit issued pursuant to the provisions of this article, the person to whom the registration, license, or permit was issued may obtain a replacement thereof upon furnishing satisfactory proof of loss, destruction, or mutilation to the Director and payment of the applicable fee established by administrative order of the County Manager. Applications for a replacement registration, license or permit shall include the following information:
<section prefix = "a">
Name and address of the applicant.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A verified explanation of the loss, destruction, or mutilation of the registration, license or permit.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Such other items and information as may be required by the Director which are consistent with the provisions of this article.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-372. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ordinance No. 97-69, § 4, adopted June 3, 1997, deleted § 8A-372 in its entirety. Formerly, such section pertained to waivers and extension of time and derived from Ord. No. 95-23, § 1, 2-7-95.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-373. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ordinance No. 97-69, § 4, adopted June 3, 1997, deleted § 8A-373 in its entirety. Formerly, such section pertained to procedure governing waiver and extensions of time and derived from Ord. No. 95-23, § 1, 2-7-95.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-374. Assurances of compliance</catch_line>
<text>
Each violation of any of the terms and conditions of a written assurance entered into pursuant to Section 8A-82.1 of the Code with respect to the matters regulated under this article shall constitute a separate offense under this article by the persons who executed the assurance, their respective officers, directors, agents, servants, and employees; and by those persons in active concert or participation with any of the foregoing persons and who receive actual notice of the assurance of compliance. Decisions, actions, and determinations of the Director, pursuant to Sections 8A-82.1 and 8A-353(r) or assurances of compliance executed thereunder, shall not be subject to review pursuant to Section 8A-357 of this Code.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-375. Presumption of continuous operation</catch_line>
<text>
Except as expressly provided otherwise in this article: any person operating as a locksmith business without first obtaining a registration pursuant to this article shall be presumed to be operating as a locksmith business on a continuous basis without a registration certificate from the date the registration certificate was first required by this article. Such presumption may be overcome by evidence presented by the locksmith business. This section creates a rebuttable presumption of continuous operation.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 8A-376—8A-379. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (16) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 95-23, § 1, adopted Feb. 7, 1995, amended this chapter by the addition of Art. XVIII, which provisions have been redesignated as Art. XVII so as to fall as the next sequential article in the chapter. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
