<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXXIII(R)._MODEL_CITY_URBAN_CENT</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.99.40. Purpose, intent and applicability</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
The regulations contained in this chapter and Chapter 18A, Landscape Code, Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall apply to this article, except as otherwise added to or modified herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
The Illustrative Master Plan (Figure 1) illustrates the citizens' vision and may be used to interpret this article. Where the Illustrative Master Plan conflicts with the provisions of this article, the provisions of this article shall govern.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Figure 1 also shows the boundaries of the Model City Urban Center District (MCUCD), as well as the boundaries of the Designated Urban Center. The MCUCD's Designated Urban Center shall consist of the areas designated as being the Core and Center Sub-districts on the Sub-districts Plan in Section 33-284.99.43 of this code. As provided in Standard Urban Center District Regulations, the Workforce Housing requirement shall apply to the area included in the Designated Urban Center boundaries. The legal descriptions of the boundaries of the MCUCD and the Designated Urban Center are on file with the Miami-Dade Department of Planning and Zoning.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
Full scale maps of the Illustrative Master Plan presented in Figure 1, as well as all the Regulating Plans and Street Development Parameters figures in this article, are on file with the Miami-Dade Department of Planning and Zoning.
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
No provision in this article shall be applicable to any property lying outside the boundaries of the MCUCD as described herein. No property lying within the boundaries of the MCUCD shall be entitled to the uses or subject to the regulations provided in this article until an application for a district boundary change to MCUCD has been heard and approved in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.
Figure 1. Illustrative Master Plan

</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 10-13, ยง 1, 2-2-10)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.99.41. Model City Urban Center District (MCUCD) requirements</catch_line>
<text>
Except as provided herein, all developments within the MCUCD shall comply with the requirements provided in Article XXXIII(K), Standard Urban Center District Regulations, of this code.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.99.42. Uses</catch_line>
<text>
Except as provided herein, all permitted, conditionally permitted, and temporary uses within the MCUCD shall comply with Section 33-284.83 of this code.
<section prefix = "A">
Permitted uses. In addition to the uses provided in Section 33-284.83(A), the following shall be permitted:
<section prefix = "1">
In the Mixed-Use Corridor Special (MCS) area, all uses provided in Section 33-284.83(A)(3) and the following uses:
<section prefix = "a">
Automobile and truck services and facilities including:
<section prefix = "1">
Open lot car and truck sales new or used, including, as ancillary uses, automobile repairs, body and top work and painting, provided that no more than fifteen (15) percent of the gross building area is devoted to such ancillary uses, and subject to the following conditions:
<section prefix = "a">
That attention attractive devices, such as blinking or flashing lights, streamer lights, pennants, banners, streamers and all fluttering, spinning advertising devices (either mobile or stationary) are prohibited.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
That outdoor lighting shall be designed to avoid spilling beyond the site boundaries.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
That no vehicular test drives shall be conducted on residential local traffic streets (fifty-foot right-of-way or less).
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
That the applicant obtains a certificate of use, which shall be automatically renewable yearly upon compliance with all terms and conditions.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
All outdoor paging or speaker systems are expressly prohibited. This provision shall also apply to all establishments in existence as of September 10, 1996.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Open lot car rental.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Automobile parts, secondhand from store building only.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Automobile body and top work and painting.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Automobile self-service gas stations. When provided, gas stations shall be exempt from the provisions of this article and shall conform to the BU-1A development standards provided in Article XXV of this code.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Engines, steam and oil; sales and service.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Garage or mechanical service, including automobile repairs, body and top work and painting. All outdoor paging or speaker systems are expressly prohibited. This provision shall also apply to all establishments in existence as of September 10, 1996.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Glass installation.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Tire vulcanizing and retreading or sale of use tires.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Truck storage, only within an enclosed building or an area enclosed by a CBS wall.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Automobile washing.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Self-service mini-warehouse storage facility in compliance with Section 33-255(23.1) of this code.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
In the Industrial District (ID) area, the following uses:
<section prefix = "a">
MC uses at maximum residential densities shown on the Density Regulating Plan in Section 33-284.99.43 of this code.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Conditionally permitted uses. Notwithstanding the provisions of Section 33-284.83(B), only the following conditional uses shall be permitted, subject to the administrative approval of a site plan pursuant to Section 33-284.88 of this code:
<section prefix = "1">
Liquor package stores only in the Core and Center Sub-districts, and only in compliance with Article X of this code.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Workforce housing requirement alternative. Notwithstanding the provisions of Section 33-284.83(A)(1), all residential or mixed-use developments within the MCUCD that have more than four (4) residential units shall provide one of the following:
<section prefix = "1">
A minimum of 12.5 percent of their units as workforce housing units; or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
A minimum of 10 percent of their units as affordable housing units. "Affordable housing unit" means a dwelling unit, the sale, rental, or pricing of which is restricted to households whose income range is up to 80 percent of the most recent median family income for the County reported by the U.S. HUD and maintained by the Department of Planning and Zoning.

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.99.43. Regulating plans</catch_line>
<text>
The Regulating Plans shall consist of the following controlling plans as defined and graphically depicted in this section:
<section prefix = "A">
The Land Use Plan, which delineates the areas where specified land uses and development of various types and intensities is permitted.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
The Density Plan, which delineates areas where specified minimum and maximum residential densities shall be permitted.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
The Building Heights Plan, which establishes the minimum and maximum allowable number of stories.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
The Sub-districts Plan, which delineates three (3) sub-districts: the Core, Center and Edge. These sub-districts regulate the allowable intensity of development in accordance with the Comprehensive Development Master Plan and this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
The Designated Open Space Plan, which designates open spaces, which shall be shown in all development plans. The designated open spaces are controlled by anchor points.
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
The New Streets Plan, which shows the location and the number of new streets needed to create the prescribed network of streets within the MCUCD District. All new A streets shall be required in the same general location as shown on the New Streets Plan. All B streets shall be located as provided in Section 33-284.86(F) of this code.

A. Land Use Plan

B. Density Plan

C. Building Heights Plan

D. Sub-districts Plan

E. Designated Open Space Plan

F. New Streets Plan

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.99.44. Development parameters</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Except as otherwise provided in this section, all new development and redevelopment within the MCUCD shall comply with the development parameters as set forth in Article XXXIII(K) of this code.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
All new development and redevelopment in areas designated MCS shall comply with the development parameters for the MC area as set forth in Article XXXIII(K) of this code, except that self-service gas stations shall comply with the development parameters applicable to the BU-1A district.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
At a minimum, streets within the MCUCD shall comply with the Street Type Parameters for Type 5, Minor Street, as provided in Section 33-284.85 of this code.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 10-13, ยง 5, 2-2-10)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.99.45. Conflicts with other chapters and regulations</catch_line>
<text>
This article shall govern in the event of conflicts with other zoning, subdivision, or landscape regulations of this code, or with the Miami-Dade Department of Public Works Manual of Public Works.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.99.46. Nonconforming structures, uses, and occupancies</catch_line>
<text>
Nothing contained in this article shall be deemed or construed to prohibit a continuation of a legal nonconforming structure, use, or occupancy in the MCUCD that either: (1) was existing as of the date of the district boundary change on the property to MCUCD; or (2) on or before said date, had received final site plan approval through a public hearing pursuant to this chapter or through administrative site plan review or had a valid building permit. However, any structure, use, or occupancy in the MCUCD that is discontinued for a period of at least six months, or is superseded by a lawful structure, use, or occupancy permitted under this chapter, or that incurs damage to an extent of 50 percent or more of its market value, shall be subject to Section 33-35(c) of this code. However, a lawfully existing single-family home use that is discontinued for a period of at least six months or that incurs damage to the roof or structure to an extent of 50 percent or more of its market value, shall not be subject to Section 33-35(c) of this code.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.99.47. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
</law>
