<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_LXXXIX._DIAL-A-LIFE_PROGRAM</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1311. Creation; operations</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Creation of the Dial-A-Life Program. There is hereby created and established the Dial-A-Life Program for the purpose of collecting cellular and/or mobile telephones and distributing them to eligible members of the Miami-Dade County community for purpose of providing them access to emergency "911" services.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Dial-A-Life Program Operations.
<section prefix = "1">
Collection from Public. The Dial-A-Life Program is to operate through the Miami-Dade Fire Rescue Department (the "Department"). The Department shall coordinate the distribution of collection bins provided by the Miami-Dade Solid Waste Department ("Solid Waste") in at least five (5) locations throughout Miami-Dade County for the purpose of collecting discarded cellular and/or mobile telephones from members of the Miami-Dade County community ("Donors"). The Department shall also be responsible for distributing information regarding the Dial-A-Life Program, and collecting any and all information and/or forms from Donors required by the Dial-A-Life Program Board, as provided in Section 2-1312, below. The Department will also distribute, if requested by Donors, receipts reflecting the approximate value of the donated cellular and/or mobile telephones.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
County Surplus Telephones. Notwithstanding anything in Administrative Order 8-2 or Section 2-11.2.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County to the contrary, the County may assign surplus mobile and/or cellular telephones with no commercial value to the Dial-A-Life Program for donation in accordance with the terms and conditions of this article; provided, however, that the Board of County Commissioners first make a finding by resolution that any surplus cellular and/or mobile telephones slated for donation through the Dial-A-Life Program are obsolete, or their continued use is uneconomical or inefficient, or that they no longer serve a useful function, and that they are without commercial value. All donation of County surplus mobile and/or cellular telephones shall be in accordance with Section 274.05 or 274.06 of the Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Distribution to Eligible Recipients. The cellular and/or mobile telephones collected by the Department for the Dial-A-Life Program shall be distributed to persons whose household income is less than twenty thousand dollars ($20,000.00) per year and/or who are:
<section prefix = "1">
Living with a physical or mental disability;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Over the age of sixty-five (65);
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Have children in the home who are at-risk or disabled; or
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Have been victims of domestic violence (collectively "Eligible Recipients").
The Dial-A-Life Program Board, as provided in Section 2-1312 below, shall establish all guidelines for the distribution of the telephones to Eligible Recipients, including, but not limited to those for: proof of income, proof of disability, and proof of domestic violence. No more than two (2) cellular and/or mobile telephones will be distributed to a household.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Sunset. The provisions of this ordinance shall sunset on June 15, 2013, unless otherwise reenacted by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 01-115, § 1, 7-10-01; Ord. No. 02-40, § 1, 3-12-02; Ord. No. 07-180, § 1, 12-18-07; Ord. No. 13-65, § 1, 7-2-13)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1312. [Program board.</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Creation of Dial-A-Life Program Board. A Dial-A-Life Program Advisory and Oversight Board (the "Board") will be formed to oversee the collection and distribution of donated cellular and/or mobile telephones, and to report to the Board of County Commissioners the status and progress of the Dial-A-Life Program.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Purpose. The Board shall have the following rights and responsibilities:
<section prefix = "1">
To oversee the collection and disbursement of the donated mobile and/or cellular telephones;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To establish guidelines and application procedures for Eligible Recipients consistent with the requirements of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
To evaluate applications of potential Eligible Recipients;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
To solicit assistance from the telecommunications industry for the repair and refurbishing of inoperable donated telephones;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
To report to the Board of County Commissioners no less than two (2) times per year the status and progress of the Dial-A-Life Program, including the number of cellular and/or mobile telephones collected by the Program, the number of applications received by potential Eligible Recipients, the number of cellular and/or mobile telephones actually distributed to Eligible Recipients, and the cost of administering the Program.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
To promulgate rules consistent with this article for the conduct of its meetings and the discharge of its responsibilities;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
To perform other functions as are set forth for the Board in this article.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Ratification by the Board of County Commissioners. Any rules, guidelines, applications, or other material established by the Board in accordance with Section 2-1312(B) shall be submitted to the Board of County Commission for ratification.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
Board Membership.
<section prefix = "1">
Members. The Board shall be composed of the following members: a County Commissioner to be appointed by the Board of County Commissioners, or his or her appointee; one (1) member who shall be selected and appointed by the County Manager; one (1) member of the Miami-Dade County Fire Rescue Department who shall be appointed by the Director; one (1) representative of the telecommunications industry who shall be selected and appointed by the Board of County Commissioners; one (1) representative from a domestic violence awareness, services, and/or prevention organization who shall be selected and appointed by the Board of County Commissioners; one (1) representative from an elderly awareness, services and/or advocacy organization who shall be selected and appointed by the Board of County Commissioners; one member of the Miami-Dade County Domestic Violence Oversight Board who shall be selected and appointed by the Board of County Commissioners; one (1) representative from a community based organization dedicated to supporting families with at-risk or disabled children who shall be selected and appointed by the Board of County Commissioners; and one (1) representative from a disability awareness, services, and/or advocacy organization who shall be selected and appointed by the County Manager; and one (1) member of the Miami-Dade Enterprise Technology Services Department, or its successor, who shall be selected and appointed by the Director of that Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Qualification. All of the Board members shall be at least twenty-one (21) years of age and be citizens of the United States. In addition to any other qualification the Board may establish from time to time, the Board members shall be of high moral character and have demonstrated business experience and acumen.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Election and Term. Board members appointed by the Board of County Commissioners shall serve two (2) years terms and may be reappointed as approved by the Board of County Commissioners. All other Board members shall serve until the earlier of:
<section prefix = "i">
The expiration of a two-year term from their appointment;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Their removal by a majority vote of the Board; or
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Their resignation from the Board.
The foregoing shall not prohibit any Board member from serving multiple or consecutive terms, if reappointed to such position. Any Board vacancies arising due to a Board member's term expiring, removal from office, resignation, or otherwise shall be filled by the entity or person responsible for the initial appointment. By example, if a Board vacancy occurs in a position appointed by the County Manager, such vacancy shall be filled by a person selected and appointed by the County Manager of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Removal. Any Board members may be removed with or without cause at any time by the vote of seven (7) of the eight (8) Board members entitled to vote at a special meeting of the Board members called for that purpose. New Board members to fill the vacancies thus created shall be elected and designated in accordance with Section 2-1312(E)(1).
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Compensation. Members of the Board shall serve without compensation, but shall be entitled to reimbursement for necessary expenses incurred in the discharge of their duties.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
Organization of the Board.
<section prefix = "1">
Meetings. The Board shall hold regular meetings, no less than four (4) times per year for calendar year 2003, and three (3) times per year for every year thereafter, and such other meetings, as it deems necessary. Three of the duly appointed and sitting members of the Board shall constitute a quorum. Minutes shall be kept of all meetings of the Board and all meetings shall be duly noticed to the public.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Applicability of County rules and procedures. The Board shall at all times operate under the Florida Open Government laws, including the "Sunshine Law," public meeting laws and public records laws and shall be governed by all State and County conflict of interest laws, as applicable, including the Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance, Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Attendance requirement. Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code, any Board member shall be automatically removed if, in a given fiscal year:
<section prefix = "i">
He or she is absent from three consecutive meetings without an acceptable excuse;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
If he or she is absent from three (3) of the Board's meetings without an acceptable excuse; or
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Whether excused or not, he or she misses two-thirds (2/3) of the Board's meetings in a given fiscal year.
A member shall be deemed absent from a meeting when he or she is not present at the meeting at least seventy-five (75) percent of the time. An "acceptable excuse" is defined as an absence for medical reasons, business reasons, personal reasons, or any other reason which the Board, by a two-thirds (2/3) vote of the membership, deems appropriate. By a two-thirds (2/3) vote of the members of the full Board, the provisions of this section may be waived.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Staff and Facility Support. The County Manager and the County Attorney shall provide such staff support to the Board as may be necessary to accomplish its purpose. The County Manager will provide such facilities as the Board may deem necessary to accomplish its purposes.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 01-115, § 2, 7-10-01; Ord. No. 04-18, § 1, 1-20-04; Ord. No. 04-96, § 1, 5-11-04; Ord. No. 07-43, § 1, 3-6-07; Ord. No. 07-180, § 2, 12-18-07; Ord. No. 11-18, § 1, 4-4-11)</history>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-1313—2-1320. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
</law>
