<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_LIII._COMMISSION_OFINQUIRY</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-601. Commission of Inquiry created</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created and established a Commission of Inquiry consisting of nine (9) members.
The mayor and each county commissioner shall nominate one (1) member to the Commission subject to ratification of five (5) additional members of the Board of County Commissioners. Each appointee shall have expertise in one or more of the following subject areas: building construction, architecture, engineering, construction finance, or construction law. No member or staff shall have had direct or indirect involvement in the design or construction of a building project in Miami-Dade County during the past five (5) years.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-602. Powers</catch_line>
<text>
Within two (2) weeks of its initial meeting, the Commission shall report to the Board of County Commissioners its goals and objectives. The Commission shall inquire into the adequacy of the South Florida Building Code, compliance therewith by the local construction industry and enforcement thereof by the county in light of the widespread damage to residential, commercial and industrial structures caused by Hurricane Andrew. The Commission shall submit a written report containing its findings, conclusions and recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners on or before March 31, 1993. The Commission may petition the Board of County Commissioners for an extension of time to conclude its inquiry and submit its written report. In conducting such inquiry, the Commission may subpoena witnesses, administer oaths and require the production of records. Upon submission of its written report, the Commission of Inquiry shall be deemed dissolved.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-603. Organization</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Commission shall elect a chairperson and other such officers as may be deemed necessary or desirable, who shall serve at the will of the Commission.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A majority of members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum necessary to hold a meeting and take any action. Except as specified elsewhere in this article, a majority vote of the members present shall be necessary to take any action. The chairperson may call meetings of the Commission. Meetings may also be called by written notice signed by six (6) members. The Commission at any meeting may fix and call a meeting on a future date. Minutes shall be kept of all meetings of the commission and all meetings shall be public.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 92-137, § 1, 10-27-92)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-604. Authority to utilize independent staff, consultants and counsel</catch_line>
<text>
The Commission shall have authority to engage the services of such independent staff, consultants and counsel as it deems necessary and proper to carry out its duties. Any such counsel shall have experience in construction law and familiarity with investigative law principles. Provided, however, the Commission shall not exceed its budgetary appropriation as authorized by the Board. No county employee shall serve as staff or consultant to the Commission.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-605. Applicability of conflict of interest, public records and open meeting requirements</catch_line>
<text>
Members of the Commission shall be subject to the Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance, including the financial disclosure provisions thereof. The Commission shall be subject to the applicable provisions of the "Government in the Sunshine" and Public Records laws, Chapters 286 and 119, Florida Statutes.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-606—2-620. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (73) ---
Cross reference— Building code, Ch. 8. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
