<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_CXXVIII._MIAMI-DADE_COUNTY_COMMU</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2011. Purpose</catch_line>
<text>
The purpose of this ordinance is to codify the standards, criteria, and applications governing the Miami-Dade County Community Periodical Program. In line with its intent when originally established, the purpose of this program is to provide news and information about Miami-Dade County's programs and services, and other public service announcements to the poor, elderly and disadvantaged citizens who cannot afford to buy a mainstream newspaper.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2012. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
"Year" means the County fiscal year which extends from October 1st to September 30th.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2013. Program described—No rights conveyed</catch_line>
<text>
It is the intention of Miami-Dade County to publish advertising in the periodicals that qualify and become a part of this program. No rights to receive advertising contracts are granted by qualifying for or participating in this program. The decision of whether, what, and how much to publish in a particular periodical remains in the sole discretion of Miami-Dade County, which may consider any lawful factor in making its decision including, but not limited to, rates, target audience, frequency and consistency of publication, while advertising rates shall remain the sole discretion of the individual periodical operating in a free market economy. The exercise of the County's discretion in this regard shall not be subject to any appeal. Nothing herein shall restrict the ability of an individual periodical to adopt whatever rate it deems appropriate, provided that Miami-Dade County may decline to purchase advertising based upon the rate. The Department charged with administering this program may periodically issue its own rate ceiling cards indicating the maximum amounts that it will pay for various categories of advertising.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2014. Qualifications</catch_line>
<text>
To qualify for participation in this program a community periodical must meet the following conditions, and have a history of meeting the conditions in subsections (b), (c), (e), (f), (g), (h), and (k), for three years prior to entering the program:
<section prefix = "a">
Be circulated free of charge. A periodical will be deemed circulating free of charge even if it charges for copies that are delivered by mail provided that at least eighty percent of its circulation is distributed at distribution points in public places in Miami-Dade County where the public can obtain copies free of any charge, as provided herein. The periodical shall not display a per edition charge anywhere in the publication, but may advertise a subscription rate for copies delivered by mail;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Contain articles of local, national, or international news of interest to the general public;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Be published in amounts of no less than 5,000 copies for each edition which must be distributed within Miami-Dade County;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Contain no less than 12 pages in each edition and contain no less than 6 pages of non-advertising content such as news, calendar items, stories, photographs, recipes, comics, puzzles, and editorials; this content must consist of no less than 1,000 words; and any content whose placement in the periodical is paid for by a third party, including commercial and political advertising, must be labeled to indicate it is paid advertising when necessary to avoid consumer confusion;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Prominently display the publication date on the masthead, cover, inside cover or other easily viewed location;
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Be published continuously throughout the year on a schedule set before the year begins, either once per month, twice per month, or four times per month;
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Have a main office or headquarters from which the periodical is published with a street address located in Miami-Dade County;
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Have an occupational license that reflects its main office or headquarters street address and that is valid for the year in which the periodical intends to participate in the program;
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Be printed in Miami-Dade County; but use of printing facilities outside of the County is permissible in emergency situations outside the control of the periodical, provided the periodical returns to printing in the County when the emergency has ended; and use of printing facilities outside of the County is also permissible when the cost of printing the periodical within the County is ten percent or more expensive than the cost of printing outside the County, as reflected in written cost estimates or bills obtained by the periodical from the printers;
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Be distributed in an established manner, either by mail or by delivery to no less than 10 different distribution points dispersed throughout the community it serves, none of which shall be a County-owned facility;
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Have a history of having published continuously for at least three years prior to the first year for which it seeks to participate in the program;
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Be registered as a vendor with the Miami-Dade County Internal Services Department, or its successor department responsible for registering vendors;
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
Have a rate card reflecting the periodical's standard rates;
</section>
<section prefix = "n">
Provide Miami-Dade County with price guarantee for rates for the year in which it intends to participate that comply with the rate requirements of this ordinance;
</section>
<section prefix = "o">
Otherwise have complied with the provisions of this ordinance regarding including, but not limited to, applications, upkeep of records, reporting changes in information, and audit; and
</section>
<section prefix = "p">
Provide business documents indicating the persons who control or own the periodical, such as articles of incorporation or partnership agreements.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2015. Applications</catch_line>
<text>
To participate, a periodical must submit an application in a form prepared by Miami-Dade County. The application will contain separate sections addressing each of the required qualifications of the program. At a minimum, the application form will require the following documents to be attached to the application: a current issue, printer's invoices, valid occupational license, proof of registration as a vendor with Miami-Dade County, rate card, business documents reflecting ownership, for example, articles of incorporation or partnership agreement. No submitted application will be complete without such documents. In addition, prior to admitting a periodical to the program, the administration will confirm the publication history by reviewing all issues published in the prior three years as required by subsection 2-2014(k). The application must be signed and notarized by an owner or officer of the periodical. The Miami-Dade County may require the applicant to file the application in person or to participate in an application review meeting. All Community Periodicals intending to participate in the program must submit new applications pursuant to this ordinance.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2016. Responsibility to update application and other information</catch_line>
<text>
The periodical will have an ongoing responsibility to update the information contained in its application and any other information it provides the County regarding this program. Such updating of information shall be filed with Miami-Dade County within ten working days of the change.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2017. Responsibility to provide copies of issues while in program</catch_line>
<text>
Once a periodical has entered the program, the periodical must provide Miami-Dade County with all copies of the issues that it publishes in order for the County to confirm that the periodical publishes on the schedule it has provided. This requirement applies whether or not the periodical is receiving advertising from the County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2018. Proof of publication and payment</catch_line>
<text>
In the event that the County contracts to have the periodical publish advertising, the following applies to payment:
<section prefix = "a">
The periodical must invoice the County for the advertising, provide a copy of issue containing the advertisement, and provide three copies of a tear sheet of the advertisement.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Miami-Dade County will remit payment within thirty (30) days of receiving these materials.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Miami-Dade County may decline to pay the invoice if the conditions governing the publication of the advertising are not met, including, but not limited to:
<section prefix = "1">
Failure to place the advertisement according to insertion order provided with the advertisement;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Failure to place advertisement according to the date stipulated on insertion order;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Placing an advertisement without having an insertion order accompany the advertisement; and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Failure to charge the correct rate that is guaranteed at time of application.

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2019. Retaining Records and Audits</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
A periodical that is paid to publish advertising as part of this program must retain for three years the following records for each year in which it received advertising:
<section prefix = "1">
Copies of publications;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Printers receipts showing the number of copies of each issue printed;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Copies of checks or other form of payment to the printer showing proof that the printer was paid for printing the issues;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The distribution points where the paper is distributed.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Audits. Any periodical that participates in this program, whether or not it receives advertising, is subject to audits by officers and agents of the County to ensure compliance with the provisions of this ordinance. The periodical will make its accounts and records, including, but not limited to, the records mentioned above, available to the County at reasonable times and places as the County determines necessary to conduct the audits. These audits may include investigations to insure that the periodicals statements regarding circulation are accurate and that the periodical has complied with the qualifications required under Section 2-2014 during the preceding three years.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 12-25, § 1, 4-3-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2020. Suspension and termination</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Suspension. The County may formally suspend a periodical for any period of time up to and including twelve months for any of the following reasons:
<section prefix = "1">
Failure to report changes in the information provided to the County within ten days of the change, when such change of information would not disqualify the periodical from participating in the program;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Failure to publish according to the schedule provided on two or three occasions in any six-month period;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
On one occasion submitting an invoice for more than the guaranteed amount or when no insertion order was sent; and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Single or accidental violations of the terms of this ordinance that County determines do not warrant termination.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Termination. The County may formally terminate a periodical for any period of time from one to three years for any of the following reasons:
<section prefix = "1">
Misrepresenting a material fact on the application that impacts the periodical's qualification for the program;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Failure to report changes in the information provided to the County within ten days of the change, when such change of information would disqualify the periodical from participating in the program;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Failure to publish according to the schedule provided on four or more occasions in any six-month period;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
On two or more occasions, submitting an invoice for more than the guaranteed amount or when no insertion order was sent; or
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Other multiple or intentional violations of the terms of this ordinance.
A periodical that is formally terminated must reapply by submitting a new application after its termination is over.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 12-25, § 1, 4-3-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2021. Departments required to purchase advertising through this program—Administrative matters</catch_line>
<text>
Community Periodical Advertising Expenditure. Each Department or County Entity that purchases print advertisements, will expend no less than one-half its discretionary print advertisement budget through this program. This requirement shall not apply to discretionary advertising or marketing that is designed to promote tourism or stimulate economic development by attracting consumers and businesses located outside of Miami-Dade County to do business within the County. As used in this section "discretionary print advertising" means all print advertisements, except those that are legally required to be published by ordinance, statute or law as a precondition to a County action or participation in a program. As part of each annual budget, the Mayor will provide the Board of County Commissioners a report that sets forth for each department the total budgeted print advertising dollars, the discretionary print advertising dollars, the print advertising dollars that are legally required to be published in newspapers of general circulation, and the non-print advertising dollars. If a specific amount for the program is established in the budget ordinance, the specific amount so established will control and the above provisions will not apply. Unless the budget ordinance indicates otherwise, moneys allocated in the budget for the program will be spent on the purchase of advertising and not on administrative expenses such as audits.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2022. Appeals</catch_line>
<text>
Any periodical aggrieved by an administrative decision may appeal that decision by filing a written notice of appeal with the Clerk of the Courts, Code Enforcement, 111 N.W. 1st Street, Suite 1750, Miami, Florida within 20 days of the issuance of the written decision. The notice must fully explain the basis for the appeal and the reasons why the periodical believes the decision was wrong. The Miami-Dade County will have the appeal scheduled to be heard by one of the Hearing Officers provided for under Chapter 8CC of the Miami-Dade County Code and a hearing will be conducted under the provisions of that Chapter. An appeal of the Hearing Examiner's decision may be taken as provided in that Chapter.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2023. Censorship</catch_line>
<text>
The County will not withhold advertising from a periodical because of the periodical's editorial or news content attacking the actions of the County government or any County official. Any County employee who receives any instruction, order, or direction to withhold advertising for this reason will immediately report the instruction, order to the Commission on Ethics and the Inspector General who shall investigate to determine the truth of the statement and may refer to appropriate agency.
</text>
</law>
