<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_I._BOMBINGS</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-1. Bombings and threats prohibited</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful for any person willfully and maliciously to destroy, damage or deface, or to threaten the destruction, damage or defacement of any person or any public or private buildings, property, place or conveyance in the County by bombs, dynamite, explosives or any other instrumentality of destructive force.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-2. Disseminating false information relating to</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful for any person knowingly or intentionally to give, transmit or disseminate, by word of mouth, telephone, written communication, or otherwise, any false information, false alarm, false report, or threat to the effect that any public or private building, property, place or conveyance (including, but not limited to, churches, schools, theaters, auditoriums, assembly halls, common carriers, private conveyances, or school buses) is, will, or may be subject to damage, destruction or defacement by bombs, dynamite, explosives or other instrumentality or destructive force.
</text>
It shall be unlawful for any person knowingly or intentionally to give, transmit or disseminate, by word of mouth, telephone, written communication, or otherwise, any false information, false alarm, false report, or threat to the effect that any public or private building, property, place or conveyance (including, but not limited to, churches, schools, theaters, auditoriums, assembly halls, common carriers, private conveyances, or school buses) is, will, or may be subject to damage, destruction or defacement by bombs, dynamite, explosives or other instrumentality or destructive force.
<catch_line>Sec. 21-3. Maliciously disrupting meetings with threats</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful for any person willfully or maliciously to cause the disruption, evacuation, abandonment, or interruption of any session or meeting at school, church, or other public or private buildings, place or property, by anonymously circulating or communicating any false report, alarm or threat to the effect that such building, place or property is, will, or may be subject to danger or hazard of damage or destruction by bombs, dynamite, explosives, or other instrumentality of destructive force.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-4. Law enforcement officers excepted</catch_line>
<text>
The provisions of this article shall not be construed to anywise interfere with, hinder or prevent any police officer, law enforcement official or other public official in the performance of his official duties or in taking such precautionary measures as may be deemed necessary to prevent the possibility of loss of life or physical injury in respect to anonymous bombing threats.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-5. Violations, penalty</catch_line>
<text>
Any person convicted for the violations of any provisions of this article shall be punished by a fine not exceeding one thousand dollars ($1,000.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for a term not to exceed one (1) year, or by both such fine and imprisonment.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (1) ---
Cross reference— Intrusion and burglary security, Ch. 8C; permit to purchase, sell, use explosives, § 13-1 et seq.; seaport security and operations, Ch. 28A. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
