<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 29 TAXATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_X._PROPERTY_TAX_EXEMPTIONS_IN_EN</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-81. Authority to grant the exemptions</catch_line>
<text>
Pursuant to the terms of this article, the Board of County Commissioners at its discretion is hereby authorized to grant by ordinance ad valorem tax exemptions to new and expanding businesses located within the enterprise zones, as defined herein, except to businesses located in the terminals of the Miami International Airport and except for real property improvements in any community redevelopment area; however, the Board of County Commissioners may grant ad valorem tax exemptions for the tangible personal property of new and expanding businesses in a community redevelopment area located within the enterprise zone in any community redevelopment area. Applications to the County for the tax exemption on tangible personal property from businesses located in municipal CRAs shall require the prior approval of the CRA Board and the governing body of the municipality in which the business is located prior to being submitted to the Board of County Commissioners for consideration. The Board of County Commissioners may also commit to grant an exemption based on presentation of substantive proposals that indicate serious intent to build a new business or expand an existing business within an enterprise zone, provided however, that the improvements to real property are made or the tangible personal property are added or increased on or after the day of the ordinance granting the exemption is adopted. The commitment by the Board to grant an exemption based on plans and proposals is contingent on the business completing the indicated improvements in substantially the same form and extent as presented.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-82. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
For the purposes of this article, the following terms are defined as follows:
<section prefix = "a">
Enterprise zone means an area either designated pursuant to Section 290.005 [Florida Statutes] and approved by the Office of Tourism, Trade and Economic Development pursuant to Section 290.0065, Florida Statutes, or authorized to be an enterprise zone pursuant to Section 290.0055, Florida Statutes, and approved by the Office of Tourism, Trade and Economic Development pursuant to Section 290.0065, Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
New business means any commercial or industrial business, excluding residential developments, located in an enterprise zone that begins operations on a site clearly separate from any other commercial or industrial operation owned by the same business and which creates five (5) or more new jobs to employ five (5) or more additional full-time employees at such location.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Expanding business or expansion of an existing business means any commercial or industrial business, excluding residential developments, located in an enterprise zone that increases operations on a site co-located with a commercial or industrial operation owned by the same business and which creates five (5) or more new jobs to employ five (5) or more additional full-time employees at such location.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-83. Scope and terms of exemptions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
If a business qualifies as a "new" or "expanding" business such exemption will be fifty (50) percent of the assessed value of all improvements to real property made by or for the use of a new business and all tangible personal property of such new business, or fifty (50) percent of the assessed value of all added improvements to real property which improvements are made to facilitate the expansion of an existing business and fifty (50) percent of the net increase in all tangible personal property acquired to facilitate such expansion of an existing business.
If twenty (20) percent or more of a business' permanent full-time employees are residents of enterprise zones, such exemption will be one hundred (100) percent of the assessed value of all improvements to real property made by or for the use of a new business and all tangible personal property of such new business, or one hundred (100) percent of the assessed value of all added improvements to real property which improvements are made to facilitate the expansion of an existing business and of the net increase in all tangible personal property acquired to facilitate such expansion of an existing business. Property acquired to replace existing property shall not be considered to facilitate a business expansion.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The exemption shall apply only to Miami-Dade County Countywide operating and unincorporated municipal service area millages and shall not apply to taxes levied for payment of bonds or to taxes authorized by a vote of the electors pursuant to Section 9(b) or Section 12, Article VII of the State Constitution.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Subject to the renewal provisions contained herein, an exemption granted pursuant to this article may remain in effect for up to five (5) years with respect to that particular facility, regardless of any change in the authority of the Board of County Commissioners to grant such exemptions. The exemption shall not be prolonged or extended by granting exemption from additional taxes or by virtue of any reorganization or sale of the business receiving the exemption.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The granting of this exemption and the length of the period for which the exemption shall be granted shall be at the discretion of the Board of County Commissioners, who shall make this determination on the basis of the factors outlined in the following section.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 88-27, § 3, 4-19-88; Ord. No. 96-74, § 2, 5-21-96; Ord. No. 06-68, § 3, 5-9-06)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-84. Eligibility requirements</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
To be eligible for this exemption, a new or expanding business must increase its employment roll over the year preceding the initial granting of the exemption by a minimum of five (5) new full-time jobs. It shall be a condition precedent to the granting of each annual renewal that the additional new jobs created as a result of the new business or expansion be maintained for the duration of the exemption.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
To be eligible for this exemption, a new or expanded business shall provide a statement, on a form approved by the Board of County Commissioners, that no less than five (5) new full-time jobs have are created; and if applicable, no less than twenty (20) percent of its permanent full-time employees are residents of an enterprise zone.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 88-27, § 3, 4-19-88; Ord. No. 96-74, § 2, 5-21-96)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-85. Application procedures</catch_line>
<text>
Any person, firm, or corporation which desires an economic ad valorem tax exemption pursuant to this article shall file a written application on a form prescribed by the Office of Community and Economic Development (OCED) for said exemption either on or before February first of the year in which new or additional real or tangible personal property is first subject to ad valorem assessment. Such application shall be filed with the Board of County Commissioners.
The application shall request the adoption of an ordinance granting the applicant an exemption pursuant to this article and shall include the following information:
<section prefix = "a">
The name and location of the new or expanding business.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The description of the improvements to real property for which an exemption is being requested, the cost of such improvements, and the date of commencement and completion of construction of such improvements.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
A description of the tangible personal property for which an exemption is requested, the cost of such property, and the date when such property was or is to be purchased.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
A copy of the building plans.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
A copy of the building permit, if available.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Proof, to the satisfaction of the Board of County Commissioners, that the application is a new business or an expansion of an existing business, as defined in this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Other information deemed necessary by the Board of County Commissioners. The applicant shall pay a reasonable nonrefundable fee for the time and work involved in processing the application.
Should a proposal to build a new business or expand an existing one be modified after the Board of County Commissioners has agreed to grant it an exemption, the decision to grant said exemption may continue to apply to the modified proposal, only if the Board of County Commissioners determines that there were extenuating circumstances that justified the modification to the original proposal.
In the event the reasons for the modification are deemed to be unsatisfactory the exemption shall be withdrawn and the business duly informed. The business, upon notification of the withdrawal of the exemption, shall have the right to appeal to the Board of County Commissioners for the reinstatement of the exemption.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Proof that property taxes are current.

The property appraiser shall report the following information to the Board:
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
The total revenue available to the County for the current fiscal year from ad valorem tax sources;
<section prefix = "ii">
Any revenue lost to the County for the current fiscal year by virtue of exemptions previously granted under this article;
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
An estimate of the revenue which would be lost to the County during the current fiscal year if the exemption applied for were granted had the property for which the exemption is requested otherwise been subject to taxation;
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
A determination as to whether the property for which an exemption is requested satisfies the eligibility requirements of a new business or an expansion of an existing business, as defined herein, which determination shall also be affixed to the face of the application.

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-86. Enactment of ordinance granting each exemption</catch_line>
<text>
After receipt of the report from the County Manager, the Board of County Commissioners, at its discretion may grant a tax exemption by ordinance as authorized herein.
The ordinance granting an exemption shall be enacted in the same manner as any other Miami-Dade County ordinance and shall include the following:
<section prefix = "a">
The name and address of the new or expanding business to which the exemption is granted;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The total amount of revenue available to the County from ad valorem tax sources for the current fiscal year, the total amount of revenue foregone by the County for the current fiscal year by virtue of economic development ad valorem tax exemptions currently in effect, and the estimated revenue foregone by the County for the current fiscal year attributable to the exemption of the business named in the ordinance as a new business or expansion of an existing business as defined herein;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The period of time for which the exemption will remain in effect and the expiration date of the exemption; and
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
A finding that the business named in the ordinance meets the requirements of Section 196.012(15) or (16), Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
A finding that the business property tax bills are current.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-87. Renewal provisions</catch_line>
<text>
Exemptions granted pursuant to this article shall be renewable each year a total of five (5) years upon application by the taxpayer on or before March 1, of the year for which renewal is sought. Failure to file a renewal application with the County Property Appraiser by March 1, of any year shall constitute a waiver of the exemption for the year. Businesses found to be not in compliance with the eligibility requirements shall be required to make payment of the taxes exempted in addition to interest accrued.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-88. First application of article to 2005 tax roll</catch_line>
<text>
Exemptions under this article shall first apply to new businesses and expansion of existing businesses as defined herein for the assessed value of improvements to real property and tangible personal property on the 2005 tax assessment rolls of Miami-Dade County. All qualified applications that were submitted to the Office of Community and Economic Development (OCED) and pending as of June 30, 2005 shall be eligible under the new program regardless of the year in which the improvements were made or placed on the tax assessment rolls of Miami-Dade County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-89. Expiration date</catch_line>
<text>
The authority of the Board of County Commissioners to grant tax exemptions pursuant to this article, shall expire on June 30, 2015 and no business shall be allowed to begin receiving such exemption after that date; however, the expiration of this section shall not affect the operation of any exemption for which a business has qualified under this section prior to June 30, 2015.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (9) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 88-27, § 3, adopted April 19, 1988, amended Ch. 29 by the addition of provisions which have been designated at the discretion of the editor as Art. X, §§ 29-81—29-89. (Back)
State Law reference— Enterprise zones, F.S. § 290.001 et seq. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
