<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_LXXV._FEDERAL_ENTERPRISE_COMMUNI</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1021. Creation</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created and established as an agency and instrumentality of Miami-Dade County, the Federal Enterprise Community Council (the "Council").
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1022. Purpose</catch_line>
<text>
The Council is created for the specific purposes of (a) advising the Board of County Commissioners (the" Board") on issues regarding the Federal Enterprise Community Strategic Plan (the "Plan") and (b) providing the mechanism by which the Plan's benchmarks and goals will be monitored, and performance evaluated.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1023. Composition, appointment and term of office</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Council shall be composed of twenty-eight (28) voting members. The members may designate an alternate to serve and/or vote on their behalf. The members shall serve without compensation.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The voting membership of the Council shall be ethnically, racially and gender balanced, and dedicated to the goals of the Plan. The Council shall be appointed by the Board with representatives from the following:
<section prefix = "1">
The Federal Enterprise Community: Two (2) representatives of each of the communities of Liberty City; Wynwood; Overtown; Little Havana; Allapattah; Melrose; Homestead and Florida City for a total of sixteen (16) representatives. The representatives will be appointed by the Board from a list of five (5) nominees for each community, to be submitted by the respective cities as follows: Wynwood, Overtown, Little Havana, Liberty City and Allapattah (City of Miami); Homestead (City of Homestead); and Florida City (Florida City). The Board will nominate representatives for Melrose.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Mayor or City Manager of the City of Miami.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Mayor or City Manager of Florida City.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Mayor or City Manager of the City of Homestead.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The County Manager of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Superintendent of the Miami-Dade County Public Schools or the Chairperson of the Miami-Dade County School Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
The District Administrator of the State of Florida Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services for the district encompassing Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Four (4) representatives from the following: Two (2) from the private sector, one (1) from the non-profit sector and one (1) from the labor sector.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
The President of Miami-Dade Community College
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
The Chairperson of the South Florida Employment and Training Consortium.
Vacancies on the Council shall be filled in the same manner by which the original members were appointed, with a special emphasis on choosing persons representative of the gender, racial and ethnic composition of the entire community, and the segments of the community necessary to achieving the goals of the Strategic Plan.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All voting members shall serve staggered terms of three (3) years each; provided, however, of the original membership, ten (10) shall serve for an initial term of one (1) year, ten (10) shall serve for an initial term of two (2) years, and eight (8) shall serve for an initial term of three (3) years.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
No member, with the exception of ex officio members, shall be permitted to serve more than two (2) consecutive and complete terms of three (3) years each unless so authorized by two-thirds (2/3) vote of the full membership of the Board. Members may be removed in accordance with the provisions of Section 2-11.38 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The Board may, from time to time, appoint ex officio members. The Directors of Miami International Airport, the Port of Miami, the Public Health Trust, and the Community Action Agency shall serve as ex officio members.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Each member shall comply with the requirements of Section 2-11.38 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 96-87, § 3, 6-4-96)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1024. Organizations and procedure</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Council shall organize after the members thereof have qualified to serve and shall select one (1) of its members as chairperson and such other officers as the Council may determine to be necessary. In addition, the Council shall make, adopt and amend bylaws, rules and regulations for its own governance. The Council shall create any committees it deems necessary.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Council shall hold regular meetings and such other meetings as it deems necessary. A majority of the members of the Council shall constitute a quorum. Minutes shall be kept of all meetings of the Council and all meetings shall be public. The Clerk of the Board shall keep minutes of all meetings of the Council.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All Council members shall comply with the Florida Open Government Laws, including the "Sunshine Law", Public Meeting Laws and Public Records Laws and shall be governed by all state and county conflict of interest laws, as applicable, including the Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance, Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 96-87, § 4, 6-4-96)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1025. Powers and functions of the Council</catch_line>
<text>
The members shall have the following powers, duties, functions and responsibilities:
<section prefix = "a">
To serve in an advisory capacity to the Board with respect to all issues affecting or relating to the implementation of the Plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
To recommend to the Board, in accordance with the Plan, an annual budget and plan for use of the federal grant and other funds allocated to carry out the Plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
To recommend to the Board, in accordance with the Plan, the allocation of funds to public agencies, the award of contracts and grants to organizations, entities and agencies, including independent 501(c)(3) corporations.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
To review the Plan on a regular basis and at least annually to assure that the Plan's implementation is achieving Plan goals and addressing the needs of the Enterprise Community.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
To evaluate performance and recommend to the Board any needed amendments or modifications.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
To submit annually to the Board of County Commissioners and the City Commissions of Miami, Florida City and Homestead, a report summarizing and evaluating the performance of all programs and activities in the Strategic Plan during the previous fiscal year, including the timetable for performance. The report shall include an audit and accounting, in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, of all funds received and expended.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
To monitor, review and evaluate Miami-Dade County's economic links to the Enterprise Community, including the airport and seaport and medical complex and the direct benefit to the residents of the Enterprise Community.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
To submit reports required by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
To monitor, review and evaluate the effectiveness of the Enterprise Community Center in its delivery of services including increasing access to capital, targeted technical assistance for businesses, job development and training.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1026. Staff support</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager shall provide to the Council adequate staff and support services to enable the Council to carry out its duties and responsibilities.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1027. Liberal construction to effectuate public purpose</catch_line>
<text>
This article being for a public purpose and for the welfare of the citizens of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall be liberally construed to effect the purposes thereof.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1028. Validity</catch_line>
<text>
If any section, subsection, sentence, clause or provision of this article is held invalid, the remainder of this article shall not be affected by such invalidity.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-1029—2-1035. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (95) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 96-87, adopted June 4, 1996, amended the Code by the addition of provisions which have been designated at the discretion of the editor as Art. LXXV §§ 2-1021—2-1028. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
