<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="2">ARTICLE_CXXIV._KENDALE_LAKES_LANDSCAPE_M</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1901. Creation of the Kendale Lakes Landscape Maintenance Special Taxing District Advisory Board</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created and established the Kendale Lakes Landscape Maintenance Special Taxing District Advisory Board.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1902. Composition, Terms</catch_line>
<text>
Kendale Lakes Landscape Maintenance Special Taxing District Advisory Board ("Advisory Board") shall be composed of seven (7) members, each residing in one of the seven regions within the Kendale Lakes Landscape Maintenance Special Taxing District ("Special Taxing District"), as more specifically set forth below. The members shall serve staggered terms of no more than two (2) years, with no member serving for more than eight (8) consecutive years.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1903. Nomination and Selection of Members</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Initial Advisory Board. The Initial Advisory Board shall be established as provided in this paragraph. Within ten (10) days following the effective date of this article, the County, under the name of the County Commissioner from District 11, shall mail to each property owner and advertise for not less than two (2) consecutive weeks in both a newspaper of general circulation throughout the County and in a local neighborhood circulated newspaper, and post in not less than five (5) places within the limit of the Special Taxing District, a notice stating where and when applications (the "Applications") for the Initial Advisory Board will be available. An Application will also be included with every notice sent by mail. The Applications will be developed by the Park and Recreation Department and will require the applicant to provide her or his name, address, proof of residence within the Special Taxing District, and proof of length of residence within the Special Taxing District.
<section prefix = "a">
The Application deadline will be no less than three (3) weeks from the date of the advertisement and mailing.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Park and Recreation Department will collect and evaluate the Applications as provided herein. At the expiration of the Application deadline, the County Representative, as defined in Section 1(c)(3), shall select the nominees for the Initial Advisory Board using the following criteria. The applicant within each Special Taxing District region who has resided longest within the region will be the nominee for that region. If there is no applicant for a region, then the County Representative will appoint the nominee from the remaining pool of applicants.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The County Representative, by and through the Park and Recreation Department, will provide the Board of County Commissioners the slate of nominees for approval.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
In order to establish staggered terms for the Advisory Board, the terms of the Initial Advisory Board members will be as provided in this section. The term of the members from odd-numbered Special Taxing District regions shall serve from the date of their approval by the Board of County Commissioners until the approval of the nominees by the Board of County Commissioners following the next annual meeting provided in Section 1(c)(3) herein, irrespective of whether those members of the Advisory Board have served a full year term. The members of the Initial Advisory Board from even-numbered Special Taxing District regions shall serve from the date of their approval by the Board of County Commissioners until the approval of the nominees by the Board of County Commissioners following the annual meeting two years following the passage of this article. For example, if this article is passed in October, 2001 and the Initial Advisory Board is empanelled and approved by November, 2001, the members of the Initial Advisory Board from odd-numbered regions will serve until the nominees from odd-numbered regions selected at the May, 2002 Nomination Meeting are approved by the Board of County Commissioners. The members of the Initial Advisory Board from even-numbered regions shall serve until the nominees from the even-numbered regions selected at the May, 2003 Nomination Meeting are approved.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Advertisement for Nomination Meeting. On or before May 1 of each year following the establishment of the Initial Advisory Board, the County, under the name of the County Commissioner from District 11, shall mail to each property owner and advertise for not less than two (2) consecutive weeks in both a newspaper of general circulation throughout the County and in a local neighborhood circulated newspaper, and post in not less than five (5) places within the limits of the Special Taxing District, a notice setting the date, place, and time of a public meeting of property owners and residents within the limits of the Special Taxing District for purpose of selecting nominees for the Advisory Board. The notice shall briefly describe purpose of the meting, the responsibilities of the Advisory Board, and advise the recipients that at the meeting nominations will be received for persons from the specified Special Taxing District regions desiring to serve as members of the Advisory Board for the upcoming two (2) year term.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Nomination Meeting. The annual nomination meeting shall be chaired by the Park and Recreation Department Special Taxing District Manager or other designee of the Park and Recreation Department Director ("County Representative"). The County Representative will open the floor for nominations only for those Special Taxing District regions with vacancies that year and shall record the names of those nominated for each vacant Special Taxing District region, as illustrated and defined in the Special Taxing District map attached as Exhibit "A." Each even-numbered year will have nominations for odd-numbered Special Taxing District regions and vice-versa. At least one person from each vacant Special Taxing District region shall be nominated for the Advisory Board. If more than one person from region is nominated for a single region, then the person residing in the region for the longest period of time shall become the region's nominee. If no nominee is secured for a given Special Taxing District region, then the Director of the Park and Recreation Department will appoint the nominee. The County Representative will be responsible for verifying the residence of all nominees, and if necessary, the length of residency within the Special Taxing District and specific region.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Board Approval of Nominees. The County Representative, by and through the Park and Recreation Department, will provide the Board of County Commissioners the slate of nominees for approval.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Vacancies. Should any Advisory Board member move out of the region for which they were nominated during the course of her or his term, but continue to reside within the Special Taxing District, then that Advisory Board member will serve out her or his term, but will not be eligible for a new term within that region, unless no resident within the region desires to be the region's nominee at the following Nomination Meeting. Should any Advisory Board member move out of the Special Taxing District during her or his term, then she or he will forfeit her or his position on the Advisory Board. Should an Advisory Board member resign during her or his term for any other reason, the term will be filled by the next person eligible who has resided in that region the longest.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 01-133, § 1, 9-13-01; Ord. No. 05-195, § 1, 11-3-05)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1904. Officers; Quorum; Compensation</catch_line>
<text>
The members of the Advisory Board shall elect a chairperson and vice chairperson, who shall serve at the will of the Advisory Board. Four (4) members of the Advisory Board shall constitute a quorum necessary to hold a meeting and take any action. A majority vote of the quorum of the Advisory Board shall be necessary to take any action. Members shall serve without compensation. The chairperson or vice chairperson may call meetings of the Advisory Board. Meetings may also be called by written notice signed by four (4) members. The Advisory Board at any duly noticed meeting may fix and call a meeting on a future date. All meetings shall be public.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1905. Duties, Powers, and Responsibilities</catch_line>
<text>
The Board shall have the following duties, powers and responsibilities:
<section prefix = "1">
To serve in an advisory capacity to the Board of County Commissioners, and the County administration, in respect to matters pertaining to the Special Taxing District.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To formulate and recommend plans and programs for the Special Taxing District.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Advisory Board shall annually report to the Board of County Commissioners as to its recommendations.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
To perform such other duties as may from time to time be assigned to it by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1906. Support</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager, County Attorney and Clerk of the Board shall provide appropriate support for the Advisory Board.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1907. Meetings of the Board</catch_line>
<text>
The Advisory Board shall hold regular meetings, no less than six times per year, and such other meetings, as it deems necessary. The Advisory Board shall at all times operate under the Florida Open Government laws, including the "Sunshine Law," public meeting laws and public records laws and shall be governed by all State and County conflict of interest laws, as applicable, including the Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance, Sec. 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-1908—2-1920. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
</law>
