<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XIXA._RU-5_RESIDENTIAL—SEMI-PROF</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-223.1. Uses permitted</catch_line>
<text>
No land, body of water or structure shall be used, or permitted to be used, and no structure shall be hereafter erected, constructed, reconstructed, moved or structurally altered or maintained for any purpose in an RU-5 District which is designed, arranged, or intended to be used or occupied for any purpose, except for one (1) or more of the following uses, and all other uses are hereby prohibited:
<section prefix = "1">
Duplex use—those uses permitted in the RU-2 District subject only to the requirements, limitations and restrictions specified in said district, and except that it shall be permissible to use a fifty- by one hundred-foot lot for two-family use in an old subdivision
(1.1)
Rowhouse development, subject only to the requirements, limitations and restrictions specified for the RU-RH district.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Apartment house as permitted in the RU-3 District subject only to the requirements, limitations and restrictions applicable in the RU-3 District for such use
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Multiple-family housing projects
(3.1)
Workforce housing units in compliance with the provisions of Article XIIA of this code.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Abstract title
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Accountants—bookkeeping
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Actuaries
(6.1)
Adult day care center
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Advertising (no shops)
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Adjusters (insurance)
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Aerial survey and photography
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Appraisals—no sale or rental of any type of merchandise or equipment
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Architects
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Attorneys
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Auditors
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
Banks without drive-in teller facilities
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
Business analysts—counselors or brokers
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
Building contractors, office only (no shops or storage)
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
Chiropodists
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
Chiropractors
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
Consulates
</section>
<section prefix = "20">
Counseling, child guidance and family service
</section>
<section prefix = "21">
Court reporter, public stenographer
</section>
<section prefix = "22">
Credit reporting
(22A)
Day nursery, kindergarten and afterschool care licensed by the State of Florida Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services and established in accordance with the requirements of Article XA
</section>
<section prefix = "23">
Dentists
</section>
<section prefix = "24">
Detective agencies and investigating service
</section>
<section prefix = "25">
Drafting and plan service
</section>
<section prefix = "26">
Engineers, professional
</section>
<section prefix = "27">
State or Federal savings and loan associations as defined in 12 U.S.C.A., Section 1464, which do not require drive-in tellers
</section>
<section prefix = "28">
Insurance and bonds
</section>
<section prefix = "29">
Manufacturers' agents
</section>
<section prefix = "30">
Market research
</section>
<section prefix = "31">
Medical doctors
</section>
<section prefix = "32">
Model agencies (no school)
</section>
<section prefix = "33">
Mortgage broker
</section>
<section prefix = "34">
Notary public
</section>
<section prefix = "35">
Optician
</section>
<section prefix = "36">
Optometrists
</section>
<section prefix = "37">
Public libraries
</section>
<section prefix = "38">
Public relations
</section>
<section prefix = "39">
Real estate
</section>
<section prefix = "40">
Real estate management
</section>
<section prefix = "41">
Secretarial service
</section>
<section prefix = "42">
Shoppers' information service
</section>
<section prefix = "43">
Social service bureau
</section>
<section prefix = "44">
Stock broker exchange—investment service
</section>
<section prefix = "45">
Tax consultants
</section>
<section prefix = "46">
Telephone answering service
</section>
<section prefix = "47">
Theater ticket agencies
</section>
<section prefix = "48">
Travel agencies
</section>
<section prefix = "49">
Zoning consultants
</section>
<section prefix = "50">
Any use which is found by the Director to be a use similar to one (1) of the above numbered uses and, in his opinion, conforms to the intent of this section.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-223.2. Minimum lot width and area</catch_line>
<text>
Minimum lot width shall be one hundred (100) feet and the minimum lot area shall be ten thousand (10,000) square feet for multiple-family housing projects, listed office uses or mixed office and residential uses except that a lot with a minimum of fifty (50) [foot] frontage and five thousand (5,000) square feet in area, which is in a platted old subdivision, can be utilized for office use upon compliance with all other requirements of this district.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-223.3. Lot coverage; setback requirements; accessory buildings; type of building permitted</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Lot coverage. The maximum lot coverage for all structures on the site shall be forty (40) percent. The structures must comply with the following minimum setback requirements.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Principal building setbacks.
<section prefix = "1">
Minimum setback from front property line shall be twenty-five (25) feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Minimum setback from side property line abutting a highway right-of-way shall be fifteen (15) feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Minimum setback from interior side property line shall be fifteen (15) feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Minimum setback from rear property line shall be twenty-five (25) feet.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Accessory buildings. No accessory building shall be permitted.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Type of building permitted. The building(s) to be erected shall be without store fronts or display windows.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 60-8, § 1C—F, 2-9-60; Ord. No. 64-18, § 2, 5-5-64; Ord. No. 83-37, § 1, 6-7-83)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-223.4. Floor area ratios and height of buildings</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Floor area ratios. The floor area ratio shall not exceed the following; provided, however, that structure parking shall not count as part of the floor area, but shall be counted in computing building height:
One story: 0.40 FAR.
Two (2) stories: 0.60 FAR.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Heights. The maximum height of any structure shall be two (2) stories but not to exceed thirty-five (35) feet above finished grade.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 60-8, § 1G, H, 2-9-60; Ord. No. 64-18, § 2, 5-5-64; Ord. No. 83-37, § 1, 6-7-83)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-223.5. Other specific requirements</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Open space. On each lot there shall be provided an open space equal to a minimum of twenty-five (25) percent of the total lot area. Said open space shall be unencumbered with any structure or off-street parking and shall be landscaped and well maintained with grass, trees and shrubbery, excepting only areas used as pedestrian walks and water bodies; provided said water bodies shall not be credited for more than twenty (20) percent of the open space required (five (5) percent of the total lot area). Open space areas may also include tree preservation zones of "natural forest communities" as defined in Section 26B-1, Code of Miami-Dade County. Tree preservation zones shall be delineated on all plans submitted to Miami-Dade County for site plan review under Section 33-223.5.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, for the purposes of determining overall preservation area and percent of overall landscaped area. The requirements contained herein do not replace or substitute for any requirements contained within Chapter 18A, Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Maintenance. All landscaped areas shall be continuously maintained in a good, healthy vigorous condition and in general good appearance equivalent to Florida No. 1 requirements as provided in the State of Florida's "Grades and Standards for Nursery Plants," Part I, dated Revised Edition 1973, and Part II, dated Revised Edition 1975, respectively. Sprinkler systems of sufficient size and spacing shall be installed to serve and irrigate all landscaped areas, except within trees preservation zones of "natural forest communities" as defined in Section 26B-1, Code of Miami-Dade County. Tree preservation zones shall also be maintained in a healthy natural condition free from trash, debris and disturbance of understory vegetation.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Reserved.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Mixed uses. Depending on lot area available, it shall also be permissible for the occupant of an office to have an accompanying residential use in connection therewith.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Wall. A decorative wall of masonry, reinforced concrete, precast concrete, or wood fence or other like material that will be compatible with the main structure, five (5) feet in height, shall be erected along all interior property lines including the rear property line; provided, however, in the event that the rear property line abuts a secondary road, said wall shall be set in ten (10) feet from the official right-of-way of the secondary road and said ten-foot strip shall be landscaped; provided further, in the event that the interior side property line abuts property zoned RU-5, RU-5A, or a more liberal zoning district, the requirement for the wall along said common interior property line shall not apply.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Through lots. Where the building site is on a through lot, the structure shall front on the principal road, and if there is any question as to which of the two (2) roads is the principal road, the decision of the Zoning Director shall be adhered to.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Trees. Landscaping and trees shall be provided in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Accessory use. A snack bar for convenience and use of the occupants and patrons of an office development shall be permitted; said snack bar shall not exceed five hundred (500) square feet in size and shall be permitted with an office facility of at least twenty thousand (20,000) square feet. Said snack bar shall be completely enclosed in the building(s) and have no outside advertising or entrance.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 60-8, § 1, I—N, 2-9-60; Ord No. 64-18, § 2, 5-5-64; Ord. No. 66-67, § 1, 12-20-66; Ord. No. 83-37, § 1, 6-7-83; Ord. No. 85-59, § 1, 7-18-85; Ord. No. 85-85, § 1, 10-1-85; Ord. No. 95-223, § 1, 12-5-95)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-223.5.1. Site plan review</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Required; purpose. The Department shall, prior to issuance of any permits, review plans for compliance with zoning regulations and for compliance with the site plan review criteria. The purpose of the site plan review is to encourage logic, imagination, innovation and variety in the design process and ensure the congruity of the proposed development and its compatibility with the surrounding area. If requested approval is denied, proposed project may be appealed to the appropriate Community Zoning Appeals Board, in accordance with regulations as provided in Chapter 33 of the Code of Miami-Dade County governing appeals from administrative decisions.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Required exhibits. The following exhibits shall be prepared by design professionals such as architects and landscape architects and submitted to the Department:
<section prefix = "1">
Site plan, including the following information:
<section prefix = "a">
Lot lines and setbacks.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Location, shape, size and height of existing and proposed buildings, decorative walls and entrance features.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Landscaping and sprinkler systems in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Location of off-street parking and loading facilities and waste collection areas.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Indication of exterior graphics.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Indication of any design methods used to conserve energy.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Floor plans and elevations of all structures, including total gross quare foot area of each floor.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Figures indicating the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Gross and net acreage.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The total building coverage.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The proposed F.A.R. in square feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The total square feet of residential uses.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The total square feet of office uses.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Total square feet of snack bar facility if proposed.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Amount of landscaped open space in square feet required and provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Amount of building coverage at ground level in square feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Total trees required and provided in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Parking required and provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Total amount of paved area in square feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Indication of the design of exterior graphics and signage.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
Such other design data as may be needed to evaluate the project.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Plan review standards. The following criteria shall be utilized in the plan review process:
<section prefix = "1">
Planning studies. Design, planning studies or neighborhood area studies accepted or approved by the Board of County Commissioners that include development patterns or environmental design criteria which would apply to the development proposal under review shall be utilized in the plan review process.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Landscape. Landscape shall be preserved in its natural state insofar as is practicable by minimizing tree removal. Landscape shall be used to shade and cool, direct wind movements, enhance architectural features, relate structure design to site, visually screen noncompatible uses and block noise generated by the major roadways and intense-use areas.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Buffers. Buffering elements in the form of architectural design and landscape design that provide a logical transition to adjoining existing or permitted uses shall be provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Scale. Scale of proposed structures shall be compatible with surrounding proposed or existing uses or shall be made compatible by the use of buffering elements.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Circulation. Pedestrian and auto circulation shall be separated insofar as is practicable, and all circulation systems shall adequately serve the needs of the development and be compatible and functional with circulation systems outside the development.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Energy conservation. Design methods to reduce energy consumption shall be encouraged. Energy conservation methods may include, but not be limited to, natural ventilation of structures, siting of structures in relation to prevailing breezes and sun angles, insulation of structures, use of landscape materials for shade and transpiration, and orientation of breezes.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Parking areas. Building wall extensions, planting, berms or other innovative methods shall be used as a means of minimizing the adverse effect of the visual impact of parking areas. This requirement is in addition to the requirements of the landscape regulations of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Open space. Open space shall relate to any natural characteristics in such a way as to preserve and enhance their scenic and functional qualities to the fullest extent possible.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Subtropic architectural characteristics. Architecture and site development should incorporate consideration of the subtropical characteristics of the area. The provision of sun-control devices, shaded areas, vegetation, roof terraces and similar features characteristic of subtropical design shall be encouraged
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Outdoor furniture and graphics. All outdoor furniture and graphics shall be designed as an integral part of the overall design of the project.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Art display. Permanent interior and exterior art displays and water features should be encouraged in the overall design of the project.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Visual screening for decorative walls: In an effort to prevent graffiti vandalism, the following options shall be utilized for walls abutting zoned or dedicated rights-of-way:
<section prefix = "a">
Wall with landscaping. The wall shall be setback two and one-half (2½) feet from the right-of-way line and the resulting setback area shall contain a continuous extensively landscaped buffer which must be maintained in a good healthy condition by the property owner, or where applicable, by the condominium, homeowners or similar association. The landscape buffer shall contain one (1) or more of the following planting materials:
<section prefix = "1">
Shrubs. Shrubs shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Hedges. Hedges shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Vines. Climbing vines shall be a minimum of thirty-six (36) inches in height immediately after planting.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Metal picket fence. Where a metal picket fence abutting a zoned or dedicated right-of-way is constructed in lieu of a decorative wall, landscaping shall not be required.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 83-37, § 1, 6-7-83; Ord. No. 95-19, § 7, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 95-223, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-127, § 12, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 99-38, § 8, 4-27-99)</history>
</law>
