<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_LIX._MIAMI-DADE_COUNTY_HOMELESS_</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-751. Creation of the Miami-Dade County Homeless Trust</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created and established as an agency and instrumentality of Miami-Dade County a revocable trust which shall be named and known as the Miami-Dade County Homeless Trust (hereinafter referred to as "the trust"). The trust shall be a public body through which its governing body may exercise all those powers either specifically granted herein or necessary in the exercise of the powers herein enumerated.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-752. Governing body</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Membership; compensation. The governing body of the trust shall be a board of trustees composed of twenty-seven (27) voting members. Trustees shall serve without compensation but shall be entitled to reimbursement for necessary expenses incurred in the discharge of their duties.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Composition. The voting membership of the board of directors shall be ethnically, racially and gender balanced and shall be composed of the following members:
<section prefix = "1">
Seven (7) members representing the civic and business community which shall be selected by the Greater Miami Chamber of Commerce. After the initial terms of these seven (7) members, the trust may recommend that four (4) of the civic and business community positions include the following: one (1) representative of the downtown Miami business community; one (1) representative from the judicial sector; one (1) representative from the medical profession and one (1) representative of the neighborhood association in the area immediately impacted by the first homeless assistance center, or from the area most affected by homeless provider services;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
A member of the Miami-Dade County Public School Board or the Superintendent of Miami-Dade County Public Schools as determined by the School Board;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners Committee on Housing and the Homeless or, in the absence of such a committee or in the absence of any other committee overseeing homeless issues, the Board of County Commissioners;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Three (3) members of the Miami-Dade League of Cities selected by the Miami-Dade League of Cities, taking into consideration the cities most impacted by the homeless issue;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The City Manager of the City of Miami;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Two (2) formerly homeless persons selected by the Homeless/Formerly Homeless Persons Coalition or in the absence of such an organization, by the Homeless Providers' Forum.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Four (4) representatives of the Homeless Providers Forum selected by the Homeless Providers Forum;
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
One (1) representative of the academic or professional sector, selected by the Chair of the Housing and Homeless Committee of the Board of County Commissioners, or in the absence of such a committee or any other committee overseeing homeless issues, the Board of County Commissioners;
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
One (1) advocate, formerly homeless person, or provider, selected by the South Florida Interfaith Coalition for the Homeless;
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Three (3) members of the Greater Miami Religious Leaders Coalition selected by the Greater Miami Religious Leaders Coalition;
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
One (1) advocate for the homeless or one (1) formerly homeless person selected by the Homeless Providers Forum;
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
The President of the Miami Coalition for the Homeless; and
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
The District Administrator of the State of Florida Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services for the District encompassing Miami-Dade County.
Vacancies on the board of trustees shall be filled in the same manner by which the original trustees were appointed, with a special emphasis on choosing persons representative of the gender, racial and ethnic composition of the entire community.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Tenure and removal of trustees. All non-ex officio trustees shall serve staggered terms of three (3) years each; provided, however, of the original board of trustees, the trust shall select one-third (1/3) for a term of one (1) year and one-third (1/3) for a term of two (2) years. No trustee, with the exception of ex officio trustees, shall be permitted to serve more than two (2) consecutive and complete terms of three (3) years each unless so authorized by two-thirds (2/3) vote of the full membership of the Board of County Commissioners. Trustees may be removed in accordance with the provisions of Chapter 2-11.38 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Qualifications. Each member of the board of trustees must comply with the requirements of Chapter 2-11.38 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Organization and procedure.
<section prefix = "1">
Officers. The board of trustees shall organize after the members thereof have qualified to serve and shall elect one (1) of its members as chairperson and such other officers as the board of trustees may determine to be necessary. In addition, the board of trustees shall make, adopt and amend bylaws, rules and regulations for its own governance.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Meetings. The board of trustees shall hold regular meetings and such other meetings as it deems necessary. A majority of the members of the trust shall constitute a quorum. Minutes shall be kept of all meetings of the trust and all meetings shall be public.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Committees. The trust shall appoint any committees it deems necessary.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Applicability of County rules and procedures. The trust shall at all times operate under the Florida Open Government laws, including the "Sunshine Law," public meeting laws and public records laws and shall be governed by all State and County conflict of interest laws, as applicable, including the Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance, Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Voting requirements. Trustees may designate alternates to serve and/or vote on their behalf.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 94-66, § 2, 5-3-94)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-753. Powers and duties</catch_line>
<text>
The trust shall have the following powers, duties, functions and responsibilities:
<section prefix = "a">
To serve in an advisory capacity to the Board of County Commissioners with respect to all issues affecting or relating to persons who have become or are about to become homeless;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
To recommend to the Board of County Commissioners, in accordance with the Miami-Dade County Community Homeless Plan, an annual budget and plan for use of the Homeless Tax;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
To recommend to the Board of County Commissioners, in accordance with the Miami-Dade County Community Homeless Plan, the award of contracts and grants from funds generated by the Homeless Tax to organizations, entities, and agencies, including an independent 501(c)(3) corporation and relevant service providers. The Board of County Commissioners shall accept such recommendations unless rejected by an affirmative vote of a majority plus one additional vote of the Board of County Commissioners.
All requests for proposals for such contracts and grants shall be prepared at the direction of the trust and issued by the County Manager. In addition the County Manager shall collect and open such proposals, evaluate each proposal for responsiveness, rank all responsive proposals and make recommendations to the trust regarding the award of the contract or grant. In the event of a bid protest, the party protesting the bid award shall first appear before the trust. The trust shall consider the protest and make a recommendation to the Board of County Commissioners;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
To review the Miami-Dade County Community Homeless Plan on a regular basis and at least annually to assure that the plan continues to serve the needs of the total community and the homeless and to recommend any needed amendments, deletions or modifications to the Board of County Commissioners. The Board of County Commissioners shall only have the power to amend the plan based upon changed circumstances;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
To develop a community-wide consolidated funding plan to implement the Miami-Dade County Community Homeless Plan including the use of the following potential funding sources:
<section prefix = "1">
The annual proceeds of the Homeless Tax;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Funding from municipalities interested in supporting implementation of the Miami-Dade County Community Homeless Plan;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Community Development Block Grant funds;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Other federal grants;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
State grants;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Private contributions.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
To submit annually to the Board of County Commissioners a report summarizing and evaluating all programs and activities undertaken by the trust during the previous fiscal year. The report shall include an audit and accounting, in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, of all funds received and expended.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
To monitor, review and evaluate the homeless assistance services, activities and expenditures of Miami-Dade County and the municipalities within Miami-Dade County to determine compliance with state law.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
To recommend through an RFP process the award of a contract to an independent 501(c)(3) corporation which will raise private funds and carry out certain functions of the Miami-Dade County Community Homeless Plan including construction, operation, and siting of housing assistance centers and any other duties the trust may so determine.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
To cooperate and work with service providers in carrying out the Miami-Dade County Community Homeless Plan.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-754. Staff support</catch_line>
<text>
The board of trustees shall select, with the approval of the County Manager, the Executive Director of the Trust. The Clerk of the Board shall record all meetings of the trust and the County Manager shall provide to the trust adequate staff and support services to enable the trust to carry out its duties and responsibilities and shall continue to coordinate all homeless provider services and assist homeless providers in applying for grants and other available funds.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-755. Liberal construction to effectuate public purpose</catch_line>
<text>
This article, being for public purpose and for the welfare of the citizens of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall be liberally construed to effect the purposes hereof.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-756—2-760. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (78) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 94-66, adopted May 3, 1994, amended the Code by the addition of provisions which have been codified herein at the discretion of the editor as Art. LIX, §§ 2-751—2-755. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
