<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 14 FIRE PREVENTION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_II._FOREST_PROTECTION</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-21. Setting fires in forest protection district; permit</catch_line>
<text>
It is unlawful for any person to carelessly burn or cause to be burned or to set fire or cause fire to be set to, any forest, grass, woods, wild lands or marshes within a forest protection district, unless written permission shall have first been received from a duly appointed Fire Warden or other person authorized to issue such permits.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-22. Unlawful to burn land belonging to another</catch_line>
<text>
It is unlawful for any person to carelessly burn or cause to be burned, or to set fire to or cause fire to be set to, any forest, grass, woods, wild lands or marshes not owned or controlled by such person.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-23. Setting fires during emergency drought conditions</catch_line>
<text>
It is unlawful for any person to set fire to any forest, grass, woods, wild lands or marshes, or to build a campfire or bonfire or to burn trash or other material that may cause a forest, grass or woods fire, within the County, or area within the county, when because of emergency drought conditions, as defined in Section 590.08, Florida Statutes, there is extraordinary danger from fire, unless the setting of any backfire during the drought emergency is necessary to afford protection as determined by a representative of the Florida Board of Forestry, or unless it can be established that the setting of such backfire was necessary for the purpose of saving life or property. The burden of proving such shall rest on such person claiming same as a defense.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-24. Setting fires on rights-of-way</catch_line>
<text>
It is unlawful for any person to set or cause to be set carelessly a fire within the confines of the right-of-way of any public road, State road, railroad, or in any other place and allow it to escape onto and burn over any adjoining land.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-25. Disposing of cigarettes, cigars, ashes</catch_line>
<text>
It is unlawful for any person to throw or drop from an automobile or vehicle, or otherwise, a lighted match, cigarette, cigar, ashes, or other flaming or glowing substance, or any substance or thing which may or does cause a forest, grass, or woods fire.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-26. Camp fires</catch_line>
<text>
It is unlawful for any individual or group of individuals to build a warming or camp fire and leave same unextinguished.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-27. Procedure to lawfully burn land</catch_line>
<text>
It is unlawful for any person carelessly to burn or cause to be burned, or to set fire to or cause fire to be set to, any forest, grass, woods, wild lands or marshes owned or controlled by such person without first giving notice to all resident owners, managers or tenants of lands adjoining and surrounding the area to be burned, said notice to be given in the presence of at least one (1) witness or in writing, not less than one (1) nor more than ten (10) days prior to such burning; or to fail to take reasonable precaution against the spreading of fire to other lands by providing adequate fire lines, man-power and fire fighting equipment for the control of such fire, or to watch over said fire until it is extinguished, or to permit fire to escape to adjoining lands; provided, however, that no notice shall be required to be given of the setting of fire in a forest protection district where written permission to set such fire has been obtained from a duly appointed Fire Warden.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-28. Penalty for violations</catch_line>
<text>
Whoever carelessly violates any of the provisions of this article, shall, upon conviction thereof, be deemed guilty of an offense and shall be punished by a fine of not more than two hundred dollars ($200.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for a term not exceeding sixty (60) days, or by both such fine and imprisonment in the discretion of the court, and the penalties herein provided shall extend to both the actual violator and to the person or persons, firm or corporation causing, directing or permitting such violation.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-29. Burden of proof</catch_line>
<text>
In any prosecution brought under the provisions of this article it shall not be necessary for the State or plaintiff to allege and prove absence of the right or authority of the defendant to set or cause to be set fire, but such right and authority shall be a matter of affirmative defense to be alleged and proved by the defendant.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-30. Forestry or fire control signs, penalty for mutilating or destroying</catch_line>
<text>
Whoever intentionally breaks down, mutilates, removes or destroys any fire control or forestry sign or poster of the State Board of Forestry erected in the administration of its lawful duties and authorities shall be guilty of an offense and shall be subject to imprisonment not exceeding sixty (60) days, by fine not exceeding two hundred dollars ($200.00), or by both such fine and imprisonment.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-31. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 87-89, § 2, adopted Dec. 15, 1987, repealed § 14-31, relative to the prosecution of article violations in metropolitan court, which derived from Ord. No. 66-24, § 11, adopted June 7, 1966.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-32. Article provisions declared supplemental</catch_line>
<text>
The provisions of this article are not intended and shall not be construed as superseding or conflicting with any statutory provisions relating to, or rules and regulations promulgated by the Florida Board of Forestry, but shall be construed as implementing and assisting the enforcement thereof.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 14-33—14-39. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (2) ---
State Law reference— Forest protection, F.S. Ch. 590. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
