<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXVII._Miami-Dade_County_TOURIST</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-248. Statement of intent</catch_line>
<text>
It is the intent of the Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners to consider the enactment of an ordinance levying and imposing a tourist development tax, as authorized by Chapter 77-209, Laws of Florida, known as the "Local Option Tourist Development Act". The ordinance is intended to be effective throughout Miami-Dade County, except for the municipal areas of Bal Harbour, Miami Beach and Surfside.
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 78-62, adopted Oct. 4, 1978, and approved at referendum on Nov. 7, 1978, provides for the levy and imposition of the tourist development tax authorized pursuant to Ch. 77-209, Laws of Fla. Provisions of Ord. No. 78-62 are codified herein at § 29-51 et seq.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-249. Miami-Dade County Tourist Development Council created; purposes and powers</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created and established in Miami-Dade County, Florida, a nine-member advisory Board to be known as the Miami-Dade County Tourist Development Council (hereinafter referred to as the "Council") for the purposes and with the powers conferred by the enabling act, Chapter 77-209, Laws of Florida. As part of its purpose and power, the council shall prepare and submit a plan for tourist development to the Board of County Commissioners for its consideration.
</text>
<EditorsNote>
A Miami-Dade County Tourist Development Council Plan was adopted pursuant to Ord. No. 78-62, § 4, adopted Oct. 4, 1978, and approved at referendum on Nov. 7, 1978. Copies of the Miami-Dade County Tourist Development Council Plan may be found on file in the Office of the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners.


Annotation—CAO 79-3.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-250. Appointment of members; qualifications for membership; terms of membership</catch_line>
<text>
The Board of County Commissioners shall, by resolution, appoint the members of the Council. The Mayor of Miami-Dade County shall be the Chairman of the Council. Two (2) members of the Council shall be elected municipal officials. Three (3) members of the Council shall be owners or operators of motels, hotels, or other tourist accommodations in the County and subject to the tax. Three (3) members of the Council shall be persons who are involved in the tourist industry and who have demonstrated an interest in tourist development, but who are not owners or operators of motels, hotels or other tourist accommodations in the County and subject to the tax. All members of the Council shall be electors of the County. Members shall serve staggered terms of four (4) years as determined in the appointing resolution.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-251. Organization of the Council; voting, quorum; conduct of meetings</catch_line>
<text>
The Chairperson of the Council shall be the Mayor of Miami-Dade County. The members of the Council, by majority vote, shall select any other officer as may be deemed necessary or desirable. Any other such officer shall serve at the will of the Council. A majority vote of the entire membership of the Council shall be necessary to take any action. A majority of the members of the Council shall constitute a quorum necessary to hold a meeting or take any action. The Chairperson may call meetings of the Council, and meetings may be called by written notice signed by five (5) members of the Council, and the Council at any meeting may fix and call a meeting for a future date. Minutes shall be kept of all meetings of the Council. All meetings shall be public. The County Manager shall provide adequate and competent clerical and administrative personnel as may be reasonably required by the Council for the proper performance as may be reasonably required by the Council for the proper performance of its duties and functions, subject to budget limitations as fixed by the County Commission.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-252. Compensation of members</catch_line>
<text>
Members of the Miami-Dade County Tourist Development Council shall serve without compensation, salary or remuneration of any nature, but the County Commission may provide in the annual County budget sufficient funds for the reasonable and necessary expenses incurred by the Council in performance of its duties and functions.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-253. Removal of members</catch_line>
<text>
Any member of the Council who ceases to be a qualified elector of Miami-Dade County shall immediately forfeit his or her office. Should a vacancy result from such forfeiture, or should any member of this Council fail to attend three (3) consecutive meetings of the Council without due cause, the Chairperson of the Council shall certify the same to the County Commission, which shall fill the vacancy created thereby by appointment. Any member of the Council may be removed from office without cause by a majority of the entire membership of the County Commission.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-253.1. Liberal construction to effectuate public purpose</catch_line>
<text>
This article, being for a public purpose and for the welfare of the citizens of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall be liberally construed to effect the purposes hereof.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (48) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 78-28, §§ 1—7, adopted April 4, 1978, did not expressly amend this Code; hence inclusion herein as Art. XXVII of Ch. 2, §§ 2-248—2-253.1, is at the discretion of the editor. (Back)
Annotation—CAO 82-18. (Back)
Cross reference— Tourist development room tax, § 29-51 et seq. (Back)
State Law reference— Tourist development council, F.S. § 125.0104(4)(c). (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
