<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_CXXXV._PERFORMANCE_AND_EFFICIENC</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2065. Creation; Powers and Duties</catch_line>
<text>
The Miami-Dade County Performance and Efficiency Commission is hereby created. The duties of the Miami-Dade Performance and Efficiency Commission shall be to:
<section prefix = "a">
Provide and obtain private and public sector input on the performance and efficiency of the operations of Miami-Dade County and prioritize recommended improvements;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Recommend cost-effectiveness measures and best business/management practices which will realize savings and improve service delivery, including, but not limited to, identifying opportunities for increased competition and efficiency, reorganizations, appropriate incentives such as performance pay and other gain sharing approaches, innovations in the building and permitting processes; and public-private price and performance competition projects which can be undertaken with county workers to ensure the highest potential value of services provided;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Recommend ways to explore and promote technology improvements as a means of achieving optimal operational effectiveness, as well as recommend ethics management and accountability measures for Miami-Dade County government;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Recommend management systems development, conduct project reviews and studies and participative management and employee recognition programs, public relations, and training and development programs;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Review the County's Strategic Plan and other administrative mechanisms to implement the County's Strategic Plan in order to accomplish the aims of this resolution; and
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Monitor the implementation of recommended changes.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2066. Membership Requirements; Appointment of Members</catch_line>
<text>
The Performance and Efficiency Commission shall consist of nineteen (19) members, who shall be residents of Miami-Dade County and shall own or operate businesses in Miami-Dade County or are employed in Miami-Dade County. The Board of the Performance and Efficiency Commission shall consist of the following appointees:
<section prefix = "a">
Six members appointed under the business category, who shall be appointed by the:
<section prefix = "1">
Greater Miami Chamber of Commerce;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Miami-Dade Chamber of Commerce;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Latin Chamber of Commerce of the United States (CAMACOL);
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Three persons appointed by the Board of County Commissioners;
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Five members appointed under the labor category, who shall be appointed by the:
<section prefix = "1">
AFSCME International;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Dade County Police Benevolent Association (PBA);
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
International Association of Firefighters, Local 1403;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Government Supervisors Association of Florida;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Services Employees International Union (SEIU) — Nurses at Jackson Memorial Hospital;
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Four members appointed under the education category, who shall be appointed by the:
<section prefix = "1">
Florida International University;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The University of Miami;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Miami-Dade College;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Florida Memorial University;
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Two Miami-Dade County Commissioners chosen by the Chairman of the Board of County Commissioners;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
One Miami-Dade County Commissioner chosen by the Chair of the Board of County Commissioners, who shall serve as the chair of the Performance and Efficiency Commission; and
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
One member chosen by the Mayor of Miami-Dade County.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2067. Officers</catch_line>
<text>
The Chairman of the Board of County Commissioners shall appoint the Chairperson and the Vice-Chairperson of the Performance and Efficiency Commission by memorandum to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2068. Reporting</catch_line>
<text>
The Performance and Efficiency Commission shall submit quarterly reports on the status of the assignments given pursuant to this resolution.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2069. Staff Support</catch_line>
<text>
The Office of the Commission Auditor shall provide primary staff support to the Performance and Efficiency Commission and its committees, including performing tasks as are assigned to such office, providing requested information, developing reports and assisting the Performance and Efficiency Commission in drafting the quarterly reports required by this ordinance. The Mayor or his designee shall also provide staff support, information and reports for the Performance and Efficiency Commission to the extent requested by the Performance and Efficiency Commission and its committees and shall promptly provide the Office of the Commission Auditor requested information and access to records and personnel needed by the Commission Auditor to carry out the responsibilities of this Section.
</text>
</law>
