<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_IV._COMBAT_AUTOMOBILE_THEFT_PROG</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-501. Established</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby established a "Combat Automobile Theft" program in Miami-Dade County which shall be administered by the Miami-Dade Police Department; in accordance with Florida Statutes, Section 316.008(6). Owners of motor vehicles wishing to participate shall enroll their vehicles with the Department and sign consent forms prescribed by the Department. The Department shall issue bright yellow decals to be displayed on the vehicle indicating its enrollment in the program.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-502. Authorization to stop vehicle during certain hours</catch_line>
<text>
A consent form signed by a motor vehicle owner shall constitute authorization for a law enforcement officer to stop the vehicle when it is being driven between the hours of 1:00 a.m. and 5:00 a.m., provided that the yellow decal is conspicuously affixed to the bottom left of the back window of the vehicle to provide notice of its enrollment in the program and of the owner's execution of the consent form.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-503. Removal of decal when terminating participation in program</catch_line>
<text>
The owner of the motor vehicle is responsible for removing the decal when terminating participation in the program, or when selling or otherwise transferring ownership of the vehicle.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-504. Civil liability</catch_line>
<text>
No civil liability shall arise from the actions of a law enforcement officer when stopping a vehicle with a yellow decal evidencing enrollment in the program provided that the stop is made in accordance with the requirements of the "Combat Automobile Theft" program.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-505. Implementation</catch_line>
<text>
This program shall be implemented upon issuance of written program materials and procedures by the Director of the Miami-Dade Police Department.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-506. Validity</catch_line>
<text>
If any section, subsection, sentence, clause, or provision of this article is held invalid, the remainder of this article shall not be affected by such invalidity.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (5) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 91-118, adopted Sept. 1, 1991, amended the Code by the addition of provisions which have been designated at the discretion of the editor as Art. IV, §§ 30-501—30-506. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
