<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXIII._COMMUNITY_RELATIONS_BOARD</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-204. Creation of Board</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created and established in Miami-Dade County an advisory Board to be known as the Miami-Dade County Community Relations Board.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-205. Membership; qualifications; terms</catch_line>
<text>
This Board shall consist of thirty (30) voting members. The membership of the Board shall be broadly representative of the various social, racial, religious, linguistic, cultural, economic, national origin and geographic groups comprising the population of this County. Each member shall be a resident of Miami-Dade County with an outstanding reputation for community pride, interest, integrity, responsibility, and business or professional ability and a documented commitment to intergroup relations.
Each Commissioner shall appoint a member to the Community Relations Board who is duly qualified under this ordinance and the criteria provided by a special nominating committee. The special nominating committee shall consist of: the Mayor or his designee, as chair; the County Manager; one person appointed by the Board of County Commissioners; and six past chairs of the Community Relations Board appointed by the Mayor. The special nominating committee will appoint thirteen duly qualified at-large members assuring diverse representation from among gender, ethnic and national origin groups. Four additional members shall serve by virtue of their election as chairpersons by the respective community advisory boards which are: Black Affairs Advisory Board, Hispanic Affairs Advisory Board, Asian-American Advisory Board and the Commission for Women. The advisory board chairpersons shall serve as voting members of the CRB during the period each holds that elected position. The remaining twenty-six (26) members of the Community Relations Board shall be appointed for an initial one year term.
Thereafter, the Community Relations Board shall consist of thirteen duly qualified members appointed by each Commissioner thirteen at-large members appointed by an ad hoc nominating committee designated by the CRB and four members elected as chairpersons by the community advisory boards.
After one year, the twenty-six appointed members will serve staggered terms chosen by lottery as follows: nine (9) members shall be appointed for terms expiring on the second anniversary of their appointment, nine (9) members shall be appointed for terms expiring on the third anniversary of their appointment, and eight (8) members shall be appointed for terms expiring on the fourth anniversary of their appointment. Subsequent appointments shall be for terms of three (3) years except that appointments to fill any vacancy shall be for the remainder of the unexpired term. Former chairpersons of the Board, who are not current members of the Board shall serve as ex officio members of the Board but shall not be entitled to vote on any matter before the Board and shall not be required to attend meetings of the Board. Members shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for necessary expenses incurred in official duties, as may be determined and approved by the County Manager. The members of the Community Relations Board at the time of the passage of this ordinance shall continue to serve until such time as the reorganized Board is convened. The reorganized Community Relations Board shall be convened by the Mayor and Board of County Commissioners within 90 days of the passage of this ordinance. The Mayor shall serve as the convening chairperson until such time as the newly constituted Board shall select an executive committee.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-206. Organization; quorum; voting; rules of procedure; records of meetings</catch_line>
<text>
The members of the Board shall select and designate from its members a Chairperson, Vice-Chairperson, Secretary, and such other officers as may be deemed necessary, who shall serve at the pleasure of the Board. Fifteen (15) members of the Board shall constitute a quorum, not withstanding Chapter 2-11.39.1. No action shall be taken except by a majority vote of those present at a duly constituted meeting of the Board; provided, however, an executive committee consisting of all officers and such other persons as the Chairperson may appoint from time to time is authorized to exercise all powers, duties and functions of the Board between Board meetings, any such action to be reported to the Board at its next meeting and the Board shall either ratify or rescind the action of the executive committee. The Board may adopt rules of procedure governing its meetings and actions on matters within its jurisdiction, not inconsistent with the provisions of this article, which rules of procedure shall be filed with the Clerk of the County Commission. Copies of the minutes of all Board meetings shall be furnished to the Chairperson of the County Commission and the County Manager.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-207. Supervision and Support</catch_line>
<text>
The Office of the Chairperson of the County Commission shall provide appropriate support for the Community Relations Board. The Chairperson of the County Commission shall have the power to appoint, employ, remove and supervise such assistants, employees, and personnel as deemed necessary to provide appropriate support to the Community Relations Board, and such assistants, employees, and personnel shall serve at the will of the Chairperson of the County Commission.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-208. Duties and functions</catch_line>
<text>
The primary mission of the Community Relations Board is to intervene and contain, as quickly as possible, community tensions.
The secondary mission of the Community Relations Board is to: work proactively to identify and relieve intergroup conflicts before crisis arise; to develop bridges of understanding, communication, and mutual respect; to develop and support local or city based Community Relations Boards throughout the County; and to assure that resources are in place to respond to community crisis.
The functions of the Board shall be:
<section prefix = "a">
To foster mutual understanding, tolerance, and respect among all economic, social, religious and ethnic groups in the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
To make studies in the field of human relations. The Board is vested with the power and authority and charged with the duty and responsibility.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
To attempt to act as conciliator in controversies involving community relations.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
To cooperate with federal, State and City agencies in developing harmonious community relations.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
To cooperate in the development of educational programs dedicated to the improvement of community relations with, and to enlist the support of, civic leaders; civic, religious, veterans, labor, industrial, commercial and eleemosynary groups; and private agencies engaged in the inculcation of ideals of tolerance, mutual respect and understanding.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
To serve as a quasi-autonomous body authorized to act independently to pursue strategies for the promotion of intergroup relations and to recommend to the Mayor, the Board of County Commissioners, and the County Manager such resolutions, ordinances and other causes of action as will aid in carrying out the purposes of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
To submit an annual report to the Mayor, the Board of County Commissioners and the County Manager.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
To accept grants and donations on behalf of the County from foundations and others for the purpose of carrying out the above listed functions, subject to approval by the County Commission.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-209. Limitation of powers</catch_line>
<text>
The powers and jurisdiction of the Board shall be purely advisory, voluntary and persuasive. The Board shall not have any power or authority to subpoena or compel the attendance of witnesses.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-210—2-214. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (40) ---
Editor's note— This article is derived from Ord. No. 63-22, adopted on June 11, 1963. The general repealer has been omitted and the sections renumbered to include the ordinance in this Code. (Back)
Annotation—CAO 76-53. (Back)
Cross reference— Discrimination, Ch. 11A. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
