<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXI._GREEN_BUSINESS_CERTIFICATIO</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-417. Creation of Green Business Certification Program</catch_line>
<text>
The Miami-Dade County Office of Sustainability is hereby authorized to create a Miami-Dade County Green Business Certification Program (Program) for the purpose of encouraging and recognizing businesses that conserve natural resources, such as water, electricity and fuel; reduce, reuse and recycle materials; reduce the use of hazardous materials and generation of hazardous waste; and take affirmative steps to prevent pollution.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-418. Standards and Criteria for Certification</catch_line>
<text>
The Green Business Certification Program shall be voluntary and target the various business sectors operating in the county; including, but not limited to, restaurants, garment cleaning, dental practices and retail offices.
In developing program standards and criteria for the various business sectors, the Office of Sustainability shall consult with the Department of Environmental Resources Management, the Department of Solid Waste Management, the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, and the Office of Economic Development and International Trade, and may consult with other relevant federal, state, regional and local agencies and departments, as well as consider industry best management practices and the feedback from interested stakeholders. In addition to program standards and criteria, a business must be in compliance with all applicable permits, licenses and regulations in order to qualify for certification as a Green Business.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-419. Application and Evaluation Process</catch_line>
<text>
Certification as a Green Business will require a business to submit an application involving an initial self-audit to assess compliance with required and recommended certification practices established for that business sector. These certification practices shall address waste reduction, energy conservation, water conservation, pollution prevention, transportation, communication and education, and carbon footprint savings, as applicable. The Program shall provide reference guides to assist businesses in the performance of self-audits.
After receipt of an application with a completed self-audit, the Program team shall conduct an onsite assessment to confirm the accuracy of the self-audit, which may include requests for the business to provide supporting documentation. A business will only be certified as a Green Business if it is in compliance with all required practices, meets the minimum thresholds and standards of the Green Business Certification Program, and is in compliance with all applicable local, state and federal regulations. In addition, a certified business will also receive a total scoring based upon the number of required and recommended practices it satisfies.
</text>
</law>
