<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_LIV._MIAMI-DADE_COUNTY_PRIVATE_A</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-621. Created; purposes</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created and established the Miami-Dade County Private Ambulance Service Study Committee. The committee is created for the specific purpose of establishing criteria for the determination of when there is a need for additional private ambulance service in Miami-Dade County and reviewing Chapter 4, Articles I and II of the Code of Miami-Dade County relating to private ambulance service (the "ordinance"); such criteria for determination of the need for private ambulance service shall include a minimum requirement "calls-to-car-ratio" of no less than 6.0, as provided in Resolution No. R-1302-90.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-622. Composition; terms</catch_line>
<text>
Committee members shall be appointed by the County Manager, as provided in Resolution No. R-1302-90 to include representatives of the private ambulance industry, the chief of the Miami-Dade County Fire Department and the Director of the Consumer Services Department of Miami-Dade County or their designees.
Committee members shall serve without compensation. The County Manager shall appoint a chairperson. The members serving on the committee pursuant to Resolution No. R-1302-90 and appointment by the County Manager shall continue to serve until the committee is dissolved pursuant to Section 2-625 or until a successor is duly appointed.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-623. Meetings</catch_line>
<text>
The committee is further authorized to meet as often as it deems appropriate. All committee meetings shall comply with the "government in the sunshine" requirements of Chapter 286, Florida Statutes, and all materials received or generated by the committee in carrying out its responsibilities are "public records" pursuant to Chapter 119, Florida Statutes.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-624. Staff</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager, County Attorney and Clerk of the County Commission shall provide appropriate staff support to such committee.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-625. Reports</catch_line>
<text>
The committee shall present quarterly progress report to the Public Safety and Community Services Committee and a written report thereon to the Board of County Commissioners, no later than March 1, 1994. The Commission shall review the final report of the committee and the ordinance. Upon submission of its report, the committee shall be dissolved.
</text>
</law>
