<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_II._COMMUNICATIONS_SERVICES_REGU</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-100. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Communications Facility or Facility or System shall mean any permanent or temporary plant, equipment and property, including but not limited to cables, wires, conduits, ducts, fiber optics, poles, antennae, converters, splice boxes, cabinets, hand holes, manholes, vaults, drains, surface location markers, appurtenances, and other equipment or pathway placed or maintained or to be placed or maintained in the Public Rights-of-Way of the County and used or capable of being used to transmit, convey, route, receive, distribute, provide or offer Communications Services.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Communications Services shall mean the transmission, conveyance or routing of voice, data, audio, video, or any other information or signals to a point, or between or among points, by or through any electronic, radio, satellite, cable, optical, microwave, or other medium or method now in existence or hereafter devised, regardless of the protocol used for such transmission or conveyance. Notwithstanding the foregoing, for purposes of this chapter "cable service", as defined in Section 202.11(2), Florida Statutes (2000), as it may be amended, is not included in the definition of "Communications Services," and cable service providers shall be subject to Article I of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Communications Service Provider shall mean any Person including a municipality or county providing Communications Services through the placement or maintenance of a Communications Facility in Public Rights-of-Way. "Communications Services Provider" shall also include any Person that places or maintains a Communications Facility in Public Rights-of-Way but does not provide Communications Services.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Consumer Services Department means the Consumer Services Department of Miami-Dade County or such other department or officer assigned by the County to administer registrations issued pursuant to this Article.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Director shall be the Director of the Consumer Services Department or his or her designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
In Public Rights-of-Way or in the Public Rights-of-Way shall mean in, on, over, under or across the Public Rights-of-Way.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Reserved.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Person shall include any individual, children, firm, association, joint venture, partnership, estate, trust, business trust, syndicate, fiduciary, corporation, organization or legal entity of any kind, successor, assignee, transferee, personal representative, and all other groups or combinations.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Place or Maintain or Placement or Maintenance or Placing or Maintaining shall mean to erect, construct, install, maintain, place, repair, extend, expand, remove, occupy, locate or relocate. A Communications Services Provider that owns or exercises physical control over Communications Facilities in Public Rights-of-Way, such as the physical control to maintain and repair, is "placing or maintaining" the Facilities.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Permit shall mean a construction permit issued by the Public Works Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Public Rights-of-Way shall mean a public right-of-way, public utility easement, highway, street, bridge, tunnel or alley for which the County is the authority that has jurisdiction and control and may lawfully grant access to and issue permits pursuant to applicable law, and includes the surface, the air space over the surface and the area below the surface. "Public Rights-of-Way" shall not include private property. "Public Rights-of-Way" shall not include any real or personal County property except as described above and shall not include County buildings, fixtures, poles, conduits, facilities or other structures or improvements, regardless of whether they are situated in the Public Rights-of-Way.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Registrant shall mean a Communications Services Provider that has registered with the Director in accordance with the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
Registration or Register shall mean the process described in this chapter whereby a Communications Services Provider provides the required information to the Director.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-167, § 1, 12-16-99; Ord. No. 01-109, § 4, 6-19-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-101. Registration required</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
A Registration from Miami-Dade County is required to commence or engage in the construction, maintenance of, or occupation of the public right-of-way with, a system designed to deliver Communications Services by utilizing the public rights-of-way. No public rights-of-way construction permits shall be issued to a Communications Service Provider without a registration issued under this Chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A Registration shall not convey any title, equitable or legal, to the Registrant in the Public Rights-of-Way. Registration under this chapter governs only the placement or maintenance of Communications Facilities in Public Rights-of-Way. Other ordinances, codes or regulations may apply to the placement or maintenance in the Public Rights-of-Way of facilities that are not Communications Facilities. Registration does not excuse a Communications Services Provider from obtaining appropriate access or pole attachment agreements before locating its Facilities on the County's or another Person's facilities. Registration does not excuse a Communications Services Provider from complying with all applicable County ordinances, codes or regulations, including this chapter.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-167, § 1, 12-16-99; Ord. No. 01-109, § 4, 6-19-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-102. Rights granted by Registration</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Subject to all existing permitting processes, the Registrant is authorized to occupy, install, lay, erect, construct, remove, relocate and maintain in, on, over or upon any and all of the public right-of-ways, as they now exist or may be hereafter constructed, opened, laid out or extended within the present limits of the County, or in such territory as may be hereafter added to, consolidated or annexed to unincorporated Miami-Dade County, any and all such conduits, cables, fiber optic lines, poles, wires, supports and other structures and appurtenances as may be reasonably necessary for the construction, maintenance and operation of a Communications System. Except as provided above, this Registration does not convey the right to attach cable or conduit to poles, or occupy or use real or personal property owned by Miami-Dade County, including, but not limited to, the Metrorail and Metromover system.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Any Registration granted under this article shall be non-exclusive, and the issuance of a Registration will not expressly or implicitly preclude the County from issuance of other Registrations to Communications Services Providers or affect the County's right to authorize use of public rights-of-way for other lawful purposes to other persons as it determines appropriate.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
This Registration authorizes the Registrant to use the public rights-of-way to provide Communications Services only. Use of the public rights-of-way for any other purpose requires separate authorization.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-167, § 1, 12-16-99; Ord. No. 01-109, § 4, 6-19-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-103. Term and renewal</catch_line>
<text>
A Registrant shall renew its Registration with the Director by April 1 of even numbered years in accordance with the Registration requirements in this chapter, except that a Registrant that initially registers during the even numbered year when renewal would be due or the odd numbered year immediately preceding such even numbered year shall not be required to renew until the next even numbered year. Within thirty (30) days of any change in the information required to be submitted pursuant to Section 8AA-107 a Registrant shall provide updated information to the Director including, on a street map provided by Miami-Dade County, the routes of a Registrant's system built after the effective date of this chapter. If no information in the then-existing Registration has changed, the renewal may state that no information has changed. Failure to renew a Registration may result in the Director restricting the issuance of additional permits until the Communications Services Provider has complied with the Registration requirements of this chapter.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-104. Communications Services Tax</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Each Registrant that provides Communications Services shall collect and remit to the Florida Department of Revenue the Communications Services Tax pursuant to chapter 202, Florida Statutes and Chapter 29 Article IV-A of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
In the event that state law is amended to allow collection of license fees from Communications Services Providers, or in the event that state law preempting the collection of such license fee is declare void by a court of competent jurisdiction, the provisions contained in this section shall automatically revert to those provisions contained in this section in effect on the date of adoption of this chapter to the extent those provisions are not inconsistent with state law.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-167, § 1, 12-16-99; Ord. No. 01-109, § 4, 6-19-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-104.1 Communications Services Providers not providing communications services directly to the public</catch_line>
<text>
Registrants that place or maintain a Communications Facility in the Public Rights-of-Way but do not provide Communications Services directly to the public shall pay to the County a fee of fifty (50) cents annually per linear foot of metallic cable, fiber optic cable, or other pathway that makes physical use of the Right-of-Way. This fee shall be due annually on February 10th of each year.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-105. Audits; inspection of records</catch_line>
<text>
All amounts paid under section 8AA-104.1 shall be subject to audit and recomputation by the County. Upon reasonable notice, the Registrant shall make available to the County once per year, during normal business hours and at the Registrant's local office, the books, records and accounts and other documentation of the Registrant (hereinafter collectively referred to as the "Reports") that are necessary to determine the accuracy of the calculations upon which the license fee payment is based. The Registrant shall maintain its records in such a manner as to clearly distinguish between linear foot calculations derived from operations in unincorporated Miami-Dade County and such linear foot calculations derived from operations in the municipalities and other jurisdictions. Miami-Dade County may waive this requirement with any particular Registrant if an agreement is reached that other methods will be utilized such as audit sampling techniques which can clearly isolate revenues and/or linear foot calculations to which the County is entitled. In the event the Reports are not made available within Miami-Dade County, the Registrant shall reimburse the County for the reasonable travel expense of the County's representative resulting from said representative's travel to the location where the Reports are maintained. The County shall maintain all books, records, accounts and other documentation of Registrant in strictest confidence to the extent allowed under the Public Records Act and other applicable Florida laws.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-105.1. Audits of amounts due prior to October 1, 2000</catch_line>
<text>
The County shall have the right and authority to inspect a Communications Services Provider's books and records and the right of audit and recomputation of any and all amounts due, under a License agreement, to the County prior to October 1, 2001. Unless otherwise agreed by the County all costs associated with any such audit shall be borne by the licensee when said audit results in increasing, by more than five (5) percent, the licensee's annual payment to the County. Upon reasonable notice, such records necessary to perform said audit and recomputation shall be made available to the County at the licensee's Miami-Dade County office.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-106. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 01-109, § 3, adopted June 19, 2001, repealed section 8AA-106 in its entirety. Former section 8AA-106 pertained to annual reports and derived from Ord. No. 99-167, § 1, adopted Dec. 16, 1999.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-107. Registration application procedure; information required</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
To obtain a Registration under this Article a person shall apply to the Director. To be acceptable for filing, an original and two (2) copies of the application must be submitted.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Each application for registration, renewal registration, and duplicate registration shall be on a form prescribed by the Director. Each application for an initial Registration shall set forth the following:
<section prefix = "1">
The name, address and telephone number of the applicant.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The name, address and telephone number of the applicant's primary contact person in connection with the Registration, and the person to contact in case of an emergency.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Identification of the applicant's fiscal year calendar.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
A description of the general nature and size of the proposed communication system's plant and equipment that Registrant intends to have occupy the public rights-of-way, including a list with descriptions of the appurtenances such as manholes, pedestals, handholes, controlled environmental vaults, etc.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
A copy of Federal and/or State certification authorizing the applicant to provide communications services.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
A copy of any administrative or legal decision in which the applicant was determined to have violated a law or regulation governing the use of the public rights-of-way.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Within thirty (30) calendar days after the awarding of the Registration, the Registrant shall file with the Director its written acceptance of the Registration, together with the insurance policy and bonding documents required by this article, and its agreement to be bound by and to comply with all requirements pursuant to the provisions of this article and the Registration.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
A Registrant may cancel a Registration upon written notice to the Director stating that it will no longer place or maintain any Communications Facilities in Public Rights-of-Way within the and will no longer need to obtain permits to perform work in Public Rights-of-Way. A Registrant shall not cancel a Registration if the Registrant continues to place or maintain any Communications Facilities in Public Rights-of-Way.
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
Registration does not in and of itself establish a right to place or maintain or priority for the placement or maintenance of a Communications Facility in Public Rights-of-Way within the County but shall establish for the Registrant a right to apply for a permit. Registrations are expressly subject to any future amendment to or replacement of this chapter and further subject to any additional County ordinances, as well as any State or Federal laws that may be enacted. In accordance with applicable County ordinances, codes or regulations, a permit may be required of a Communications Services Provider that desires to place or maintain a Communications Facility in Public Rights-of-Way. A Registration shall be a condition of obtaining a permit. Notwithstanding a Registration, permitting requirements shall apply. A permit may be obtained by or on behalf of a Registrant having a Registration if all permitting requirements are met.
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
A Communications Services Provider with an existing Communications Facility in the Public Rights-of-Way of the County has sixty (60) days from the effective date of this chapter to comply with the terms of this chapter, including, but not limited to, Registration, or be in violation thereof.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-167, § 1, 12-16-99; Ord. No. 01-109, § 4, 6-19-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-108. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 01-109, § 3, adopted June 19, 2001, repealed section 8AA-108 in its entirety. Former section 8AA-108 pertained to application fee and derived from Ord. No. 99-167, § 1, adopted Dec. 16, 1999.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-109. Issuance of registration</catch_line>
<text>
The Director has the authority to and shall grant a Registration to an applicant who files a completed application and complies with the application requirements herein; provided however, the Director shall have the authority to deny a Registration if the applicant fails to meet the application requirements or the proposed use of the public rights-of-way presents a danger to the general public and other users of the public rights-of-way.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-110. Notice of Transfers, Sales or Assignments of Assets in Public Rights-of-Way</catch_line>
<text>
If a Registrant transfers, sells or assigns its assets located in Public Rights-of-Way incident to a transfer, sale or assignment of the Registrant's assets, the transferee, buyer or assignee shall be obligated to comply with the terms of this chapter. Written notice of any such transfer, sale or assignment shall be provided by such Registrant to the Director within twenty (20) days after the effective date of the transfer, sale or assignment. If the transferee, buyer or assignee is a current Registrant, then the transferee, buyer or assignee is not required to re-Register. If the transferee, buyer or assignee is not a current Registrant, then the transferee, buyer or assignee shall Register as provided in Section 8AA-107 within sixty (60) days of the transfer, sale or assignment. If permit applications are pending in the Registrant's name, the transferee, buyer or assignee shall notify the Public Works Department that the transferee, buyer or assignee is the new applicant.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 8AA-111—8AA-122. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 01-109, § 3, adopted June 19, 2001, repealed sections 8AA-111—8AA-122 in their entirety. Former sections 8AA-111—8AA-122 pertained to use of county public rights-of-way, construction requirements, alteration of the system, access by county; right to use easement and streets not warranted; other agreements, permits and easements requirements; no property rights conveyed; location/relocation of facilities; work in the public right-of-way and easements; safety; county's right to inspect; unauthorized work; protection of county property; electrical standards; and emergency, respectively, and derived from Ord. No. 99-167, § 1, adopted Dec. 16, 1999.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-123. Service to the county</catch_line>
<text>
If controlling law changes to require the Registrant, or to authorize Miami-Dade County to require the Registrant, to provide Communications Services or facilities to schools, hospitals, government or other public facilities, Miami-Dade County reserves the right to require such service or facilities.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-124. Insurance</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Registrant shall provide, pay for and maintain, throughout the term of its Registration, and with companies satisfactory to the County, the types of insurance described herein. All insurance shall be from responsible companies duly authorized to do business in the State of Florida and having a financial rating in Best's Insurance Guide of A X or better. The insurance coverage obtained by the Registrant shall be approved by the Risk Management Division of the General Services Administration. All liability policies shall provide that the County is an additional insured as to the operations under this Registration and shall provide the severability of interest provision. The required coverages must be evidenced by properly executed Certificates of Insurance. The Certificates must be manually signed by the authorized representative of the insurance Registrant. Thirty (30) days advance written notice by registered or certified mail must be given to the County of any cancellation, intent not to renew or reduction in the policy coverages, which notice shall be sent by registered mail to the Consumer Services Department. Companies issuing the insurance policies shall have no recourse against the County for payment of any premiums or assessments, and same shall be the sole responsibility of the Registrant.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The limits of coverage of insurance required shall be not less than the following:
<section prefix = "1">
Worker's Compensation and Employer's Liability Insurance as required by Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Comprehensive General Liability Bodily injury and property damage one million dollars ($1,000,000.00) combined single limit each occurrence.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Automobile Liability Bodily injury and property damage one million dollars ($1,000,000.00) combined single limit each accident covering all owned, non-owned, and hired vehicles.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Upon thirty (30) days notice, the insurance coverage and policy requirements may be changed and increased from time to time at the discretion of the Board of County Commissioners to reflect changing liability exposure and limits.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
These insurance requirements may be met by evidence of participation of a bona-fide captive insurance or self insurance program that is established and regulated by a governmental entity.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-167, § 1, 12-16-99; Ord. No. 01-109, § 4, 6-19-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-125. Faithful performance and payment bond</catch_line>
<text>
The Registrant shall within thirty (30) days of the effective date of a Registration granted under this article, furnish to the Consumer Services Department a performance bond or an irrevocable letter of credit issued by a Florida bank or a federally insured lending institution in the amount of one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00). Such bond shall be maintained by the Registrant throughout the term of the Registration. The Registrant shall pay all premiums and keep the bond in full effect and force at all times throughout the term of the Registration, including, if necessary, the time required for removal of all the Registrant's system installed in the County's streets, and for one (1) year after the Registration expires or is terminated. The bond shall contain a provision that it shall not be terminated or otherwise allowed to expire without thirty (30) days prior written notice first being given to the Director and the Risk Manager. The performance bond or letter of credit shall be used to guarantee the compliance with performance requirements and payment of all sums which may become due to the County under this chapter. The Registrant shall maintain a copy of the bond on file with the County along with written evidence of the required premiums.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-126. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 01-109, § 3, adopted June 19, 2001, repealed section 8AA-126 in its entirety. Former section 8AA-126 pertained to indemnification and derived from Ord. No. 99-167, § 1, adopted Dec. 16, 1999.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-127. Termination of Registration</catch_line>
<text>
The County may declare a forfeiture and termination of, and revoke and cancel all rights granted under this Registration if (a) a federal/state authority suspends, denies, or revokes a Communications Services Provider's certification to provide Communications Services; (b) the Registrant's use of the public rights-of-way presents a danger to the general public and other users of the public rights-of-way; or, (c) the Registrant has abandoned its Communications Facilities in the Public Rights-of-Way and has not complied with Section 8AA-127.1. Prior to such termination by the County, the Registrant shall be served by the County with a written notice setting forth all matters pertinent to the termination action, including which of (a) through (c) above is applicable as the reason therefore, and describing the action of the County with respect thereto. The Registrant shall have sixty (60) days after service of such notice within which to address or eliminate the reason, or within which to present a plan, satisfactory to the County, to accomplish the same. In the event of such termination, the Registrant shall, within a reasonable time following demand by the County, remove or abandon the Communications Facilities and take such steps as are necessary to render every portion of the Communications Facilities remaining within the public rights-of-way of the County safe, and shall thereupon be deemed to have abandoned same in its entirety; and the same shall thereupon become the sole property of the County without payment to the Registrant. If Miami-Dade County agrees to abandonment, the Registrant shall incur, from that time forward, no future obligations with respect to the Communications Facilities.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-128. Continuing police powers</catch_line>
<text>
The Registrant shall at all times during the life of the Registration be subject to all lawful exercise of the police power of the County and to all lawful nondiscriminatory regulations as the County subsequently enacts based upon its existing powers or additional powers given it in the future. The Registrant shall comply with all laws, statutes, codes, ordinances, rules, or regulations applicable to its business. The Registrant shall at all times comply with the requirements of Article III of this Chapter. Specific and exact compliance to all zoning and building regulations shall be adhere[d] to by the Registrant.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-129. Consumer protection</catch_line>
<text>
Miami-Dade County may oversee compliance with all applicable consumer protection laws and regulations, including the enforcement of Chapter 8A, Business Regulations, of the Code of Miami-Dade County and may participate in any federal, state and local proceedings involving or on behalf of consumers in Miami-Dade County. Miami-Dade County reserves the right to enact additional consumer protection provisions to the extent authorized by state and federal law.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-130. Failure to enforce Registration</catch_line>
<text>
The Registrant shall not be excused from complying with any of the terms and conditions of this Article by any failure of the County, upon any one (1) or more occasions, to require the Registrant's performance or compliance with any one (1) or more of such terms or conditions.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-131. Future rules by the director</catch_line>
<text>
The Director reserves the right to promulgate rules, regulations, and procedures to implement the intention of this article.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-132. Authority of the director</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Director shall have the responsibility for overseeing the day-to-day administration of this article and authorizations granted hereunder. The Director, or any member of the Director's staff so designated by the Director, may administer oaths, certify to official acts, issue subpoenas, and compel the attendance of witnesses and the production of papers, account books, contracts, documents and other records, data or information, when necessary, convenient, or appropriate in the discharge of the duties of his office. The Director shall be empowered to take all administrative actions on behalf of the County, including adopting forms for application and reporting and other administrative procedures as are necessary.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Director shall have the authority to initiate legal actions in the name of Miami-Dade County through the County Attorney, seeking declaratory judgment, injunctive, equitable, and legal relief to enforce the provisions of this Article.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-167, § 1, 12-16-99)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-133. Director's settlement authority</catch_line>
<text>
The Director is hereby authorized to resolve by settlement any notice of violation or lawsuit initiated by the Director. In deciding to settle a dispute over an alleged violation, the County shall consider:
<section prefix = "1">
The probability of success in proving the violation;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The nature and seriousness of the violation;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Registrant's past history concerning similar violations;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Mitigating factors; and
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The Registrant's success in resolving the dispute with affected customers.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-134. Appeals of actions, decisions or determinations of the director; judicial review</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Any Registrant who is aggrieved by any final action, decision or determination of the Director pursuant to this article may appeal to a hearing officer. Appeal shall be initiated by filing a written notice of appeal with the Director within fifteen (15) days after the date of the action, decision or determination complained of. The written notice of appeal shall set forth the nature and date of the action, decision or determination to be reviewed and a brief summary of the grounds for the appeal. Upon such filing, an administrative hearing shall be scheduled and heard by a hearing officer pursuant to Section 8CC of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. The Hearing Officer shall set the matter for hearing on the earliest practicable regularly scheduled hearing date or as soon as possible, but no sooner than ten (10) days after the request has been filed and shall cause notice of the hearing to be served upon the aggrieved party by first class mail. The notice may include, but not be limited to, the applicable Sections of 8CC-6(b)(2) through (9) of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. The hearing officer shall hear and consider all relevant facts in accordance with the procedures set forth in Sections 8CC-6(e), (f), (g), (i), (j), (k), (l), (m)(2), and (n) of the Code of Miami-Dade County (any reference in these sections to Inspector shall mean "Director" and to violator shall mean "the person filing the appeal"), and may affirm, modify or reverse the action, decision or determination appealed from. The decision of the Hearing Officer shall constitute final administrative review and no rehearing shall be permitted. Nothing herein shall be construed to prevent or prohibit the Director from instituting any civil action or proceeding authorized by this Article at any time.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Director, the Miami-Dade County Consumer Advocate, or any Registrant who is aggrieved by any decision of the Hearing Officer may appeal a final order of the Hearing Officer by filing a notice of appeal in the Circuit Court in and for Miami-Dade County, Florida, in accordance with procedures and within the time provided by the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure for review of administrative action. The words "action," "decision" and "determination" as used herein shall not include the filing or institution of any action, conference or proceeding by the Director in any court otherwise.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Any regulated person making the appeal shall be required to pay the Director a fee, to be established by administrative order of the County Manager, to defray the costs of preparing the record on appeal. Said fee shall be effective upon approval by the Commission.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-167, § 1, 12-16-99; Ord. No. 01-109, § 4, 6-19-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-135. Civil penalties</catch_line>
<text>
In addition to any other judicial or administrative remedies or penalties provided by law, rule, regulation or ordinance, any person who violates any of the provisions of this article, any cease and desist order of the Director, any notice to correct a violation or any assurance of voluntary compliance pursuant to Section 8A-82.1 of the Code and this Article with respect to matters regulated under this Article or any other lawful order of the Director shall be subject to the judicial imposition and recovery of a civil penalty in an amount of not more than ten thousand dollars ($10,000.00) per offense. Each day during any portion of which such violation occurs or continues to occur constitutes a separate offense. Such monies recovered by the Director shall be deposited in a separate county fund to be used exclusively for enforcement of this Article. For purposes of this Article, all references to Chapter 8A in Section 8A-82.1 shall mean this Article.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-136. Enforcement procedure; remedies; attorney's fees; costs</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It shall be unlawful for any person to violate any of the provisions of this article. In addition to any other judicial or administrative remedies provided by law, rule, regulation, ordinance, or this article, the Director shall have the following judicial remedies available to enforce the provisions of this article:
<section prefix = "1">
The Director may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to seek temporary or permanent declaratory or injunctive relief to enforce compliance with or prohibit the violation of any of the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Director may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to impose and recover a civil penalty in an amount of not more than ten thousand dollars ($10,000.00) for each violation of any of the provisions of this article. Each day during any portion of which such violation occurs or continues to occur constitutes a separate violation. The right of trial by jury shall be available in any court to determine both liability for and the amount of the civil penalties to be imposed and recovered hereunder.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Director may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to seek restitution and other equitable relief to recover any sums and costs expended by the Director for tracing, investigating, preventing, controlling, abating or remedying any violation of any of the provisions of this article.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Upon the rendition of a judgment or decree by any of the courts of this state against any person and in favor of the Director under any of the provisions of this article, the trial court, or, in the event of an appeal in which the Director prevails, the appellate court, shall adjudge or decree against said person and in favor of the Director a reasonable sum as fees or compensation for the Director's attorney prosecuting the suit in which the recovery is had. Where so awarded, compensation or fees of the attorney shall be included in the judgment or decree rendered in the case. This provision shall apply to all civil actions, legal or equitable, filed after the effective date of this article by the Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All the judicial and administrative remedies in this article are independent and cumulative.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-167, § 1, 12-16-99)</history>
<catch_line>Secs. 8AA-137—8AA-149. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (2) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 01-109, § 4, adopted June 19, 2001, changed the name of article II from telecommunications regulations to communications services regulations. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
