<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_LXXX._MIAMI-DADE_COUNTY_HIV/AIDS</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1101. Creation and purpose</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created and established the Miami-Dade HIV/AIDS Partnership (hereinafter referred to as the "Partnership"). The Partnership's purpose is to enable the County and other governmental entities to apply for, receive, plan for, assess, and allocate financial assistance under the Title XXVI of the Public Health Service Act as amended by the Ryan White HIV/AIDS Treatment Modernization Act of 2006 (hereinafter called the "Ryan White Program"), Healthy Communities 2010 Objectives, AIDS Housing Opportunity Act, and Housing and Community Development Act of 1992, State of Florida General Revenue Care and Treatment Allocations, and other HIV/AIDS related funding as it becomes available; and to advise the Board of County Commissioners, the Mayor, and other governmental entities on HIV/AIDS related issues. Except where Federal or State laws or regulations mandate to the contrary the provisions of this article shall apply.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1102. Membership requirements; appointment of members; terms; removal</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
All members of the Partnership shall be permanent residents and electors of Miami-Dade County, unless the Board of County Commissioners, by a two-thirds vote of its membership, waives this requirement and shall have reputations for integrity and community service. Notwithstanding the qualified elector requirement stated herein, applicants for or members of the Partnership who are appointed to fill the seat of a former inmate of a local, state, or federal prison as described in Section 2-1102 (23) of this code shall be exempt from the qualified elector requirement set forth herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Partnership shall be composed of thirty-eight (38) voting members from the following categories of representatives:
<section prefix = "1">
Fifteen (15) member representatives of affected communities that include individuals with HIV disease, who are not affiliated or employed by a Part A funded provider and are recipients of Part A services, and historically underserved groups and subpopulations that reflect the demographics of the population within the eligible metropolitan area, and constitute;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
One (1) Health care provider, which must represent a Federally Qualified Health Center;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
One (1) Community based AIDS service organization;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Two (2) Housing, Homeless or Social Service providers;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
One (1) Mental health provider;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
One (1) Substance abuse provider;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
One (1) HIV prevention provider;
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
One (1) Hospital or health care planning agency;
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
One (1) representative from agencies receiving grants under Part C of the Ryan White Program;
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
One (1) representative from agencies receiving grants under Part D of the Ryan White Program, or from organizations with a history of providing services to children, youth, and families if funded locally;
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Four (4) grantee representatives of Other Federal HIV programs including Ryan White Program Part F and HOPWA, if funded locally;
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
One (1) Ryan White Program Part A local grantee;
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
One (1) State government/Ryan White Program Part B grantee representative;
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
One (1) State government/Medicaid Agency representative;
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
One (1) Local public health agency representative from the Miami-Dade County Health Department;
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
One (1) Miami-Dade County Public Schools representative;
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
One (1) Non-elected community leader who does not provide HIV related health care services subject to funding under Partnership programs;
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
One (1) former inmate of a local, state, or federal prison released from the custody of the penal system during the preceding three (3) years and had HIV disease as of the date of his release, or a representative of HIV+ incarcerated persons;
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
One (1) State of Florida General Revenue grantee representative;
</section>
<section prefix = "20">
One (1) representative of a federally recognized Indian tribe as represented in the population from the affected community;
</section>
<section prefix = "21">
One (1) representative co-infected with hepatitis B or C from the affected community.
<section prefix = "b">
Ex officio members shall be appointed in the same manner by which voting members are appointed, and at a minimum shall include ex officio members from the following categories of representatives:
<section prefix = "1">
One (1) representative from the Office of the Mayor;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
One (1) representative from the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Three (3) representatives of the affected community who are not affiliated or employed by a Part A funded provider, and are recipients of Part A services shall also be appointed as alternates. Alternate members may be assigned as voting members of committees, but are non-voting members of the full Partnership except when the voting member appointed to that category of representatives is unable to serve, at which time an alternate member of the same category of representatives designated by the chairperson shall serve as voting member for the full Partnership.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The Partnership shall maintain at all times a fair and open nominations process as written in its By-Laws which shall result in a recommended slate of candidates, including alternates, which is forwarded to the Mayor for his consideration. Members and alternates shall be appointed by the Mayor, who shall designate which category listed in subsections (a) and (b) above each member shall represent. Members shall be appointed in accordance with Sections 2-11.38 and 2-11.38.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Vacancies on the Partnership shall be filled in the same manner as above, except for affected community positions, which may be filled by an affected community alternate member appointed by the Partnership.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Appointment shall comply with the following requirements:
<section prefix = "1">
Composition of the Partnership shall reflect in its composition the demographics of the epidemic in Miami-Dade County with particular consideration given to disproportionately affected and historically underserved groups, subpopulations, and geographic areas in Miami-Dade County
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Composition of the Partnership, including committee membership, shall strive to assure the following:
<section prefix = "A">
Parity, with each member having equal opportunity for input and participation as well as equal voice in voting and other decision making activities;
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Inclusiveness, that all affected communities are represented and involved in a meaningful manner in the community planning process;
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Representation, that members who represent a specific community truly reflect that community's values, norms and behaviors.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
No more than fifteen (15) individuals shall be appointed who personally provide, who represent entities that provide, or who otherwise possess a financial relationship with entities that provide HIV related services funded by Partnership programs.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
No funded provider shall have more than one (1) representative or employee as a member, except as mandated by the legal requirements of Partnership programs.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
The term of office of members shall be in accordance with Section 2-11.38.2 of the Code of Miami-Dade County. Members shall be appointed to three (3) year terms, which shall end concurrent with the last day of the county's fiscal year, except that initially twelve (12) members shall be appointed to a one (1) year term and twelve (12) members appointed to a two (2) year term.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
No member shall be permitted to serve more than two (2) consecutive and complete terms of three (3) years except as required by law. Notwithstanding the term limit requirements set forth herein, members appointed to fill government or grantee seats are excepted from these requirements and shall serve as members of the Partnership for as long as they are designated by their respective agencies to serve in this capacity.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Attendance requirements for members shall be in accordance with Section 2-11.39, except that five (5) absences, excused or unexcused, in any fiscal year shall also constitute grounds for removal and except absences that are due to Partnership business related travel are not counted against the total of five (5) absences. If a member appointed to represent a category listed in subsection (a) or (b) above loses such representative status, fails to maintain the qualifications for membership set forth in Section 2-11.38, fails to maintain attendance requirements, voluntarily resigns, or for other good cause is removed, the member shall forfeit membership on the Partnership.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Members shall serve without compensation but shall be entitled to reimbursement for necessary authorized expenses incurred in the discharge of their duties pursuant to policies and procedures published by the County.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 98-127, § 2, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 02-35, § 2, 2-26-02; Ord. No. 07-71, § 2, 6-5-07)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1103. Organization</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Partnership shall establish, adopt, and amend bylaws, rules, and regulations for its own governance.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Partnership shall elect a chairperson and a chair-elect from among its members, who shall serve at the will of the Partnership. The chairperson and chair-elect shall not personally provide, represent entities that provide, or otherwise possess a financial relationship with entities that provide HIV related services funded by programs under the purview of the Partnership. The chairperson and chair-elect shall not be a representative of a grantee organization for any HIV/AIDS related program under the purview of the Partnership.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The chairperson shall preside at all meetings at which he or she is present. The chair-elect shall act as chairperson in the absence or inability of the chairperson.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The Partnership shall have assistance from staff designated by the county manager and other governmental entities and legal representation from the county attorney's office. The staff shall maintain and keep the records of the Partnership; prepare, in cooperation with the chairperson, the agenda for each meeting; be responsible for the preparation of such reports, minutes, documents, resolutions or correspondences as the Partnership may direct; and generally administer the business and affairs of the Partnership, subject to budgetary limitations.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
In order to transact any business or to exercise any power vested in the Partnership, a quorum consisting of no less than thirteen (13) voting members shall be present.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
All meetings of the Partnership shall be open to the public and shall be held only after adequate notice to the public. The records, reports, transcripts, minutes agenda and other documents which are made available to or prepared for or by the Partnership shall be available for public inspection and copying at a single location consistent with Chapter 119 of the Florida Statutes and the Federal Advisory Council Act.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
The Partnership shall not transact business or exercise its powers unless a majority of the quorum in attendance agrees to the activity. The chairperson, or five (5) Partnership members upon written request to the chairperson, may call for a special meeting.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
The Partnership may appoint committees to accomplish its tasks, and may appoint as committee members individuals who are not Partnership members.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Each committee shall strive to maintain no less than one-third (1/3) membership by representatives of the affected community.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 98-127, § 3, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 02-35, § 3, 2-26-02; Ord. No. 07-71, § 2, 6-5-07)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1104. Powers and duties</catch_line>
<text>
The Partnership shall have the following powers, duties, functions and responsibilities:
<section prefix = "a">
Establish methods for obtaining input on community needs and priorities which may include public meetings, conducting focus groups, and convening ad-hoc panels.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Develop a community-wide comprehensive plan for the Partnership and health services that is compatible with the State of Florida and the County's plan regarding the provision of health services to individuals with HIV/AIDS.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Establish prevention, housing, and care and treatment recommendations, including priorities.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Establish priorities for the allocation of Part A funds within the County, including how best to meet each such priority and individual factors that the County should consider in allocating funds under Part A of the Ryan White Program based on the:
<section prefix = "1">
Documented needs of the population affected by HIV/AIDS within the County;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Cost and outcome effectiveness of proposed strategies and interventions, to the extent that such data are reasonably available;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Priorities of the communities affected by HIV/AIDS for whom the services are intended; and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Availability of other governmental and non-governmental resources.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Make recommendations for service priorities for the use of other funds, to the areas of greatest need, with equal weight and attention provided to HIV/AIDS prevention, health and supportive services, and housing, including but not limited to the use of the following funding sources:
<section prefix = "1">
Part B of the Ryan White Program.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Housing Opportunities for Persons with AIDS program.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
State of Florida General Revenue Care and Treatment funding.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Other federal and state grants
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Funding from municipalities interested in supporting implementation of the Partnership's Comprehensive Plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Private Foundation grants.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Private contributions.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
To serve in an advisory capacity to the Board of County Commissioners, the Mayor, and other governmental entities with respect to all issues affecting or relating to persons at risk of contracting the virus and persons living with the virus.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Participate in the development of the Statewide Coordinated Statement of Need initiated by the State of Florida's public health agency responsible for administering grants under the Ryan White Program.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Establish procedures within the Partnership's By-Laws for addressing grievances with respect to Part A funding and any other matter deemed appropriate by the Partnership, including but not limited to procedures for submitting grievances for Part A allocations that cannot be resolved by binding arbitration as required by the Ryan White Program. Grievance procedures developed by the Partnership shall be submitted for review and approval to the appropriate federal agency. Upon approval, these procedures shall become the sole dispute resolution mechanism and shall take precedence over all other County dispute resolution mechanisms, including but not limited to the County bid protest procedures.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Assess the efficiency of the administrative mechanism in rapidly allocating funds to the areas of greatest need with the County and, at the discretion of the Partnership, assess the effectiveness and quality, either directly or through contractual arrangements, of the services offered in meeting the identified needs.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Those powers and duties granted by the Ryan White Program, Healthy Communities 2010 Objectives, AIDS Housing Opportunity Act, and Housing and Community Development Act of 1992, and State of Florida General Revenue Care and Treatment Allocations as presently exist or as may be amended.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1105. Conflict of interest</catch_line>
<text>
Section 2-11.1 (c) and (d) of the Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance of Miami-Dade County are waived for Partnership members for transactions arising from the exercise of those powers granted the Partnership herein and by the requirements of the Partnership programs. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the Partnership and its members shall comply with all other provisions set forth in Section 2-11.1 and any other applicable state and federal laws.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1106. Reports</catch_line>
<text>
The chairperson or chair-elect's designee shall present to the Board of County Commissioners on an annual basis a written report describing the Council's activities and shall appear as needed before the Board to present any matters pertinent to the Partnership.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-1107—2-1110. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
</law>
