<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 29 TAXATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XIV._1993_CAPITAL_IMPROVEMENTS_L</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-110. Short title</catch_line>
<text>
This article shall be known as the "Dade County 1993 Capital Improvements Tax Ordinance."
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-111. Tax levied; effective period</catch_line>
<text>
Pursuant to Section 336.025, Florida Statutes (1993), the Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners hereby levies and imposes a tax of five cents ($0.05) on every gallon of motor fuel sold in Miami-Dade County, Florida and taxed under the provisions of Part I of Chapter 206, Florida Statutes (1993). This tax shall be known as the "1993 Capital Improvements Local Option Gas Tax," and shall be imposed as of January 1, 1994.
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ordinance No. 96-101, ยง 1, adopted June 20, 1996, amended section 8 of Ord. No. 93-91 to rescind two cents of 1993 Five Cents Capital Improvements Local Option Gas Tax. The remaining three cents of such tax shall remain in full force and effect.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-112. Relationship to state law</catch_line>
<text>
This ordinance is adopted and shall be subject to the provisions of Section 336.025, Florida Statutes (1993).
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-113. Distribution of proceeds</catch_line>
<text>
Proceeds of the 1993 Capital Improvements Option Gas Tax shall be distributed among the county government and eligible incorporated municipalities based upon the Interlocal Agreement in the form approved by the Board through Resolution No. R-996-93, adopted on July 27, 1993 and executed by all parties prior to September 1, 1993. A fully executed copy of said Interlocal Agreement is on file with the Clerk of the Board.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-114. Termination of Interlocal Agreement</catch_line>
<text>
If, for any reason, the Interlocal Agreement herein referred to shall be terminated or deemed of no force and effect, the Capital Improvements Local Option Gas Tax shall continue to be imposed and upon notification by the County, the Florida Department of Revenue shall distribute the proceeds of said tax to the County and eligible municipalities within the County in accordance with the method set forth in Section 336.025(4)(a), Florida Statues (1993).
</text>
</law>
