<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XI._PUBLIC_WELFARE_DEPARTMENT</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-87. Established; Director as head; appointment; term; operating procedures</catch_line>
<text>
A Public Welfare Department is established. The head of the Department is the Director of Public Welfare who shall be appointed by the Manager and shall serve at the Manager's will. The organization and operating procedures of the Department shall be prescribed in administrative orders and regulations of the Manager. The Manager shall appoint such employees and other personnel as may be necessary to operate the Department. The salaries and compensation of all personnel, except employees in the classified service, shall be fixed by the County Commission upon recommendation of the Manager.
</text>
A Public Welfare Department is established. The head of the Department is the Director of Public Welfare who shall be appointed by the Manager and shall serve at the Manager's will. The organization and operating procedures of the Department shall be prescribed in administrative orders and regulations of the Manager. The Manager shall appoint such employees and other personnel as may be necessary to operate the Department. The salaries and compensation of all personnel, except employees in the classified service, shall be fixed by the County Commission upon recommendation of the Manager.
Charter reference— For authority of Manager to issue and place into effect administrative orders, rules and regulations and to prescribe the organization and operating procedure of departments of the County, § 4.02.
<catch_line>Sec. 2-88. Powers and duties</catch_line>
<text>
The Public Welfare Department shall:
<section prefix = "1">
Administer public assistance and care and child welfare programs.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Operate County welfare institutions for children, the aged and the infirm.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Accumulate and analyze data concerning the volume, nature, and cost of welfare programs, assemble data for State and national reporting systems, serve as liaison between the County and the reporting units of other public and privately sponsored welfare organizations, and conduct special research studies of welfare problems, programs and activities.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Inform the public of the operations and programs of the Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Perform specialized case work directed toward returning persons to self-support or self-care; provide employment and placement services; and be responsible for the conduct of a rehabilitation program for recipients of welfare services.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Administer programs of financial aid and care for families and unattached individuals in need, supplemental aid to persons on State public assistance or awaiting eligibility for State grants, and aid and service to nonresidents; certify eligibility for hospital care under the State hospital aid program.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Administer a program of assistance and care to adults and the aged; provide housekeeper and homemaker services, place adults and the aged in foster family homes; provide placement in boarding and nursing homes, including placement in voluntary nonprofit institutions, and certify cases for admission to the County home for the aged and infirm.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Accept for shelter in the Home for Dependent Children, maintained and operated by the County, any children who are referred to it by the Juvenile and Domestic Relations Court.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Administer programs of housekeeper, homemaker, and day care services to children in their own homes where necessary and advisable as an alternative to placement in foster homes.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Place children in foster homes both directly and through voluntary agencies and the State Department of Public Welfare; provide adoption services, and place children needing special treatment or care in the County children's home or with other group care agencies.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-88.1. Lien on property of welfare recipients—Created</catch_line>
<text>
Any person requesting or receiving public assistance or other welfare payments from Miami-Dade County funds shall agree to creation of a lien in favor of Miami-Dade County upon any real property then owned or later acquired by him. Before any application for such assistance or payments are approved any applicant owning real estate shall execute an agreement for lien in a form prescribed by the Miami-Dade County Department of Public Welfare. Such form shall describe with particularity any real property owned by the applicant and shall be executed in the presence of two (2) subscribing witnesses and acknowledged in the same manner as a mortgage.
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Sections 2-88.1 through 2-88.4 are derived from Ord. No. 59-11, §§ 1 through 4 adopted May 19, 1959. Ord. No. 60-1 declared Ord. No. 59-11 to be amendatory to this Code.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-88.2. Same—Persons presently receiving benefits</catch_line>
<text>
Any person presently [22] receiving the public assistance or other welfare payments aforesaid who now owns or hereafter acquires real estate, in order to be eligible for benefits to be paid on or after September 1, 1959, shall execute an agreement for lien in the same form as prescribed hereinabove; provided, however, that such lien shall secure only those payments made to the recipient on or after September 1, 1959.
</text>
Any person presently [22] receiving the public assistance or other welfare payments aforesaid who now owns or hereafter acquires real estate, in order to be eligible for benefits to be paid on or after September 1, 1959, shall execute an agreement for lien in the same form as prescribed hereinabove; provided, however, that such lien shall secure only those payments made to the recipient on or after September 1, 1959.
Note—See editor's note following § 2-88.1
<catch_line>Sec. 2-88.3. Same—Effective date; superiority; filing</catch_line>
<text>
The lien created hereunder shall be effective from the date the agreement for lien is filed in the Office of the Clerk of the Circuit Court in the County in which real property owned by the recipient is located. Such lien shall secure the principal amount of all assistance paid from Miami-Dade County funds on or after September 1, 1959, whether paid before or after execution and filing of the agreement of lien. Said agreement shall be filed and cross-indexed in the same manner as other liens or judgments of record and if the property is located within Miami-Dade County the Clerk shall file such notice without cost to Miami-Dade County. Such agreement for lien shall be filed in each county in which a recipient owns real property. Such lien shall be superior to all subsequent liens except that the Miami-Dade County Welfare Director shall have authority to subordinate any lien created hereunder to a mortgage or lien created against the property of a recipient for necessary repairs or improvements to such property, and shall have authority to enter into an agreement with appropriate federal or State authorities claiming reimbursement for public assistance payments made pursuant to Chapter 409, Florida Statutes, to divide the lien proceeds, after deduction of costs, in proportion to contributions made by the United States, the State of Florida, and Miami-Dade County.
</text>
The lien created hereunder shall be effective from the date the agreement for lien is filed in the Office of the Clerk of the Circuit Court in the County in which real property owned by the recipient is located. Such lien shall secure the principal amount of all assistance paid from Miami-Dade County funds on or after September 1, 1959, whether paid before or after execution and filing of the agreement of lien. Said agreement shall be filed and cross-indexed in the same manner as other liens or judgments of record and if the property is located within Miami-Dade County the Clerk shall file such notice without cost to Miami-Dade County. Such agreement for lien shall be filed in each county in which a recipient owns real property. Such lien shall be superior to all subsequent liens except that the Miami-Dade County Welfare Director shall have authority to subordinate any lien created hereunder to a mortgage or lien created against the property of a recipient for necessary repairs or improvements to such property, and shall have authority to enter into an agreement with appropriate federal or State authorities claiming reimbursement for public assistance payments made pursuant to Chapter 409, Florida Statutes, to divide the lien proceeds, after deduction of costs, in proportion to contributions made by the United States, the State of Florida, and Miami-Dade County.
Note—See editor's note following § 2-88.1
<catch_line>Sec. 2-88.4. Same—Foreclosure</catch_line>
<text>
Liens created hereunder shall be foreclosed in the same manner provided for foreclosure of mortgages, except that no deficiency decree shall be entered. The lien created hereunder shall not be a debt of the recipient of assistance nor a charge against his personal property. Such lien may not be foreclosed during the occupancy of the real property by the recipient, a surviving spouse, by any minor dependent child, or by a dependent adult child of such recipient who is incapable of self support because of total mental or physical disability.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-89. County home for aged and infirm</catch_line>
<text>
The County home for the aged and infirm shall provide group care for adults unable to provide self-care. Admission to the home shall be prescribed by the Director.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-90. County children's home</catch_line>
<text>
The County children's home shall provide group care of children requiring special care in a group setting. Admission to the home shall be prescribed by the Director.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (21) ---
Annotation—AO 9-1 (Back)

--- (22) ---
Editor's note— The Ord. from which this section is derived was adopted May 19, 1959. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
