<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_VII._UNIFORM_PENAL_CODE</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-80. Title</catch_line>
<text>
This article shall be designated and cited as the Uniform Penal Ordinance of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-81. Misdemeanor; adoption of State law; penalties</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It shall be unlawful and a violation of this article for any person to commit within Miami-Dade County, Florida, any act which is recognized by the laws of the State of Florida as a misdemeanor.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
All statutes of the State of Florida defining and prohibiting criminal offenses against the State not punishable by death or by imprisonment in the state prison and defined by State law as misdemeanors are adopted and incorporated by reference as part of this article to the same extent and to the same effect as if the provisions of each such statute was set out in full herein defining and prohibiting each such offense against the State to be an act prohibited by or an offense in violation of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All acts defined as misdemeanors in said State statutes are hereby prohibited and declared to be violations of this article and any person or corporation shall, upon conviction in the court of appropriate jurisdiction for violation thereof, be punished by a fine not exceeding five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for not more than sixty (60) days, or by both such fine and imprisonment, but in no case shall the fine or imprisonment imposed under this article be greater than the maximum fine or penalty for the same offense under the State statute.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 70-15, § 1, 2-25-70)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-82. Parties to violations</catch_line>
<text>
Every person who commits, attempts to commit, conspires to commit, or aids and abets in the commission of any act declared herein to be in violation of this article, whether individually or in connection with one (1) or more persons, or as a principal, agent or accessory, shall be guilty of such offense and every person who falsely, fraudulently, forcibly or wilfully induces, causes, coerces, requires, permits or directs another to violate any provisions of this article is likewise guilty of such offense.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-83. Declaration of legislative intent</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The provisions and penalties of this article are not intended to and shall not be construed as changing, modifying, amending, repealing, superseding or conflicting with any provisions or sections of the Florida Statutes defining or penalizing misdemeanors, but shall be construed as supplemental and additional thereto and not as a substitute therefor; nor shall this article be construed as impairing the jurisdiction of the Criminal Court of Record of Miami-Dade County, Florida, impairing the jurisdiction of the Juvenile and Domestic Relations Court in and for Miami-Dade County, Florida, or impairing the jurisdiction of any municipal court within Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
This article does not supersede any municipal ordinances or codes, or any existing County ordinances but is in supplement of and additional to all municipal and County penal ordinances.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 70-15, §§ 3, 6, 2-25-70)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-84. Applicability</catch_line>
<text>
It is hereby provided that this article shall constitute a penal code applicable in all the unincorporated and incorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-85. Enforcement of article</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It shall be the duty of all peace and police officers of Miami-Dade County, including municipal police officers within their boundaries, to enforce the provisions of this article, to make arrests for violations hereof, to assist in the prosecution of persons charged with such violations, to investigate violations of this article, and to carry out the duties specifically imposed by this article, provided, however, that where an act is also a violation of a municipal ordinance, a municipal police officer may, in his discretion, make an arrest for a violation of the municipal ordinance instead of for a violation of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Any municipal police officer observing the violation of this article within his jurisdiction shall have authority to follow said violator into any of the incorporated or unincorporated areas for the purposes of making arrests.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 70-15, § 7, 2-25-70)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-86. Court of appropriate jurisdiction vested with trial jurisdiction</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Exclusive jurisdiction; exception. All violations of this article shall be prosecuted only in the court of appropriate jurisdiction which shall have original, exclusive jurisdiction to try all cases arising hereunder. Provided, however, that where an act is recognized by State law as a misdemeanor and by this article as an offense, complaints against persons charged with such unlawful acts may be filed and prosecuted in either the court of appropriate jurisdiction or the Criminal Court of Record of Miami-Dade County, Florida, as the prosecuting attorney shall direct. Provided, further, that where an act is recognized as an offense, both by this article and a municipal ordinance, complaints against persons charged with such unlawful acts may be filed and prosecuted in either the court of appropriate jurisdiction or the appropriate municipal court.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Trial in Juvenile and Domestic Relations Court. Where offenses set forth involve violations by juveniles, the same shall be tried in the Miami-Dade County Juvenile and Domestic Relations Court when required by the laws of the State of Florida; however, such offenses involving traffic violations shall be tried in accordance with Section 11-1.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Chapter 30 Nothing in this article is intended to nor shall it have the effect of superseding, nullifying or amending any provision of Chapter 30 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. All laws pertaining to traffic violations shall continue to be prosecuted under and pursuant to the provisions of Chapter 30 of the Code of Miami-Dade County from and after the effective date of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Prosecution by State agency officers. When and if any officer of a State agency deems it desirable and in the public interest to prosecute in the court of appropriate jurisdiction violators of State laws, rules and regulations adopted by reference herein, he shall do so with the permission of the prosecuting attorney, and may issue summons or have warrants issued as he deems appropriate.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 70-15, § 4, 2-25-70)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-87. Probation of defendants</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
The court of appropriate jurisdiction, where the defendant has been found guilty or has entered a plea of guilty or a plea of nolo contendere, may at a time to be determined by the court, either with or without an adjudication of the guilt of the defendant, hear and determine the question of the probation of such defendant.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Prior to such hearing the court may refer the case to the Probation and Parole Commission for investigation and recommendation. The court, upon such reference, shall direct the commission to make an investigation and report in writing at a specified time to the court upon the circumstances of the offense, the criminal record, the social history, and the present condition of the defendant together with its recommendation.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
If it appears to the court upon a hearing of the matter that the defendant is not likely again to engage in an unlawful course of conduct and that the ends of justice and the welfare of society do not require that the defendant shall presently suffer the penalty imposed by law, the court, in its discretion, may either adjudge the defendant to be guilty or stay and withhold the adjudication of guilt and in either case stay and withhold the imposition of sentence upon such defendant, and shall place him upon probation under the supervision and control of the Probation and Parole Commission for the duration of such probation. And the said Commission shall thereupon and thereafter, during the continuance of such probation, have the supervision and control of the defendant.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Whenever punishment by imprisonment in the County Jail is prescribed, the court, in its discretion, may at the time of sentencing direct the defendant to be placed on probation upon completion of any specified period of such sentence. In such case, the court shall stay and withhold the imposition of the remainder of sentence imposed upon the defendant, and direct that the defendant be placed upon probation after serving such period as may be imposed by the court.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
In no case shall the imposition of sentence be suspended and the defendant thereupon placed on probation unless such defendant be placed under the custody of said Probation and Parole Commission.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 70-15, § 5, 2-25-70)</history>
<catch_line>Secs. 21-88—21-100. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (4) ---
Editor's note— Article VII, §§ 21-80—21-137, derived from Ord. No. 65-1, adopted January 12, 1965, as amended by Ord. No. 65-31, adopted April 20, 1965, was repealed by Ord. No. 65-57, § 1, enacted September 14, effective September 24, 1965. Article VII was previously designated "Miami-Dade County Penal Code," however, it was never officially in effect, as the original ordinance, Ord. No. 65-1, was not to become effective until May 1, 1965, and prior to that time Ord. No. 65-31 postponed the effective date to October 1, 1965. Article VII, §§ 21-80—21-87 is now derived from Ord. No. 70-15, §§ 1—8, enacted Feb. 25, 1970, and was codified in this manner at the discretion of the editors, pursuant to authority in § 10 of this ordinance. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
