<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXXIII._CULTURAL_AFFAIRS_COUNCIL</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-291. Miami-Dade County Cultural Affairs Council created; purpose; objectives</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created and established the Miami-Dade County Cultural Affairs Council, hereinafter referred to as the Council, a part of the government of Miami-Dade County, Florida, for the purpose of developing, coordinating and promoting the performing and visual arts and the sciences, in Miami-Dade County, contracting for artistic services, performances, and exhibits, and developing physical facilities for the use of the arts and sciences, all for the enjoyment, education, cultural enrichment, and benefit of the citizens of Miami-Dade County. In furtherance of said purpose, the Council shall attempt to accomplish the following objectives:
<section prefix = "1">
Stimulate greater governmental and public awareness and appreciation of the importance of the arts and sciences to the people of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Encourage and implement greater and more efficient use of governmental and private resources for the development and support of the arts and sciences.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Encourage and implement opportunities for County residents to participate in artistic and scientific activities.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Promote the development of Miami-Dade County artists, scientists and institutions and community organizations sponsoring arts and science activities, and audiences.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Survey and assess the needs of the arts and sciences, and of the people of this County relating thereto and make such information promptly and regularly available to all interested agencies and persons upon request.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Support and implement the preservation and growth of the County's artistic and scientific resources.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Foster the development of a receptive climate for the arts and sciences to culturally enrich and benefit the citizens of Miami-Dade County in their daily lives, to make Miami-Dade County visits and vacations all the more appealing to the world and to attract to Miami-Dade County residency additional outstanding creators in the field of arts and sciences through appropriate programs of publicity, education, coordination and to sponsor activities such as the presentation of lectures and exhibitions and central compilation and dissemination of information on the progress of the arts and sciences in Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Encourage and coordinate the artistic and scientific activities of other governmental agencies, including those concerned with the public educational system.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Provide Miami-Dade County cultural organizations with information and assistance.

The purposes and objectives provided by this section are hereby deemed to be public purposes.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-292. Definition of "the arts and sciences.</catch_line>
<text>
The boundaries of the arts and sciences are constantly changing, but for the purposes of this article shall include, without limitation, all phases of the visual and performing arts and shall also include the exhibition of all forms of history and science, when such activities are conducted by nonprofit organizations.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-293. Membership and organization</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Each Council member will be charged with the responsibility of serving the best interests of the arts and sciences in the County within the purposes of this article, and no Council member shall view his or her Council role to be that of representing any particular geographic area of the County, interest group, arts or science institution, community organization, or audience.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
(1) The Council shall consist of fifteen (15) members. No person shall be qualified to sit as a member of the Cultural Arts Council if he or she is a salaried Manager, administrator or director of any cultural organization in Miami-Dade County. Each Council member: (i) shall be affiliated with one or more local cultural organizations, (ii) shall be an active member of one or more charitable, educational or other organizations which provide community benefits, (iii) shall have relevant professional experience or (iv) shall possess stature within the community.
<section prefix = "2">
Vacancies on the Council shall be filled by the County Commission. The members shall be appointed for staggered terms. Each board member shall be appointed to a term which shall end concurrently with the last day of the term of the County Commissioner who appointed the Board member, as provided in Section 2-38.2 of this Code. If a vacancy occurs prior to the expiration of the Board member's term, the County Commissioner who appointed that member shall appoint a new member to fill the balance of the term. Subject to the provisions of this paragraph, the Council's fifteen (15) members shall consist of thirteen (13) members appointed by individual Commissioners and two (2) members appointed by the Board of County Commissioners to a term of four (4) years. Individual Commissioners shall each appoint one (1) member until thirteen (13) members shall have been appointed by individual Commissioners. The next two (2) appointments shall be made by the Board of County Commissioners. In filling any vacancy to be filled by the Commission, the County Commission shall select the replacement Council member from a list of three (3) candidates to be submitted by the remaining members of the Council. In the event that none of the three (3) candidates suggested meets Commission approval, the Council shall submit another and entirely different list for Commission consideration. This process shall continue until a suitable replacement has been found to fill the existing or anticipated vacancy.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Council shall endeavor to make the public aware of any vacancy which occurs, or which is expected, by complying with the notice and publication requirements established in subsection (f) of this section. The Council shall then receive open nominations from citizens of Miami-Dade County before submitting any list of candidates to the County Commission. As any vacancies occur, the Council shall furnish the Board of County Commissioners with a list of the qualifications and demographic backgrounds of the present members of the Council.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All members of the Council shall be qualified electors residing in the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
No Council member shall serve more than eight (8) consecutive years on the Council; provided that this limitation shall not be applicable to Council members with unexpired terms on November 1, 1993 who were reappointed after that date. Nothing shall prohibit any individual from being reappointed to the Council after a hiatus of two (2) years.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
No Council member may receive compensation for his or her services, but the council may approve reimbursement for expenses necessarily incurred in the performance of a member's duties.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
For purposes of this section, notice and publication requirements shall be deemed to have been met by advertisement three (3) consecutive days in a newspaper of County-wide circulation at least fourteen (14) days prior to the taking of the intended action.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 76-34, § 3, 4-20-76; Ord. No. 89-106, § 1, 11-7-89; Ord. No. 94-06, §§ 1, 2, 1-18-94)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-294. Council officers</catch_line>
<text>
The Council shall elect annually one of its members to be its Chairperson, and another as Vice-Chairperson.
</text>
The Council shall elect annually one of its members to be its Chairperson, and another as Vice-Chairperson.
Annotations—CAO's 76-31, 78-44, 81-22.
<catch_line>Sec. 2-295. Executive Director</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager, with the advice and consent of the Council, and subject to approval by the County Commission, shall appoint an Executive Director who shall be a full-time employee and shall receive a salary fixed by the County Commission. The Executive Director shall carry out the policies and programs established by the Council, shall employ, subject to Council approval, such full-time and part-time staff and consultants as appropriate to carry out those policies and programs and shall be in charge of the day-to-day operation of those policies and programs.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-296. Powers of the Council</catch_line>
<text>
The Council shall have all legal powers necessary and appropriate to effectuate its objectives and the purposes as set forth in this article, subject to the approval of the County Commission, including, but not limited to, the power:
<section prefix = "1">
To have a seal and to alter the same at pleasure.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To provide financial support, including grants, matching grants, loans and guarantees, when other sources of financial support are unavailable or impractical, to Florida artists, arts institutions, local arts interests, and community organizations sponsoring arts activities pursuant to such regulations as the Council may adopt and publish.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
To adopt rules for the regulation of its affairs and the conduct of its business.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
To acquire by grant, purchase, gift or devise all property, real or personal, or any estate or interest therein necessary, desirable or convenient for the purpose of this article, and to lease or rent all or any part thereof and to exercise all of its powers and authority with respect thereto.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
To lease or contract for the operation of any part of any of the cultural facilities of the Council, subject to reasonable notice, bids and hearing.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
To fix and collect rates, rentals, fees and charges for the use of any and all of the cultural facilities of the Council.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
To contract for the operation of concessions on or in any of the cultural facilities of the Council, subject to reasonable public notice, bids and hearing.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
To advertise within or without the State any of the activities, events or facilities of the Council.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
To make and enter into all contracts and agreements necessary or incidental to the purposes and the performance of the duties imposed and the execution of the powers granted under this article, and to employ such Director, consulting services, engineers, superintendents, managers, construction and financial experts and attorneys, and such employees and agents as may, in the judgment of the Council, be deemed necessary, and to fix their compensation.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
To cooperate and contract with the government of the United States or the State of Florida, or any agency or instrumentality thereof, or with any municipality, district, private corporation, copartnership, association, or individual providing for or relating to cultural activities, events or facilities.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
To organize advisory committees.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
To recommend for consideration the names of at least three (3) qualified persons for each vacancy that occurs on the Council that will be filled by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
To give such priority to the accomplishment of the purposes, objectives, and duties of the Council as it shall determine to be in the best interests of the arts and sciences and the people of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
To request and obtain such assistance, services, and information from other governmental agencies or entities as will enable the Council to properly carry out its objectives under this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
To do all acts or things necessary or convenient to carry out the powers expressly granted in this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
To seek and accept appropriations or funds from any federal, State, County, city, or municipal governmental entity, or any individual, partnership, joint venture, or corporation.
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
To create associate memberships.
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
To recommend certain grant awards to be made final by the County Manager without further action of the Board of County Commissioners.
<section prefix = "a">
The Council may by this method recommend grant awards subject to the following:
<section prefix = "i">
Grantees shall be nonprofit corporations or, notwithstanding the provisions of Section 2-10 herein, units of local or State government;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
The Council may recommend up to three thousand nine hundred ninety-nine dollars ($9,999.00) in one (1) fiscal year to each grantee;
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
The Council shall recommend grant awards by a method that recognizes the cultural and ethnic diversity of this community; and
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
Each grant shall be for the purpose of enhancing cultural and community activities within Miami-Dade County, to assist in the creation of a nurturing climate for artists and Miami-Dade County audiences, to enhance the quality of life in Miami-Dade County for residents and visitors and to make Miami-Dade County a better place in which to live, work and visit.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
All recommended grant awards shall be reviewed by the County Attorney and approved as to form and legal sufficiency prior to award.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Approval of any proposed grant that fails to meet any of the conditions of paragraph (18)(a) or (b) can only be accomplished by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The Council shall furnish a report to the culture and recreation committee no less frequently than monthly listing all grants awarded under this subsection (18).

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-297. Council meetings; public hearings; committees and advisors; reports; rules</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
(1) All meetings shall be open to the public. Council meetings shall be held at least quarterly pursuant to notice and at such times and places as the Council shall determine. One-half of the Council membership, plus one (1), shall comprise a quorum for the transaction of business at Council meetings.
<section prefix = "2">
Continued and unexcused absence from Council meetings shall constitute cause for a member's removal from the Council, and replacement as provided for in subsection (b) of Section 2-293. Such action shall be taken only with approval of two-thirds of the remaining Council members.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Council shall hold at least one public hearing annually, pursuant to public notice specifying the date and place of hearing and the subjects to be considered, specifically for the purpose of making the Council's work known and investigating and assessing the needs and development of the arts and sciences in the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Council may establish such working committees of Council members as it deems appropriate to carry out its purposes, objectives, duties and powers.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The Council may convene such advisory panels and may consult with such advisors and experts as it deems necessary and appropriate for carrying out its objectives, duties and powers, and it shall initially establish and consult a professional advisory committee.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The Council shall formulate and publish rules and regulations setting forth the criteria pursuant to which its financial aid is given, and such other rules regarding its activities as it deems appropriate.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The Council shall annually file with the Board of County Commissioners a report summarizing its activities conducted during the preceding year and setting forth such recommendations, including recommendations with respect to present or proposed legislation, concerning State encouragement and support of the arts, as it considers appropriate. The Council's annual report, and such other reports as it deems appropriate, shall be made available to the public.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 76-34, § 7, 4-20-76)</history>
Annotations—CAO's 76-28, 77-6.
<catch_line>Sec. 2-298. Initial Council; funding</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Selection of initial members. The initial fifteen (15) Council members shall be selected as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
The Planning Advisory Board shall submit all public nominations received by it as of March 31, 1976, to both the Mayor's Advisory committee on the Arts and the Cultural Executive Council/Junior League.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Both the Mayor's Advisory Committee on the Arts and the Cultural Executive Council/Junior League shall consider said public nominations, together with any additional nominations that either group may have, and each group will submit forty-five (45) nominations to the Planning Advisory Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Planning Advisory Board will select forty-five (45) nominations from the total of ninety (90) received and submit these forty-five (45) nominations to the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
From the forty-five (45) names submitted by the Miami-Dade County Planning Advisory Board the initial fifteen (15) Council members shall be appointed by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Fundings by Miami-Dade County. Requests of the Council for funding by Miami-Dade County shall be initiated through the County Manager in accordance with established procedures.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 76-34, § 8, 4-20-76)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-299. Construction of provisions</catch_line>
<text>
This article, being for a public purpose and for the welfare of the citizens of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall be liberally construed to effect the purposes hereof.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (54) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 76-34, enacted April 20, 1976, amended this Code, but did not specify the manner thereof, hence inclusion of §§ 1—9 herein as Art. XXXIII, §§ 2-291—2-299, was at the discretion of the editors. (Back)
Annotation—CAO 82-18. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
