<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">Chapter 25B PARKS AND RECREATION GENERALLY</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="2">ARTICLE_II._STANDARDS_FOR_ACCEPTANCE_OF_</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 25B-11. Legislative intent, findings and purposes</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Outdoor recreational and park lands, lands qualified as environmentally endangered, and land and water areas containing animals or vegetation native to Miami-Dade County, Florida, are valued natural and ecological resources. Such lands and water areas provide needed open spaces for clean-air sheds, as well as for scenic, aesthetic, and conservation purposes. Such lands are under urban pressure from expanding metropolitan areas. This urban pressure takes the form of scattered development in wide belts around urban areas, and brings conflicting land uses into juxtaposition, creates high costs for public services and stimulates land speculation. The intent of the Commission is to provide a means by which outdoor recreational land, environmentally endangered land, and land and water areas containing native animals or vegetation may be protected and enhanced as resources of major importance. The Legislature of the State of Florida has recognized and has granted the authority to communities within the State to adopt such a procedure. This article is declared to be a proper and necessary exercise of the aforesaid powers.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The statements heretofore made are declared to be the Legislative intent, findings, and purposes of the Board of County Commissioners and are hereby adopted and made a part hereof.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 75-33, § 1, 5-21-75; Ord. No. 79-105, § 1, 12-4-79)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 25B-12. Option of owners in fee to convey development right or covenant with Board for specified term of years</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The owner or owners in fee of any land or water area containing at least five (5) acres and located within Miami-Dade County, Florida, which either qualifies as environmentally endangered and is so designated by the Board, or which is utilized for outdoor recreational or park purposes, may by appropriate instrument for a specific term of not less than ten (10) years:
<section prefix = "1">
Convey the development rights in said land to the Board; or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Covenant with the Board that the said land shall be maintained in its present natural state and be subject to one (1) or more conservation restrictions if necessary to maintain such present state, or shall not be used for any purpose other than outdoor recreational or park purposes.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Notwithstanding the requirement of a minimum of a five-acre area set forth in subsection (a) above, any land or water area containing less than five (5) acres may qualify for the provisions of this article and subsection (a) above if such land or water area qualifies as environmentally endangered and is so designated by the Department of Environmental Resources Management prior to being considered by the Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The action by the owner to convey the development right or execute a covenant pursuant to this article, or to obtain a written instrument from the Board reconveying all or part of the development right to the owner or releasing the owner from the terms of the covenant, shall be by unanimous written consent if more than one (1) owner holds fee simple title to the land subject to the conveyance or covenant. All mortgagees holding a mortgage on the subject property must join in the conveyance or covenant.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 75-33, § 2, 5-21-75; Ord. No. 79-105, § 1, 12-4-79)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 25B-13. Provisions of conveyance of development right or covenant</catch_line>
<text>
The conveyance of the development right or covenant shall expressly provide the following:
<section prefix = "a">
That the County through its authorized agents shall have the right, upon written notification to the owner, to inspect the premises at a reasonable time to determine whether the land is being used or maintained in the manner promised by the owner and as permitted by this article. Where a determination is made by the County after such inspection that some curative action on the land is necessary in order to preserve the terms of the covenant or conveyance, the County shall notify the owner in writing by certified mail, return receipt requested, of the particular curative action to be taken and the reasons therefor. The owner shall have the right to appeal such proposed action to the Board by filing a written objection with the Clerk of the Board within thirty (30) days after receipt of the written notification of proposed curative action and reasons therefor.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
That land used for outdoor recreational or park purposes under this article shall be open to the general public.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
That the owner shall indemnify and hold Miami-Dade County harmless from any and all liability or claims arising out of the public access to the land permitted by the above subsection (b).

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 25B-14. Review of instrument by appropriate County department</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Upon receipt of a proposed covenant or conveyance concerning outdoor recreational or park land the Park and Recreation Department shall review same and make recommendations to the Board as to whether the land is used for and meets the criteria of outdoor recreational or park purposes as defined in this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Upon receipt of a proposed covenant or conveyance concerning environmentally endangered land, the Department of Environmental Resources Management shall review same and make recommendations to the Board as to whether the land qualifies as environmentally endangered as defined in this article and as to what conservation restrictions, if any, should be imposed on the land and its owner.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 75-33, § 4, 5-21-75; Ord. No. 79-105, § 1, 12-4-79)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 25B-15. Board may accept instrument by resolution; filing of instrument and resolution</catch_line>
<text>
The Board, in its discretion, may accept by resolution any instrument conveying the development right or establishing a covenant pursuant to the provisions of this article. If accepted, the instrument, together with a certified copy of the resolution of acceptance, shall be promptly filed with the appropriate officer for recording in the same manner as any other instrument affecting title to real property.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 25B-16. Assessment of lands which are subject of conveyance or covenant</catch_line>
<text>
When the development right in real property has been conveyed to and accepted by the Board or a covenant has been executed and accepted by the Board pursuant to the provisions of this article, the Miami-Dade County Property Appraiser, in valuing for tax purposes the lands which are the subject of such conveyance or covenant, shall consider no factors other than those relative to its value for the present use and shall follow the intent of the Legislature of this State expressed in the preamble to Chapter 67-528, Laws of Florida.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 25B-17. Reconveyance of development rights or release of owner from terms of covenant; payment of deferred tax liability</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
After making a conveyance of the development right or executing a covenant pursuant to this article, the owner of said land or anyone with the owner's knowledge or consent shall not use said land in any manner inconsistent with the development right voluntarily imposed, or with the terms of the covenant without first obtaining a written instrument from the Board, which instrument reconveys all or part of the development right to said owner or releases said owner from the terms of the covenant, and which instrument must be promptly recorded in the same manner as any other instrument affecting the title to real property. Any violation of this section shall constitute a breach of the conveyance or covenant, for which breach the Board, after holding a hearing, may reconvey the conveyance or revoke the covenant and require the owner of the land to pay the deferred tax liability as such term is defined in Section 25B-17(b).
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The reconveyance or release shall only be made to the owner upon payment of the deferred tax liability, which shall be an amount equal to the difference between the total amount of taxes which would have been due in March in each of the previous years in which the covenant or conveyance was in effect if the property has been assessed under the provisions of Section 193.011, Florida Statutes, and the total amount of taxes actually paid in those years when the property was assessed under the provisions of this article, plus six (6) percent per annum interest on the amount so established. This payment shall be extended on the tax bill as a separate item by the County Tax Collector and shall be payable, without discount, at the time of payment of the other taxes on the bill.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Board, as title holder of the development right pursuant to this article, shall not convey said development right to anyone other than the record owner of the fee interest in the land to which the development right attaches or his heirs, assigns, or devisees. The release from a covenant or reconveyance to the owner of the fee or his heirs, assigns or devisees shall be made only after a determination by the Board that such release or reconveyance would not adversely affect the interest of the public. The Board shall not release a covenant or reconvey the development right to the record owner of the fee interest or his heirs, assigns or devisees without first holding a public hearing. Notice of said public hearing shall be published once a week for at least two (2) weeks in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County, Florida, prior to said hearing.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 75-33, § 7, 5-21-75; Ord. No. 79-105, § 1, 12-4-79)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 25B-18. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
The following terms whenever used in this article shall have the following meanings unless a different meaning is clearly indicated by the context:
<section prefix = "a">
Outdoor recreational or park purposes includes, but is not necessarily limited to, boating, golfing, swimming, horseback riding, and historical or scenic sites, and applies only to land which is open to the general public.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Qualified as environmentally endangered means land which has unique ecological characteristics, rare or limited combinations of geological formations, or features of a rare or limited nature constituting a habitat suitable for fish, plants, or wildlife, and which, if subject to development or conservation restrictions, would be consistent with the conservation, recreation, open space, and, if applicable, coastal protection elements of the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan; archaeological or scientific sites of lands subject to regulation by the State of Florida Department of Environmental Regulation or by the United States Army Corps of Engineers and defined as submerged lands by said respective agency. Examples of land qualified as environmentally endangered under this section are vegetative areas containing mangrove forests, hammock and tree islands, pinelands, wetlands, and native cypress forests.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Development right is the right of the owner of the fee interest in the land to change the use of the land.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Conservation restriction means a limitation on a right to the use of land, for purposes of conserving or preserving land or water areas predominantly in their natural, scenic, open or wooded condition, retaining such areas as suitable habitat for fish, plants or wildlife, or maintaining existing land uses by prohibiting or limiting:
<section prefix = "1">
Construction or placing of buildings, roads, signs, billboards or other advertising, utilities, or other structures on or above the ground.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Dumping or placing of soil or other substance or material such as landfill, trash, waste, or unsightly or offensive materials.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Planting, removal or destruction of trees, shrubs or other vegetation.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Excavation, dredging, or removal of loam, peat, gravel, soil, rock or other material substance in such a manner as to affect the surface.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Surface use, except for purposes that permit the land or water area to remain predominantly in its natural condition.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Activities detrimental to drainage, flood control, water conservation, erosion control, soil conservation, or fish and wildlife habitat preservation.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Any other act or use detrimental to the preserving or conserving of such areas for the purposes stated herein.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Present use is the manner in which the land is utilized on January first of the year in which the assessment is made.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Board is the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Covenant is a covenant running with the land.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Owner shall mean the owner or, if more than one (1) owner, the owners who have the fee simple title to the land. If the minimum contiguous area referred to above is under fee simple ownership of more than one (1) owner, then such owners may jointly submit a conveyance or covenant to meet the minimum area requirements herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Land shall mean a land or water area.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 25B-19. Savings clause</catch_line>
<text>
Unless the owner indicates otherwise to the Board, covenants and conveyances accepted by this Board prior to amendments of this article or the State enabling law (Section 193.501, Florida Statutes) shall remain in effect for the first ten-year period of such covenant or conveyance, provided that the terms and conditions of the covenant or conveyance are maintained.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (2) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 75-33, enacted May 21, 1975, provided that the provisions of said ordinance be included in this Code, but did not specify the manner thereof; hence codification of §§ 1—9 herein as Art. II, §§ 25B-11—25B-19, was at the discretion of the editors. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
