<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">Chapter 9 STANDARDS FOR CONSTRUCTION OF COUNTY BUILDINGS, ROADS, BRIDGES AND CAUSEWAYS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_III._SUSTAINABLE_BUILDINGS_PROGR</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 9-71. Title</catch_line>
<text>
This Article shall be entitled, "The Sustainable Buildings Program."
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 9-72. Policy</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be the policy of Miami-Dade County to incorporate, wherever practical, green building practices into the planning, design, construction, management, renovation, maintenance and decommissioning of buildings owned, financed, and/or operated by the County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 9-73. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
Unless specifically defined elsewhere in this Chapter, the definitions provided in this Section shall apply.
<section prefix = "a">
Green building is a structure that is designed, built, renovated, operated and reused in an ecological and resource-efficient manner.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Green building practices are environmentally and socially-conscious practices that emphasize processes and methods of design and construction that:
<section prefix = "i">
reduce exposure to noxious materials,
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
conserve non-renewable energy and scarce materials,
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
minimize life-cycle ecological impact of energy and materials,
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
employ renewable energy or materials that are sustainably harvested,
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
protect and restore local air, water, soils, flora and fauna, and
</section>
<section prefix = "vi">
support pedestrians, bicycles, mass transit and other alternatives to fossil-fueled vehicles.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
New construction is the design and construction of any new building, or an addition to an existing building.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Major renovation/remodel is any design and construction project that alters the structure of an existing building where the cost of construction is equal to or exceeds 50% of the building's replacement cost.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Non-major renovation/remodel is any design and construction project that alters the structure of an existing building where the cost of construction is less than 50% of the building's replacement cost.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Renovate is to improve or repair the condition of a building.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Sustainable building means building processes that integrate materials and methods that promote environmental quality, economic vitality, and social benefit through the design, construction and operation of the built environment.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 9-74. Staffing</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Sustainability Manager. The County Manager, or his designee, shall appoint a qualified staff person to serve as the Sustainability Manager, who will be charged with implementing the requirements of this Article, as well as coordinating the sustainability initiatives of other County departments and agencies. The Sustainability Manager shall be authorized to interpret and enforce all of the provisions of this Article.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Sustainability Liaison. All County departments engaged in designing and constructing County-owned buildings shall designate a staff member with authority or expertise in project management, architecture, landscape architecture, design, engineering, resource conservation, budget analysis and other skills to act as a liaison with the Sustainability Manager.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 07-65, ยง 3, 5-8-07)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 9-75. Measurement Standards and Compliance</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Rating System. The Sustainability Manager shall select a nationally-recognized rating system that sets standards for implementing green building practices in design and construction, which may include, but not be limited to, the Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design Rating System administered by the U.S. Green Building Counsel. This rating system will be used to measure compliance with the terms of this Article. The rating system selected for each category of construction by the Sustainability Manager shall be set forth in an Implementing Regulation to be approved by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Standard for County-owned buildings. All new construction, major renovations/remodels, and non-major renovations/remodels of County-owned buildings shall adhere to the nationally-recognized rating system standards designated by the Sustainability Manager for that particular category of construction, as described in subsection (a) above.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Standard for County-financed, County-leased, and County-operated buildings. The Sustainability Manager shall evaluate and propose criteria for the use of green building practices in connection with County-financed, County-leased, and County-operated buildings. The criteria shall be set forth in an Implementing Regulation to be approved by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Interpretations, exemptions and waivers. The Sustainability Manager shall establish such processes, policies, and procedures as may be necessary to guide the consideration of requests for interpretations of this Article, or for exemption or waiver from the requirements of this Article.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 07-65, ยง 3, 5-8-07)</history>
</law>
