<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_CI._SOUTH_MIAMI-DADE_DEVELOPMENT</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1481. Creation of the South Miami-Dade Development Agency</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created and established as an instrumentality of Miami-Dade County an agency which shall be named and known as the South Miami-Dade Development Agency (hereinafter referred to as the "Agency"). The Agency may exercise all those powers either specifically granted herein or necessary in the exercise of the powers herein enumerated.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1482. Composition</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Membership. Members of the Agency shall serve without compensation. The voting membership, reflecting the ethnic, racial, and gender diversity of Miami-Dade County, shall be composed of the designated representatives of each of the following organizations:
<section prefix = "1">
Chamber South
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Perrine Cutler Ridge Council
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Vision Council
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Greater Homestead/Florida City Chamber of Commerce
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Everglades National Park
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Biscayne National Park
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Tropical Everglades Visitor Association
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
City of Homestead
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
City of Florida City
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Empowerment Zone-Florida City Neighborhood Assembly
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Empowerment Zone-Homestead Neighborhood Assembly
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
West Perrine CDC
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Goulds CDC
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
Naranja-Princeton CDC
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
South Miami Heights CDC
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
Princeton CDC
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
Leisure City OCED
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
Haitian Organization for Women
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
Unique Coalition of Minority Businesses (UCOMB)
</section>
<section prefix = "20">
Greater Miami Convention and Visitors Bureau
</section>
<section prefix = "21">
Cutler Ridge Business Improvement District
</section>
<section prefix = "22">
Naranja Lakes Community Redevelopment Agency
</section>
<section prefix = "23">
Park of Commerce (Rockefeller Group)
</section>
<section prefix = "24">
Homestead Air Reserve Base
</section>
<section prefix = "25">
Agri-Council
</section>
<section prefix = "26">
Florida Nurserymen and Growers Association
</section>
<section prefix = "27">
Dade County Farm Bureau
</section>
<section prefix = "28">
Everglades Coalition
</section>
<section prefix = "29">
Beacon Council
</section>
<section prefix = "30">
Greater Miami Chamber of Commerce
</section>
<section prefix = "31">
Coalition of Florida Farmworkers Organizations
</section>
<section prefix = "32">
Dade County Public Schools Region 5
</section>
<section prefix = "33">
Dade County Public Schools Region 6
</section>
<section prefix = "34">
Miami-Dade Community College-Homestead Campus
</section>
<section prefix = "35">
Job Corps
</section>
<section prefix = "36">
University of Miami
</section>
<section prefix = "37">
Florida International University
</section>
<section prefix = "38">
University of Florida
</section>
<section prefix = "39">
Urban Land Institute/Southeast Council
</section>
<section prefix = "40">
Newly Incorporated Municipalities within the geographic boundaries of this article
</section>
<section prefix = "41">
Board of County Commission District Eight Office (ex officio)
</section>
<section prefix = "42">
Board of County Commission District Nine Office (ex officio)
</section>
<section prefix = "43">
South Miami-Dade State Legislative Districts (ex officio)
</section>
<section prefix = "44">
Miami-Dade County Mayor's Office (ex officio)
</section>
<section prefix = "45">
South Miami-Dade Congressional Districts (ex officio)
</section>
<section prefix = "46">
City of Palmetto Bay
If any Member's designated representative also holds a federal, state, or local elected office, that representative shall serve in an ex officio capacity. No person may serve simultaneously as the designated representative for more than one Member. Additional Members may be added as set forth in the by-laws. Vacancies shall be filled in the same manner by which the original representatives were appointed, with a special emphasis on choosing persons representative of the gender, racial and ethnic composition of the entire community.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Removal of Members. Members and designated representatives may be removed in accordance with the provisions of Chapter 2-11.38 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Tenure. Terms shall be established by the Agency by-laws.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
Qualifications. Each Member and designated representative must comply with the requirements of Chapter 2-11.38 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
Organization and procedure.
<section prefix = "1">
Officers. The Agency shall organize after the Members and designated representatives thereof have qualified to serve and shall elect one (1) of its representatives as chairperson and such other officers as may be necessary. In addition, the Agency shall make, adopt and amend by-laws, rules and regulations for its own governance.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Meetings. The Agency shall hold regular meetings and such other meetings as it deems necessary. Quorum shall be defined in the Agency by-laws. Minutes shall be kept of all meetings and all meetings shall be public.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Committees. The Agency shall appoint any committees it deems necessary.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 02-218, § 2, 12-18-02)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1483. Applicability of County rules and procedures</catch_line>
<text>
The Agency shall at all times operate under the Florida Open Government laws, including the "Sunshine Law," public meeting laws and public records laws and shall be governed by all State and County conflict of interest laws, as applicable, including the Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance, Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1484. Voting requirements</catch_line>
<text>
Designated Representatives may not in turn designate alternates to serve and/or vote on their behalf.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1485. Powers and duties</catch_line>
<text>
The Agency shall have the following powers, duties, functions and responsibilities:
<section prefix = "A">
To serve in an advisory capacity to the Board of County Commissioners with respect to all issues affecting economic development in South Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
To serve in an advisory capacity to the Board of County Commissioners with respect to implementation of the Homestead Reuse Plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
To recommend expenditure of funds either derived from or allocated to the reuse of the former Homestead Air Force Base surplus property.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
To serve as a clearinghouse of information regarding South Miami-Dade County economic development.
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
To encourage economic development initiatives in South Miami-Dade County from Southwest 152 Street to the Monroe County line.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1486. Staff Support</catch_line>
<text>
The Agency shall select, with the approval of the County Manager, a full-time Executive Director. The Clerk of the Board shall record all meetings and the County Manager shall provide adequate funding, staff and support services to enable the Agency to carry out its duties and responsibilities.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-1487—2-1500. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (110) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 02-218, §§ 1—6, adopted Dec. 18, 2002, did not specifically amend the Code. Hence, its inclusion herein as article CI, sections 2-1481—2-1486, was at the discretion of the editor. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
