<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">Chapter 9 STANDARDS FOR CONSTRUCTION OF COUNTY BUILDINGS, ROADS, BRIDGES AND CAUSEWAYS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_I._IN_GENERAL</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 9-1. Construction of expressway in south Miami-Dade area east of U.S. Highway No. 1 prohibited</catch_line>
<text>
No person, as defined in Section 1.01(3), Florida Statutes (1971), nor public body, as defined by Section 1.01(9), Florida Statutes (1971), shall construct any expressway, as defined by Section 33-121.10(a), Miami-Dade County Code, in that area of Miami-Dade County east of U.S. Highway No. 1 (South Dixie Highway) and south of Flagler Street. The word "construct" as used herein includes, but is not limited to, the expansion of any existing road, street, highway or other public right-of-way into an expressway.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 9-2. Expansion of Old Cutler Road</catch_line>
<text>
The expansion of that particular road in Miami-Dade County known as Old Cutler Road, from its present character as a country road, is hereby prohibited, and no person, as defined by Section 1.01(3), Florida Statutes (1971), nor public body, as defined by Section 1.01(9), Florida Statutes (1971), shall undertake to widen or expand Old Cutler Road from its presently existing paved right-of-way; provided, for the purpose of assuring safe travel on Old Cutler Road, the Board of County Commissioners, after public hearing with the reasonable notice by newspaper publication, may permit the limited expansion of intersections of said Old Cutler Road.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 9-2.1. Expansion of Coral Way between LeJune and Red Road</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The expansion of that particular road in Miami-Dade County known as Coral Way (between LeJune and Red Roads), from its present character as an historic, canopied roadway, is hereby prohibited, and no person, as defined by Section 1.01(3), Florida Statutes (1971), nor public body, as defined by Section 1.01(9), Florida Statutes (1971), shall undertake to widen or expand Coral Way (between LeJune and Red Roads) from its presently existing paved right-of-way.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Both the expansion of the original plazas known as Ponce de Leon, Columbus, Balboa, Segovia and LeJune and the removal or alteration of the live oak trees which canopy the roadway are hereby prohibited and no person, as defined by Section 1.01(3), Florida Statutes (1971), nor public body, as defined by Section 1.01(9), Florida Statutes (1971), shall undertake to alter or remove said plazas or live oak trees as they presently exist.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 76-54, §§ 1, 2, 6-15-76)</history>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 76-54, §§ 1, 2, is included herein as § 9-2.1 at the discretion of the editors.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 9-2.2. Expansion of Main Highway (between Charles Street and Douglas Road), Ingraham Highway (between Douglas Road and LeJune Road) and Douglas Road (between Main Highway and Ingraham Highway)</catch_line>
<text>
The expansion of the particular roads in Miami-Dade County known as Main Highway (between Charles Street and Douglas Road) and Ingraham Highway (between Douglas Road and LeJune Road) and Douglas Road (between Main Highway and Ingraham Highway) from their present character as historic, canopied roadways is hereby prohibited, and no person, as defined by Section 1.01(3), Florida Statutes (1971), nor public body, as defined by Section 1.01(9), Florida Statutes (1971), shall undertake to widen or expand Main Highway (between Charles Street and Douglas Road) or Ingraham Highway (between Douglas Road and LeJune Road) or Douglas Road (between Main Highway and Ingraham Highway) from their presently existing paved right-of-way.
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 76-55, § 1, is included herein as § 9-2.2 at the discretion of the editors.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 9-2.3. Expansion of Sunset Drive between Cocoplum Circle and Galloway Road</catch_line>
<text>
The expansion or widening of that particular road in Miami-Dade County known as Sunset Drive (S.W. 72nd Street) from Cocoplum Circle to Galloway Road (S.W. 87th Avenue), except those portions of Sunset Drive within the corporate limits of the City of South Miami, is hereby prohibited. No person or entity, whether public or private, shall undertake to expand or widen the foregoing portions of Sunset Drive from Cocoplum Circle to Galloway Road.
</text>
<EditorsNote>
At the discretion of the editor, § 1 of Ord. No. 83-10, adopted March 1, 1983, has been included as Code § 9-2.3
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 9-2.4. Expansion of Crandon Boulevard on Key Biscayne</catch_line>
<text>
The expansion or widening of that particular road in Miami-Dade County known as Crandon Boulevard on Key Biscayne is hereby prohibited. No person or entity, whether public or private, shall undertake to expand or widen the foregoing roadway, or to alter the median strip thereof or to construct a bicycle path (except for landscape maintenance and enhancement); provided, however, for the purpose of assuring safe travel on Crandon Boulevard, the Board of County Commissioners, after public hearing, with reasonable notice by newspaper publication, may permit the limited expansion of intersections or the alteration of the median strip or the construction of a bicycle path of said Crandon Boulevard.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 9-3. Contract extensions; exemption from requirements</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
When, following the receipt of competitive bids, the County has entered into a contract with a particular builder or contractor calling for the construction of a project and that contract requires the builder to complete the project or some defined portion thereof by a specified date or else be liable to the County for liquidated damages, the Board of County Commissioners may, in its discretion, by majority vote extend the period of time in which the project may be completed for good cause shown and demonstrated, before or after the specified date for completion of the project stated in the contract. For purposes of this section, good cause may be established only if the cause of the construction delay is expressly contemplated and provided for in the underlying contract, and if such delay is non-contractor caused and non-compensable to the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
This section shall not apply to any contracts for the construction of all or any part of Stage I of the Rapid Transit System under Section 2-171, or to any contracts for the Aviation Department under Section 2-285 or to any contracts covered by Section 2-8.2.7
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 72-73, § 1, 10-12-72; Ord. No. 79-76, § 3, 9-18-79; Ord. No. 95-64, § 4, 4-6-95; Ord. No. 98-96, § 2, 7-7-98; Ord. No. 00-34, § 1, 3-9-00)</history>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 72-73, § 1, added § 9-1, which was redesignated as § 9-3 at the discretion of the editors inasmuch as §§ 9-1 and 9-2 already existed in the Code.

Note—See editor's footnote to Art. XX of Ch. 2
Cross reference— County Manager's authority to manage Stage I of the Rapid Transit System, § 2-171.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Secs. 9-4—9-50. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
</law>
