<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_CXXIII._NW_7TH_AVENUE_CORRIDOR_C</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1881. Community Redevelopment Agency created</catch_line>
<text>
Pursuant to the provisions of Section 163.356, Florida Statutes, this Board created a public body corporate and politic to be known as the NW 7th Avenue Community Redevelopment Agency (the "Agency"). The Agency shall be constituted as a public instrumentality and the exercise by the Agency of the powers conferred by the Act and delegated by the Board shall be deemed and held to be the performance of an essential public function.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1882. Purpose</catch_line>
<text>
The purpose of the Agency is to carry out the community redevelopment purposes of the Act.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1883. Membership</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The board of commissioners of the Agency shall consist of not fewer than five or more than nine commissioners. The terms of office of the commissioners shall be for four (4) years, except that three of the members first appointed shall be designated to serve terms of one (1), two (2) and three (3) years, respectively, from the date of their appointments, and all other members shall be designated to serve for terms of four (4) years from the date of their appointments. A vacancy occurring during a term shall be filled for the unexpired term. Any person may be appointed as commissioner if he or she resides or is engaged in business, which means owning a business, practicing a profession, or performing a service for compensation, or serving as an officer or director of a corporation or other business entity so engaged, within the area of operation of the agency, which shall be coterminous with the area of operation of the County, and is otherwise eligible for such appointment under the Act. Each commissioner shall hold office until his or her successor has been appointed and has qualified. A certificate of the appointment or reappointment of any commissioner shall be filed with the Clerk of the Board, and such certificate shall be conclusive evidence of the due and proper appointment of such commissioner.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A commissioner shall receive no compensation for services, but is entitled to the necessary expenses, including travel expenses, incurred in the discharge of duties.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Board may remove a commissioner for inefficiency, neglect of duty or misconduct in office only after a hearing and only if he or she has been given a copy of the charges at least ten (10) days prior to such hearing and has had an opportunity to be heard in person or by counsel.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 06-18, § 3, 2-7-06)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1884. Procedure</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Chair. The Board shall designate a chair and vice-chair from among the commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Meetings. The powers of the Agency shall be exercised by the commissioners thereof. A majority of the commissioners constitutes a quorum for the purpose of conducting business and exercising the powers of the agency and for all other purposes. Action may be taken by the Agency upon a vote of a majority of the commissioners present, unless in any case the bylaws require a larger number.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 06-18, § 4, 2-7-06)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1885. Public officials, commissioners and employees subject to code of ethics</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The officers, commissioners and employees of the Agency shall be subject to the provisions and requirements of Part III of Chapter 112, Florida Statutes, and Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
If any official, commissioner or employee presently owns or controls, or owned or controlled within the preceding two (2) years, any interest, direct or indirect, in any property which he or she knows is included or planned to be included in the NW 7th Avenue Corridor Community Redevelopment Area, he or she shall immediately disclose this fact in the manner provided in Part III of Chapter 112, Florida Statutes. Any disclosure required to be made by this section shall be made prior to taking any official action.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
No commissioner or other officer of the Agency exercising powers pursuant to the Act shall hold any other public office under the County other than his or her commissionership or office with respect to such Agency.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 06-18, § 5, 2-7-06)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1886. Powers</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Board hereby delegates the following community redevelopment powers to the Agency in accordance with the Act:
<section prefix = "i">
Initiate, prepare and adopt a plan of redevelopment and any amendments thereto, which plan and amendments shall be subject to subsequent review and approval by the Board; and
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
All powers not specifically delegated to the Agency are reserved exclusively by the Board.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Agency cannot commit itself or the County to any expenditure of funds without the specific approval of the Board.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 06-18, § 6, 2-7-06)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1887. Staff</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager and the Office of the County Attorney shall provide to the Agency adequate staff and support services to enable it to carry out its purposes.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1888. Annual Report</catch_line>
<text>
No less than once per year, the Agency shall submit a written report to the Board detailing its activities during the past year and outlining its contemplated activities for the ensuing year.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1889. Appointments</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Board hereby appoints the following persons to the position of commissioners of the Agency each of whom shall serve a four-year term from the effective date of their appointments pursuant to Resolution Nos. R-1370-08, R-86-09 and R-571-11, respectively, which are ratified and approved by this ordinance:
<section prefix = "i">
Mack Samuel;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Dr. Mae Bryant;
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Alphoncia Lafrance-Mompremier;
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
Todd Ruderman;
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
Gene Lamondo:
</section>
<section prefix = "vi">
William Wallace IV; and
</section>
<section prefix = "vii">
Donald E.W. Kressly.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Board hereby designates Alphoncia Lafrance-Mompremier as Chair and Todd Ruderman as Vice Chair of the Agency.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All future appointments of chairs, vice-chairs and board of commissioners of the Agency shall be made by amendment to this Ordinance.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
All prior and current appointments made pursuant to Resolution Nos. R-1370-08, R-86-09, R-164-10 and R-571-11 are ratified and approved by this ordinance, as of the effective date of the appointments provided by these resolutions.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 06-18, § 9, 2-7-06; Ord. No. 12-23, § 1, 4-3-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1890. [Annual report; financial statement; publication.</catch_line>
<text>
The Agency shall file with the Board and with the State of Florida, on or before March 31 of each year, a report of its activities for the preceding fiscal year, which report shall include a complete financial statement setting forth its assets, liabilities, income, and operating expenses as of the end of such fiscal year. At the time of filing the report, the Agency shall publish in a newspaper of general circulation in the County a notice to the effect that such report has been filed with the County and that the report is available for inspection during business hours in the office of the Clerk of the Board and in the office of the Agency.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-1891—2-1900. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
</law>
