<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_X._DOWNTOWN_KENDALL_SYSTEM_BETTE</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-201. Agreement</catch_line>
<text>
This Board finds that it is in the best interest of Miami-Dade County to waive competitive bidding procedures and the provisions of Administrative Order 3-2 and hereby authorizes the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department (Department), to enter into an agreement with Downtown Dadeland Residential Condominiums, LLC, to install new water and sewer lines in North Kendall Drive; formal bidding being waived by two-thirds (2/3) vote of the Board, pursuant to Section 255.20(1)(a)(10) of the Florida Statutes and Section 4.03(D) of the Home Rule Charter.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-202. Lump sum payment</catch_line>
<text>
The Board hereby authorizes the Department to pay Downtown Dadeland Residential Condominiums, LLC, a maximum lump sum amount of $572,897 for the installation of new water and sewer lines within a certain limited area of the Downtown Kendall Urban Center District.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-203. Special water construction connection charge</catch_line>
<text>
The Board hereby approves the imposition of a special water construction connection charge of $0.58 per average daily gallon per day of water capacity at the time water service is requested for all buildings and properties located south of North Kendall Drive, east of the Palmetto Expressway (S.R. 826) and northwest of the Metrorail Corridor, which utilize the new water system capacity provided by the new water lines.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-204. Special sewer construction connection charge</catch_line>
<text>
The Board hereby approves the imposition of a special sewer construction connection charge of $0.73 per average daily gallon per day of sewer capacity at the time sewer service is requested for all buildings and properties located south of North Kendall Drive, between the Palmetto Expressway (S.R. 826) and Dadeland Boulevard, and lying northwest of the Metrorail Corridor, system capacity provided by the new sewer lines..
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-205. Collection of charges</catch_line>
<text>
The Department is hereby authorized and empowered to charge and collect the special water and sewer construction connection charges from property owners and developers who receive new or increased water and sewer service from the new lines and the capacity provided thereby after the effective date herein and to require payment of said charges as a condition precedent to the provision of water and/or sewer service. Connection charges as required in this Section shall be supplemental to all other charges, including connection charges, due the Water and Sewer Department.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-206. Properties exempt from charges</catch_line>
<text>
Properties and buildings located south of North Kendall Drive, east of the Palmetto Expressway (S.R. 826) and northwest of the Metrorail Corridor which are receiving water and/or sewer service or have previously obtained contractual commitment for water and/or sewer service from the Department on the effective date of this ordinance shall not be subject to payment of the special water and sewer construction connection charges; however, the charge shall be imposed for additional water and/or sewer capacity furnished after said date.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-207. Termination of authority</catch_line>
<text>
The authority to charge and collect the special water and sewer construction connection charges shall terminate when the Department has been reimbursed for actual project construction costs of the new water and sewer lines, including engineering costs.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-208. Other charges</catch_line>
<text>
The special water and sewer construction connection charges shall be required in addition to other charges including standard water and sewer connection charges.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (10) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 03-95, §§ 2—9, adopted April 22, 2003, did not specifically amend the Code. Hence, its inclusion herein as article X, sections 32-201—32-208, was at the discretion of the editor. Ord. No. 06-128, § 2, adopted Sept. 12, 2006, changed the title of article X from Downtown Dadeland Residential Condominiums to Downtown Kendall System Betterment. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
