<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XVIII._MIAMI-DADE_COUNTY_REMETER</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-380. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
The following words and phrases when used in this section shall have the following meanings:
AWWA shall mean the American Water Works Association.
CSD shall mean the Miami-Dade County Consumer Services Department.
Code shall mean Code of Miami-Dade County.
Commission shall mean the Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners.
Director shall mean the Director of the CSD or his/her designee.
Individual unit shall mean the occupied space by a specific resident in a multiple unit property, including but not limited to individual units, common areas and swimming pools.
Master meter shall mean a meter used to measure all water service usage of a multiple unit property, including but not limited to individual units, common areas and swimming pools.
Multiple unit property shall mean a property where two (2) or more units are served by a single master meter, including but not limited to, condominiums, cooperatives, apartment and office buildings, town houses, mobile home parks and shopping centers.
Municipality shall mean any self-governing jurisdiction in Miami-Dade County.
Owner shall mean a person, firm, corporation or other business entity who owns a multiple unit property and who purchases water service from WASD at retail rates, and provides remetering.
Partial submetering shall mean the use of a submeter which does not measure the total water service consumption of an individual unit in a multiple unit property resulting in a prorated or estimated water service bill.
Registration shall mean the authorization by the Director required by this article in order to engage in remetering.
Remeterer shall mean a person, firm, corporation or other business entity that provides two (2) or more services to the Owner pertaining to remetering, including but not limited to, submeter installation, submeter reading, billing and record keeping.
Remetering shall mean the resale of water service by use of a submeter by an Owner at a rate or charge which does not exceed the Owner's actual purchase price.
Resident shall mean a person who purchases water service from an Owner.
Submeter shall mean the meter serving an individual unit of a multiple unit property and that is installed after the outlet side of the master meter that allows the reading of individual water service consumption.
Submetering shall mean the measuring of water service to an individual unit by placing a submeter after the outlet side of the master meter to obtain actual readings for the individual unit.
WASD shall mean the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department.
Water service shall mean water and/or sewer service as provided by WASD.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-381. Intent and application</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It is the intent of this article to permit remetering and encourage the conservation of water resources.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The provisions of this article shall be construed liberally to promote the following: To establish a comprehensive regulatory system to assure that the practice of remetering of water services and billing are just and reasonable; to assure that billing for water service at multiple unit properties is based on individual unit usage; to assure that Residents are charged fairly for the services provided by those engaged in remetering; to assure that Owners and Residents are protected from unscrupulous business practices; and to establish the rights and responsibilities of the Owner, Resident and the Remeterer.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The provisions of this article shall apply to multiple unit properties utilizing water services. Effective January 1, 2009, all permit applications for new multifamily residential developments shall be required to include a submeter for each individual dwelling unit.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Any Owner or Remeterer who has installed submeters and who has been individually billing Residents for water service prior to the adoption of this article shall have ninety (90) days from the date of enactment to comply with the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Any municipality that operates its own water utility in Miami-Dade County may petition, in writing, that the CSD enforce remetering for their retail customers provided that the municipality adopts an ordinance or resolution authorizing Miami-Dade County to regulate water remetering in its municipality. In such cases, all references to WASD shall apply to that municipality's water service.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 96-137, §§ 1, 2, 9-17-96; Ord. No. 08-14, § 5, 2-5-08; Ord. No. 08-100, § 3, 9-2-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-382. Registration required</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Initial and annual registrations are required of owners and Remeterers. Each application for initial registration, renewal registration and duplicate or amended registration shall be on a form prescribed by the Director and shall be accompanied by a fee in such amount as shall be established by Administrative Order of the County Manager. Such fees shall be effective upon approval by the Commission. All fees collected shall be deposited in a separate County fund to be utilized solely for the administration and enforcement of this article. No part of such fund shall be used for purposes other than the aforesaid.
<section prefix = "1">
Each application for registration by an Owner shall contain the following information:
<section prefix = "a">
Name, address and type of property to be remetered; Owner's name, telephone number and tax identification number and/or social security number, legal business and trade name, if applicable; names and addresses of any partners, officers, other corporations, entities or trade names through which business is conducted; number of units being remetered; name, address, contact person and telephone number of Remeterer; and name, address, contact person and telephone number of management company, if applicable.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Copy of sample lease or condominium agreement that states individual unit is or may be submetered.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Date billing is to begin and copy of bill format that meets the requirements of Section 8A-385(a)(3)f.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Copies of plumbing and electrical permits, where applicable.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Specifications, as approved by AWWA Standards, of submeters and testing equipment to be used.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Schedule of submeter installations pursuant to Section 8A-387(d), if applicable.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Comparison report of Owner's regular water service charges from WASD and charges billed to the Residents by the Owner for the same period of time. This requirement is not necessary during initial registration.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
A list of all properties served in Miami-Dade County to include the property name, service address, contact person and telephone number.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Other additional information and items as the Director shall require to enforce the provisions of this article.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Each application for registration by a Remeterer shall contain the following information:
<section prefix = "a">
Company's legal business and trade name, principal or main address and telephone number, tax identification number and/or social security number, names and addresses of any other corporations, entities or trade names through which business is conducted; and names and addresses of Business Owners or Corporate Officers.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Copy of occupational license permitting company to do business in Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Copy of Certificate of Competency as a registered or certified plumbing contractor from Miami-Dade County or the State of Florida, if applicable.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Proof of workers' compensation insurance coverage, as required by Chapter 440 of the Florida Statutes, or a state certificate of exemption.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Proof of comprehensive general liability which shall have a minimum limit of three hundred thousand dollars ($300,000.00) per occurrence combined single limit for bodily injury and property damage liability.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Specifications, as approved by AWWA Standards, of submeters and testing equipment to be used.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Other additional information and items as the Director shall require to enforce the provisions of this article.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Each initial application for registration by an Owner or Remeterer who has installed submeters and has been individually billing Residents for water service usage prior to the adoption of this article shall contain, in addition to the requirements in paragraphs (1) and (2) above, the following information:
<section prefix = "a">
Comparison report of Owner's regular water service charges from WASD and charges billed to the Residents by the Owner for the same period of time.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Copy of the signed plumbing and/or electrical permit card or other form of approval issued by the appropriate governmental agency of jurisdiction for the installed submeters.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Any change in ownership, address, telephone number, contact person or other information recorded on a registration application shall be reported to the Director, in writing, within ten (10) days of the change.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Registrations shall become effective upon the date the application is approved by the Director. Completed renewal applications must be submitted to the Miami-Dade County Consumer Services Department, by mail or in person, at least thirty (30) days prior to the expiration of the registration. An incomplete application shall be considered abandoned if an applicant fails to complete their application within sixty days from the date that the application is filed with the CSD. An application submitted subsequent to the abandonment of a former application shall be treated as a new application.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 96-137, §§ 1, 2, 9-17-96; Ord. No. 03-44, § 1, 3-11-03)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-383. Regulations</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Employees of the Owner and Remeterer performing work related to remetering, including but not limited to, submeter readers and submeter testers, shall display identification reflecting the Owner's or Remeterer's name and logo.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Only individual units may be submetered and each submeter shall only serve one (1) unit.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 96-137, §§ 1, 2, 9-17-96)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-384. Records and reports</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Owner shall maintain the following records and reports:
<section prefix = "1">
Name, address and telephone number of Owner; name, address and telephone number of the Remeterer; and name, address and telephone number of management company, if applicable.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Person to be contacted concerning questions or complaints about service and billing.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Resident's name and location of each unit being submetered.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Copies of the plumbing and electrical permits, where applicable.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Specifications, as approved by AWWA Standards, of submeters and testing equipment to be used on the subject property.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Other information as may be required by CSD to enforce the provisions of this article.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Resident access to submetering records. Upon reasonable request of a Resident, the Owner shall make available for the Resident's inspection, at an agreed upon time and place, the following records during normal business hours (normally, Monday through Friday between the hours of 8:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m.):
<section prefix = "1">
The billing from WASD to the Owner for the current month and the twelve (12) preceding months.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The calculation for billing, i.e., gallons or hundred (100) cubic feet (ccf), for the current month and the twelve (12) preceding months.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
All submeter readings and Resident billings for the individual unit for the current month and the twelve (12) preceding months.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
All submeter test results for the individual unit for the current month and the twelve (12) preceding months.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Documentation of separate account records for rent and/or maintenance fees and submetered water bills, including date of transaction, as required in Section 8A-385(a)(3)d.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Submeter records and reports. The Owner and/or Remeterer shall maintain the following submeter records and reports.
<section prefix = "1">
Submeter equipment record. A record of all submeters, showing the Resident's name and address, date of installation, submeter serial number and date of the last certified test.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Record of submeter tests. All submeter tests shall be referenced in the submeter record required by this section. The record of each test made shall show the serial number of the submeter, the type and manufacturer of the submeter and any testing equipment used, the date of calibration and certification of the testing equipment, unit number where submeter is installed, the date and type of test made, who performed the test, the error and/or accuracy percentage of testing and mathematical data to permit verification of all calculations.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Records and reports pertaining to paragraphs (a) and (b) above must be maintained for a period of four (4) years. Records and reports pertaining to paragraph (c) above must be maintained for a period of ten (10) years. All records and reports shall be provided and/or made available to the CSD upon request in Miami-Dade County.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 96-137, §§ 1, 2, 9-17-96)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-385. Billing</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The billing process for remetering activities shall be as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
Sale/rental agreement for submetering. All sale/rental agreements between the Owner and the Resident shall clearly state that the unit is or may be submetered, that bills for water service will or may be issued on a submetered basis, and that bills shall not include charges for water service for common areas and facilities. The Resident shall initial this provision on the sale/lease agreement. Each Owner shall provide the Resident, at the time the sale/lease is signed, a copy of a narrative summary prepared by CSD (one (1) copy will be provided by the CSD to the Owner) to inform the Resident about remetering. Current Residents must be notified of the information required in this section ninety (90) days prior to the implementation of the service, unless notice was otherwise provided in the Resident's sale/rental agreement.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Condominiums, cooperatives and other such properties in which the units are owned by the Residents shall be billed in the same manner as paragraph (1) above. All common area's water service usage shall be paid by all owners of the association as designated in their by-laws.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Rendering and form of submetered bill.
<section prefix = "a">
Bills shall be rendered for the same billing period as that of WASD, generally monthly or quarterly, unless service is rendered for less than that period. The submeters shall be read either during or no later than five (5) business days (excluding weekends and legal holidays) after WASD's scheduled window for reading the master meter. Bills shall be rendered as promptly as possible following the reading of the submeters.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The billing rate shall be that used by WASD in its billing to the Owner for water service.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Owner shall ensure that water service consumption billed to each individual unit is only for each unit's submetered usage.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
A separate bill must be issued with the submetered billing information, separate and distinct from any other charges, and shall not be combined with the sale, rental and/or maintenance payment or with any other service provided to the Resident.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The bill shall reflect only submetered usage and the applicable taxes.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The Resident's water service submeter bill shall show all of the following information:
<section prefix = "1">
The date and submeter reading of the period for which the bill is rendered.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The prior and current submeter readings.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The total gallons of ccf of water service being billed.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The computed rate for gallons or ccf being billed.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The total amount due for water service used and applicable taxes.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
The name and address of the Resident to whom the bill is issued.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
The name of the company rendering the submetering bill and the address and telephone number of the person or section from that firm that is to be contacted in case of a billing dispute.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
The date by which the Resident must pay the bill.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
The name, address and telephone number of the party to whom payment is to be made, if different from paragraph 7. above.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
If it is an estimated bill, the bill shall be distinctly marked as such.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
The telephone number of the CSD with a statement that indicates the CSD may be contacted if disputes are not resolved amicably with Owners and Remeterers.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Due date. The due date of the bill shall not be less than fifteen (15) days after issuance. A bill for service may be considered delinquent if not received by the due date. The postmark date, if any, on the envelope of the bill or on the bill itself shall constitute proof of the date of issuance. An issuance date on the bill shall constitute proof of the date of issuance if there is no postmark on the envelope or bill. If the due date falls on a holiday or weekend, the due date for payment purposes shall be the next business day after the due date.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Disputed bills. In the event a Resident disputes a bill, the Resident shall provide written notice to the Owner which specifically states the reason for the dispute. The Owner shall forthwith conduct an investigation and report the results, in writing, to the Resident within thirty (30) days. The investigation and report shall include, but not be limited to, the nature of the complaint; how the complaint was investigated; an explanation of the results, which shall include identification of any leaks, damaged pipes and running toilets; and, the corrective measures taken or the justification for the bill. A corrected bill must be issued if the disputed bill was found to be in error.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Overbilling and underbilling. If billings are found to be in error, the Owner and/or the Remeterer shall calculate a billing adjustment. If the Resident is due a refund, an adjustment shall be made for the entire period of the overcharges. If the Resident was undercharged, the Owner and/or Remeterer may backbill the Resident for the amount which was underbilled for a period not to exceed six (6) months. If the underbilling is twenty-five dollars ($25.00) or more, the Resident shall be offered a deferred payment plan option, for the same length of time as that of the underbilling. Adjustments for usage by a previous Resident may not be backbilled to the current Resident, except that condominium associations may transfer liabilities from owner to owner according to their condominium by-laws.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Delinquent accounts. A one-time per month penalty on current billing not to exceed ten (10) percent of current billing, or a flat rate fee not to exceed ten (10) percent of current billing, may be applied to delinquent accounts. If such penalty is applied, the bill shall indicate the amount due if paid by the due date and the amount due if the late penalty is incurred. No late penalty may be applied if the Resident has not been informed, in writing, of this condition and of the exact dollar amount or percentage amount of such late penalty. No late penalty may be applied if the bill is in dispute until ten (10) days after the dispute has been resolved.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Owners and remeterers shall not impose any extra charges on the Resident over and above the water service charges and including the applicable taxes that are billed by WASD to the Owner. The bill may not include a deposit, reconnect charge, or additional late penalty, other than as provided in item (7) above.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Estimated submetering bills. Estimated bills shall not be rendered unless:
<section prefix = "1">
The submeter has been tampered with or bypassed. The estimated billing shall not exceed two (2) billing periods.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The submeter is found not to be in conformance with AWWA accuracy standards or has stopped and found not to register for any period. The Owner may impose an estimated charge for a period not to exceed one (1) billing period, based on amounts used under similar conditions by the same resident during periods preceding or subsequent thereto, or during the corresponding period in previous years.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 96-137, §§ 1, 2, 9-17-96)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-386. Submeters</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Submeter requirements are as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
Use of submeter. All water resold by an Owner shall be charged for by submeter measurements. The submeter shall conform to AWWA Standards C700, C708 or C710. All submeters shall be rated for a working pressure of at least 150 psi.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Installation by Owner and/or Remeterer. Each Owner and/or Remeterer shall be responsible for providing, installing and maintaining in good working condition all submeters necessary for the measurement of water service to the Residents. A shut-off valve shall be installed on the water line on the inlet side of the submeter.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Tamper-proof seal. Each submeter must have a tamper-proof seal or device. This seal or device shall be clearly noticeable to detect if the submeter has been tampered with.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Submeter readings. Each submeter shall indicate clearly the gallons and/or ccf of water for which charge is made to the Resident.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Location of submeters. Submeters and shut-off valves used in conjunction with the submeters shall be installed in accordance with AWWA Standards, and shall be accessible for reading, testing and inspection where such activities will cause minimum interference and inconvenience to the Resident.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Submeter testing.
<section prefix = "1">
[Tested and inspected for applicable size and type submeter.] All submeters must be tested and inspected, within the time intervals recommended by the AWWA for the applicable size and type submeter, by a facility that is accredited and in compliance with AWWA Standards.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Accuracy requirements for submeters. Submeters shall be tested for accuracy of registration at flow rates and test flow quantities in accordance with the applicable AWWA Standard.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Submeter tests requested by the Resident. Each Owner shall, upon a reasonable written request from the Resident and, if the Resident so desires, in the presence of the Resident or their authorized representative, perform a test of the accuracy of the submeter. Prior to scheduling the test, the Resident shall be advised of their liability, if any, for the testing and plumbing charge pursuant to paragraph (4) below. The test shall be made during normal business hours (normally, Monday through Friday between the hours of 8:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m.), at a time convenient to the Resident desiring to observe the test. Submeter tests must be performed by an accredited and certified water meter testing facility.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
[Test results.] Following completion of any test pursuant to paragraph (3) above, the owner shall advise the Resident in a timely manner but not to exceed sixty (60) days, in writing, of the test results. if the test results are within the AWWA Standard for the applicable water meter, the Owner may charge a reasonable testing and plumbing charge to the Resident. If the submeter's accuracy is not within the appropriate accuracy standards, no charge shall be made to the Resident for the test.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Submeter tests prior to installation. No submeter shall be placed into service unless it has been factory tested or tested by a certified testing facility to comply with AWWA Standards for accuracy. A certification of accuracy shall be required and made available to the CSD upon request. If any submeter is removed from service and replaced by another submeter for any purpose whatsoever, the CSD must be notified, in writing, of the serial number of the new submeter placed in the unit.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Submeter testing facilities and equipment.
<section prefix = "1">
Each Owner shall provide or have access to suitable measuring instruments for insuring the accuracy of shop and portable instruments used for testing submeters used in billing.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
All testing equipment shall be submitted once each year to a standardizing laboratory of recognized standing, for the purpose of testing and adjustment, and shall be accurate to within twenty-five hundredths (0.25) percent of the actual quantity of water, in accordance with AWWA Standards. Owners and Remeterers who do not own testing equipment must use an AWWA accredited facility to do testing when needed and obtain from them proof that instruments used have been tested and adjusted yearly.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
All shop and portable instruments used for testing submeters used in billing shall be calibrated by comparing them with a reference standard at least once each year. Test equipment shall at all times be accompanied by a certified calibration card signed by an AWWA approved facility, giving the date when it was last certified and adjusted. Records of certifications and calibrations shall be kept on file in the office of the Remeterer, Owner or the Owner's designee for no less than four (4) years.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 96-137, §§ 1, 2, 9-17-96; Ord. No. 03-44, § 1, 3-11-03)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-387. Prohibited practices</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It shall be unlawful for any person, firm, corporation or other business entity to engage in remetering in violation of the provisions of this article or to individually bill for water service other than by remetering.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
It shall be unlawful for any person, firm, corporation or other business entity to engage in the resale of water service without registering with the CSD.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
It shall be unlawful for any person, firm, corporation or other business entity to resell water service by use of a submeter at a rate or charge which exceeds the actual purchase price from WASD.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
No unit may be submetered unless all units are submetered in each building served by a master meter; provided, however, a building may be submetered in phases over a twelve-month period in accordance with a schedule filed with the CSD.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The submeters cannot be used to avoid water main extensions or payment of appropriate connection charges and other fees due to WASD.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Partial submetering and its billing based on a proration of water service is prohibited.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
It shall be unlawful for Owners to make a profit from remetering.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
It shall be unlawful for any person, firm, corporation or other business entity to place a submeter in use that is not registering in accordance with the AWWA specifications set forth in this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Disconnection of water service by an Owner or a Remeterer for delinquent bills is prohibited. Water service may only be disconnected for emergency purposes, such as water service line problems, leakage, flooding or in the event that a dangerous condition exists which is related to the service being provided.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 96-137, §§ 1, 2, 9-17-96)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-388. Administration</catch_line>
<text>
The CSD shall be responsible for the administration and enforcement of the provisions of this article.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-389. Director's duties, functions and powers</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The duties, functions, powers and responsibilities of the Director shall include the following:
<section prefix = "1">
Enforce all of the provisions of this article and any regulations promulgated thereunder.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Upon receipt of complaints or upon the Director's initiative, investigate, inspect, sample and test any matters regulated hereunder.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Issue, deny, revoke and suspend registrations and impose conditions, limitations and restrictions upon same in accordance with Section 8A-382 and Section 8A-391 of this Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Issue cease and desist orders, notices to correct violations and any other lawful orders of the Director which shall briefly set forth the general nature of the violation of this article and specify the time within which the violation shall be rectified or stopped. If an order to cease and desist or notice to correct violations or any other lawful order of the Director is not obeyed, the Director shall have the power and authority to revoke or suspend the registration of the person, firm, corporation or other business entity engaged in remetering, or deny the issuance of registration and take such other action authorized by this article. Notwithstanding the foregoing, no revocation or suspension of a registration by the Director shall be effective until the rendition by the hearing officer of the appeal, if any, of such revocation or suspension pursuant to Section 8A-397 of the Code of Miami-Date County, Florida, or until the time period for filing such appeal has expired, whichever is later. Orders to cease and desist, notices to correct violations and any other lawful orders of the Director hereunder may be enforced by the institution by the Director of civil actions for mandatory and prohibitory injunctions, civil penalties and other remedies and attorney's fees as set forth in Section 8A-396 of the Code of Miami-Dade County in a court of competent jurisdiction.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Institute civil actions or proceedings to enforce all the provisions of this article and subpoena issued by the Director or the hearing officer, including seeking mandatory and prohibitory injunctions, the imposition and recovery of civil penalties, restitution and such other remedies and attorney's fees as set forth in Section 8A-396 of the Code. Such civil actions or proceedings may be instituted by the Director regardless of whether a cease and desist order or notice to correct the violation or other lawful order of the Director has been issued or other administrative proceeding is pending.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Prosecute through the State Attorney in the criminal courts for violations of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Issue subpoena to compel the presence of any person or document or thing at any hearing, conference or proceeding authorized herein upon information or belief by the Director that a violation of any provision of this article has occurred or may occur.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Inquire into the practices, functions and policies of Owners and/or Remeterers and make such recommendations to the Commission as the Director may deem necessary.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Administer oaths and certify official acts of the Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Investigate, upon the Director's initiative, the practices of any Owner and/or Remeterer.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Apply to any judge of the circuit or county court, criminal or civil division, for the issuance of an administrative search warrant.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Conduct a program for monitoring consumer satisfaction levels in the field of remetering and make such monitoring information available to the Commission and the public.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Institute informal conferences for discussing and resolving any matter covered by this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
Publish and disseminate information to the public concerning remetering.
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
Submit to the Commission additional rules, regulations and standards to effectuate the purposes of this article. No such proposed rules, regulations or standards shall become effective until approved by the Commission by ordinance.
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
Enter into written assurances of compliance pursuant to Sections 8A-82.1 and 8A-390 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, with respect to the matters regulated under this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
The powers of the Director enumerated herein shall be in addition to and not a limitation of any other powers of the Director pursuant to any other provisions of this article or any other provisions of law or ordinance.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 96-137, §§ 1, 2, 9-17-96)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-390. Assurances of compliance</catch_line>
<text>
Each violation of any of the terms and conditions of a verified, written assurance entered into pursuant to Section 8A-82.1 of the Code with respect to the matters regulated under this article shall constitute a separate offense under this article by the persons who executed the assurance, their respective officers, directors, agents, servants and employees and by those persons in active concert or participation with any of the foregoing persons and who receive actual notice of the assurance of compliance. Decisions, actions and determinations of the Director, pursuant to Sections 8A-82.1 and 8A-389(16) or assurances of compliance executed thereunder, shall not be subject to review pursuant to Section 8A-397 of this Code.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-391. Denial, suspension and revocation</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Director may deny, suspend, or revoke a registration issued pursuant to the provisions of this article if the Director determines that the applicant or registrant has:
<section prefix = "1">
Submitted an application that is not filed in accordance with Section 8A-382, is incomplete or untrue in whole or in part.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Violated any provision of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Misrepresented or concealed a material fact on the application, renewal application or replacement application.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Aided or abetted a person who has not obtained a registration to evade or avoid the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Engages in fraudulent conduct in connection with remetering.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Violated any condition, limitation or restriction of a registration imposed by the Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Was enjoined by a court of competent jurisdiction from engaging in the trade or business of remetering or was enjoined by a court of competent jurisdiction with respect to any of the requirements of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Failed to comply with the terms of a cease and desist order, notice to correct a violation, written assurance of compliance or any other lawful order of the Director.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Notwithstanding the foregoing, no denial, suspension or revocation of a registration by the Director shall be effective until the rendition by the hearing officer of the appeal, if any, of such denial, suspension or revocation pursuant to Section 8A-397 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida or until the time period for filing such appeal has expired, whichever is later.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 96-137, §§ 1, 2, 9-17-96)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-392. Civil penalties</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Director may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to impose or recover a civil penalty in an amount of not more than ten thousand dollars ($10,000.00) for each violation of any of the provisions of this article. Each day during any portion of which such violation occurs or continues to occur constitutes a separate violation. The right of trial by jury shall be available in any court to determine both liability for and the amount of the civil penalties to be imposed and recovered hereunder.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Director may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to seek restitution and other equitable relief as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
To recover any sums and costs expended by the Director for investigating, preventing, controlling, abating or remedying any violation of any of the provisions of this article or of the regulations.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To provide restitution to any Owner and/or Resident injured by any violation of any of the provisions of this article or of the regulations.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Upon the rendition of judgment or decree by any of the courts of this state against any person or in favor of the Director under any of the provisions of this article, the trial court or in the event of an appeal, the appellate court, shall adjudge against any such person and in favor of the Director a reasonable sum as fees or compensation for the Director and attorney prosecuting the suit in which recovery is had.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
To seek temporary or permanent, prohibitory or mandatory injunctive relief to enforce compliance with or prohibit the violation of any of the provisions of this article or of the regulations.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 96-137, §§ 1, 2, 9-17-96)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-393. Criminal penalties</catch_line>
<text>
In addition to any other judicial or administrative remedies or penalties provided by law, rule, regulation or ordinance, if any person intentionally violates or fails or refuses to obey or comply with any of the provisions of this article or any lawful order of the Director or any cease and desist order of the Director or any notice to correct a violation or any assurance of compliance entered into pursuant to Section 8A-82.1 of the Code and this article, or any condition, limitation or restriction of a registration issued by the Director, such person, upon conviction of any such offense, shall be punished by a fine not to exceed two thousand five hundred dollars ($2,500.00), or by imprisonment not to exceed sixty (60) days in the County jail, or both, at the discretion of the court. Each day or portion thereof of continuing violation shall be deemed a separate offense.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-394. Presumption of continuous operation</catch_line>
<text>
Except as expressly provided otherwise in this article, any person operating in the resale of water service without first registering pursuant to this article shall be presumed to be operating on a continuous basis without registering from the date the registration was first required by this article. Such presumption may be overcome by evidence presented by the reseller of water service. This section creates a rebuttable presumption of continuous operation.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-395. Private cause of action</catch_line>
<text>
Any person who suffers a loss as a result of a violation of any of the provisions of this article, any lawful order of the Director, any cease and desist order or notice to correct a violation issued by the Director or any assurance of compliance entered into pursuant to Section 8A-82.1 of the code and this article, may recover compensatory damages, punitive damages, attorney's fees and court costs as allowed by law from the person committing such violation. Nothing herein shall be construed to require the Director to bring any such action on behalf of a private person.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-396. Attorney's fees and costs</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Upon the rendition of a judgment or decree by any of the courts of this state against any person and in favor of the Director under any of the provisions of this article, the trial court, or, in the event of an appeal in which the Director prevails, the appellate court, shall adjudge or decree against such person and in favor of the Director a reasonable sum as fees or compensation for the Director's attorney prosecuting the suit in which the recovery is had. Where so awarded, compensation or fees of the attorney shall be included in the judgement or decree rendered in the case. This provision shall apply to all civil actions, legal or equitable, filed after the effective date of this article by the Director. Cessation of any violation of any of the provisions of this article whatsoever, prior to rendition of a judgment or entry of a temporary or final decree, or prior to execution of a negotiated settlement, but after an action is filed by the Director under any of the provisions of this article, shall be deemed the functional equivalent of a confession of judgment or verdict in favor of the Director, for which attorney's fees shall be awarded by the trial court as set forth herein above.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
All judicial and administrative remedies in this article are independent and cumulative.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 96-137, §§ 1, 2, 9-17-96)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-397. Appeals and judicial review</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Any person, firm, corporation or other business entity regulated by this article who is aggrieved by any action, decision or determination of the Director, pursuant to this article may appeal, in writing, by filing a notice of appeal to a hearing officer appointed pursuant to Section 8CC-2 of the Code of Miami-Dade County within fifteen (15) days after the date of the action, decision or determination complained of. The notice of appeal shall be sent to the address indicated ont he action, decision or determination. The notice shall set forth the nature of the action, decision or determination to be reviewed and the basis for the appeal. The hearing officer shall specially set such appeal for hearing no later than at the earliest practicable regularly scheduled hearing date or as soon thereafter as possible, but no sooner than ten (10) days after the notice of appeal has been filed, and shall cause notice thereof to be served upon the person filing the appeal by first class mail. The hearing officer shall hear and consider all facts material to the appeal, in accordance with the procedures set forth in Sections 8CC-6(e), (f), (g), (i), (j), (k), (l), (m)(2), (n) of the Code of Miami-Dade County (any reference in these sections to Inspector shall mean "Director" and to violator shall mean "the person filing the appeal"), and may affirm, modify or reverse the action, decision or determination appealed from. The decision of the hearing officer shall constitute final administrative review and no rehearing shall be permitted. Nothing herein shall be construed to prevent or prohibit the Director from instituting any civil or criminal action or proceeding authorized by this article at any time. Customers shall not be deemed to be persons regulated by this article for the purposes of this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Director, the Miami-Dade County Consumer Advocate or any person, firm, corporation or other business entity regulated by this article who is aggrieved by any decision of the hearing officer pursuant to this section may seek judicial review in accordance with the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure. The words "action," "decision" and "determination" as used herein shall not include the filing or institution of any action, conference or proceeding by the Director in any court or otherwise. Customers shall not be deemed to be persons regulated by this article for the purpose of this section.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 96-137, §§ 1, 2, 9-17-96)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-398. Compliance with the South Florida Building Code</catch_line>
<text>
Any person, firm, corporation or other business entity engaged in remetering shall comply with the provisions of the South Florida Building Code. Such compliance shall include, but not be limited to, applying for and obtaining a plumbing permit and, where applicable, an electrical permit. Nothing in this section is intended to create an obligation on or the authority for the CSD to enforce the requirements of the South Florida Building Code.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-399. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (17) ---
Editor's note— Ordinance No. 96-137, §§ 1, 2, adopted September 17, 1996, repealed §§ 8A-380—8A-391 and enacted new §§ 8A-380—8A-398. Formerly, such sections pertained to similar provisions and derived from Ord. No. 95-101, § 1, 6-20-95. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
