<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="2">ARTICLE_XXXVII._MIAMI-DADE_WATER_AND_SEW</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-340. Declaration of legislative intent</catch_line>
<text>
The Board of County Commissioners hereby declares it to be the policy of Miami-Dade County to establish, own and operate a Countywide sanitary sewage collection and disposal system and water supply, treatment and distribution system. The Board finds that in order to best administer a Countywide water and sewer service within the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County with the ability effectively to provide for water and sewer services in conjunction with the growth and expansion needs of Miami-Dade County, it is necessary that the administration and policies of said agency be closely coordinated with the overall County plans and programs for growth and development. It is the further intent of this Board that the most effective method of implementing the foregoing policies and considerations is by creating a Countywide Water and Sewer Department to be administered under policy determinations of the Board of County Commissioners and the supervision of the County Manager through a Director of the Water and Sewer Department acting with the advice and assistance of a Water and Sewer Advisory Board.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-341. Establishing Department; Director; organization and employees</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created and established a County department to be known as the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department (hereinafter called "Department"). The Department shall be an agency Countywide in scope and authority, with the power to acquire, construct and operate water and sewer systems within the incorporated and the unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County and shall have the responsibility to develop and operate a Countywide water and sewer system for the purpose of providing potable water, sewage collection and disposal and water pollution abatement to the citizens of Miami-Dade County. The Director of the Department shall be appointed by the County Manager subject to the approval of the Board of County Commissioners and shall serve at the will of the County Manager. The organization and operating procedures and any future name changes of the Department shall be prescribed by administrative orders and regulations of the Manager. The Manager shall appoint such employees as may be necessary to operate the Department. The salaries and compensation of all personnel shall be determined by the County Commission upon recommendation of the Manager.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-342. Water and Sewer Advisory Board established</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created and established in Miami-Dade County an advisory Board to be known as the Miami-Dade County Water and Sewer Advisory Board.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-343. Membership of Board</catch_line>
<text>
The Water and Sewer Advisory Board shall consist of nine (9) members, each of whom shall be an individual of outstanding reputation, integrity, responsibility and business ability; provided, however, that no person who is an officer or employee of any water or sewer system or company operating within Miami-Dade County, shall be eligible for membership. The members of said Board shall be appointed and serve in accordance with the provisions of Sections 2-11.38, 2-11.38.1, 2-11.38.2, and 2-11.39 inclusive of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-344. Duties and functions of Board</catch_line>
<text>
The Water and Sewer Advisory Board shall have the following duties, functions and responsibilities:
<section prefix = "a">
To serve in an advisory capacity to the County Commission and the Department with respect to matters relating to long-range planning of a Countywide water and sewer system.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
To make a continuing study of the County's needs for water and sewer services.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
To formulate plans and programs for the implementation of necessary activities to effectuate its recommendations.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
To devise methods by which the existing water and sewer service may be improved to more fully provide service to the general public.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
To perform and carry out such duties and functions of an advisory nature as may be assigned by the Board of County Commissioners.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-345. Transfer of obligations</catch_line>
<text>
Immediately upon the effective date of the ordinance from which this article derives, Miami-Dade County, by and through its Board of County Commissioners, shall serve as the legally and validly organized successor to the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority and shall assume all of the rights, obligations, properties, and duties of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-346. Audit Review Committee</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
An Audit Review Committee is to be established composed of any or all of the following persons designated by the City of Miami: City Manager or designated representative; City Internal Auditor or designated representative; Director of Finance or designated representative; Public Works Director or designated representative; five (5) members of the public to be appointed by the City Commission.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
This Committee will perform a review of the annual budget, finances and operation of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority Department to ensure that all Department funds remain segregated from the general funds of Miami-Dade County and that all proceeds received by the Department are used for the operation, maintenance and improvement of the water and sewer system of Miami-Dade County, including administrative overhead billed by other County departments.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The review will be performed within the months of April through June of each year.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The findings of the Committee shall be reported to both the City Manager and County Manager for presentation by each Manager to their respective Boards of Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority Department will provide to each member of the Audit Review Committee information normally furnished to bondholders, other interested parties and any other information as shall be requested by the Board relevant to the performance of the review.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The Committee shall have such staff support from the Department as they may reasonably require to perform their responsibilities.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 86-8, §§ 1—6, 2-4-86)</history>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 86-8, adopted Feb. 4, 1986, did not amend the Code; therefore, codification of §§ 1—6 as § 2-346 has been at the editor's discretion.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-347. Service area of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority Department</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Section 2-340 of the Code of Miami-Dade County declares that it is the policy of Miami-Dade County to establish, own and operate a Countywide sanitary sewage collection and disposal system and water supply, treatment and distribution system. Accordingly, it is the intent of the Board of County Commissioners and of this section that the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority Department shall provide and furnish water and sewer service to all areas in Miami-Dade County located outside of municipal boundaries as existing on the effective date of this section which areas have not previously been granted or assigned by the Miami-Dade County Water and Sewer Board to a private or municipal water or sewer utility. The Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority Department is hereby empowered to decline to serve portions of the aforementioned service area whenever the Director of the Department or his designee determines that same is in the best interests of Miami-Dade County and the water and sewer customers. If a private or municipal water or sewer utility proposes to expand its assigned service area in Miami-Dade County, the utility shall make a written request to the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority Department. The Director of the Department or his designee shall determine whether or not the Department shall release the portion of the service area requested. The Director or his designee shall use the Director's or designee's best efforts to render a determination within thirty (30) days of receipt of the request. In making the aforesaid determinations, the Director or his designee shall consider the following evaluation factors:
<section prefix = "1">
Location of area proposed to be released.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Size of area.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Type of development planned for area.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Location of Department water and sewer facilities and those of the other utility.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Capability of Department water and sewer facilities and those of the other utility to serve the area.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Construction costs necessary to connect to Department facilities and to the facilities of the other utility.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Special considerations involving the public health, welfare and interest.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
If the Director of the Department or his designee makes a determination to release the Department's right to serve the area, the release shall be subject to the following conditions:
<section prefix = "1">
The public or private utility shall comply with the fire flow requirements set forth in the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The design and construction of all water and sewer facilities by the public or private utility must conform to the standards of the Department. All plans of proposed water and sewer facilities must be approved by the Department prior to construction.
The determination by the Director or his designee shall be in writing and shall be sent by regular mail to the requesting utility.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The provisions of this section shall not apply to areas within municipal boundaries as existing on the effective date of this section. However, this section shall be applicable to areas annexed by municipalities after the effective date of this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
A public or private utility which is aggrieved by a decision of the Director of the Department or his designee hereunder shall have the right to have the decision reviewed by the Board of County Commissioners by filing a petition with the Board within thirty (30) days of the written decision. The utility shall have the opportunity to present written and oral arguments to the Board in opposition to a decision of the Director or his designee. The Board of County Commissioners shall consider the evaluation factors listed above and may affirm, modify or reverse the decision of the Director or his designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
A public or private utility aggrieved by a decision by the Board of County Commissioners with respect to a release of service area by the Department may seek judicial review in accordance with the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 89-15, §§ 1—3, 3-7-89)</history>
<EditorsNote>
Sections 2 and 3 of Ord. No. 89-15 have been included herein at the discretion of the editor as 2-347(d) and (e).
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-348. Exemption from payment of water and sewer connection charges</catch_line>
<text>
Commercial or industrial real property development, as defined herein, shall be exempt from payment of water and sewer connection charges imposed by the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority Department, (hereinafter referred to as "Department") subject to the provisions of this section. For the purposes of this section, "commercial or industrial real property development" shall mean development of commercial or industrial real property for which new or increased water or sewer service or both is required as determined by the Department, excluding, however, commercial real property used for residential or dwelling purposes.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-348.1. Determination of exemption</catch_line>
<text>
An exemption from payment of water and sewer connection charges for commercial or industrial real property development shall be granted only upon a determination by the Board of County Commissioners that such real property development conforms to the following requirements:
<section prefix = "a">
The commercial or industrial real property development is consistent with the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The commercial or industrial real property development is located within an existing designated enterprise zone as defined in Section 290.004, Florida Statutes (1989), as the same may be amended from time to time, provided that: (1) the commercial or industrial real property development has been granted a property tax exemption under Sections 29-81 through 29-89 of the Code of Miami-Dade County; and (2) if such commercial or industrial real property development is located within a municipality, the municipality has also granted a property tax exemption under the aforesaid Sections 29-81 through 29-89; and
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Twenty five (25) percent of the employees of the commercial or industrial real property development are residents of the enterprise zone.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-348.2. Refund of connection charges</catch_line>
<text>
If an exemption is sought, water or sewer connection charges or both shall be paid prior to rendition of water and sewer service at the time required by the Department or volume customer of the Department, as may be applicable. The paid connection charges shall be refunded to the payor if so determined by the Board pursuant to Section 2-348.1.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-348.3. Dispute resolution procedure</catch_line>
<text>
This section establishes procedures for resolving disputes and protests between Miami-Dade County and persons adversely affected by the planning, design, construction and operation of sewage or wastewater treatment facilities financed by a loan from the State's Sewage Treatment Revolving Loan Fund authorized by Section 403.1835, Florida Statutes.
<section prefix = "1">
Applicability. This section applies only to those persons, other than participants in a competitive process, who are adversely affected by the planning, design, construction, and operation of sewage or wastewater treatment facilities owned by Miami-Dade County which are financed pursuant to Section 403.1835, Florida Statutes. Any protest made by any participant in a competitive process shall utilize the procedures set forth in Section 2-8.4 of the Code of Miami-Dade County. A person shall be defined as an individual, corporation, partnership, joint venture or other business entity.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Protest procedures. Any person subject to this section who is adversely affected shall file a written protest with the Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department within ten (10) calendar days after the basis of the protest is known or should have been known, whichever is earlier. Telephonic or verbal protests will not be considered. Filing shall be complete upon physical delivery to the Director or his designee. A protest which is untimely will not be considered. A complaining person (hereinafter complainant) shall bear the risk of nondelivery of a written protest, whether the protest is mailed or otherwise sent.
<section prefix = "a">
The written protest shall state the following:
<section prefix = "1">
The name, address and telephone number of the complaining person;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
A statement describing how the complainant is adversely affected;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
A statement describing how and when the complainant became aware of the basis for the protest;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
A statement identifying and describing the specific facts which are the basis of the protest;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
A statement which identifies and describes the specific laws, rules and regulations which are alleged to be the basis of the protest; and
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
The arguments in support of the complainant's position.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The complainant shall be given the opportunity to appear at a hearing before the Director to present all written and oral arguments in support of the protest. The complainant may be represented by an attorney. The complainant may present testimony of witnesses and may present facts, evidence and arguments in support of his position. The complainant shall have the right to cross examine witnesses. The Director shall ensure that an appropriate record of the entire hearing is made which record shall include the Director's ultimate findings and conclusions. All interested persons shall be afforded the same rights as the complainant.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Director shall consider all facts, evidence and testimony presented and shall render an appropriate ruling within ten (10) days which shall be conveyed in writing to the complainant and all other interested persons.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
A complainant who is aggrieved by a ruling of the Director shall have the right to have the ruling reviewed by the Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners by filing a petition with the Clerk of the Board, within thirty (30) days of the date of the Director's written ruling. The Clerk of the Board shall provide due notice of the hearing date. The complainant shall have a de novo hearing before the Board including all other rights which are provided pursuant to a hearing before the Director. The Board shall consider all facts, evidence and testimony presented and shall affirm, modify or reverse the ruling of the Director based on the showing made at the hearing. The Clerk shall ensure that a proper record of the entire hearing is made.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
No person who is adversely affected by the planning, design, construction, and operation of facilities financed pursuant to Section 403.1835, Florida Statutes, may apply to the courts for judicial review unless all administrative remedies provided for herein have been exhausted. It is the intention of the Board of County Commissioners that all steps as provided by this section shall be taken before any application is made to a court of competent jurisdiction.

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-349. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (62) ---
Cross reference— Water supply for fire suppression, § 2-103.20 et seq.; environmental control, Ch. 24; water and sewer regulations, Ch. 32; Miami-Dade County Water and Sewer Board, § 32-11 et seq.; Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority Department billing procedures, § 32-91 et seq. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
