<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_VI._PRIVATE_SECURITY_AGENCIES</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-151. Private security agencies; uniforms and vehicles; certain insignia prohibited</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful for any person:
<section prefix = "1">
To wear a badge, shield, clothing or uniform displaying in any manner the word "police," "sheriff," "deputy" or any group of words which includes the said words or any other marking or insignia customarily used to identify municipal police officers or officers of the Miami-Dade Police Department, unless such person is in fact a federal, State, County or municipal law enforcement officer; or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To own or operate a motor vehicle in the County marked or identified by the word "police" or any group of words which includes the said word or any other marking or insignia identifying the vehicle as a police vehicle, including but not limited to stars, badges, or shields, unless such vehicle is owned and operated by a federal, State, County or municipal law enforcement agency.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-152. Private security guards; wearing of certain uniforms prohibited</catch_line>
<text>
After June 1, 1971, it shall be unlawful for any employee of any private security agency to wear any badge, uniform, or insignia of such similarity of design, color or inscription to the official badge, uniform, or insignia of the Miami-Dade Police Department or of any municipal police department of the County which is indistinguishable therefrom at a distance of twenty (20) feet.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-153. Penalty for violation of article</catch_line>
<text>
Every person who is convicted of a violation of this article shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for not more than sixty (60) days or by both such fine and imprisonment.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (7) ---
Cross reference— Intrusion and burglar security, Ch. 8C. (Back)
State Law reference— Investigative and patrol services, F.S. ch. 493. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
