<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XVIII._RU-4_HIGH_DENSITY_APARTME</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-208. Uses permitted</catch_line>
<text>
Sec. 33-208. Uses permitted.
No land, body of water or structure shall be used, or permitted to be used and no structure shall be hereafter erected, constructed, moved or reconstructed, structurally altered or maintained for any purpose in an RU-4, High Density Residential District, which is designed, arranged or intended to be used or occupied for any purpose, except for one (1) of the following uses:
<section prefix = "1">
Those uses permitted in the RU-1, RU-1M(a), RU-1M(b), RU-2, RU-3, RU-TH and RU-RH Districts subject only to the requirements, limitations, and restrictions applicable thereto in said districts, including, but not limited to, lot width, area, setbacks, yard areas, height and coverage.
(1.1)
Workforce housing units in compliance with the provisions of Article XIIA of this code.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Multiple family apartment house containing fewer than eleven (11) units in a single building.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Multiple family apartment house containing eleven (11) or more units, subject to site plan review hereinafter provided. Where the applicant fails to secure the approval of the Department of Planning and Zoning the site plan reviewed shall be deemed denied. Where the site plan has been denied the applicant may correct the same to secure the approval of both Departments or appeal the denial for review by the Community Zoning Appeals Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Multiple family housing developments, provided that they are reviewed under the provisions of site plan review hereinafter provided, and only on approval after staff review of the site plan(s) to ensure compliance with all RU-4 District requirements and site plan review criteria. Said plan shall be in compliance with the requirements hereinafter provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Housing projects, whether in single or multiple buildings, and as defined in Chapter 421, of the Florida Statutes, built for or by the Miami-Dade County Department of Housing and Urban Development.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
A community residential facility as defined in Section 33-1(30.1) shall be permitted in a dwelling unit upon establishing the following:
<section prefix = "a">
That the total number of resident clients on the premises not exceed fourteen (14) in number. Facilities for more than fourteen (14) resident clients must be approved through public hearing pursuant to Section 33-13
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
That the operation of the community residential home be licensed by the State of Florida Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
That the community residential home not be located within a radius of one thousand two hundred (1,200) feet of another existing, unabandoned legally established community residential home in a multi-family zone. The one thousand two hundred-foot distance requirement shall be measured by following a straight line from the nearest portion of the structure of the proposed use to the nearest portion of the structure of the existing use;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
That the community residential home conform to existing zoning regulations applicable to other multiple family uses permitted by this section;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
That the sponsoring agency of the community residential home notify the Director in writing of its intention to establish said facility. Such notice shall contain the address and legal description of the site, the number of resident clients, as well as a statement from the State of Florida Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services indicating the need for and licensing status of the proposed facility. Absence of this notification and statement shall prohibit the use and occupancy of any structure for use as a community residential home; and
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Nothing in this section shall permit persons to occupy a community residential home who would constitute a direct threat to the health and safety of other persons or whose residency would result in substantial physical damage to the property of others.

Provisions of Ord. No. 82-5 shall not apply to those buildings for which a building permit has been issued and is in effect or where multiple family housing development or project site plan has been approved prior to February 2, 1982, by resolution of the Zoning Appeals Board or Board of County Commissioners, or prior to February 2, 1982, an agreement, letter of intent, or performance standards encompassing all of the basic items constituting a site plan has been recorded or adopted by resolution of the Zoning Appeals Board or the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-208.1. Site plan review—Generally</catch_line>
<text>
The Department shall review plans for compliance with zoning regulations and for compliance with the site plan review criteria. The purpose of the site plan review is to encourage logic, imagination, innovation and variety in the design process and thereby ensure the congruity of the proposed development and its compatibility with the surrounding area. All plans submitted to the Department shall be reviewed and approved or denied within fifteen (15) days from the date of submission. The applicant shall have the right to extend the fifteen-day period by an additional fifteen (15) days upon timely request made in writing to the Department. The Department shall have the right to extend the fifteen-day period by written notice to the applicant that additional information is needed to process the site plan. Denials shall be in writing and shall specifically set forth the grounds for denial. If the plan is disapproved, the applicant may appeal to the appropriate Community Zoning Appeals Board in accordance with procedure established for appeals of administrative decisions.
Procedure. Exhibits prepared by design professionals such as architects and landscape architects shall be submitted to the Department and shall include, but not be limited to the following:
<section prefix = "1">
Site plan including the following information:
<section prefix = "a">
Lot lines and setbacks.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Location, shape, size and height of existing and proposed buildings, decorative walls and entrance features.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Landscaping in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Location of off-street parking and loading facilities and waste collection areas.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Indication of exterior graphics, as required.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Indication of any site design methods used to conserve energy.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Floor plans and elevations of all structures, including total gross square foot area of each floor.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Figures indicating the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Gross and net acreage.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Amount of landscaped open space in square feet required and provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Amount of building coverage at ground level in square feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Total trees required and provided in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Parking required and provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Total amount of paved area in square feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Such other design data as may be needed to evaluate the project.

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-208.2. Same—Criteria</catch_line>
<text>
The following criteria shall be utilized in the plan review process:
<section prefix = "1">
Purpose and intent: The proposed development fulfills the objectives of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Planning studies: Design, planning studies or neighborhood area studies accepted or approved by the Board of County Commissioners that include development patterns or environmental design criteria which would apply to the development proposal under review shall be utilized in the plan review process.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Landscape: Landscape shall be preserved in its natural state insofar as is practicable by minimizing tree removal. Landscape shall be used to shade and cool, direct wind movements, enhance architectural features, related structure design to site, visually screen noncompatible uses and block noise generated by the major roadways and intense-use areas.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Buffers: Buffering elements in the form of architectural design and landscape design that provide a logical transition to adjoining existing or permitted uses shall be provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Scale: Scale of proposed structures shall be compatible with surrounding proposed or existing uses or shall be made compatible by the use of buffering elements.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Circulation: Pedestrian and auto circulation shall be separated insofar as is practicable, and all circulation systems shall adequately serve the needs of the development and be compatible and functional with circulation systems outside the development.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Energy considerations: Site design methods to reduce energy consumption shall be encouraged. Energy site conservation methods may include siting of structures in relation to prevailing breezes and sun angles and use of landscape materials for shade and transpiration.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Parking areas: Building wall extensions, planting, berms or other innovative methods shall be used as a means of minimizing the adverse effect of the visual impact of parking areas. This requirement is in addition to the requirements of the landscape regulations of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Open spaces: Open spaces shall relate to any natural characteristics in such a way as to preserve and enhance their scenic and functional qualities to the fullest extent possible.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Graphics: Graphics, as required, shall be designed as an integral part of the overall design of the project.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Art display: Permanent interior and exterior art displays and water features should be encouraged in the overall design of the project.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Visual screening for decorative walls: In an effort to prevent graffiti vandalism, the following options shall be utilized for walls abutting zoned or dedicated rights-of-way:
<section prefix = "a">
Wall with landscaping. The wall shall be setback two and one-half (2½) feet from the right-of-way line and the resulting setback area shall contain a continuous extensively landscaped buffer which must be maintained in a good healthy condition by the property owner, or where applicable, by the condominium, homeowners or similar association. The landscape buffer shall contain one (1) or more of the following planting materials:
<section prefix = "1">
Shrubs. Shrubs shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Hedges. Hedges shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Vines. Climbing vines shall be a minimum of thirty-six (36) inches in height immediately after planting.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Metal picket fence. Where a metal picket fence abutting a zoned or dedicated right-of-way is constructed in lieu of a decorative wall, landscaping shall not be required.

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-209. Minimum lot width and area</catch_line>
<text>
The minimum lot width for apartment use shall be one hundred (100) feet and the minimum lot area shall be ten thousand (10,000) square feet.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-210. Lot coverage</catch_line>
<text>
The lot coverage for all buildings on the site shall not exceed forty (40) percent of the total lot area.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-211. Apartment setback requirements</catch_line>
<text>
The setbacks shall be as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
Front setback. For structures not exceeding thirty-five (35) feet in height, the minimum setback shall be twenty-five (25) feet; for structures over thirty-five (35) feet in height the setbacks shall be increased by forty (40) percent of the additional height provided, however, that the required front setback shall not exceed fifty (50) feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Rear setback. For structures not exceeding thirty-five (35) feet in height, the minimum setback shall be twenty-five (25) feet; for structures over thirty-five (35) feet in height the setbacks shall be increased by forty (40) percent of the additional height.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Interior side setbacks and side street setbacks. Minimum setbacks for all structures shall be determined by a sixty-three-degree line projected from the interior side property line(s) or side street property line(s) upward towards the center of the site; provided, however, that no structure shall be permitted to be closer than twenty-five (25) feet to the interior side property line(s) or side street property line(s) (see the following sketch) and further provided that the passageways to Biscayne Bay or the Atlantic Ocean are adhered to as provided in this article.


</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Minimum setback between buildings shall be twenty (20) feet except where doors, windows or other openings in the building wall of a living unit face a wall of the same building and/or a wall of another building on the same site. In that case there shall be provided a minimum clear distance of not less than thirty (30) feet, said distance to be measured on a line projected at right angles from the opening to the opposite wall. Cantilevers and open porches may project from the building wall into the required open space (court only) not more than six (6) feet and stairways may project from the building wall into the required open space (court only) not more than ten (10) feet. Stairways when located in the required open space (court) shall be supported by the necessary columns only; support by a wall is strictly prohibited.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-211.1. Passageway areas to the bay or ocean</catch_line>
<text>
There shall be a visual passageway area for sites abutting the bay or ocean, said area to extend from the bay or ocean to the street most nearly parallel to the mean high water line. Twenty (20) percent of the total frontage dimension of said sites shall be unencumbered with any structure or off-street parking, with the area(s) running the full length of the property from the street most nearly parallel to the mean high water line, to the bay or ocean. The maximum required view corridor for any one (1) development shall be one hundred (100) feet in width.
Properties donated or dedicated to Miami-Dade County and accepted by the Board of County Commissioners, or encumbered with a public or semipublic easement that lies within the interior setback areas shall be credited toward this requirement. The purpose of said dedications/easements is to encourage views of the bay or ocean and features such as walkways, public parking areas, fishing piers, gazebos, art objects and other similar amenities. A floor area ratio bonus shall be given for developments abutting the bay or ocean where said dedications/easements are granted pursuant to the provisions of Section 33-213.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-212. Height</catch_line>
<text>
On sites which abut dedicated rights-of-way of one hundred (100) feet or more, each proposed building or structure which exceeds one hundred (100) feet in height shall be designed and situated such that the shadow created by the sun at 12:00 noon on December 21 (a sun angle of forty-one (41) degrees) will not fall on any adjacent property except for public road rights-of-way. Shadow studies shall be provided to the Department. Buildings or structures may be proposed to any height except as controlled by this shadow provision and other provisions in the Code, such as floor area ratio, setbacks, airport regulations, etc. For all other sites, no building or structure or part thereof shall be of a height greater than the width of the widest street upon which such building abuts, unless approved for additional height as a result of public hearing. (See following sketch.)
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-213. Floor area ratio</catch_line>
<text>
The floor area ratio shall not exceed the following, provided, however, that structure parking shall not count as a part of the floor area, but shall be counted in computing building height.
<section prefix="1" type="table">
<table class="table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Height of<br />Building</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Floor Area Ratio</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1 story</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0.40</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2 story</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0.60</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3 story</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0.80</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">4 story</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1.00</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">5 story</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1.20</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6 story</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1.40</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">7 story</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1.60</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">8 story</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1.80</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">9 story or over</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2.00</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 

A floor area ratio bonus shall be given for developments abutting the bay or ocean where easements are dedicated or granted to Miami-Dade County and accepted by the Board of County Commissioners and improved with features such as landscape, walkways, public parking areas, fishing piers, gazebos, restrooms, art objects and other similar amenities. Such areas are to extend the full length of the property from the street most nearly parallel to the mean high water line, to the bay or ocean. Such areas are to be included in density, open space and setback calculations.
The bonus shall be an additional two (2) square feet of floor area for each one (1) square foot of area devoted and improved for public access.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-214. Maximum number of units</catch_line>
<text>
The maximum number of dwelling units shall not exceed a density of fifty (50) dwelling units per net acre or eight hundred seventy-one and two-tenths (871.2) square feet of lot area per dwelling unit.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-215. Parking</catch_line>
<text>
Where a parking garage is not more than four (4) feet above grade, it shall not be considered as a structure for zoning purposes in the RU-4 District except as it applies to the special setback provisions in Section 33-43; the same setbacks shall apply as with surface parking. The garage will not be calculated as a part of lot coverage requirements and will not be allowed in the twenty (20) percent unencumbered area, as enumerated in Section 33-211.1.
If the garage is to be used for parking on the top deck, it must be landscaped according to the provisions of Chapter 18A of the Code of Miami-Dade County; if it is not to be used for parking on the top deck, it shall be developed with landscaping, recreational facilities, etc., with those portions devoted to landscaping being counted as open space pursuant to the provisions of Section 33-216.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-215.1. Trees</catch_line>
<text>
Landscaping and trees shall be provided in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-216. Open space</catch_line>
<text>
On each lot there shall be provided an open space equal to a minimum of forty (40) percent of the total lot area. Said open space shall be unencumbered with any structure or off-street parking, and shall be landscaped and well maintained with grass, trees, and shrubbery, excepting only areas used as pedestrian walks and ingress and egress drives provided that such drives shall not exceed the minimum width required to serve the parking area.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-216.1. Convenience retail facilities</catch_line>
<text>
Apartment developments having a minimum of three hundred (300) residential units may have BU-1 type convenience uses not exceeding one thousand (1,000) square feet as an accessory use to apartment developments, provided that:
<section prefix = "1">
Such services relate to the needs of the inhabitants of the proposed complex;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Such services are not provided direct access from public roads;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Such services are not visible from public roads;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Detached signs and signs visible from public roads are not used; and
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Such services are designed as an integral part of the total design as determined by site plan review; and
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Such services are located in the principal structure or in a community service center structure.

An additional one (1) square foot of retail area shall be permitted for each apartment unit above three hundred (300) units; provided, however, that the maximum square footage for such facilities shall not exceed three thousand (3,000) square feet.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-216.2. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 82-5, § 1, adopted Feb. 2, 1982, deleted § 33-216.2, concerning site plan reviews, as derived from Ord. No. 72-91, § 1, adopted Dec. 5, 1972.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-216.3. Consolidation of requests requiring approval by public hearing into one (1) hearing application</catch_line>
<text>
All requests requiring approval by public hearing may be consolidated into one (1) hearing application.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (23) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 72-91, § 1, adopted Dec. 5, 1972, amended Art. XVIII to read as set out in §§ 33-208—33-216.3. Formerly Art. XVIII, §§ 33-208—33-216, was derived from Ord. No. 57-19, § 12(A)—(I), adopted Oct. 22, 1957 and Ord. No. 70-65, § 1, adopted Sept. 1, 1970. (Back)
Cross reference— Height of fences, walls land hedges in RU District, § 33-11. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
