<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XV._DEPARTMENT_OF_PLANNING_DEVEL</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-104. Established; Director as head; appointment; term; assistants; qualifications</catch_line>
<text>
The Department of Planning and Zoning is established. The Manager shall appoint a Director of Planning and Zoning who shall head the Department, and Assistant Directors, all of whom shall serve at the will of the Manager. The Director shall be qualified in the field of planning, and the Assistant Directors shall be qualified in their respective fields, by special training and experience. The Manager shall be responsible for coordinating the work of the Department of Planning and Zoning, the Department of Public Works, and the Department of Parks and Recreation.
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Reference in the last sentence of § 2-104 to a Director of Traffic and Transportation has been deleted as obsolete.

Cross reference— Planning Director excepted from classified service, § 2-41.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-105. Director—Duties</catch_line>
<text>
Under the supervision of the Manager and with the advice of the Planning Advisory Board, the Director shall among other things:
<section prefix = "a">
Conduct studies of County population, land use, facilities, resources, and needs and other factors which influence the County's development and on the basis of such studies prepare official and other maps and reports.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Prepare for review and public hearing by the Planning Advisory Board, and for adoption by the Commission, zoning, subdivision and related regulations for the unincorporated areas of the County and minimum standards governing zoning, subdivision, and related regulations for the municipalities.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Prepare recommendations to effectuate the master plan and to coordinate the County's proposed capital improvements with the master plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Review the municipal systems of planning, zoning, subdivision, and related regulations and make recommendations thereon with a view to coordinating such municipal systems with one another and with those of the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Upon request of the Commission to the Manager conduct special surveys and studies and make reports thereon.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Promote public understanding of and interest in the master plan and community development.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Examine and approve all proposed plats and proposed local area developments.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Provide for public hearings before the Planning Advisory Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Have the right to enter upon any land and make examinations and surveys, and place and maintain necessary monuments and markers.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Call upon any municipal or County official to appear before the Planning Advisory Board within a reasonable length of time and to bring with him such records or information as may be requested pertaining to any matter pending before the Planning Advisory Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
To enter into an "essentially built out" agreement with a developer and the state land planning agency where it has been finally determined that a development of regional impact ("DRI") is "essentially built out", in accordance with the procedures set forth in Section 33-303.1. Code of Miami-Dade County, as amended, and Section 380.06(15)(g)(3), Florida Statutes, as amended.

The Department of Planning and Zoning shall be responsible for the enforcement of the Planning and Zoning laws of the County, in accordance with the provisions of this Code, including but not limited to Sections 2-968, 2-969 and 33-39.21, and shall perform such other duties and functions as the County Commission may prescribe.
The Department is authorized to charge and collect fees and furnish copies of plans, permits, and other department records to the public provided that a schedule of the type and amount of fees to be charged is first filed with the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners in accordance with the provisions of Section 2-3 of this Code.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-105.1. Same—Responsibility for preparation of Comprehensive Development Master Plan</catch_line>
<text>
Pursuant to Section 4.07, Charter of Miami-Dade County, and Section 163.3174(4)(a), Florida Statutes, the Director of Planning and Zoning, with the support of the Department, shall have the responsibility to prepare the comprehensive plan and all elements thereof, and any proposed amendments which, in his discretion, warrant initiation for public hearing and consideration by the Board of County Commissioners. The Director shall also have the responsibility to make recommendations to the Planning Advisory Board in its capacity as the local planning agency as provided in Section 2-108.1, and to the Board of County Commissioners on proposed comprehensive plan amendments and on the evaluation and appraisal report (EAR) prepared pursuant to Section 2-116. The Director shall also have the responsibility to monitor and oversee the effectiveness and status of the comprehensive plan including the timely preparation of proposed periodic evaluation and appraisal reports required by Section 163.3191, Florida Statutes. Any such proposed comprehensive plans, elements, or portions thereof or proposed amendments thereto, and proposed evaluation and appraisal reports shall be subject to duly noticed public hearings and to recommendations by the Planning Advisory Board acting as the local planning agency, and shall be presented to the Board of County Commissioners for their consideration. The Director shall work in close coordination with the County Manager in directing the Department in the exercise of these responsibilities.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-106. Organization; appointment of employees; salaries</catch_line>
<text>
The organization and operating procedures of the Department shall be prescribed in administrative orders and regulations of the Manager. The Manager shall appoint such employees and other personnel as may be necessary to operate the Department. The salaries and compensation of all personnel, except employees within the classified service, shall be fixed by the County Commission upon recommendation of the Manager.
</text>
The organization and operating procedures of the Department shall be prescribed in administrative orders and regulations of the Manager. The Manager shall appoint such employees and other personnel as may be necessary to operate the Department. The salaries and compensation of all personnel, except employees within the classified service, shall be fixed by the County Commission upon recommendation of the Manager.
Charter reference— Authority of Manager to issue and place into effect administrative orders, rules and regulations and to prescribe the organization and operating procedure of departments of the County, § 4.02.
<catch_line>Sec. 2-106.1. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 92-17, § 1 adopted March 17, 1992, repealed former § 2-106.1, relative to the Planning Department designated as the local planning agency, which derived from Ord. No. 76-441, § 1, adopted May 18, 1976 and Ord. No. 86-97, § 1, enacted Dec. 16, 1986.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-107. Planning Advisory Board—Established; composition; compensation of members; new member orientation; annual orientation workshop</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
A Planning Advisory Board is hereby established. This Board shall consist of:
<section prefix = "1">
Seventeen (17) voting members appointed by the County Commission. Each County Commissioner shall nominate one (1) member. The remaining four (4) members, each of whom shall be a professional in architecture, landscape architecture, urban design, urban planning, real estate or a similar field, shall be at-large appointments. Nominations for the at-large appointments shall be submitted to the Chair of the Board of County Commissioners to be voted on by the Board. Members shall serve without compensation, but shall be entitled to be reimbursed for necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties, upon approval by the County Commission.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The following nonvoting members:
<section prefix = "a">
A representative appointed by the School Board of Miami-Dade County, who may attend those meetings at which the Board considers an application to amend the comprehensive plan that would, if approved, increase residential density on the property that is the subject of the application.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A representative appointed by the commanding officer of the Homestead Air Reserve Base, who may attend those meetings at which the Board considers an application to amend the comprehensive plan that, if approved, would affect the intensity, density, or use of the land adjacent to or in close proximity to the military installation.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
New members of the Planning Advisory Board appointed to the Board after the effective date of this ordinance shall attend a New Member Orientation Seminar conducted by the Department of Planning and Zoning and the County Attorney's Office. The seminar shall include, but shall not be limited to, a review of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan and issues related thereto, incorporation and annexation issues, and a review of applicable laws, rules and regulations pertaining to duties and responsibilities of Planning Advisory Board members.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Planning Advisory Board members shall attend an Annual Planning Advisory Board Workshop organized and conducted by the Department of Planning and Zoning and the County Attorney's Office. The Workshop shall include, but shall not be limited to, a review of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan and issues related thereto, incorporation and annexation issues, and a review of applicable laws, rules and regulations pertaining to duties and responsibilities of Planning Advisory Board members.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 57-8, § 14.03, 8-30-57; Ord. No. 59-2, § 1, 1-20-59; Ord. No. 64-39, § 10, 9-1-64; Ord. No. 73-20, § 1, 3-8-73; Ord. No. 81-53, § 1, 5-5-81; Ord. No. 94-119, § 1, 6-9-94; Ord. No. 05-90, § 1, 5-3-05; Ord. No. 05-188, § 2, 11-3-05; Ord. No. 07-146, § 1, 10-2-07)</history>
Charter reference— Authority to establish Planning Advisory Board, § 4.08(A).
<catch_line>Sec. 2-108. Same—Duties</catch_line>
<text>
The Planning Advisory Board shall perform such duties as are conferred on it by this article and shall hold at least one (1) meeting a month to review the work of the Planning and Zoning Director and to consider such matters as may be referred to it by the Director or the County Commission.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-108.1. Same—Responsibilities aslocal planning agency</catch_line>
<text>
Pursuant to the provisions of Chapter 163, Part II, Florida Statutes, the Planning Advisory Board shall serve as the local planning agency (LPA) fulfilling the following specific responsibilities:
<section prefix = "a">
Hold at least one (1) public hearing with due public notice on the proposed comprehensive plan, plan element or portion thereof or proposed amendment thereto, and on proposed plan evaluation and appraisal reports prepared by the Department of Planning and Zoning;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Review the proposed comprehensive plan, plan element or portion thereof or proposed amendments thereto, and the Department of Planning and Zoning's recommendations, reports on proposed amendments, and proposed plan evaluation and appraisal reports prepared by the Department of Planning and Zoning pursuant to Section 2-116, and make final recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners prior to Commission action on transmittal to the State land planning agency or final action on such proposals or reports;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Complete the preparation of evaluation and appraisal reports for submission to the Board of County Commissioners and the State land planning agency pursuant to Section 163.3191(4), Florida Statutes; and
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Conduct all meetings as public meetings with records properly maintained and available to the public.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-109. Same—Terms of office; vacancies</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The terms of office of the members of the Planning Advisory Board shall end December 31, 1994 for members nominated by the County Commissioners representing Commission Districts 2, 4, 6, 8, 10 and 12 and shall end December 31, 1996, for members nominated by the County Commissioners representing Commission Districts 1, 3, 5, 7, 9, 11 and 13, with appointments thereafter for terms of four (4) years each. The membership of each appointee expires when the Commissioner who nominated that member leaves office. The four at-large members shall serve terms of two (2) years each. Each member shall hold office until his or her successor has been duly appointed and qualified. Any member of the Planning Advisory Board may be removed from office at any time by two-thirds vote of the County Commission.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A member's position shall become vacant when:
<section prefix = "1">
The member is absent from three (3) consecutive meetings, regardless of reason, provided that absences from emergency meetings or specially called meetings shall not count toward the attendance requirement;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The member's term expires; or
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The member resigns or is removed.
Any vacancy occurring during the unexpired term of office of any member of the Planning Advisory Board shall be filled for the unexpired term by the County Commission within thirty (30) days after the vacancy occurs.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 57-8, § 14.05, 8-30-57; Ord. No. 59-2, § 1, 1-20-59; Ord. No. 94-119, § 1, 6-9-94; Ord. No. 05-188, § 3, 11-3-05)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-110. Same—Organization; meetings; quorum; rules; records of meetings</catch_line>
<text>
The Planning Advisory Board shall elect a Chairperson and such other officers as may be necessary from among its members to serve for a one (1) year term commencing March first. Elections shall be held in February of each year, and each officer shall serve until his or her successor is elected. The Director of Planning and Zoning shall be the executive director and secretary of the Planning Advisory Board. Such staff as may be necessary to assist and advise the Planning Advisory Board in the fulfillment of its duties shall be furnished by the Department of Planning and Zoning. All meetings of the Board shall be held in a public place and shall be open to the public. Six (6) members of the Board shall constitute a quorum, and, except as otherwise provided, decisions may be made by majority vote of the members present at a meeting at which a quorum is present. The Planning Advisory Board may prescribe other rules for the conduct of its affairs. The Chairperson, or in his or her absence, the Acting Chairperson, may administer oaths and compel the attendance of witnesses in the manner prescribed for the attendance of witnesses in the County Court. The Planning Advisory Board shall keep minutes of its proceedings and records of its other official actions, showing the vote of each member on each question. If a member is absent or fails to vote, the record shall indicate such fact. All records shall be filed immediately in the Department of Planning and Zoning office and shall be open to the inspection of the public.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-111—2-112.2. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 92-17, § 1, adopted March 17, 1992, repealed former §§ 2-111—2-112.2, relative to the procedure for adopting a master plan and Comprehensive Development Master Plan, which derived from Ord. No. 57-8, §§ 14.07, 14.08, enacted Aug. 30, 1957; Ord. No. 75-22, § I, adopted March 31, 1975; and Ord. No. 79-63, §§ 1, 2, adopted July 11, 1979.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-113. Adoption of Comprehensive Development Master Plan—Findings of fact; declarations of policy; purpose</catch_line>
<text>
The Board of County Commissioners for Miami-Dade County, Florida, hereby declares and finds that uncoordinated use of lands within the County threatens the orderly development, the environment of the County, and the health, safety, order, convenience, prosperity and welfare of the people of this County. The Board of County Commissioners, recognizing that man depends on his biological and physical surroundings for food, shelter, and other needs, and for cultural enrichment as well; in recognizing further the profound impact of man's activity on the interrelations of all components of the natural environment, particularly the profound influences of population growth, high-density urbanization, industrial expansion, resource utilization and exploitation, and new and expanding technological advances; and recognizing further the critical importance of restoring and maintaining environmental quality to the overall welfare and development of man, declares that it is the continuing policy of Miami-Dade County, Florida, in cooperation with federal, State, regional and local governments, and other concerned public and private organizations, to use all reasonable means and measures to:
<section prefix = "a">
Foster and promote the general welfare;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Create and maintain conditions under which man and nature can exist in productive harmony; and
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Fill the social, economic and other requirements of the present and future generations of citizens of Miami-Dade County, Florida.

Accordingly, it is the purpose of this Commission in adopting the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan to declare a County policy which will [encourage productive and enjoyable harmony between man and his environment, to promote reasonable efforts which will] prevent or eliminate unreasonable or unnecessary damage to the environment and the biosphere, to stimulate the health and welfare of man, and to enrich the understanding of the ecological systems and natural resources important to the County, the State and the nation. It is the purpose and intent of this plan to assure for all people of Miami-Dade County safe, healthful, productive and aesthetically and culturally pleasing surroundings; to attain the widest range of beneficial uses of the environment without unreasonable degradation, risk to the health or safety, or other undesirable and unintended consequences; to preserve important historic, cultural and natural aspects of our national heritage; to maintain, wherever possible, environment which supports diversity and variety of individual choice; to achieve a balance between population and natural and man-made resources which will permit the high standards of living and a wide sharing of life's amenities, and to enhance the quality of renewal resources and approach the maximum attainable recycling of depletable resources. Accordingly, this Commission hereby recognizes that each person has a fundamental and inalienable right to a healthful environment, and that each person has a responsibility to contribute to the preservation and enhancement of the environment. The Commission further adopts the goals and objectives of the Local Government Comprehensive Planning and Land Development Regulation Act, Chapter 163, Part II, § 163.3161 et seq., Florida Statutes (1987), and dedicates its decision-making function in furtherance of the express intent of said act.
</section>
</text>
The Board of County Commissioners for Miami-Dade County, Florida, hereby declares and finds that uncoordinated use of lands within the County threatens the orderly development, the environment of the County, and the health, safety, order, convenience, prosperity and welfare of the people of this County. The Board of County Commissioners, recognizing that man depends on his biological and physical surroundings for food, shelter, and other needs, and for cultural enrichment as well; in recognizing further the profound impact of man's activity on the interrelations of all components of the natural environment, particularly the profound influences of population growth, high-density urbanization, industrial expansion, resource utilization and exploitation, and new and expanding technological advances; and recognizing further the critical importance of restoring and maintaining environmental quality to the overall welfare and development of man, declares that it is the continuing policy of Miami-Dade County, Florida, in cooperation with federal, State, regional and local governments, and other concerned public and private organizations, to use all reasonable means and measures to:
<section prefix = "a">
Foster and promote the general welfare;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Create and maintain conditions under which man and nature can exist in productive harmony; and
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Fill the social, economic and other requirements of the present and future generations of citizens of Miami-Dade County, Florida.

Accordingly, it is the purpose of this Commission in adopting the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan to declare a County policy which will [encourage productive and enjoyable harmony between man and his environment, to promote reasonable efforts which will] prevent or eliminate unreasonable or unnecessary damage to the environment and the biosphere, to stimulate the health and welfare of man, and to enrich the understanding of the ecological systems and natural resources important to the County, the State and the nation. It is the purpose and intent of this plan to assure for all people of Miami-Dade County safe, healthful, productive and aesthetically and culturally pleasing surroundings; to attain the widest range of beneficial uses of the environment without unreasonable degradation, risk to the health or safety, or other undesirable and unintended consequences; to preserve important historic, cultural and natural aspects of our national heritage; to maintain, wherever possible, environment which supports diversity and variety of individual choice; to achieve a balance between population and natural and man-made resources which will permit the high standards of living and a wide sharing of life's amenities, and to enhance the quality of renewal resources and approach the maximum attainable recycling of depletable resources. Accordingly, this Commission hereby recognizes that each person has a fundamental and inalienable right to a healthful environment, and that each person has a responsibility to contribute to the preservation and enhancement of the environment. The Commission further adopts the goals and objectives of the Local Government Comprehensive Planning and Land Development Regulation Act, Chapter 163, Part II, § 163.3161 et seq., Florida Statutes (1987), and dedicates its decision-making function in furtherance of the express intent of said act.
Note—See editor's note following § 2-112.1.
</section>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-113.1. Adoption of Comprehensive Development Master Plan—Plan contents designated, official text to be maintained</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida, hereby declares that the Comprehensive Development Master Plan shall consist of the following adopted statement and elements as the same may be amended from time to time:
<section prefix = "i">
Statement of Legislative Intent.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Elements:
<section prefix = "1">
Land Use Element.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Traffic Circulation Element.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Mass Transit Element.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Port and Aviation Element.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Conservation, Drainage, and Aquifer Recharge Element.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Coastal Management Element.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Housing Element.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Water, Sewer and Solid Waste Element.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Recreation and Open Space Element.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Intergovernmental Coordination Element.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Capital Improvements Element.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
An official true and correct copy of all elements of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan as adopted and as amended from time to time shall be maintained by the Director of the Department of Planning and Zoning.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 75-22, § 3, 3-31-75; Ord. No. 76-100, § 3, 11-2-76; Ord. No. 77-49, § 3, 7-12-77; Ord. No. 78-45, § 3, 7-11-78; Ord. No. 79-63, § 4, 7-11-79; Ord. No. 88-110, § 3, 11-29-88; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 1, 9-3-98)</history>
Note—See the editor's note following § 2-112.1.


Annotation—CAO 83-13.

<catch_line>Sec. 2-114. Adoption of Comprehensive Development Master Plan—Legal status of plan; relationship to neighborhood, area, and functional studies; legislative intent; definitions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Legal status. The Comprehensive Development Master Plan is hereby declared to be the official long-range and comprehensive guide for the orderly growth and development of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and is adopted to direct and achieve coordinated and harmonious development and land use in a manner which will permit the planning for adequate community facilities and protect the ecological balance of the environment, in order to promote the public health, safety, convenience, prosperity and general welfare of Miami-Dade County's citizens and visitors. In furtherance hereof, this Commission hereby declares its policy and intent to evaluate and consider all its public actions involving development orders or land development regulations as defined by Section 163.3164(6), (7), and (22), Florida Statutes (1987) or affecting land use or development, including action on applications for zoning relief, to be in conformity with and consistent with the Comprehensive Development Master Plan, as provided by Section 163.3194(3)(a), Florida Statutes (1987), and to determine whether such action or actions will better serve the community. Pursuant hereto, all County actions, including, but not limited to, those for capital improvements, transportation, housing, health, parks, recreation, culture and libraries shall be coordinated and rendered consistent with the Comprehensive Development Master Plan. In recognition that developmental actions and orders have been and shall continue to be a major tool for the implementation of land use and development policies, it shall henceforth be required that applicants for developmental actions or orders shall be determined to further the attainment of the intent of this plan, which embodies the essence of the community's development policy. Any deviations from the plan shall be approved only if the provisions of subsection 2-114(c) are applicable, and further may only be approved by not less than a majority of the total membership of the Board of County Commissioners on applications for development orders pending before it, or by not less than a majority of the total membership a Community Zoning Appeals Board on applications for development orders pending before it. It shall be the responsibility of the Department of Planning and Zoning or other appropriate Miami-Dade County Boards, departments and agencies to formulate recommendations for the resolution of any conflicts in the interpretation or application of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan in a manner which will best serve the spirit and intent of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan. Any decisions relating to such conflict shall contain specific findings by the board, department or agency making said decisions.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Relationship to neighborhood, area, and functional studies. Notwithstanding any other ordinance, or regulation of Miami-Dade County, Florida, neighborhood, area, and functional studies are not a part of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan. The Comprehensive Development Master Plan is hereby declared to supersede all neighborhood, area, and functional studies, which studies shall be advisory only, and the Comprehensive Development Master Plan shall prevail in the event of any conflict or difference with any such study.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Legislative intent.
<section prefix = "1">
No taking or abrogation of vested rights. Nothing in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan shall be construed or applied to constitute a temporary or permanent taking of private property without just compensation (hereinafter "taking") or the abrogation of vested rights.
<section prefix = "a">
Vested rights or taking. Nothing contained in this ordinance or in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan shall be construed or applied to constitute a temporary or permanent taking of private property or the abrogation of validly existing vested rights. It shall be the duty and responsibility of the party alleging a taking or vested rights to affirmatively demonstrate the legal requisites of a taking or vested rights. Rights shall vest upon a demonstration to an appropriate County board or agency that the provisions of Section 163.3167(8), Florida Statutes (1987) apply or that the applicant (1) has relief in good faith (2) upon some act or omission of the government and (3) has made such a substantial change in position or incurred such extensive obligations and expenses to their detriment that it would be highly inequitable to deny relief. The mere existence of zoning contrary to the Comprehensive Development Master Plan shall not be determined to vest rights. To establish a taking, the burden shall be on the applicant to demonstrate that (1) denial of the application will deny the applicant all beneficial use of the property; and (2) that no variances, alternative uses or other forms of relief are available which could, if approved, afford the applicant a beneficial use of the property. Mere diminution in property value shall not constitute a temporary or permanent taking of private property.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Notwithstanding any contrary provisions of the Code of Miami-Dade County, no applicant claiming that the Comprehensive Development Master Plan, as applied to a particular development action or order, constitutes or would constitute a temporary or permanent taking of private property or an abrogation of vested rights may pursue such claim in court or before a quasi-judicial body unless he has first exhausted the administrative remedies provided in Section 2-114.1
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Comprehensive Development Master Plan shall not be construed to preempt considerations of fundamental fairness that may arise from a strict application of the Plan. Accordingly, the Plan shall not be deemed to require any particular action: (a) where the plan is incomplete or internally inconsistent, (b) that would constitute a taking of private property without due process or fair compensation; or (c) which would deny equal protection of the laws.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Nothing contained in this ordinance or in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan shall limit or modify the rights of any person to complete any development that has been authorized as a development or regional impact pursuant to Chapter 380, Florida Statutes or who has been issued a final local development order and development has commenced and is continuing in good faith as provided by Section 163.3167(8), Florida Statutes (1987).
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The Comprehensive Development Master Plan is intended to set general guidelines and principles concerning its purposes and contents. The Comprehensive Development Master Plan is not a substitute for land development regulations as defined by Section 163.3164(22), Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The Comprehensive Development Master Plan is not intended to preempt the processes whereby applications may be filed for relief from land development regulations. To the contrary, it is the intent of the Board of County Commissioners that such applications be filed, considered and finally determined, where a strict application of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan would contravene the legislative intent as expressed herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
The Board recognizes that a particular application may bring into conflict, and necessitate a choice between, different goals, priorities, objectives, and provisions of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan. While it is the intent of the Board that the land use element be afforded a high priority, other elements must be taken into consideration in light of the Board's responsibility to provide for the multitude of needs of a large heavily populated and diverse community. This is especially true with regard to the siting of public facilities.
Recognizing that County boards and agencies will be required to balance competing policies and objectives of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan, it is the intention of the County Commission that such boards and agencies consider the overall intention of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan as well as portions particularly applicable to a matter under consideration.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
The Comprehensive Development Master Plan as adopted by the Board of County Commissioners shall be controlling and shall prevail over any error contained in a reprinting of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan or any of its parts, provided, however, this shall not preclude correction of scrivener's errors contained in the original documents.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Definitions.
<section prefix = "1">
"Developmental action or order defined." "Developmental action or order" shall mean any action or order granting, denying, or granting with conditions an application for a development permit, which shall include any building permit, zoning permit, subdivision approval, rezoning, certification, special exception, variance, environmental permit, or any other official action of Miami-Dade County having the effect of permitting the development of land.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
"Consistent with" and "in conformity with" defined. For the purposes of this section, the terms "consistent with" and "in conformity with" shall mean that all developmental actions or orders shall tend to further the Comprehensive Development Master Plan and will not inhibit or obstruct the attainment of the articulated policies contained therein. A development approved or undertaken shall be consistent and in conformity with the Comprehensive Plan if the land uses, densities or intensities, capacity or size, timing, and all other aspects of the development are compatible with and further the objectives, policies, land uses, and densities or intensities in the Comprehensive Plan.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
If particular provisions of the CDMP differ from a municipal comprehensive plan that authorizes existing or proposed facilities, the particular CDMP provisions shall not supersede the municipal plan and nothing in this section shall be construed to preclude County actions pertaining to the facilities when consistent with the municipal plan, if the following conditions are met:
<section prefix = "1">
The existing or proposed facilities shall be located entirely within the municipality and shall be consistent with the municipal comprehensive plan;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The municipality shall have building permit and zoning jurisdiction over such facilities;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The County and the municipality shall have entered an interlocal agreement relating specifically to the facilities, mutually funding them to be in the public interest; and the County's actions pertaining to the facilities are not inconsistent with such agreement.
County actions within the scope of this subsection shall be deemed consistent with the CDMP.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
In evaluating or rendering a decision on any application for developmental action or order, all County departments and boards shall deem land to be inside the Urban Development Boundary only if the land is inside and not on the marked Urban Development Boundary Line denoted on the Land Use Plan Map of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan. It is provided, however, that where there is a discrepancy between the Urban Development Boundary Line on the Land Use Plan Map versus the legal description of an approved application to expand the Urban Development Boundary, the legal description shall prevail.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 75-22, § 4, 3-31-75; Ord. No. 79-63, § 5, 7-11-79; Ord. No. 88-3, § 1, 2-2-88; Ord. No. 88-110, § 4, 11-29-88; Ord. No. 89-10, § 1, 2-21-89; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-89, § 1, 6-18-96; Ord. No. 96-127, § 1, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 98-125, § 1, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 06-169, § 1, 11-28-06)</history>
Note—See the editor's note following § 2-112.1.
<catch_line>Sec. 2-114.1. Administrative review of takings and vested rights claims</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Documentation of claim.
<section prefix = "1">
Any applicant alleging that the Comprehensive Development Master Plan, as applied to a particular development order or action, constitutes or would constitute a temporary or permanent taking of private property or an abrogation of vested rights (taking or abrogation) and any person or entity claiming a potential taking or abrogation under Chapter 33 of this Code must affirmatively demonstrate the legal requisites of the claim by exhausting the administrative remedy provided in this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Claims of a taking or abrogation of vested rights are limited solely to extreme circumstances rising to the level of a potential denial of rights under the Constitutions of the United States and the State of Florida. The procedures provided herein for demonstrating such a taking or abrogation of vested rights are not intended to be utilized routinely or frivolously, but only in the extreme circumstances described above. The claimant or the attorney for the claimant shall exercise due diligence in the filing and argument of any sworn statement, notice of invoking administrative remedy or other claim for a taking or abrogation of vested rights. The signature of the claimant or the attorney for the claimant upon any document in connection with a claim of taking or abrogation of vested rights shall constitute a certificate that the person signing has read the document and that to the best of his knowledge it is supported by good grounds and that it has not been presented solely for delay. The claimant and the attorney for the claimant shall have a continuing obligation throughout the proceedings to correct any statement or representation found to have been incorrect when made or which becomes incorrect by virtue of changed circumstances. If a claim of taking or abrogation of vested rights is: (1) based upon facts that the claimant or the attorney for the claimant knew or should have known were not true; or (2) frivolous or filed solely for the purposes of delay, the appropriate County board or agency shall make such a finding and may pursue any remedy or impose any penalty provided by law or ordinance.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Definitions.
<section prefix = "1">
Developmental permit defined. For purposes of this section a "developmental permit" shall mean a developmental order or action which may be issued by an administrative official without the necessity of a hearing on the application for said developmental permit.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Developmental resolution defined. For purposes of this section, a "developmental resolution" shall mean a developmental order or action which requires the approval of a County board or agency after a hearing on the application for said developmental resolution prior to its issuance.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Sworn statement defined. For purpose of this section, "sworn statement" shall mean the sworn statement described in Section 2-114.1(a) together with all accompanying documents, witness lists, items and things supporting the applicant's claim and an administrative fee established by administrative order of the County Manager to be approved by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Invocation of administrative remedy.
<section prefix = "1">
Any developmental permit denied on the grounds of inconsistency with the Comprehensive Development Master Plan shall state in writing that the permit has been denied on such basis. Any applicant seeking to appeal the denial of a developmental permit on the grounds set forth in Section 2-114.1(a) shall file a notice of invoking administrative remedy with the Developmental Impact Committee Coordinator on a form prescribed by the Director within fifteen (15) days of the denial of said developmental permit. Any claimant contending that action upon a County application will result in a taking or abrogation of vested rights under Section 33-311 of this Code shall file a notice of invoking administrative remedy with the Developmental Impact Committee Coordinator on a form prescribed by the Director within thirty (30) days of receipt of the certified mail notice required by Section 33-311, provided the County Commission may extend the thirty-day filing period prescribed by this sentence upon a showing of good cause as provided by Section 33-311. The applicant shall file a complete sworn statement within ninety (90) working days of the filing of the notice of invoking administrative remedy. Failure to file the sworn statement within the time specified in this paragraph shall constitute an irrevocable waiver of claim.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Any applicant alleging that the action of the Board of County Commissioners or a Community Zoning Appeals Board upon an application for a zoning action under Chapter 33 would constitute a temporary or permanent taking of private property or an abrogation of vested rights shall file a complete sworn statement with the Developmental Impact Committee Coordinator not later than forty-five (45) days before the first hearing on the developmental resolution. No oral testimony or written reports or documents in support of any argument that the denial of the developmental resolution would constitute a temporary or permanent taking of private property or would abrogate vested rights shall be considered as evidence at the public hearing unless the complete sworn statement has been timely filed pursuant to this paragraph; provided, however, that where an applicant has failed to timely file a sworn statement pursuant to this paragraph, the Board of County Commissioners, Environmental Quality Control Board, or any other board taking action on a developmental resolution may defer the hearing on an application for a developmental resolution to avoid a manifest injustice and to provide adequate time for review of the sworn statement by the Developmental Impact Committee or, in the event of an application initiated by a party other than the affected property owner, to provide adequate time for the property owner to invoke the administrative remedy and to adhere to the time schedules provided herein.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Review by Developmental Impact Committee and County Boards.
<section prefix = "1">
It shall be the duty and responsibility of the Executive Council of the Developmental Impact Committee to review all sworn statements timely filed with the Developmental Impact Committee Coordinator pursuant to this section. The Developmental Impact Committee shall have the authority to request additional information from the applicant.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
If the Executive Council of the Developmental Impact Committee finds that a denial of a developmental permit would result in a temporary or permanent taking or abrogation of vested rights, it shall reverse or modify said denial. Otherwise, the Executive Council shall affirm said denial. Within fourteen (14) days the applicant may appeal the decision of the Executive Council to the Board of County Commissioners pursuant to Section 33-314 of the Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Notwithstanding any other provision of the Code of Miami-Dade County to the contrary, the Board of County Commissioners shall have jurisdiction to review conflicts between decisions of the Executive Council of the Developmental Impact Committee regarding developmental permits made pursuant to this section and decisions of any other County board made pursuant to an appeal of an administrative decision.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The Executive Council of the Developmental Impact Committee shall prepare a written recommendation to the appropriate County board regarding sworn statements filed in connection with an application for a developmental resolution. With the exception of County boards whose decisions are directly reviewable by an appellate court, the Board of County Commissioners shall have exclusive jurisdiction to consider and take action upon all applications for developmental resolutions for which the applicant has invoked the administrative remedy set forth in this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The appropriate County board may elect to first consider the primary application rather than concurrently conduct a hearing upon a claim of taking or abrogation of vested rights. If the Board's determination is that the primary application should be denied in whole or in part, such determination shall not be a final decision but shall be subject to a further determination of a claim of taking or abrogation of vested rights. The Board may either hear directly the claim of taking or abrogation of vested rights, may defer consideration of the claim to a subsequent hearing, or may refer the same to the Executive Council of the Development Impact Committee for further review and recommendation prior to taking final action. If the Board shall finally determine that denial of the primary application would result in a taking or abrogation of vested rights, the Board shall grant appropriate relief which would avoid such result. Upon a determination by the Board that denial of the primary application would not effect a taking or abrogate vested rights, the preliminary determination to deny shall become final.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Notwithstanding any contrary provision of the Code of Miami-Dade County, a developmental resolution adopted by any County board other than the Board of County Commissioners shall not be deemed to be a final order for any purpose where: (1) the administrative remedy of this section has been invoked; and (2) the Executive Council of the Developmental Impact Committee has appealed said developmental resolution to the Board of County Commissioners. Said appeal shall be filed within fourteen (14) days of the date of the adoption of the developmental resolution.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Exhaustion of administrative remedies. A developmental order or action shall not be deemed a final order in any court or quasi-judicial proceeding challenging the denial of the developmental order or action as a temporary or permanent taking of private property or an abrogation of vested rights unless the remedies set forth in this section have been exhausted.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 89-10, § 2, 2-21-89; Ord. No. 94-37, § 1, 3-3-94; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-127, § 1, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 97-198, § 1, 11-4-97; Ord. No. 98-125, § 1, 9-3-98)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-114.2. Supplemental optional vested rights procedure</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Purpose. Any property owner who has received a master tentative plat, tentative plat or waiver of plat approval prior to July 1, 1989, may apply for a determination of whether the owner has a vested right to obtain specified developmental permits or developmental resolutions, as defined in Section 2-114.1(b), for the purpose of accomplishing a specifically described development, notwithstanding provisions of the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan (CDMP) or County land development regulations.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Standards, procedures, requirements and definitions. Unless otherwise specifically provided, all standards, procedures, requirements and definitions of Sections 2-114 and 2-114.1 of the Code shall be applicable to proceedings under this section, Sections 2-114.3 and 2-114.4 and shall be in addition to the provisions of this section.
The following definitions shall apply to this section and Sections 2-114.3 and 2-114.4 unless otherwise indicated herein.
<section prefix = "1">
Consistent with and in conformity with shall have the definitions set forth in Section 2-114(d)(2) of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida (Code).
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Continuing in good faith. Continuing shall mean a progression of steps taken to proceed with and complete the development authorized by a development permit in a diligent, prudent and businesslike manner, in compliance with all applicable laws and regulations. Good faith shall not encompass dishonest, fraudulent, or deceitful action, ignorance or circumvention of legal requirements, or delay resulting from neglect or lack of diligence.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Development shall have the definition set forth in Sections 163.3164(5) and 380.04, Florida Statutes, as the same may from time to time be amended.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Development permit shall mean any official action of local government having the effect of permitting the development of land without any further local government action, which may include, but is not limited to, a building permit, zoning permit, subdivision approval, rezoning, certification, special exception, or variance. For purposes of this section, a development permit shall be deemed a final local development order within the meaning of Section 163.3167(8), Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Land development regulations shall mean the County's service concurrency management program contained in Chapter 33G of the Code, as the same may be amended from time to time.

</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Application. An application form to accomplish the purposes of this section shall be prescribed by the Chairman of the Executive Council of the Developmental Impact Committee (DIC). Such form shall require information relevant and material to a determination of vested rights, including but not limited to:
<section prefix = "1">
Detailed description of the particular development in question, including but not limited to (a) authorized land use; (b) density or intensity of development; (c) staging, phasing or timing of development; and (d) other conditions of development or mitigation that are specific to prior development permits;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
An itemization of all actions or omissions of Miami-Dade County allegedly relied upon, together with specific acts of reliance pertaining to each;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
A complete itemization of government approvals to the extent practicable (e.g. permits or resolutions) needed to complete the development for which applicant claims vested rights in relationship to the CDMP and land development regulations;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
An itemization of all CDMP provisions or land development regulations adopted subsequent to December 6, 1988 which, if applied, would allegedly abrogate vested rights;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The period of time for which the applicant claims rights are vested; and
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Any and all conditions and limitations applicable to the claimed vested development right.
In addition to all items otherwise required by the Chairman or by Section 2-114.1, the applicant shall attach the following to the application: (1) copies of any applicable development permits and development orders, and (2) any other documents which support or negate the claim of vested rights. To the extent there is a claim of reliance upon an act or omission of Miami-Dade County under subsection 2-114.2(d)(1), the applicant shall submit all available documentation showing such reliance, including bills, statements, copies of canceled checks, and a complete itemization and total of all expenses incurred in reliance upon such act or omission. The applicant shall submit with his application a letter of intent explaining the basis of his claim for vested rights and a notice, including the mailing address, of all parties who hold a security interest in the affected property. The mere existence of zoning prior to the effective date of this section shall not vest rights.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Standards. In order to establish vested rights pursuant to this section and Section 2-114.3, the applicant shall establish:
<section prefix = "1">
That he has (1) relied in good faith (2) upon some act or omission of Miami-Dade County occurring prior to December 6, 1988 as related to the CDMP and prior to July 1, 1989 for those matters related to the County's Service Concurrency Management Program, Chapter 33G, Code, and (3) has made such a substantial change in position or incurred such extensive obligations and expenses to his detriment that it would be highly inequitable to deny relief; or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The applicant has the right to complete development pursuant to Section 163.3167(8), Florida Statutes, because a development permit issued from Miami-Dade County, and development has lawfully commenced on the property for which the applicable development permit has been issued and is continuing in good faith. The development permit must have issued prior to the adoption of the land development regulations which the applicant contends should not be strictly applied to him because of vested rights.
Good faith reliance shall not include ignorance or unawareness of the law.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Notice.
<section prefix = "1">
The meeting of the DIC Executive Council at which an application shall be considered pursuant to this section shall be held upon at least fifteen (15) days' notice of the time and place of such meeting published in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County, which publication shall include the time and place of hearing before the DIC. A courtesy notice containing general information as to the date, time, and place of the meeting, the property location and general nature of the application shall be mailed to the property owners of record, within a radius of three hundred (300) feet of the property described in the application, or such greater distance as the DIC Coordinator may prescribe; provided, however, that failure to mail or receive such courtesy notice shall not affect any action or proceeding taken hereunder. To provide additional notice to the public, the property shall be posted by a sign or signs indicating the action desired and the time and place of the public meeting thereon. Failure to post such property shall not affect any action taken hereunder.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
In addition, notice of all DIC Executive Council meetings in which recommended vested rights determinations shall be considered shall be published in the regularly published calendar of County events known as the "Metro Calendar."
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Additional notice shall be given by the DIC Coordinator by posting a short, concise statement of the action requested to be taken on a conspicuous bulletin board that may be seen by the public at reasonable time and hours within or adjacent to the offices of the Department of Planning and Zoning.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Review of application by DIC Executive Council.
<section prefix = "1">
An application filed pursuant to this section shall be reviewed by the DIC Executive Council at a meeting of the council. The council, board, agency or official having responsibility for the issuance of any and all development resolutions or permits encompassed by the application shall be requested by the Executive Council, and is required hereby, to submit a report addressing the application as it relates to the function of said council, official, agency or board. Where the issuance of a development resolution or permit encompassed by the application must be preceded by a public hearing conducted by a board, the report to the Executive Council shall be made by staff who are responsible for reporting to such board. Except as otherwise provided herein, the DIC Executive Council shall conduct its review in accordance with the standards and procedures of Section 2-114 and Section 2-114.1
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Within fifteen (15) days after receipt of an application for a recommended vested rights determination, the DIC Coordinator shall determine and notify the applicant whether the application information is sufficient to enable the DIC Executive Council to issue a recommended vested rights determination, and the DIC Coordinator shall request any additional information needed. If the DIC Coordinator determines that the information in the application is not sufficient, the applicant shall either provide additional information as requested, or shall notify the DIC Coordinator in writing that the information will not be supplied and the reasons therefor. If the applicant declines to provide the requested information, the DIC Executive Council will begin the recommended vested rights determination. If the applicant does not respond to the request for additional information within ninety (90) days, then the application shall be deemed to be withdrawn. If the applicant provides requested additional information, the DIC Coordinator shall, within fifteen (15) days from receipt of the additional information, determine whether the additional information furnished is sufficient to comply with this request. If the additional information is not sufficient, the DIC Coordinator shall notify the applicant of the respects in which the information does not comply with the original request. When all requested information is received, the application will be considered sufficient and the applicant will be so notified.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The DIC Executive Council shall review the completed application and any additional information provided. It shall consider all written documents, written statements, and information submitted by the applicant or gathered and made part of the record by the DIC Coordinator during the investigation and evaluation of the application. The DIC Coordinator may solicit and shall accept submission of relevant information from any other appropriate departments or agencies of Miami-Dade County. The DIC Coordinator may solicit and shall accept information from any third persons who may possess factual information relevant to the investigation of an application. Copies of such information obtained by the DIC Coordinator shall be furnished to the applicant, and the applicant shall be given an opportunity to respond to the information. The applicant shall be given an opportunity to address the DIC Executive Council and present evidence and argument in favor of its application, and respond to any questions or concerns raised by members of the DIC Executive Council.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Within sixty (60) days after acknowledging receipt of a sufficient application, or receiving notification that additional information requested pursuant to subsection (f)(2) will not be supplied, the DIC Executive Council shall give notice and review the application in accordance with the procedures contained herein and shall issue its vested rights recommended determination. The time for issuance of the recommended vested rights determination by the DIC Executive Council may be extended by agreement between the applicant and the DIC Executive Council. A recommended vested rights determination shall contain findings of fact and conclusions supporting the said recommended determination.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Vested rights determination. If the recommended determination of the DIC Executive Council is favorable to the applicant either in whole or in part, the recommended determination shall be as specific as possible in articulating all those matters set forth in subsections (c)(1)—(6). Additionally, the recommended determination shall specify what development permits or development resolutions are vested in relation to specific provisions of this CDMP or land use regulations. Further, the recommended determination shall clearly state that vested rights are not found to be applicable to any development permits or resolutions other than those specified in the recommended determination, nor do vested rights apply against the application or enforcement of any provisions of the CDMP or the County's land use regulations other than those specified in the recommended determination. The vested rights determination shall state that the vested rights determination may be reconsidered if it is subsequently found that the determination was based upon substantially inaccurate information provided by the applicant.
The DIC Executive Council's recommended determination shall be promptly transmitted to each County official, agency, board or department having authority to issue any development permit or resolution encompassed by the recommended vested rights determination.
Official public notice of the issuance of the recommended determination shall be given by posting a short, concise statement of the action taken on a conspicuous bulletin board that may be seen by the public at reasonable times and hours in the office of the Department of Planning and Zoning. If the recommended determination of the DIC Executive Council pertains in any way to a request for a developmental resolution or any other matter over which the Board of County Commissioners may subsequently have original (nonappellate) jurisdiction, the Executive Council's recommended determination shall automatically be placed upon the agenda of the Board of County Commissioners simultaneously with the request for original County Commission action, shall not be binding upon the Board of County Commissioners, and shall be noticed and heard pursuant to the procedure of subsection (h) below. With regard to any application not encompassed by the preceding sentence, the determination of the Executive Council shall become final unless the same is appealed pursuant to the provisions of subsection (h) below.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Appeal, exhaustion of administrative remedies and judicial review. An appeal of a recommended determination of the Executive Council may be taken to the Board of County Commissioners pursuant to the procedures of Sections 33-312 and 33-313 of the Code. The County Commission hearing shall be after notice in accordance with Section 33-313 of the Code which section incorporates the notice provisions of Sections 33-310(c), (d), (e), and (f) of the Code. The Board of County Commissioners shall conduct a de novo hearing and, by resolution, issue a final vested rights determination pursuant to the procedures of Section 33-314 of the Code. Section 33-316 of the Code (Exhaustion of Administrative Remedies, Hearing Procedure and Judicial Review) shall apply to appeals filed pursuant to this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Filing period. Any application for an initial determination of vested rights, pursuant to Section 2-114.2, shall be filed with the DIC Coordinator within: (A) eighteen (18) months after the effective date of this section; or (B) one (1) year after the effective date of any land development regulation enacted subsequent to the effective date of this section [Ordinance No. 90-76] if applicant is seeking a determination that vested rights exempt it from compliance with such subsequently enacted land development regulation.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Effect of vested rights determination. If an affirmative vested rights determination becomes final, then the particular provisions of the CDMP or County land development regulations specified in the final determination shall not limit or modify the vested right of the applicant to complete the particular project in question. However, such a final vested rights determination shall not limit the applicability of any other provisions of the CDMP or any other ordinances, rules, regulations and requirements of Miami-Dade County. Nor shall the vested rights determination entitle the applicant to the issuance of any development resolution or permit not specified in the final vested rights determination. Within these limitations of this subsection, the development rights specifically protected by this section may include, but are not limited to, the following:
<section prefix = "1">
Authorized land use;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Density or intensity of development;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Staging, phasing or timing of development; and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Other conditions of development or mitigation that are specific to the development approval or to the final local development order.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Duty to continue development in good faith.
<section prefix = "1">
In order to implement effective decision-making by the County with regard to the planning, financing and construction of infrastructure, any applicant affirmatively demonstrating the existence of vested rights pursuant to this section and Sections 2-114.3 and 2-114.4 must continue in good faith to develop the vested project after the date of the vested rights determination.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
For any affirmative vested rights determination the DIC Executive Council may include definite criteria and requirements which, if satisfied, will establish conclusively that the applicant has continued in good faith to develop after the date of the vested rights determination. These criteria and requirements shall include one (1) or more of the following:
<section prefix = "a">
A reasonable deadline for commencement of physical development, if such development has not commenced as of the date of the vested rights determination;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Phasing or staging requirements, as appropriate, including but not limited to deadlines for requesting or receiving permits or approvals for initiating and completing various development activities;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Termination dates, which shall reasonably reflect the time required to complete the phase in question or to complete the development, as applicable, and which may take into consideration the requirements of lenders while diligently enforcing security interests; or
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Any other appropriate development requirements set forth in prior development permits.
An applicant's failure to satisfy such criteria and requirements will not necessarily establish that applicant has not continued in good faith to develop the project. However, the vested rights determination for the project will be suspended and all applications for development permits will be subject to the CDMP and applicable land development regulations unless and until the applicant has received a further determination of vested rights pursuant to paragraph (k)(4) below.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The DIC Executive Council may require the submission of annual reports by the applicant on forms to be prepared by the DIC Executive Council, on the anniversaries of the vested rights determination, which include such information as the development activity actually conducted for the past year, sales of undeveloped parcels to third parties, as assessment of the applicant's compliance with the criteria and requirements set forth in the vested rights determination and with any conditions of the original approval, and any other information reasonably required by the DIC Executive Council.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
If an applicant has failed to satisfy the criteria and requirements incorporated in the vested rights determination pursuant to paragraph (k)(2), then the applicant may apply to the DIC Executive Council for a determination that it has in fact continued to develop in good faith since the date of the vested rights determination. Such subsequent determination will be limited solely to a consideration of applicant's development activities and other matters occurring since the date of the vested rights determination, in order to ascertain whether the applicant has continued in good faith to develop since the date of the vested rights determination. That determination shall be governed by the procedures for an initial recommended vested rights determination under this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Nothing set forth in this subsection shall apply to any development that has been authorized as a development of regional impact pursuant to Chapter 380, Florida Statutes, prior to July 1, 1989.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 90-76, § 1, 7-24-90; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-127, § 1, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 98-125, § 1, 9-3-98)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-114.3. Reaffirmation of vested rights</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Requirements to invoke. In lieu of the procedures set forth in Section 2-114.2 of the Code, a property owner shall be entitled to utilize the reaffirmation procedures of this section when (1) there has been a previous determination of vested rights pursuant to Sections 2-114.1 through 2-114.4 of the Code; (2) all "zoning action" (as defined in Section 33-302 of the Code) required for the development sought to be vested was in existence at the time of the previous vested rights determination or was obtained pursuant to the vested rights determination; and (3) subsequent to the prior vested rights determination, the development has received:
<section prefix = "1">
A Class IV permit within one hundred twenty (120) days; or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
A building permit within one hundred twenty (120) days; or
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Approval of a tentative plat within ninety (90) days, approval of a final plat within an additional one hundred eighty (180) days thereafter, and a building permit within an additional ninety (90) days thereafter.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Application. An application form to accomplish the purposes of this section shall be prescribed by the Chairman of the DIC Executive Council. The form shall require information relevant and material to a determination of reaffirmation of vested rights, including but not limited to:
<section prefix = "1">
A detailed description of the particular development in question;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
A complete itemization of each development permit in question;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
A sworn statement by the applicant establishing issuance of the prior vested rights determination and the fulfillment of one (1) or more of the three (3) conditions described in subsection (a). The sworn statement shall have attached a copy of the prior vested rights determination and documentation establishing the extent of compliance with the conditions of that determination. The applicant shall submit with his application a letter of intent explaining the basis of his claim for reaffirmation of vested rights.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Procedure. Except as otherwise specified all standards, procedures, requirements and definitions of Sections 2-114, 2-114.1, and 2-114.2 shall be applicable to applications and proceedings under this section. An application for reaffirming of vested rights shall be filed with the DIC Coordinator. The DIC Coordinator shall verify the correctness of the application and sworn statement and shall give a notice to all County departments affected by the application. The DIC Coordinator shall, within thirty (30) days after receiving a complete application, forward a recommendation to the Chairman of the DIC Executive Council. Except as otherwise provided herein, the DIC Executive Council shall conduct its review in accordance with the standards and procedures of Sections 2-114.1, and 2-114.2. If the Chairman finds that the aforementioned conditions have been met he shall issue a reaffirmation that the prior determination of vested rights still remains in effect. This reaffirmation shall describe, with particularity, the development in question as well as any and all development permits which are vested. If the Chairman finds such conditions have not been met, he shall issue a denial of reaffirmation.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Appeal. Within fourteen (14) days after the issuance of a reaffirmation of vested rights or a denial of reaffirmation, an appeal of that determination to the Board of County Commissioners may be filed pursuant to Sections 33-312 and 33-313 of the Code. The requirement to exhaust remedies, as prescribed by Section 33-316 of the Code, shall apply to the approval or denial of reaffirmation of vested rights.
Such County Commission hearing shall be after notice in accordance with Section 33-313 of the Code, which section incorporates the notice provisions of Sections 33-310(c), (d), (e), and (f) of the Code. The Board of County Commissioners shall conduct a de novo hearing and, by resolution, issue a final vested rights reaffirmation determination pursuant to the procedures of Section 33-314 of the Code. Judicial review shall be pursuant to Section 33-316 of the Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Filing period. Any application for reaffirmation of vested rights pursuant to this section, shall be filed with the DIC Coordinator within sixty (60) days after (a) the expiration of the original determination or a reaffirmation or modification of vested rights, or (b) the applicant's failure to meet a specific timetable identified in the previous vested rights determination, reaffirmation, or modification.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 90-76, § 2, 7-24-90; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-127, § 1, 9-4-96)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-114.4. Modification of vested development</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Purpose and persons eligible to apply. An owner of property which is the subject of (1) a current, valid vested rights determination, (2) a pending application relating thereto pursuant to Sections 2-114.1, 2-114.2, or 2-114.3 of the Code, or (3) a development order approving a development of regional impact subject to the provisions of Section 163.3167(8), Florida Statutes, may file an application for modification of vested development pursuant to this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Application. An application form to accomplish the purposes of this section shall be prescribed by the Chairman of the DIC Executive Council. Such form shall require sworn information relevant and material to a determination of modification of vested development, including but not limited to:
<section prefix = "1">
A statement of the applicant establishing either the issuance of a prior final vested rights determination or a pending application pursuant to Sections 2-114.1, 2-114.2, or 2-114.3 of the Code;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
A detailed description of the existing or pending vested rights determination for the particular development in question, including the period of time for which the applicant claims rights are vested and any and all conditions and limitations applicable to the asserted existing or pending application for vested right to develop;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
A detailed description of the proposed change to the vested development;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
A detailed comparison of the impacts on governmental facilities and services for which the CDMP establishes level of service standards, for both the vested development and the proposed modified development;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
A detailed comparison of the vested development with the proposed modified development pertaining to impacts upon the environment; and
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
A complete itemization of governmental approvals (e.g. permits and resolutions) encompassed by the vested development as compared with those encompassed by the proposed modified development.
In addition to all items otherwise required by the Chairman, the applicant shall attach: (1) copies of any applicable development permits and development orders; and (2) any other documents which either support or negate the relief sought by the applicant.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Standards. A development which is the subject of a current valid vested rights determination or reaffirmation pursuant to Sections 2-114.1, 2-114.2, or 2-114.3 of the Code may be modified without the loss of vested rights upon an affirmative finding that:
<section prefix = "1">
The proposed modified development shall not generate increased impacts on any governmental facilities or services for which the CDMP establishes level or service standards, when compared with the vested development; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The proposed modified development shall not generate increased impacts on the environment when compared to the vested project.
If both of the foregoing standards are met, the proposed modified development may incorporate a land use not previously approved for the vested project, provided that such land use does not exceed either fifteen (15) percent of the acreage of the vested project or fifteen (15) percent of the gross floor area for the vested project, and further provided that this ordinance shall not entitle the applicant or the development to alternate or additional land use approvals, including but not limited to (i) zoning actions as defined by Section 33-302(1) of the Code, or (ii) a use in conflict with the land use element of the CDMP.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Notice; review of application; appeal. The requirements of Section 2-114.2(e) relating to notice, and Section 2-114.2(f) relating to review of the application, shall be applicable to proceedings under this section and shall be in addition to the provisions of this section. Unless otherwise specifically provided herein or required as a matter of practicality, all standards, procedures, and requirements of Sections 2-114, 2-114.1, and 2-114.2 of the Code shall be applicable to applications and proceedings under this section and shall be in addition to the provisions hereof.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Effect of modification of vested development. If an affirmative DIC Executive Council recommendation pertaining to modification of vested development becomes a final determination, then the particular provisions of the CDMP or the County land development regulations specified in the final determination shall not limit or modify the right of the applicant to complete the particular modified development in question. A final determination of modification of vested development, however, shall not limit the applicability of any other provisions of the CDMP or any other ordinances, rules, regulations and requirements of Miami-Dade County. Nor shall the determination of modification of vested development entitle the applicant to the issuance of any development resolution or permit not specified in the final determination. The existence of a final determination of a modification of vested development shall not have any relevance to an application for any such development permit or development resolution other than to provide evidence that the development specified in said determination is subject to vested rights in relation to CDMP provisions or land development regulations specified in the determination.
An applicant who has obtained a determination regarding a modified project shall not be required to commence development of the modified project, and may elect to commence, continue or complete the vested project. However, if the modified development is commenced, the development plan for the original vested development shall stand abandoned together with any determination or reaffirmation of vested rights pertaining thereto.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 90-76, § 3, 7-24-90)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-115. Adoption of Comprehensive Development Master Plan—Relationship to County agencies, boards and departments</catch_line>
<text>
All County agencies, boards and departments shall act consistently with the Comprehensive Development Master Plan when considering and taking action affecting land use and development in Miami-Dade County. In accordance herewith, copies of this ordinance, together with the Comprehensive Development Master Plan, shall be furnished to all County boards, departments and agencies and shall be made a part of the public records. The goals, objectives and policies shall be broadly construed and shall apply to all developmental actions and orders of all County agencies and Boards, whether or not specifically named in said policies. Moreover, the County Manager is authorized to designate alternative or additional County Boards, departments, and agencies to conduct activities necessary to implement the goals, objectives or policies.
</text>
All County agencies, boards and departments shall act consistently with the Comprehensive Development Master Plan when considering and taking action affecting land use and development in Miami-Dade County. In accordance herewith, copies of this ordinance, together with the Comprehensive Development Master Plan, shall be furnished to all County boards, departments and agencies and shall be made a part of the public records. The goals, objectives and policies shall be broadly construed and shall apply to all developmental actions and orders of all County agencies and Boards, whether or not specifically named in said policies. Moreover, the County Manager is authorized to designate alternative or additional County Boards, departments, and agencies to conduct activities necessary to implement the goals, objectives or policies.
Note—See editor's note following § 2-112.1.

Annotation—AO 4-59.
<catch_line>Sec. 2-115.1. Adoption of Comprehensive Development Master Plan—Necessity for further implementation</catch_line>
<text>
It is hereby declared that the Comprehensive Development Master Plan shall be the basis for more specific rules, regulations and ordinances which shall implement the policies, standards and objectives expressed in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan. Further, such implementation shall include and encourage the continuance of an affirmative action program for the construction and development of low and moderate income housing with Miami-Dade County, Florida. The statutory requirement that a local government shall not issue a development order or permit which results in a reduction in the level of services for the affected public facilities below the level of services provided in the comprehensive plan shall not take effect until the County has adopted land development regulations specifically addressing said statutory requirement. Said land development regulations shall be adopted not later than the date specified in Section 163.3202, Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time.
</text>
It is hereby declared that the Comprehensive Development Master Plan shall be the basis for more specific rules, regulations and ordinances which shall implement the policies, standards and objectives expressed in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan. Further, such implementation shall include and encourage the continuance of an affirmative action program for the construction and development of low and moderate income housing with Miami-Dade County, Florida. The statutory requirement that a local government shall not issue a development order or permit which results in a reduction in the level of services for the affected public facilities below the level of services provided in the comprehensive plan shall not take effect until the County has adopted land development regulations specifically addressing said statutory requirement. Said land development regulations shall be adopted not later than the date specified in Section 163.3202, Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time.
Note—See the editor's note following § 2-112.1.
<catch_line>Sec. 2-115.2. Fire Protection and Rescue Services Master Plan for the Miami-Dade County Area—Adoption and amendment</catch_line>
<text>
The Board of County Commissioners hereby adopts all recommendations (1 through 36) contained in the Miami-Dade County Fire Protection and Rescue Services Master Plan for the Miami-Dade County Area and accepts the balance of the report (as revised dated October 28, 1976), as a further refinement of the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan and a component part thereof. A copy of the Fire Protection and Rescue Services Master Plan for the Miami-Dade County Area as revised dated October 28, 1976, shall be on file at all times with the Clerk of the County Commission. The County Commission may amend the Miami-Dade County Fire Protection and Rescue Services Master Plan by ordinance.
</text>
The Board of County Commissioners hereby adopts all recommendations (1 through 36) contained in the Miami-Dade County Fire Protection and Rescue Services Master Plan for the Miami-Dade County Area and accepts the balance of the report (as revised dated October 28, 1976), as a further refinement of the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan and a component part thereof. A copy of the Fire Protection and Rescue Services Master Plan for the Miami-Dade County Area as revised dated October 28, 1976, shall be on file at all times with the Clerk of the County Commission. The County Commission may amend the Miami-Dade County Fire Protection and Rescue Services Master Plan by ordinance.
<catch_line>Sec. 2-115.3. Fire Protection and Rescue Services Master Plan for the Miami-Dade County Area—Legal status</catch_line>
<text>
The Fire Protection and Rescue Services Master Plan for the Miami-Dade County Area is hereby declared to be a further refinement of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and shall constitute a guide for the orderly growth and development of Miami-Dade County, Florida. In furtherance thereof, the Board of County Commissioners declares its policy and intent to evaluate and consider the criteria established in the Fire Protection and Rescue Services Master Plan for the Miami-Dade County Area as an element in future land planning and development decisions. The failure or inability of Miami-Dade County or others to meet any criteria in the plan shall not, in and of itself, constitute grounds for restrictions or limitations on land use or development, or for the denial of any application for zoning.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-115.4. Transportation Plan for Miami-Dade County—Adoption</catch_line>
<text>
The Board of County Commissioners hereby enacts the twenty-page document entitled "Long Range Element of the Year 2005 Miami-Dade Transportation Plan" (June 1985) as the Transportation Plan for Miami-Dade County, revised, hereinafter referred to in its entirety as the "Transportation Plan" or "Plan."
Such Plan lists transportation improvements to be implemented during the twenty-year period. The order or priority in which such improvements are to be made is not part of the plan, and the establishment of or change in such order or priority by appropriate MPO action shall not constitute an amendment to the plan.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-115.5. Transportation Plan for Miami-Dade County—Legal status and amendment requirements</catch_line>
<text>
The adopted Transportation Plan for Miami-Dade County is hereby declared to be ancillary to but not a part of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan of Miami-Dade County, and shall constitute a guide for the programming and provision of transportation improvements in Miami-Dade County. In furtherance thereof, the Board of County Commissioners declares its policy and intent to evaluate and consider this plan in all future decisions relating to transportation improvements. The failure or inability of Miami-Dade County or others to adhere to this plan shall not, in and of itself, constitute grounds for restrictions or limitations on land development use or development, or for any application for zoning.
Any requested amendment to the adopted Transportation Plan shall be considered by the Board of County Commissioners only after the transportation Planning Council of the Metropolitan Planning Organization, the Miami-Dade County Citizens' Transportation Advisory Committee, the Miami-Dade County Planning Advisory Board and the Department of Planning and Zoning have forwarded to the County Commission their recommendations regarding the disposition of the requested amendment. All amendments to the Transportation Plan shall be by ordinance.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-115.6. Agricultural Land Use Plan—Findings and legislative intent</catch_line>
<text>
The foregoing declarations and findings are found to be true and are hereby adopted as the legislative intent of the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and are made a part hereof. The Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida, hereby declares and finds that it is essential to encourage and protect agriculture as a viable economic use of Miami-Dade County's land. This Board declares and finds that the agricultural land use plan provides a comprehensive framework to guide future planning, land use, and land development decisions in a manner that will minimize the adverse effects of continuing urban growth on Miami-Dade County's farmland; will help maintain a supply of land for a diversity of viable agricultural uses; will protect and enhance agriculture as a resource of economic, social and environmental importance to Miami-Dade County; will help maintain an adequate supply of land for urban uses; and will provide for continuing urban growth. It is the purpose and intent of this Board to protect the health, safety, and welfare of the present and future inhabitants of Miami-Dade County through implementation of the "final proposals" of the "Agricultural Land Use Plan for Miami-Dade County, Florida," dated March 1983.
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 83-24, adopted May 3, 1983, amended Ch. 2, Art. XV, but did not specify disposition of individual sections; therefore, codification of §§ 1—5 as §§ 2-115.6—2.115.10 has been at the editor's discretion. The "whereas" clauses, adopted by reference in § 2-115.6, are not reproduced herein.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-115.7. Agricultural Land Use Plan—Adoption and acceptance</catch_line>
<text>
The Board of County Commissioners hereby adopts as policy subject to further implementation the "Final Proposals of the Agricultural Land Use Plan" dated March, 1983, which appear on pages ii through vi of the document titled "Agricultural Land Use Plan for Miami-Dade County, Florida," dated March, 1983. The Board of County Commissioners accepts, as background and informational material used for the preparation of the plan and as a guide for the preparation of future studies, the document titled "Agricultural Land Use Plan for Miami-Dade County, Florida," dated March, 1983, and the background reports listed in Appendix C of that document which were prepared by the agricultural land use planning project.
</text>
The Board of County Commissioners hereby adopts as policy subject to further implementation the "Final Proposals of the Agricultural Land Use Plan" dated March, 1983, which appear on pages ii through vi of the document titled "Agricultural Land Use Plan for Miami-Dade County, Florida," dated March, 1983. The Board of County Commissioners accepts, as background and informational material used for the preparation of the plan and as a guide for the preparation of future studies, the document titled "Agricultural Land Use Plan for Miami-Dade County, Florida," dated March, 1983, and the background reports listed in Appendix C of that document which were prepared by the agricultural land use planning project.
Note—See the editor's note for § 2-115.6
<catch_line>Sec. 2-115.8. Agricultural Land Use Plan—Legal status</catch_line>
<text>
The adopted "Final Proposals of the Agricultural Land Use Plan" are hereby declared to be ancillary to but not a part of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan of Miami-Dade County (CDMP) and shall constitute a guide for land use in a manner that will minimize adverse impacts upon agricultural land use in areas designated "agricultural area" on the map in Figure 1 of the "Final Proposals of the Agricultural Land Use Plan." In furtherance thereof, the Board of County Commissioners declares its policy and intent to evaluate and consider the final proposals in all its zoning and other public actions involving or affecting land use or development within areas designated "agricultural area" on the above-reference map as may be amended from time to time through the CDMP amendment process.
In the event that any inconsistencies or conflicts are found between the adopted "Final Proposals of the Agricultural Land Use Plan" and the materials accepted herein as background information, the adopted "Final Proposals" shall prevail.
</text>
The adopted "Final Proposals of the Agricultural Land Use Plan" are hereby declared to be ancillary to but not a part of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan of Miami-Dade County (CDMP) and shall constitute a guide for land use in a manner that will minimize adverse impacts upon agricultural land use in areas designated "agricultural area" on the map in Figure 1 of the "Final Proposals of the Agricultural Land Use Plan." In furtherance thereof, the Board of County Commissioners declares its policy and intent to evaluate and consider the final proposals in all its zoning and other public actions involving or affecting land use or development within areas designated "agricultural area" on the above-reference map as may be amended from time to time through the CDMP amendment process.
In the event that any inconsistencies or conflicts are found between the adopted "Final Proposals of the Agricultural Land Use Plan" and the materials accepted herein as background information, the adopted "Final Proposals" shall prevail.
Note—See the editor's note for § 2-115.6
<catch_line>Sec. 2-115.9. Agricultural Land Use Plan—Relationship to County agencies, boards and departments</catch_line>
<text>
All County agencies, boards and departments shall take into consideration and be guided by the "Final Proposals of the Agricultural Land Use Plan" when considering and taking action affecting land use and development in Miami-Dade County. In accordance herewith, copies of the ordinance, from which this section derives, together with the "Final Proposals of the Agricultural Land Use Plan," shall be furnished to all affected County boards, departments and agencies and shall be made a part of the public records.
</text>
All County agencies, boards and departments shall take into consideration and be guided by the "Final Proposals of the Agricultural Land Use Plan" when considering and taking action affecting land use and development in Miami-Dade County. In accordance herewith, copies of the ordinance, from which this section derives, together with the "Final Proposals of the Agricultural Land Use Plan," shall be furnished to all affected County boards, departments and agencies and shall be made a part of the public records.
Note—See the editor's note for § 2-115.6
<catch_line>Sec. 2-115.10. Agricultural Land Use Plan—Necessity for further implementation</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager is hereby instructed to prepare and submit to the Board of County Commissioners ordinances and regulations which are necessary to implement the "Final Proposals of the Agricultural Land Use Plan."
</text>
The County Manager is hereby instructed to prepare and submit to the Board of County Commissioners ordinances and regulations which are necessary to implement the "Final Proposals of the Agricultural Land Use Plan."
Note—See the editor's note for § 2-115.6
<catch_line>Sec. 2-115.11. Biscayne National Park Buffer Development Review Committee; intent and purpose; establishment; membership; qualifications; appointment; term; duties; staff support</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Legislative intent and purpose.
<section prefix = "a">
It is the intent of the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida, to develop a plan and study, to be known collectively as the South Miami-Dade Land Use and Water Management Plan (hereinafter referred to as "the Plan"), pursuant to policy established in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan (CDMP). The purposes of this Plan shall be:
<section prefix = "i">
To identify and protect lands, including their uses and functions, that are essential for preserving the environmental, economic and community values of Biscayne National Park;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
To identify and establish mechanisms for protecting constitutional private property rights of owners of lands identified in (1)(a)i. above.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
To support a viable, balanced economy including agriculture, recreation, tourism, and urban development in the planning area, hereafter defined as the area from the C-2 (Snapper Creek) canal basin south as the primary area, and the C-3 (Coral Gables) to C-2 canal basin as a secondary area, as said canal basins are delineated in the South Florida Water Management District's November 1995 Update of the Surface Water Improvement and Management (SWIM) Plan for Biscayne Bay.
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
To assure compatible land uses and zoning decisions in the planning area consistent with long-term objectives for a sustainable south Miami-Dade.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
In the interim, until the plan is adopted, it is the intent of the Board of County Commissioners to conservatively manage land and water resources within the described plan area east of US-1 outside the Urban Development Boundary (UDB) as delineated in the CDMP (hereinafter referred to as the "Review Area") to enable the prospective plan to accomplish its purposes. Toward that end, until the plan is prepared and the Board of County Commissioners takes final action on the proposed plan, all County boards shall apply heightened scrutiny to potential impacts on Biscayne National Park that might result from any requests for CDMP amendments or other development approvals in the Review Area that require approval at a public hearing.
Until the plan is completed, a review committee shall be created to advise appropriate County boards regarding certain requests for CDMP amendments and development approvals in the Review Area, in the manner provided herein.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Biscayne National Park Buffer Development Review Committee.
<section prefix = "a">
There is hereby established an advisory board to be known as the Biscayne National Park Buffer Development Review Committee. The Committee shall be composed of nine (9) members, appointed as follows: one representative from Biscayne National Park; one representative from the South Florida Water Management district; two (2) representatives from nonregulatory environmental organizations/advocacy groups; one representative of landowners; one representative of a local lending institution having an equity interest in land, in the Review Area; two (2) representatives from local agricultural organizations; and one representative from a Chamber of Commerce active in south Miami-Dade.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Each member shall be appointed by the County Manager and approved by the Board of County Commissioners to serve a term lasting the duration of the Committee's life or until replaced by the County Manager with the approval of the Board of County Commissioners. Appointments and activities of the Committee shall otherwise comply with requirements of Sections 2-11.36 through 2-11.40 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. At its first meeting and annually thereafter, the Committee shall elect a Chair and Vice Chair. It is the Chair's responsibility to chair all meetings, to certify the recommendations issued by the Committee to the final decision-making body, and to issue an annual report to the Board of County Commissioners in accordance with Section 2-11.37(a), Code of Miami-Dade County. A simple majority of the Committee members shall constitute a quorum and a simple majority of a quorum of the Committee shall be required for the passage of any motion or approval of any recommendation.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The responsibility of the Biscayne National Park Buffer Development Review committee shall be to evaluate and make recommendations on requests for CDMP amendments and development approvals in the Review Area which require approval after a public hearing pursuant to the requirements of Chapter 33, Miami-Dade County Code, including, but not limited to, zoning district boundary changes, special exceptions, unusual uses, use variances, nonuse variances, and nonadministrative site plan reviews. The Committee's recommendations shall specifically address and be limited to potential impacts on Biscayne National Park and consistency with relevant provisions of the CDMP. The Committee's recommendations may include appropriate justifications for their conclusions, and recommendations for approval may include conditions where appropriate. In formulating its recommendations, the Committee shall consider County staff's evaluation and/or recommendations if timely available, public comments, and other information received during public meetings conducted by the Committee. Any such information or considerations shall be made part of the public record of the Committee. If a proposal is scheduled for review by the Committee at a properly noticed public meeting, and the Committee fails to adopt a recommendation on the proposal, the Committee's recommendation shall be deemed to be without objection to the proposal.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The County Manager shall assign appropriate staff, who shall prepare necessary meeting materials and advertisements, arrange meeting locations, and transmit the recommendations of the Committee to the appropriate body. The Committee's meetings and actions shall be scheduled in a manner that will enable timely issuance of recommendations in advance of agenda preparation for the final decision-making body without delaying the established procedure of that body.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
After January 2002 and until the Watershed Plan is implemented, the Review Committee shall apply the following interim measures to the Board of County Commissioners to further the purposes of the Plan and to assist in the heightened scrutiny required by this section. These measures are as follows:
<section prefix = "i">
Applicants for uses other than those permitted as of right in the applicable Comprehensive Development Master Plan designation and by the existing zoning should be required to demonstrate that the proposed use is a public necessity, or is in the public interest and that no suitable site for the use exists outside of the Review Area.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
For each application involving a telecommunications tower in the Review Area, the applicant shall provide the Review Committee and the applicable community zoning appeals board with a regional map showing the location of existing and permitted telecommunication towers and available data on the impact of existing towers on birds, in areas comparable to the Review Area. Further, the applicant shall document that co-location opportunities, existing public structures and already developed public lands have been utilized to the maximum extent feasible and that design aesthetics have been incorporated. Assessment of feasibility shall include consideration of the technical requirements of differing types of telecommunications providers. The County shall review all documentation submitted by the applicant pursuant to the above requirements for technical accuracy. The Committee and the applicable community zoning appeals board shall defer or deny actions on applications for telecommunications towers in the Review Area until the above listed items are provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
County staff from DERM and the Department of Planning and Zoning shall coordinate reports on all issued and pending state and federal environmental permits associated with a specific, pending development proposal in the Review Area. These reports should be presented by representatives of the permitting agencies, including the South Florida Water Management District, the Florida Department of Environmental Protection, and the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, at public meetings conducted by the Committee, and/or submitted in writing prior to public meetings.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The Committee may issue recommendations for revisions to these interim measures or for additional interim measures from time to time until the Plan is approved.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 97-22, § 1, 3-18-97; Ord. No. 99-43, § 1, 4-27-99; Ord. No. 01-111, § 1, 6-19-01; Ord. No. 02-233, § 1, 10-22-02)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-115.12. Advisory committee for the South Miami-Dade Watershed Plan</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Legislative intent and purpose.
<section prefix = "a">
It is the intent of the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County to establish a broad-based Advisory Committee (the Committee) to participate in the formulation of the South Dade Watershed Plan (the Watershed Plan) to be prepared pursuant to policy established in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan (CDMP). The purposes of the Committee and duties of its members shall be as follows:
<section prefix = "i">
To serve as a conduit of information between project supervisors, consultants retained to prepare the Watershed Plan, and community interests represented by the Committee members;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
To advise the consultants and assigned County, South Florida Water Management District, and Regional Planning Council staff as to the views of the Committee members and represented community interests;
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
To inform the membership of represented interest organizations as to the purpose of the watershed planning project, status of planning activities, findings and proposals, and bases thereof;
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
To suggest information sources to the consultants; and
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
To review and comment on the proposed scope of work and subsequent consultant drafts and deliverables;
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
South Miami-Dade Watershed Plan Advisory Committee.
<section prefix = "a">
There is hereby established an advisory committee to be known as the South Miami-Dade Watershed Plan Advisory Committee. The Committee shall be comprised of voting and nonvoting members as follows:
<section prefix = "i">
Voting members shall be representatives of the Miami-Dade Agri-Council, the Miami-Dade County Agricultural Practices Study Advisory Board, the Miami-Dade County Farm Bureau, the Potato Grower Exchange, the Miami-Dade County Chapter of the Florida Nurserymen and Grower's Association, the Florida Lime and Avocado Committee, the Tropical Everglades Visitor Association, the Homestead-Florida City Chamber of Commerce, Chamber South, the Florida Engineering Society, a citizens' organization active in the combined geographic area of Community Councils 11 and 12, a citizens' organization active in the combined geographic area of Community Councils 13 and 15, the Redland Citizens' Association as the citizens' organization active in the area of Community Council 14, one building industry organization, the National Audubon Society, the Tropical Audubon Society, the Sierra Club Miami Group, Biscayne National Park, Everglades National Park, the cities of Homestead and Florida City, one member from the community at large appointed by the County Manager to serve as Chairperson and two at large members recommended by the Chairperson.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Non-voting members shall be representatives of the Miami-Dade Department of Planning and Zoning, the Miami-Dade Department of Environmental Resources Management, the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, the South Florida Water Management District, the South Florida Regional Planning Council, and the Florida Department of Environmental Protection.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Each member shall be appointed by the County Manager and approved by the Board of County Commissioners to serve until the Board of County Commissioners takes final action on the proposed Watershed Plan, or until replaced by the County Manager with the approval of the Board of County Commissioners. The provision in Section 2-11.38 of this Code prohibiting simultaneous membership on more than one County board shall not apply to those members of the Miami-Dade County Agricultural Practices Study Advisory Board, the Floodplain Management Task Force, the Redland Area Municipal Advisory Committee, and the Biscayne National Park Buffer Development Review Committee who are appointed to the Committee. Appointments and activities of the Committee shall otherwise comply with the requirements of Sections 2-11.36 through 2-11.40 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. The County Manager shall appoint the Chair. It is the Chair's responsibility to chair all meetings and to issue an annual report to the Board of County Commissioners in accordance with Section 2-11.37(a). Code of Miami-Dade County. A simple majority of the Committee members shall constitute a quorum, and a two-thirds majority of a quorum of the Committee shall be required for the passage of any motion. The Committee may establish other procedures and protocols regarding attendance, alternate attendees, and voting. The Committee shall automatically sunset upon adoption of the Plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The County Manager shall assign appropriate staff to assist the Committee in accomplishing its purpose, including the following: prepare necessary meeting materials and notices; arrange meeting locations; prepare meeting summaries; and transmit communications between the Committee, project consultants, and participating agencies.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 00-37, § 1, 3-21-00; Ord. No. 01-97, § 1, 5-24-01; Ord. No. 01-200, § 1, 12-4-01; Ord. No. 04-62, § 1, 3-16-04)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-115.13. Citizens' Advisory Committee for the Agriculture and Rural Area Study; intent and purpose; establishment; membership; qualifications; appointment; term; duties; staff support</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Legislative intent and purpose.
<section prefix = "a">
It is the intent of the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County to establish a broad-based Citizens' Advisory Committee (the CAC) for the Agriculture and Rural Area Study (the Study) pursuant to policy established in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan (CDMP). The purposes of the CAC and duties of its members shall be:
<section prefix = "i">
To serve as a two-way conduit of information between consultants retained to assist in the study and community interests represented by the CAC members;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
To advise the consultants and assigned County, South Florida Water Management District, and U.S. Army Corps of Engineers staff as to those views represented by the CAC members;
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
To suggest information sources to the consultants; and
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
To review and comment on the consultants' draft and all deliverables, including recommendations on polices, programs, and strategies.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Citizens' Advisory Committee for the Agriculture and Rural Area Study.
<section prefix = "a">
There is hereby established an advisory board to be known as the Citizens' Advisory Committee (CAC) for the Agriculture and Rural Area Study. The CAC shall be composed of sixteen (16) members appointed as follows: one representative from the row crop industry, to be recommended by the Miami-Dade County Farm Bureau; one representative from the lime and avocado industry, to be recommended by the Florida Lime and Avocado Growers Association; one representative from the tree crop industry, to be recommended by Tropical Fruit Growers of South Florida; two representatives from the nursery industry, to be recommended by the Florida Nurseryman and Growers Association; one agribusiness representative, to be recommended from the Florida Fertilizer and Agri-Chemical Association; one agri-banking representative, recommended from a bank in South Dade with significant involvement in commercial/banking aspects of the agricultural industry; one representative from and recommended by the Homestead/Florida City Chamber of Commerce; one representative from and recommended by the Redland Citizen's Association; one representative of farm labor recommended by the Coalition of Florida Farmworkers Organizations; one representative of the aquaculture industry, recommended by the South Florida Aquaculture Association; one representative of the agricultural land leasing real estate industry, to be recommended by the Agricultural Practices Study Advisory Board; one representative from and recommended by the Redland Conservancy; one representative from and recommended by the National Audubon Society; one representative from and recommended by Sierra Club; and one representative from and to be recommended by the Miami-Dade County Agri-Council.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Each member shall be appointed by the County Manager and approved by the Board of County Commissioners to serve until submission of the study to the Board of County Commissioners or until replaced by the County Manager with the approval of the Board of County Commissioners. Except for the provision prohibiting membership on two County boards, appointments and activities of the CAC shall otherwise comply with the requirements of Sections 2-11.36 through 2-11.40 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. At its first meeting, the CAC shall elect a Chair and Vice-Chair. It is the Chair's responsibility to chair all meetings and to issue an annual report to the Board of County Commissioners in accordance with Section 2-11.37(a), Code of Miami-Dade County. A simple majority of the CAC members shall constitute a quorum and a simple majority of a quorum of the CAC shall be required for the passage of any motion. The CAC shall automatically sunset upon the completion of the Study.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The County Manager shall assign appropriate staff. Designated staff shall prepare necessary meeting materials and advertisements, arrange meeting locations, and undertake other responsibilities associated with staffing the CAC.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 00-136, § 1, 10-3-00)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-116. Evaluation and appraisal of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The evaluation and appraisal process shall be the principal process for updating the Comprehensive Development Master Plan (CDMP) to reflect changes in state policy on planning and growth management. The evaluation and appraisal of the CDMP shall be prepared and presented in a report. Such report shall contain an assessment and evaluation of the success or failure of the comprehensive plan or element or portion thereof, and shall also recommend changes needed to update the comprehensive plan, or elements or portions thereof, including reformulated objectives, policies, and standards and shall contain a schedule for reviewing and taking final action on the proposed amendments.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Director of the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources, or successor agency (hereinafter referred to as "the Department") shall prepare the evaluation and appraisal report pursuant to Section 2-105.1, Code of Miami-Dade County, for finalization by the Planning Advisory Board acting in its capacity as the Miami-Dade County local planning agency (LPA) pursuant to Section 2-108.1, Code of Miami-Dade County, and for adoption by the Board of County Commissioners as provided in this section. Not less than three (3) months prior to the deadline established by the State Land Planning Agency to comply with Section 163.3191, F.S., for evaluating the comprehensive plan, the Director of the Department shall deliver the proposed report to the Planning Advisory Board acting in its capacity as the LPA.
Upon receipt of the proposed plan evaluation and appraisal report, the Planning Advisory Board acting as the LPA shall conduct one (1) or more public hearings duly noticed in accordance with Section 163.3164(17), F.S.
Following the public hearing(s), the Planning Advisory Board acting as the LPA, shall complete preparation of the report, including their recommendations, and submit it to the Board of County Commissioners not less than two (2) months prior to the deadline established by the State Land Planning Agency to comply with Section 163.3191, F.S. The Department may issue recommendations regarding the report as finalized by the LPA.
The Board of County Commissioners shall by resolution adopt, or adopt with changes, the report or portions thereof on or before the date established by the State Land Planning Agency to comply with Section 163.3191, F.S.
Not less than six (6) months prior to the deadlines established by the State Land Planning Agency to comply with Section 163.3191, F.S., the Department shall publish in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County a schedule of all activities required by law for evaluating the comprehensive plan. Any changes in the schedule shall be published in the same manner. The published schedule and changes thereto shall be delivered to the Board of County Commissioners and the Planning Advisory Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
At any time prior to or during preparation or review of the proposed or recommended evaluation and appraisal report, the Board of County Commissioners, Planning Advisory Board or the Department may conduct public meetings or public workshops in addition to the public hearing specified herein to address the matters set forth in Section 163.3191(4), F.S. Any such public workshop shall be advertised in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County, at least once seven (7) to fourteen (14) days prior to the date of said workshop.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 75-22, § 7, 3-31-75; Ord. No. 76-4, § 1, 1-20-76; Ord. No. 76-95, § 1, 10-19-76; Ord. No. 78-48, § 1, 7-18-78; Ord. No. 79-80, § 1, 10-2-79; Ord. No. 88-18, § 1, 4-5-88; Ord. No. 90-2, § 1, 1-16-90; Ord. No. 92-17, § 3, 3-17-92; Ord. No. 92-120, § 1, 10-13-92; Ord. No. 93-23, § 1, 3-30-93; Ord. No. 93-131, § 1, 11-16-93; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 1, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 13-25, § 1, 3-5-13)</history>
Annotations—AO's 4-49, 4-81.
<catch_line>Sec. 2-116.1. Amendment procedure for Comprehensive Development Master Plan</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Scope of eligibility.
<section prefix = "a">
Any person or organization, including the federal government, the State of Florida, Miami-Dade County, any municipality in Miami-Dade County and any of their agencies, authorities and departments may request the initiation of the amendatory process provided below.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
If the applicant has an ownership interest in any real property covered by an application to amend the land use element of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan, such interest shall be disclosed in the same manner as required of zoning applicants in Section 33-304 of the Miami-Dade County Code. If the applicant is acting as agent or attorney for a principal, the principal's interest shall be disclosed in the same manner as required of zoning applicants in Section 33-304 of the Miami-Dade County Code. This subsection (b) shall not apply to governmental applicants.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Application. Except as specifically provided below for applications pursuant to a compliance agreement, pursuant to a State statutory requirement, or pursuant to a concurrently requested development of regional impact (DRI) development order or change to an existing DRI development order, or for applications relating to reuse of military bases pursuant to Chapter 288, F.S., any request for amendments, modifications, additions or changes to the Comprehensive Development Master Plan shall be submitted to the Miami-Dade County Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources or successor agency (hereinafter referred to as "the Department") during the period between May 1 and May 31 inclusive (hereinafter "May period"), and during the period between November 1 and November 30 inclusive (hereinafter "November period"), in each year only in accordance with the following provisions:
<section prefix = "a">
Applications requesting amendment to the Urban Development Boundary (UDB) or to the Urban Expansion Area (UEA) boundary depicted on the Land Use Plan map, or to the land use classification of land located outside of said Urban Development Boundary may be filed only during the May period in odd-numbered years. The Director of the Department may also file applications requesting amendments to the UDB, UEA or to the land use classification of land located outside of said UDB for processing during either the May or November period following the adoption of an evaluation and appraisal report, provided that the amendments proposed in said applications are suggested in the adopted evaluation and appraisal report.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
All requests shall be made by filing an application in a form and containing the information prescribed by the Director of the Department. Applicants seeking to have their requests considered to be small-scale amendment applications, as provided in Section 163.3187, F.S., and eligible for processing in accordance with the procedures provided herein for final action, shall clearly state such request in the application. Small-scale amendment applications shall not be eligible to request amendments to modify or expand the UDB or UEA. All proposed plan amendment applications not requested for adoption as small-scale amendment applications, and all requested small-scale amendment applications which are not adopted but which are transmitted to the State Land Planning Agency and other review agencies for review and comment are hereby defined as standard expedited amendment applications. Applications which are deemed by the Department to be unclear or incomplete may be supplemented no later than the seventh (7th) business day following notice from the Department that the application filed is deficient.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners may, by resolution or ordinance, at any time initiate a request to amend, modify, add to or change the Comprehensive Development Master Plan, or may, by resolution or motion, authorize or direct the County Mayor to utilize the optional procedure provided in Section 288.975, F.S., and Section 2-116.1(5)(b), herein, to amend the CDMP to enable military base reuse. Except for requests by the Board of County Commissioners to amend the Comprehensive Development Master Plan in the case of a compliance agreement as provided in Section 163.3187(5). F.S., in the case of a State statutory requirement, in the case of an application necessary to authorize a Development of Regional Impact initiated by the County, in the case of an application for a small-scale amendment pursuant to Section 163.3187, F.S., in the case of an application relating to military base reuse, prepared pursuant to Section 288.975, F.S., or unless otherwise provided by said resolution or ordinance, the content, activities, and time periods herein provided, as quantified by number of days, shall be substantially applicable to such a request from the date of the adoption of the resolution or ordinance. Said resolution or ordinance shall direct the County Mayor to include the special application for review and action along with May period or November period applications as provided herein or that the special application shall be reviewed and action shall be taken on a special schedule prescribed in the resolution or ordinance. In no instance shall the filing or authorization of applications by the Board of County Commissioners for processing on a special schedule result in adoption of more than two (2) Comprehensive Development Master Plan amendments in any calendar year except in the case of a concurrent approval of a Development of Regional Impact as provided in Section 380.06(6)(b), F.S., approval of a small-scale amendment as provided in Section 163.3187, F.S., a compliance agreement as provided in Section 163.3187(1)(e), F.S., or utilization of the optional CDMP amendment procedure for military base reuse as provided in Section 288.975, F.S.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
In the event that the Board of County Commissioners has entered into a compliance agreement pursuant to Section 163.3184(6), F.S., requiring the filing of an application to amend, modify, add to or change the Comprehensive Development Master Plan, the County Mayor or the Mayor's designee shall file an application pursuant to the terms of the approved settlement agreement in accordance with the content, activities and time periods provided by the terms of the compliance agreement and by the resolution approving such agreement and in accordance with the procedures provided in Section 163.3184(6), F.S.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Procedure upon application; Director of Regulatory and Economic Resources, Community Councils, Planning Advisory Board (PAB), and Board of County Commissioners; or applications pursuant to a compliance agreement.
<section prefix = "a">
Upon receipt of an application for amendment, modification, addition or change to the Comprehensive Development Master Plan, the Director of the Department shall consult with other County personnel, departments or agencies, a municipality or County having jurisdiction over or adjacent to the area in question as he deems necessary to evaluate the proposed application. Each application may be deemed by the Board of County Commissioners to include similarly situated or adjoining property which could be affected by the adoption of the request in whole or in part, except that no such determination by the Board of County Commissioners shall cause a requested small-scale amendment to exceed the conditions for such amendments enumerated in Section 163.3187(1)(e), F.S.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Director of the Department shall prepare an applications report listing all applications received, including small-scale amendment applications and staff applications, including the nature of the application and the reasons stated for requesting the proposed amendment, modification, addition or change. The report shall also itemize proposals suggested and under evaluation by the Department staff; however, this initial identification of staff proposals shall not preclude further staff proposals. Such staff proposals, except those initiated in direct response to the written comments submitted by the State Land Planning Agency and other review agencies pursuant to Section 163.3184(3) and (4), F.S., shall be finalized no later than the advertised notice of the public hearing to be conducted by the Community Councils pursuant to Section 2-116.1(3)(e), Code of Miami-Dade County. Further staff proposals initiated in direct response to the written comments submitted by the State Land Planning Agency and other review agencies shall be finalized no later than two weeks prior to the date of the Board of County Commissioners final public hearing pursuant to Section 2-116.1(4)(b), Code of Miami-Dade County. The Department and the local planning agency are authorized to recommend, and the Board of County Commissioners is authorized to adopt, CDMP amendments with changes to include, (a) similarly situated or adjoining property which could be affected by the adoption of a request, (b) staff proposals in whole or in part as provided in this section, (c) changes within the scope of the applications and staff proposals, or (d) changes to ensure internal consistency among plan elements, applications or staff proposals.
On or before June 21st following the filing of May period applications and December 21st following the filing of November period applications, the applications report shall be submitted to the Planning Advisory Board and directly impacted Community Councils as determined by the Director of the Department and shall be available to the public at the same time. Any small-scale application may be withdrawn by written notice by the applicant filed with the Director on or before the deadline established in paragraph (3)(f) for formulation of recommendations by the Planning Advisory Board acting as the local planning agency, and any standard or transmitted application may be withdrawn by written notice by the applicant filed with the Director on or before the deadline for formulation of final recommendations by the Department. After these dates a withdrawal may be authorized only by affirmative vote of the Board of County Commissioners. However, in no instance shall a filing fee be refunded unless timely request for withdrawal and refund is filed in accordance with paragraph (8), herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
For the purposes of preparing the initial recommendations of the Department, the Director shall request an evaluation from all county departments and agencies responsible for supplying and maintaining infrastructure and services relevant to the CDMP as determined by the Director. Such departments and agencies shall respond with a written evaluation of the estimated incremental and cumulative impact on Miami-Dade County for bringing such infrastructure and services to the area as well as the costs of annually operating and maintaining such infrastructure and services. The evaluation shall estimate the extent to which the costs of the required infrastructure and services will be borne by the described property or will require general taxpayer support, and an estimate of the amount of such support. The Director shall also request a similar report from non-County authorities and agencies which may be affected by a proposed land use change including but not limited to the Metropolitan Planning Organization, Miami-Dade County Public School District, and the South Florida Water Management District. The Director shall consider responses received in writing by any person or organization, on or before the tenth (10th) day in July following the filing of May period applications and on or before the tenth (10th) day of January following the filing of November period applications. The Director shall also consider and evaluate the information presented at any public workshops which are held in accordance with this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
On or before the twenty-fifth (25th) day in August following the filing of May period applications and the twenty-fifth (25th) day of February following the filing of November period applications, the Department shall issue its initial recommendations on the applications. The initial recommendations of the Department shall refer to each application specifically or as combined with other similar applications and shall consider all comments, information and recommendations received in accordance with paragraph (c) above. The initial recommendations of the Department are not necessarily limited to specific applications but may deal with any aspect of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan.
<section prefix = "1">
The proposed future land use plan map designation of the subject property; the boundary of the subject property and its location in relation to the surrounding street and thoroughfare network shall be shown on (a) map(s);
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The land use designations of the subject property and abutting properties currently designated on the future land use plan map shall be shown on (a) map(s);
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The size of the subject property in acres or fractions thereof shall be indicated;
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
A description of the availability of, and the demand on, the following public facilities shall be included: sanitary sewer, solid waste, drainage, potable water, traffic circulation and recreation, as appropriate, and any others deemed appropriate by the Director; and
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Information regarding the compatibility of the proposed land use amendments with the objectives and policies of the land use element and those of other affected elements.
<section prefix = "e">
Each Community Council may at its option conduct one (1) public hearing per amendment cycle to address proposed CDMP amendment applications, or portions thereof that would directly impact the Council's area as determined by the Director of the Department. All Community Council hearings on CDMP amendment applications shall occur either during September following the filing of May period applications or during March following the filing of November period applications. Upon conclusion of a public hearing addressing CDMP amendment applications, the Community Council may, at its option, make recommendations to the Planning Advisory Board and the Board of County Commissioners on the applications. Recommendations may address the decisions to be made by the Board of County Commissioners regarding transmittal of the applicable applications to the State Land Planning Agency and other review agencies for review and comment, and regarding ultimate adoption, adoption with change, or denial of the applicable applications. Public hearings of Community Councils shall be advertised in the manner provided in the "Requirements for the Conduct of Community Council's Non-Zoning Business" adopted by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners, A decision by any Community Council not to conduct a public hearing or not to adopt recommendations within the time frame established in this paragraph shall not preclude the Planning Advisory Board acting as the Local Planning Agency, or the Board of County Commissioners, from conducting public hearings or taking actions required by this section. In the event that the Board of County Commissioners by ordinance or resolution authorizes or requests a committee, board, council or similar entity to review proposed CDMP amendment applications, such reviews shall also occur during September following the filing of May period applications and during March following the filing of November period applications.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The Planning Advisory Board acting as the local planning agency shall hold one (1) public hearing in October following the filing of May period applications and in April following the filing of November period applications. Such public hearings shall be preceded by a notice of the time, place and purpose of such hearing published in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County not less than ten (10) days prior to the date of the hearing. In the event that the Planning Advisory Board acting as the local planning agency determines it to be necessary or desirable, it may continue the hearing to one (1) or more additional dates during the same month in which the hearing commenced. No additional public notice shall be required for the continued hearing, provided that the date and time are announced at the hearing being continued. The purpose of the public hearing shall be to receive public comments and to address the amendment applications, the initial recommendations of the Department, and the questions of, (1) the adoption of requested small-scale amendment applications, (2) transmittal of the standard expedited applications, and (3) transmittal of the State coordinated review applications. and any small-scale amendment applications not recommended for adoption to the State Land Planning Agency and other review agencies for review pursuant to Section 163.3184(3) and (4), F.S., and (4) subsequent approval of transmitted applications, by the Board of County Commissioners. At the conclusion of each public hearing conducted pursuant to this paragraph, the Planning Advisory Board acting as the local planning agency shall issue recommendations regarding adoption of any small-scale amendment requests, recommendations regarding transmittal by the Board of County Commissioners, to State agencies for review pursuant to Section 163.3184(3) and (4), F.S., of the expedited standard amendment applications. State coordinated review applications and any small-scale amendment applications not recommended for adoption, and recommendations regarding subsequent final action by the Board of County Commissioners on the transmitted plan amendment(s).
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
The Board of County Commissioners shall hold one public hearing during November following the filing of May period applications and during May following the filing of November period applications. Hearing(s) held pursuant to this paragraph shall be advertised in accordance with Section 163.3184(11)(b), F.S., and shall be held on a weekday not less than ten (10) days after the day that the advertisement is published. At these hearings the Department shall present to the Board the listing of applications filed pursuant to Section 2-116.1(3)(b), Code of Miami-Dade County, and the Board shall consider the adoption or adoption with change of any requested small-scale amendments, the transmittal of the expedited standard amendment applications and the transmittal of the State coordinated review amendment applications to the State Land Planning Agency and other review agencies and any requested small-scale amendments not adopted. If any requested small-scale amendments will be considered for adoption at a public hearing conducted pursuant to this paragraph, the Department shall, prior to said hearing, submit to the Board of County Commissioners an ordinance for first reading providing for Commission action on said small-scale amendments. The action to adopt any small-scale amendment to the CDMP shall be by ordinance enacted only upon vote of the majority of the total membership of the County Commission then in office. Notwithstanding any other provision to the contrary, any decision to make amendments, modifications, additions, or changes to a declaration of restrictive covenants that was accepted in connection with a prior application to amend the CDMP shall require a vote of two-thirds (2/3) of members present, but not less than seven affirmative votes. The transmittal action shall be taken by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners. The decision to transmit shall be by affirmative vote of not less than a majority of the total membership of the County Commission then in office. Following the adoption of the resolution pertaining to transmittal, the Board may consider the approval on first reading of one (1) or more ordinances to subsequently take final action on the transmitted applications. The Board of County Commissioners hereby authorizes and directs the County Mayor or the Mayor's designee to transmit all documents and information required by Sections 163.3184(3) and (4), F.S., following the hearing, on behalf of the Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
The Department shall evaluate all of the information received at the transmittal hearing or within thirty (30) days after action by Board of County Commissioners addressing transmittal of the applications and may present final recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners.
<section prefix = "4">
Procedures for final actions after transmittal to state review agencies. After the County Mayor or his designee transmits the applications instructed by the Board of County Commissioners pursuant to foregoing paragraph 3(g), subsequent County actions shall be as follows:
<section prefix = "a">
The Board of County Commissioners shall conduct one (1) or more advertised public hearings not later than forty-five (45) days after receipt of comments from the State Land Planning Agency and other review agencies, unless a greater time period is deemed necessary by the Director. At such hearing(s) the Board of County Commissioners shall take final action to adopt, adopt with changes or not adopt each of the applications. Any changes must be within the scope of the applications filed and the proposals made pursuant to, and as authorized by, Sections 2-116.1(2)(a), (b), (c), and (d), and (3)(a) and (b), Code of Miami-Dade County, or within the scope of the written comments submitted by the State Land Planning Agency and other review agencies pursuant to Section 163.3184(6)(3) and (4), F.S. The deadline established in this paragraph may be extended by sixty (60) days where all pending plan amendments are proposed to implement an adopted evaluation and appraisal report of the CDMP.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
All public hearings conducted by the Board of County Commissioners pursuant to foregoing paragraph (4)(a) to take final action on applications to amend the CDMP shall be advertised in the manner required by Section 163.3184(11), F.S. All such hearings shall be held on a weekday approximately ten (10) days after the date that the advertisement is published. All amendments, modifications, additions or changes to the comprehensive development master plan shall be by ordinance enacted only upon vote of the majority of the total membership of the County Commission then in office, except that any decision to include any additional land within the Urban Development Boundary, or to redesignate to an urban use any land located outside the UDB shall require a vote of two-thirds (2/3) of the total membership of the County Commission then in office. Notwithstanding any other provision to the contrary, any decision to make amendments, modifications, additions, or changes to a declaration of restrictive covenants that was accepted in connection with a prior application to amend the CDMP shall require a vote of two-thirds (2/3) of members present, but not less than seven affirmative votes. Findings, if any, made by the Board of County Commissioners which are not included in the ordinance adopting plan amendments and which provided the basis for adoption or determination not to adopt shall be transmitted to the State Land Planning Agency and other review agencies with the adopted amendments. In addition, the Department shall prepare for transmittal a statement in support of the Commission's actions indicating the relationship, if any, of the changes not previously reviewed by the State Land Planning Agency and other reviewing agencies to the comments submitted by said agencies pursuant to Section 163.3184(3) and (4), F.S. The County Mayor or the Mayor's designee is hereby authorized and directed to transmit, on behalf of the Board, the adopted amendments, adopting ordinance and all other necessary information and documents required by Section 163.3184(3)(c)2. and (4), F.S. Copies of adopted proposals shall be transmitted by the County Mayor or the Mayor's designee to said agency after adoption pursuant to Section 163.3184(3) and (4), F.S.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Applications filed pursuant to a compliance agreement, concurrent approval of a Development of Regional Impact (DRI), or to enable reuse of a military base designated for closure or closed by the Federal Government. Notwithstanding other requirements of this subsection, any application filed pursuant to a compliance agreement as provided in Section 163.3184(6), F.S., shall be subject only to the procedural requirements for such applications found in Section 163.3184, F.S., and to the procedural requirements of the resolution or other action of the Board of County Commissioners approving the filing of such application. Applications which are subject to concurrent approval of, or change to, a development of regional impact development order shall be subject only to the procedural requirements for such applications provided in Section 380.06(6)(b), F.S., and in Section 2-116.1(5)(a)(1) through (7), herein.
<section prefix = "a">
Procedure for amendment concurrently with Development of Regional Impact Development Order, Applications related to a proposed development of regional impact (DRI) including requests for approval of a substantial deviation from an approved DRI, may be filed at times other than May and November as provided by Section 380.06(6)(b), F.S., in instances where a CDMP amendment would be necessitated by the DRI approval sought. Such applications shall be processed in accordance with the following provisions:
<section prefix = "1">
Whenever an applicant for a DRI development order seeks a related amendment to the CDMP, the applicant must inform the Director of the Department of the amendment requested by filing an application in the form prescribed by the Director pursuant to this section. The application must be accompanied by a copy of the letter submitted to the regional planning council applying for DRI development approval, the data and analysis and any other information specified at the preapplication conference with the regional planning council staff, or its successor agency, upon which the County can determine whether or not to transmit the proposed CDMP amendment pursuant to Section 163.3184(4), F.S. The application filing date is hereby deemed to be the later of the dates on which the Director of the Department receives a completed CDMP amendment application, or the date on which the Director receives notification from the regional planning council or its successor agency that the application for development approval is sufficient,
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Where an application directly impacts a Community Council as determined by the Director of the Department, the subject Community Council shall be provided with an opportunity to conduct a public hearing and issue recommendations on the application in the manner set forth in paragraph 2-116.1(3)(e), herein; provided, however, such hearing and review shall take place within twenty (20) days after an application is filed pursuant to this paragraph and before the public hearing conducted by the Local Planning Agency. The Planning Advisory Board acting as the Local Planning Agency (LPA) shall conduct a public hearing to address the application not later than thirty (30) days after an application is filed pursuant to this paragraph. This public hearing shall be noticed in accordance with the notice provisions contained in Section 2-116.1(3)(f), herein. At the conclusion of the public hearing, the LPA shall issue the following to the Board of County Commissioners: (1) recommendations regarding transmittal of the application by the Board of County Commissioners to the State review agencies pursuant to Section 163.3184(3), F.S.; and (2) recommendations regarding subsequent final action by the Board of County Commissioners on the plan amendment(s) being proposed for transmittal to the State Land Planning Agency and other review agencies.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Not later than sixty (60) days after the filing of an application pursuant to this paragraph, the Board of County Commissioners shall conduct a public hearing and make a determination on the transmittal of the application pursuant to Section 163.3184(4), F.S. The public hearing shall be advertised once not later than thirty (30) days after the filing of the application in the manner required by Section 163.3184(11), F.S., for the advertisement of public hearings at which the Board of County Commissioners will consider the transmittal of proposed plan amendments. The transmittal actions of the Board of County Commissioners and the transmittal by the County Mayor or the Mayor's designee shall occur in the manner prescribed in Section 2-116.1(3)(g), herein, for transmittal of applications filed during May and November CDMP amendment filing periods.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The Board of County Commissioners shall take final action on the application filed pursuant to this paragraph at the same public hearing as it acts upon the application for approval of or the proposed change to, the DRI development order. However, the Board of County Commissioners shall take action separately on the application for development approval or the proposed change and on the CDMP amendment. This public hearing shall occur no sooner than thirty (30) days and no later than sixty (60) days after receipt of the response from the State Land Planning Agency and other review agencies pursuant to Section 163.3184, F.S. This public hearing to consider amending the CDMP shall be advertised in the manner prescribed in Section 163.3184(11), F.S., for the advertisement of public hearings at which the Board of County Commissioners will consider adoption of CDMP amendments.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Board of County Commissioners actions to transmit, adopt, or adopt with changes any application filed pursuant to this paragraph shall be by affirmative vote of not less than a majority of the total membership of the County Commission then in office, except that any decision to include any additional land within the Urban Development Boundary, or to redesignate to urban use any land outside the Urban Development Boundary, or to modify the Urban Expansion Area boundary shall require the affirmative vote of two-thirds (2/3) of the total membership of the County Commission then in office. Notwithstanding any other provision to the contrary, any decision to make amendments, modifications, additions, or changes to a declaration of restrictive covenants that was accepted in connection with a prior application to amend the CDMP shall require a vote of two-thirds (2/3) of members present but not less than seven affirmative votes.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
The deadlines established in paragraphs 2-116.1(5)(a)(2) through (4), above, may be extended only at the written request of the applicant received by the Director of the Department prior to the earliest of the dates that the Department submits public hearing advertisements for newspaper publication or mails hearing notices to neighboring property owners. After this date, such written requests may be approved only by motion by the Board of County Commissioners.
<section prefix = "b">
Procedure for amendments implementing military base reuse plans, pursuant to Section 288.975, F.S. Notwithstanding other requirements of this section, applications requesting amendments to the CDMP, to enable base reuse activities authorized by a base reuse plan approved by record of decision issued by the military branch having jurisdiction over a military base which has been closed or which is designated for closure or realignment, may be filed and approved in accordance with the optional procedures provided in Section 288.975, F.S., and in Section 2-116.1(5)(b) through (5)(b)(12), herein, if authorized by the Board of County Commissioners or County Mayor as provided in paragraph (5)(b)(1). CDMP amendments necessary to initially adopt the military base reuse plan pursuant to Section 288.975, F.S., shall be exempt from the limitation on frequency of plan amendments contained in Section 2-116.1(2), herein.
<section prefix = "1">
Any decision by Miami-Dade County to use the optional procedure established in Section 288.975, F.S., shall be made by motion or resolution by the Board of County Commissioners. Such decisions shall be made not less than seven (7) days prior to the deadline established in Section 288.975(3), F.S., for issuing notice of intent to the State Land Planning Agency of the County's intent to use the optional procedure provided in Section 288.975, F.S. If a decision is made to use the optional procedure, the County Mayor or the Mayor's designee shall, within the time frame established in Section 288.975(3), F.S., notify the State Land Planning Agency in writing; by hand delivery or return receipt requested, of the County's intent to use the optional provisions of Section 288.975, F.S. The Board of County Commissioners or County Mayor may designate a County agency to have principal responsibility to manage the facility or County portion thereof (hereinafter the base management agency). Any written notice issued by the Miami-Dade County Aviation Department to the State Land Planning Agency prior to the effective date of this provision indicating Miami-Dade County's intent to use the optional procedures provided in Section 288.975, F.S,, is hereby deemed sufficient and approved.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Whenever Miami-Dade County shall be the host local government as defined in Section 288.975(2)(d), F.S., (a) the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources or successor agency shall coordinate all CDMP amendment activities in close consultation with, and with the assistance of, the designated base management agency, if any, and (b) the Department, or the Aviation Department solely in the case of Homestead Air Reserve Base, shall request the State Land Planning Agency to coordinate a presubmission workshop in Miami- Dade County pursuant to Section 288.975(8), F.S. The Department and base management agency shall be the Miami-Dade County agencies with which the State Land Planning Agency shall coordinate the workshop, and the County shall request the State Land Planning Agency to invite all Miami-Dade County agencies represented on the Miami-Dade County Developmental Impact Committee (DIC) to attend.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Application to amend the CDMP shall be filed with the Department in a form prescribed by the Director pursuant to Section 2-116.1(2)(b), herein, and shall contain all information required by Section 288.975(4)(a) through (4)(e), F.S., and all information necessary to ensure consistency as required by Section 288.975(7), F.S. If all information data and analysis required by Section 288.975, F.S., Chapter 163, Part 2, F.S. and administrative rules adopted thereunder, are not submitted with the application initially submitted, the initial application shall contain a scope of work and schedule for production of all such supporting information, deemed necessary by the Director, for submission on a date specified by the Director which will ensure timely submittal to, and analysis by, the Department and review by the Planning Advisory Board, but not later than the last day of the ninth month following issuance of notice pursuant to Section 2-116.1(5)(b)(1), herein. Applications shall be deemed by the Director to be complete upon his confirmation that the application content and supporting information, data, and analyses reasonably respond to the requirements of laws referenced herein. Completion of an application shall not preclude the preparation or submittal of additional information, data, or analyses by the applicant or Department, or recommendations by the Department for submittal of additional information.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Upon receipt of an application, the Director may distribute the application to the Director of the MPO Secretariat and to other County agencies he deems necessary for review and comment on aspects of the application which pertain to matters under the jurisdiction of the agency and which are within the scope of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan. Any such requested comments shall be returned to the Director by the director of the requested agency or his designee on a date specified by the Director in his request.
(4.5)
Not later than seventy (70) days prior to the due date for transmittal of a proposed plan pursuant to Section 288.975(9), F.S., the Director shall submit to the Planning Advisory Board, acting as the Local Planning Agency (LPA), and any Community Council(s) directly impacted by the application as determined by the Director of the Department, the complete application along with supporting information, data and analyses or summaries thereof. The Director shall submit the Department's initial recommendations on the application not less than ten (10) days before the respective public hearing(s) conducted pursuant to Section 2-116.1(5)(b)(5) and (6), herein. In formulating its initial recommendations, the Department shall consider the supporting information submitted by the applicant, government agencies, and timely public comments. The initial recommendations shall reflect consideration of the factors and information noted in Section 2-116.1(3)(d), herein. The Director's recommendations may suggest changes to the application as filed, may address subsequent adoption of the application with or without changes, may recommend production of additional supporting analyses or information, and may recommend an alternative schedule for submission of the application to state review agencies if changes to the application or production of addition information is recommended.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
At least six (6) weeks before the date scheduled for the Board of County Commissioners public hearing to be conducted pursuant to Section 2- 116.1(5)(b)(7), herein, the Community Council(s) directly impacted, as determined by the Director, by an application filed pursuant to this section may at its option conduct a public hearing and issue recommendations addressing the proposed amendments. The public hearing shall occur in the manner set forth in paragraph 2-116.1(3)(e), herein; provided, however, such hearing and review shall occur during the period provided in this paragraph, and before the hearing conducted by the Local Planning Agency.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
The Planning Advisory Board acting as the LPA shall conduct one (1) public hearing at least three (3) weeks before the date scheduled for the Board of County Commissioners public hearing to be conducted pursuant to Section 2-116.1(5)(b)(7), herein, and approximately ten (10) days after publication of an advertisement in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County. If it finds it necessary, the LPA may continue the public hearing once to a date not later than three (3) weeks prior to the date scheduled for the Board of County Commissioners hearing. No additional public notice shall be required for the continued hearing provided that the date and time are announced at the hearing being continued. The purpose of the public hearing shall be to receive public comments on the CDMP amendment proposals contained in the application and to address the initial recommendations of the Department, the questions of transmittal of the amendment proposals to State agencies for review pursuant to Section 288.975(9)(a), F.S., and subsequent adoption of the proposed amendments by the Board of County Commissioners, or if justified and necessary in accordance with Section 288.975(9), F.S., a request for an extension of the deadline for transmitting the proposed amendments to the State review agencies. At the conclusion of the public hearing, the Planning Advisory Board acting as the LPA shall issue recommendations regarding transmittal of the amendment proposals to the State for review, and recommendations regarding subsequent final action by the Board of County Commissioners to adopt, adopt with changes, or not adopt the proposed amendments contained in the application, or if necessary to comply with Section 288.975, F.S., to recommend that the Commission request an extension of the deadline for submission.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
The Board of County Commissioners shall hold one (1) public hearing not later than fifty (50) weeks after the County Mayor or the Mayor's designee submits notice to the State Land Planning Agency of Miami-Dade County's intent to use the optional provisions of Section 288.975, F.S. The hearing held pursuant to this paragraph shall be advertised in accordance with Section 163.3184(11), F.S., and shall be held on a weekday approximately ten (10) days after the day that the advertisement is published. At this hearing the Board shall consider transmitting to the State agencies listed in Section 288.975(8), F.S., (hereinafter State review agencies) a copy of the amendments proposed pursuant to Section 288.975, F.S., or petitioning the secretary of the State Land Planning Agency for an extension of the deadline if justified and necessary, in conformance with Section 288.975(9)(b), F.S. The transmittal action shall be taken by approving on first reading an ordinance to take final action on the proposed amendments. The Board of County Commissioners shall take final action after future public hearing to occur after State review agencies have received the transmitted proposed amendments and had opportunity to review and comment. Notwithstanding any other provision of this Section, petition for extension of the deadline may be approved by motion approved by majority of a quorum of the Board of County Commissioners in attendance at any meeting of the Board of justified and necessary in conformance with Section 288.975(9)(b), F.S, The County Mayor or the Mayor's designee is authorized and directed to transmit to the state review agencies the amendments authorized by approval at first reading along with all supporting information required by Section 288.975 and Chapter 163, Part 2, F.S., and pertinent administrative rules adopted pursuant thereto. Transmittal shall occur by hand delivery, or certified or express mail service, with return receipt, not later than ten (10) days after approval of transmittal by the Board of County Commissioners, and the transmittal letter shall specify that all State review agencies shall return comments directly to the Miami-Dade County Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources or successor agency as the County's coordinator of the CDMP amendment process. Not more than five (5) days after transmittal of the proposed plan amendments to the State, the Department shall cause the commencement of the State review period to be advertised in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County with invitation for public comments to be submitted to the Department within sixty (60) days after publication of this advertisement. Miami-Dade County shall consider all comments received not later than sixty (60) days after publication of this advertisement. If a listed State review agency has not provided comments within seventy (70) days after transmittal, the Director may determine that comments have not been timely provided and that no objection has been issued by that agency and he may proceed to schedule the activities listed in following paragraphs (8) through (12), herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Not later than fourteen (14) days after the Department receives comments from all State review agencies or the Director determines that no additional comments are timely as provided in foregoing paragraph (7), the Department, in consultation with the base management agency and any other agencies deemed appropriate by the Director shall issue to the LPA revised recommendations for the Board of County Commissioners to adopt, adopt with changes, or not adopt the proposed amendments.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Not later than thirty (30) days after the Department determines that it has received all timely comments from the listed State review agencies, the Planning Advisory Board acting as the LPA shall conduct a duly noticed public hearing. The purpose of the public hearing shall be to receive public comments on the proposed amendments, on the initial recommendation of the LPA issued prior to transmittal, on any comments received from State review agencies, on the current recommendations of the Department, and on the questions of adoption by the Board of County Commissioners pursuant to Section 288.975, F.S., and to formulate its revised recommendations. In the event that the LPA determines it to be necessary, it may continue the hearing to a date not later than thirty-five (35) days after the Department has received timely comments from the listed State review agencies. No additional public notice shall be required for the continued public hearing, if any, provided that the date and time are announced at the hearing being continued. At the conclusion of the public hearing the Planning Advisory Board acting as the local planning agency shall deliberate and formulate final recommendations. The Department may also modify its previous recommendations. If the Local Planning Agency has issued recommendations prior to transmittal, failure by the Local Planning Agency to timely conduct a public hearing or issue recommendations pursuant to this paragraph shall not preclude the Board of County Commissioners from conducting a public hearing and taking final action pursuant to Section 2-116.1(5)(b)(10), herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
<section prefix = "a">
Not later than sixty (60) days after the Department has received timely comments from all of the State review agencies, the Board of County Commissioners shall conduct a public hearing and shall take final action to adopt, adopt with changes or not to adopt the proposed amendments. Any such changes must be within the scope of the application filed and the proposals made pursuant to, and as authorized by, Section 2-116.1, Code of Miami-Dade County, or within the scope of the written comments received from the State review agencies or other affected persons pursuant to Section 288.975, F.S. The public hearing conducted by the Board of County Commissioners to take final action on the proposed amendments to the CDMP shall be advertised in the manner required by Section 163.3184(11), F.S. The hearing shall be held on a weekday approximately ten (10) days after the date that the advertisement is published. All amendments, modifications, additions or changes to the Comprehensive Development Master Plan shall be by ordinance enacted only upon vote of the majority of the total membership of the County Commission then in office, except that any decision to include any additional land within the Urban Development Boundary (UDB), or to redesignate land outside the UDB to an urban use, or to include or exclude any land within the Urban Expansion Area boundary, shall require a vote of two-thirds (2/3) of the total membership of the County Commission then in office. Notwithstanding any other provision to the contrary, any decision to make amendments, modifications, additions, or changes to a declaration of restrictive covenants that was accepted in connection with a prior application to amend the CDMP shall require a vote of two-thirds (2/3) of members present, but not less than seven affirmative votes.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Whenever the sixty-day period prescribed in the preceding paragraph is waived pursuant to Florida Statutes, the time for the taking of final action upon a proposed amendment implementing a military base reuse plan shall be extended through and including one hundred seventy-nine (179) days after the sixty-day period prescribed by the preceding subsection 2-116.1(5)(b)(10)(a). It is the express intent of this subsection to permit, inter alia, further consideration of an application, even after "final action" under subsection (10)(a). In the event that a hearing under subsection (10)(a) is concluded and a further hearing on the merits is held under this subsection (10)(b), all advertising and other requirements of subsection (10)(a) shall separately apply to such further public hearing. It is provided, however, that once a public hearing is advertised, the same may be recessed without the requirement of further advertisement if the date, time and place of the continuation of the hearing are announced during the hearing at the time the matter is recessed.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Within ten (10) days after adoption of CDMP amendments, the County Mayor or the Mayor's designee shall forward a copy of the adopted amendments to any affected local government and regional and State agencies that submitted comments on the proposed plan amendments. In addition the Department shall publish notice in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County indicating how and where a copy of the Plan amendments may be obtained or inspected. The County Mayor and County Attorney, in consultation with the Director of the Department and the director of the base management agency, are hereby authorized and instructed to resolve any challenge or dispute which may resolve any challenge or dispute which may arise pursuant to Section 288.975(12), F.S. Miami-Dade County shall utilize the procedures established in Section 288.975(12) through (12)(d), F.S., to resolve any such challenge.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Not later than one hundred thirty-five (135) days following adoption of the base reuse CDMP amendments by the Board of County Commissioners pursuant to Section 288.975, F.S., and resolution of any petitions filed pertaining to the amendments, the County Mayor, in consultation with the Directors of the Department, base management agency, and other affected County agencies, shall submit for first reading by the Board of County Commissioners any ordinances necessary to create or amend Miami-Dade County's land development regulations necessary to fully implement the CDMP amendments adopted pursuant to Section 12-116.1(5)(b), herein.
<section prefix = "6">
Optional Public Workshops. At any time prior to final action by the Board of County Commissioners, the Board of County Commissioners, Planning Advisory Board or Department may conduct public workshops in addition to the public hearings required by this Section. Any such public workshop shall be advertised in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County at least once seven (7) to fourteen (14) days prior to the date of the workshop.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Consideration of economic reports, appraisals, etc. No economic reports or studies, real estate appraisals or reports, and/or written reports of consultants or other experts shall be considered as evidence by either the Planning Advisory Board, the Department, or the Board of County Commissioners during their consideration of final action on the amendments unless filed with the Director not later than thirty (30) days after the Board of County Commissioners takes action to transmit the subject proposed application(s) to the State review agencies. Submittal of such reports after this date is hereby authorized only to respond to comments submitted after this date by the State Land Planning Agency or its successor or delegates. This deadline may be waived to permit the submission of such materials addressing matters other than the comments of the State Land Planning Agency only after an affirmative vote of the Board of County Commissioners which may approve such submittal of material upon a demonstration by any interested party that an injustice will occur.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Schedule of fees. All fees charged for filing, processing and evaluating applications requesting amendments to the Comprehensive Development Master Plan by the Department are established by separate administrative order which shall not become effective until approved by the Board of County Commissioners. In approving the administrative order, the Board shall consider the cost to the county in processing amendments to the Comprehensive Development Master Plan. Fees will be returned to any applicant who requests an application withdrawal on or before the fifth work day following the deadlines established in this section for filing applications, or the actual date of filing of an application pursuant to Section 2-116.1(5)(a)(1), herein. After these dates no fees shall be returned to any applicant withdrawing their application without express approval by the Board of County Commissioners. Such administrative order shall also provide that a portion of the fee will be returned to the applicant for any application which is not eligible for adoption as a small-scale amendment application and which is denied transmittal by the Board of County Commissioners to the State Land Planning Agency or its successor or designees pursuant to paragraph 2-116.1(3)(g) of this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
No applicant or applicant's representative seeking a recommendation for approval or approval of an amendment to the land use map shall be permitted to argue or represent to the Board of County Commissioners or other recommending County board that the property which is the subject of the application will be put to a specific use or uses or to exclude a use or uses authorized by the proposed land use designation, unless the applicant has submitted a restrictive covenant committing to such representation which has been submitted to the Director and has received approval as to form. This subsection shall not apply, however, if a CDMP amendment is being reviewed concurrently with an application seeking approval or modification of a Development of Regional Impact ("DRI") development order, if the proposed DRI development order application incorporates an Application for Development Approval ("ADA") or Notification of Proposed Change ("NOPC") with the express restrictions limiting development in the same manner as represented by the applicant in the CDMP amendment process.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Adjustment of dates. Regarding all dates and time computations contained in this section, except those pertaining to advertising dates, when the last day of a time period falls on a Saturday, Sunday, or official County holiday, that time period will be expanded to include the following business day.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
All references in this Section to Florida Statutes shall also refer to any amendments thereto and successor legislation or rules.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
The foregoing procedure shall be the exclusive procedure for amending all elements of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan (CDMP); however, annual updates to the capital improvements element schedule of improvements shall not be deemed to be amendments to the CDMP and may be made by ordinance of the Board of County Commissioners without regard to foregoing subsections (1) through (7).
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 76-4, § 3, 1-20-76; Ord. No. 76-95, § 2, 10-19-76; Ord. No. 78-48, § 2, 7-18-78; Ord. No. 78-49, § 1, 7-18-78; Ord. No. 78-50, § 1, 7-18-78; Ord. No. 78-85, § 1, 11-21-78; Ord. No. 86-97, § 2, 12-16-86; Ord. No. 88-18, § 2, 4-5-88; Ord. No. 89-24, § 2, 4-4-89; Ord. No. 89-66, § 3, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 89-121, § 1, 12-5-89; Ord. No. 90-2, § 2, 1-16-90; Ord. No. 90-19, § 1, 3-6-90; Ord. No. 90-111, § 1, 9-25-90; Ord. No. 90-135, § 1, 12-4-90; Ord. No. 92-17, § 3, 3-17-92; Ord. No. 92-120, § 1, 10-13-92; Ord. No. 93-23, § 2, 3-30-93; Ord. No. 93-131, § 2, 11-16-93; Ord. No. 95-69, § 1, 4-18-95; Ord. No. 95-96, § 1, 6-6-95; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-104, § 1, 7-2-96; Ord. No. 97-150, § 1, 9-9-97; Ord. No. 98-125, § 1, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 98-143, § 11, 9-18-98; Ord. No. 99-30, § 1, 3-18-99; Ord. No. 00-50, § 1, 4-11-00; Ord. No. 01-163, § 1, 10-23-01; Ord. No. 03-40, § 1, 3-11-03; Ord. No. 08-52, § 1, 5-6-08; Ord. No. 10-10, § 1, 2-2-10; Ord. No. 12-81, § 1, 10-2-12; Ord. No. 13-25, § 2, 3-5-13)</history>
Note—According to Ord. No. 97-150, § 2, adopted September 9, 1997: Any CDMP amendment applications filed prior to the adoption of this ordinance in accordance with the then existing provisions of Section 2-116.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County shall be processed according to those provisions until this ordinance becomes effective. After this ordinance becomes effective, Section 2-116.1 of the Code as amended by Section 1 of this ordinance shall govern May 1997-98 CDMP amendment cycle activities with the following exceptions to the schedule of activities:

A) The public hearing and action to be taken by Community Councils and other entities authorized or requested pursuant to paragraph 2-116.1(3)(e) shall occur during October 1997;


B) The public hearing and action to be taken by the Planning Advisory Board pursuant to paragraph 2-116.1(3)(f) shall occur during November 1997; and


C) The public hearing and actions to be taken by the Board of County Commissioners pursuant to paragraph 2-116.1(3)(g) shall occur during December 1997.
<catch_line>Sec. 2-116.1.1. Fees for furnishing publications</catch_line>
<text>
The Director of Planning and Zoning may prescribe reasonable charges for publications of the Department.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-116.1.2. Applicability of Comprehensive Master Plan to Municipalities</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The location of the Urban Development Boundary (UDB) and permitted land uses outside the UDB shall be governed by the Miami-Dade County comprehensive Development Master Plan (CDMP) notwithstanding the fact that the UDB may lie within a municipality.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Any amendments to the UDB line or land uses permitted by the CDMP shall be filed and processed in accordance with procedures for applications located within the unincorporated area.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All municipal land use decisions outside the UDB line shall be consistent with the CDMP.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 95-177, § 2, 10-5-95)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-116.2. Area planning reports—Legislative intent</catch_line>
<text>
It is the purpose of Sections 2-116.2 through 2-116.11 to provide a process for preparing and implementing "area planning reports" for portions of the unincorporated area which process shall include, but not be limited to, the following:
<section prefix = "a">
A procedure for initiating the preparation of growth management planning reports on an area basis;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A means of citizen participation in the preparation of area planning reports at a time reasonably convenient to the area residents, owners of property, members of homeowner associations or civic groups and other interested parties during the study process;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
A method for preparing and periodically revising area planning reports that may be more detailed than the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan, and that may provide the basis for subsequent amendments to the master plan or for zoning district boundary changes and other suggested implementation actions; and
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
A procedure for Planning Advisory Board recommendation on area planning reports and acceptance of such reports by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
A requirement for the Department of Planning and Zoning initiation of the implementation actions contained in accepted area planning reports.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-116.3. Area planning reports—Initiation</catch_line>
<text>
The Board of County Commissioners, an individual, a group or an entity, including the Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning, may petition the County Manager for the preparation of an area planning report. The County Manager shall direct the Department of Planning and Zoning to review petitions from entities other than the Department of Planning and Zoning, meeting with the petitioner(s) as needed, and within sixty (60) days to recommend to him whether the requested area planning report should be prepared and, if so, the issues, objectives, boundaries, approach, schedule, and magnitude of staff resources required and available for the preparation of the requested area planning report. A Department of Planning and Zoning petition for an area planning report shall contain the same type of information as does its recommendation to the County Manager on a petition by another entity.
Upon receipt of a Department of Planning and Zoning petition for an area planning report or the Department of Planning and Zoning's recommendation regarding a petition submitted by another entity, the County Manager shall transmit such petition or recommendation to the Board of County Commissioners, together with the County Manager's recommendation as to whether the requested area planning report should be prepared. After consideration of the petition for the preparation of the area planning report and the recommendation of the County Manager, the Board of County Commissioners shall either deny the petition or by resolution direct the County Manager to direct the preparation of an area planning report by the Department of Planning and Zoning. Such resolution shall set forth the objectives, boundaries, approach, schedule and magnitude of staff resources to be used in the preparation of the area planning report. The boundaries of the area designated as the subject of an area planning report shall be described by reference to streets, highways or other geographic boundaries.
When the area planning reports procedure is utilized in conjunction with the building and zoning moratoria provisions of Section 33-319 through 33-324, Code of Miami-Dade County, the time limitations therein contained shall govern the schedule for completion of the report established in the authorizing resolution. The County Manager shall have discretion as to whether or not to incorporate any or all of an area planning report into his report pursuant to Sections 33-319 through 33-324 of the Code.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-116.4. Area planning reports—Scope and contents</catch_line>
<text>
An area planning report may address demographic, land use, environmental, facilities and services, aesthetics, design, economic or social considerations that are determined by the Department of Planning and Zoning to be related to the physical maintenance or improvement of the study area or to the preservation or enhancement of the natural or man-made environment of the area consistent with the intent or objectives of the study set forth in the authorizing resolution. An area planning report may include the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Historic information on the development patterns of the area;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Existing and, to the extent feasible, future conditions in the area including:
<section prefix = "1">
Agricultural land considerations,
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Environmental considerations,
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Population characteristics,
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Socioeconomic factors,
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Land uses and densities,
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Housing characteristics,
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Thoroughfares and traffic circulation,
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Public facilities and services,
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Land ownership and parcelization patterns,
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Urban design parameters,
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Appearance and amenities, and
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Zoning and other developmental approval patterns and any judicial determinations affecting these patterns;
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Analysis and recommendations regarding land use and physical development of the area including:
<section prefix = "1">
Future development pattern including land use,
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Urban design and appearance considerations,
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Comprehensive development master plan provisions,
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Zoning changes,
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Public facilities and services, and
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Other development regulation changes.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Proposed implementation actions for the area to be initiated by the Department of Planning and Zoning including the following:
<section prefix = "1">
Applications to amend the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan,
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Applications for zoning changes,
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Requests for capital improvements,
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Requests for special tax districts,
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Revisions or additions to development regulations, and
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Other appropriate growth management initiatives.

Nothing contained herein shall be deemed exclusive, and any characteristics and issues germane to a specific area may be discussed and evaluated in the area planning report.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-116.5. Area planning reports—Preparation</catch_line>
<text>
The Department of Planning and Zoning shall prepare a proposed area planning report in cooperation and coordination with other County departments and municipal governments (where applicable) and with residents and owners of property in the area. Following the preparation of a proposed area planning report, the Department of Planning and Zoning shall hold at least one (1) public meeting in the area or its vicinity. An advertisement of such public meeting, including the meeting time and place, a map depicting the area being studied and the purpose of the meeting shall be published in the newspaper of largest general circulation in Miami-Dade County not less than seven (7) days prior to the public meeting. Additionally, written courtesy notices of said public meeting, containing the time, place, description of the area being studied, and a brief summary of the contents of the preliminary area planning report shall be mailed to any individual or group representative who has made a written request to the Department of Planning and Zoning for such notice. Failure to mail or to receive written notice shall not affect the validity of the public meeting or any other matter to which this ordinance pertains.
The Department of Planning and Zoning shall seek to obtain concurrence with the proposed area planning report from the residents, owners of property, and residents or property owner associations and other organizations having an interest in the study area. Such concurrence may be determined by the submission to the Department of resolutions from said groups, letters or petitions from residents and owners of property in the area. Summaries of the public meeting(s), which shall be prepared by the Department, should indicate the number of persons attending the meetings and the level of their support for the proposed area planning report.
If the Department believes that substantial revisions to the proposed report are appropriate and would facilitate obtaining greater concurrence with the report by the residents, owners of property, resident and property owner associations in the area, the department may hold another public meeting. Such additional public meeting may either be announced at the conclusion of the prior public meeting or advertised and noticed in the same manner provided in this section.
Following the public meeting(s), the Department of Planning and Zoning shall complete the preparation of the proposed area planning report and submit it to the Miami-Dade County Planning Advisory Board.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-116.6. Area planning reports—Planning Advisory Board action</catch_line>
<text>
Upon receipt of a proposed area planning report from the Department of Planning and Zoning, the Planning Advisory Board shall forthwith hold a public hearing thereon in the area or its vicinity, and invite the participation of interested persons, to consider the proposed area planning report including the actions proposed for its implementation. An advertisement of such public hearing, including the meeting time and place and a map depicting the area being studied and the purpose of the hearing shall be published in the newspaper of largest general circulation in Miami-Dade County not less than seven (7) days prior to the public hearing. Additionally, written courtesy notices of said public hearing, containing the time, place, description of area being studied, and a brief summary of the contents of the proposed area planning report shall be mailed to any individual or group representative who has made a written request to the Department of Planning and Zoning for such notice. Failure to mail or to receive such written notice shall not affect the validity of the public hearing or any other matter to which this ordinance pertains. Copies of the proposed area planning report shall be made available to the general public prior to and during the public hearing.
At the conclusion of the public hearing, the Planning Advisory Board shall take one (1) of the following actions:
<section prefix = "a">
By resolution make recommendation to the County Manager and Board of County Commissioners on the proposed area planning report, or state the reason(s) it is unable to make any recommendation,
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Return the proposed area planning report to the Department of Planning and Zoning for further consideration and evaluation, to be followed by a further public hearing in accordance with this subsection, or
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Conduct another public hearing for the purpose of soliciting or suggesting revisions to the proposed area report. Such additional public hearing may either be announced at the conclusion of the previous public hearing or advertised and noticed in the manner provided in this section.

The above actions shall in no way prejudge or predetermine the actions of the Planning Advisory Board on any amendments to the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan or other implementation actions proposed in the report that may be subsequently heard and acted upon by the Planning Advisory Board.
The Planning Advisory Board shall complete its action on the area planning report within the schedule established by the Board of County Commissioners or obtain a time extension from the commission by resolution.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-116.7. Area planning reports—Board of County Commission Action</catch_line>
<text>
Following the action by the Planning Advisory Board pursuant to Section 2-116.6 above, the Department shall: a) prepare its recommendations on the proposed area planning report including proposed implementation actions; and b) transmit the area planning report and the resolution of the Planning Advisory Board, together with the recommendations of the Department, through the County Manager to the Board of County Commissioners.
Upon receipt of the proposed area planning report and recommendations of the Department and recommendations, if any, of the planning advisory board, the Board of County Commissioners shall conduct a public hearing on the proposed area planning report. An advertisement of such public hearing, including the meeting time and place and a map depicting the area being studied and the purpose of the hearing shall be published in the newspaper of largest general circulation in Miami-Dade County not less than seven (7) days prior to the public hearing.
At the conclusion of the public hearing, the Board of County Commissioners shall by resolution:
<section prefix = "1">
Accept or accept with modification, the proposed area planning report including proposed implementing actions,
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Resubmit the proposed area planning report to the Department of Planning and Zoning for further consideration and for revision, or
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Reject the proposed area planning report in its entirety.

The acceptance of an area planning report shall be by resolution and shall henceforth be referred to as the accepted area planning report.
The above actions shall in no way prejudge or predetermine the actions of the Board of County Commissioners on any amendments to the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan or other implementation actions proposed in the report that may be subsequently heard and acted upon by the Commission. Acceptance of proposed implementation actions shall be solely for the purpose of considering such actions at an appropriate future time.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-116.8. Area planning reports—Implementation</catch_line>
<text>
Following acceptance of an area planning report by the Board of County Commissioners, the Department of Planning and Zoning shall within one (1) year make official requests for the various implementing actions proposed in the report, except that 1) proposed amendments to the Urban Development Boundary of the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan shall be initiated at the next filing opportunity authorized by Section 2-116.1(2) Code of Miami-Dade County, and 2) proposed zoning changes that require prior amendments to the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan shall be filed no later than three (3) months following the enactment of such plan amendments.
Within five (5) years after County Commission acceptance of an initial or amended area planning report, the Department of Planning and Zoning shall review the subject area planning report and prepare and provide to the Board of County Commissioners a written evaluation presenting: 1) an assessment of the success or failure in accomplishing the purposes of the subject area planning report and in implementing the recommendations contained in the report, and of the continuing applicability of the report to conditions and circumstances within, and in the vicinity of the area; and 2) any need for amendment or rescission of the report as may be warranted by any changes to such conditions and circumstances.
After receipt of the evaluation, the Board of County Commissioners shall conduct a public hearing on the evaluation. An advertisement of such public hearing, including the meeting time and place and a map depicting the area covered by the area planning report being evaluated and the purpose of the hearing shall be published in the newspaper of largest general circulation in Miami-Dade County not less than seven (7) days prior to the public hearing.
At the conclusion of the public hearing, the Board of County Commissioners shall by resolution:
<section prefix = "1">
Accept or accept with modification, the area planning report evaluation including any need for amendment or rescission,
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Resubmit the area planning report evaluation to the Department of Planning and Zoning for further consideration and for revision, or
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Reject the area planning report evaluation in its entirety.

Following acceptance or acceptance with modification of an area planning report evaluation by the Board of County Commissioners, the Department of Planning and Zoning shall petition the County Manager for amendment or rescission of the area planning report pursuant to Section 2-116.9 if a need therefor has been identified in the accepted evaluation.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-116.9. Area planning reports—Amendment or rescission</catch_line>
<text>
An area planning report shall be amended or rescinded only pursuant to the procedures set forth in Sections 2-116.2 through 2-116.8, and shall be implemented pursuant to Section 2-116.8.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-116.10. Area planning reports—Legal status</catch_line>
<text>
Accepted area planning reports prepared or amended pursuant to Sections 2-116.2 through 2-116.9 are hereby declared to be nonbinding informational considerations available to the Board of County Commissioners, the County Manager and to county agencies, departments and personnel responsible for a) preparing recommendations for, or acting on, amendments to the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan and applications for zoning relief, b) preparing or administrating land development regulations, or c) any other matter proposed as part of such area planning report. Area planning reports are declared to be informational only and not a part of the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan. However, the acceptance of an area planning report pursuant to this process shall constitute a directive to the Department of Planning and Zoning to file official requests for the various implementing actions proposed in the report.
Notwithstanding any inconsistencies or ambiguities between any existing neighborhood study or area study adopted by the Board of County Commissioners as of the effective date of this ordinance, and the Comprehensive Development Master Plan (CDMP), the CDMP shall govern.
Furthermore, land uses permitted by the CDMP shall not be limited or constrained by the provisions of any area planning report or of any area study or neighborhood study adopted or accepted prior or subsequent to such effective date. It is provided, however, that this paragraph shall not limit the informational or advisory status of any area or neighborhood study as otherwise provided by ordinance.
No area planning report, nor any other planning study, shall in itself constitute a finding of land use or zoning inconsistency with the comprehensive development master plan. Such findings of inconsistency shall be made only by the Board of County Commissioners in conjunction with particular zoning actions. In furtherance hereof, the Board of County Commissioners declares its policy and intent to evaluate and consider its public actions involving or affecting land use and development, including action on applications for comprehensive development master plan amendments and for zoning action in relationship to area planning reports, if applicable, in addition to considering all other criteria established by ordinance or otherwise required for consideration by law.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-116.11. Area planning reports—Previous studies</catch_line>
<text>
All neighborhood or area studies previously accepted and adopted by the Board of County Commissioners, and in effect on the effective date of this ordinance, shall continue to have the same legislative and legal status as prior to the adoption of this ordinance, consistent with the provisions of Section 2-114(b) Code of Miami-Dade County, unless such studies are specifically repealed or modified by Board of County Commissioners action.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (29) ---
Annotation—AO 9-1 (Back)
Charter reference— Charter provisions providing for Department of Planning, § 4.07. (Back)
Cross reference— Subdivisions, Ch. 28; urban renewal, Ch. 30A; zoning, Ch. 33; developments in incorporated areas creating County impact, Ch. 33A. (Back)

--- (30) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 92-46, § 1, adopted June 2, 1992, repealed former §§ 2-116.2—2-116.9, relative to neighborhood or area studies, and enacted new §§ 2-116.2—2-116.11 to read as herein set out. The provisions of former §§ 2-116.2—2-116.9 derived from Ord. No. 75-48, §§ 1—8, adopted June 18, 1975; Ord. No. 76-64, §§ 1, 2, adopted July 6, 1976; Ord. No. 79-79, §§ 1, 2, 4, adopted Oct. 2, 1979; and Ord. No. 80-72, §§ 1, 2, adopted July 1, 1980. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
