<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_III._PUBLIC_RIGHTS-OF-WAY_REGULA</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-150. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Abandonment shall mean the permanent cessation of all uses of a Communications Facility; provided that this term shall not include cessation of all use of a Facility within a physical structure where the physical structure continues to be used. By way of example, and not limitation, cessation of all use of a cable within a conduit, where the conduit continues to be used, shall not be "Abandonment" of a Facility in Public Rights-of-Way.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Director shall mean the Director of the Consumer Services Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Facility for purposes of this article shall mean a "Cable System" as defined by Article I of this chapter or a "Communications Facility" as defined by Article II of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
In Public Rights-of-Way or in the Public Rights-of-Way shall mean in, on, over, under or across the Public Rights-of-Way.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Place or Maintain or Placement or Maintenance or Placing or Maintaining shall mean to erect, construct, install, maintain, place, repair, extend, expand, remove, occupy, locate or relocate. A Provider that owns or exercises physical control over Communications Facilities in Public Rights-of-Way, such as the physical control to maintain and repair, is "placing or maintaining" the Facilities.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Permit shall mean a construction permit issued by the Public Works Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Provider for purposes of this article shall mean a provider of "Cable Service" as defined by Article I of this chapter or a "Communications Service Provider" as defined by Article II of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Public Rights-of-Way shall mean a public right-of-way, public utility easement, highway, street, bridge, tunnel or alley for which the County is the authority that has jurisdiction and control and may lawfully grant access to and issue permits pursuant to applicable law, and includes the surface, the air space over the surface and the area below the surface. "Public Rights-of-Way" shall not include private property. "Public Rights-of-Way" shall not include any real or personal County property except as described above and shall not include County buildings, fixtures, poles, conduits, facilities or other structures or improvements, regardless of whether they are situated in the Public Rights-of-Way.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 01-109, § 5, 6-19-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-151. Intent and purpose</catch_line>
<text>
It is the intent of the County to promote the public health, safety and general welfare by: providing for the placement or maintenance of Communications Facilities in the Public Rights-of-Way within the County; adopting and administering reasonable rules and regulations not inconsistent with State and Federal law, including Section 337.401, Florida Statutes (2000), as it may be amended, the County's home-rule authority, and in accordance with the provisions of the Federal Telecommunications Act of 1996 and other Federal and State law; establishing reasonable rules and regulations necessary to manage the placement or maintenance of Communications Facilities in the Public Rights-of-Way by all Communications Services Providers; and minimizing disruption to the Public Rights-of-Way. It is the intent of the County to treat all Providers in a nondiscriminatory and competitively neutral manner when imposing rules or regulations governing the placement or maintenance of Facilities in the public roads or Public Rights-of-Way.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-152. Use of County Public Rights-of-Way; Construction Requirements; Alteration of the System; Access by County</catch_line>
<text>
Subject to all applicable provisions of the County, Provider may perform all necessary work to construct, occupy and maintain its Facilities. The Provider must comply at all times with all policies, procedures and directives of the Public Works Department, the Planning and Zoning Department and the Building Department. Prior to the installation, placement or removal of any conduits, cables or pole lines, facilities, or the start of any other type of construction on the County's public rights-of-way, the Provider shall, pursuant to the requirements of existing or subsequently enacted County ordinances, obtain all permits from, and where applicable pay all fees to, the Public Works Department, the Planning and Zoning Department and the Building Department. The issuance of a permit by the County shall not be construed by the Provider as a warranty that the placement by the Provider of its conduits, cables or pole lines, facilities, or the start of construction, is in compliance with any applicable rules, regulations or laws. All construction and maintenance of the Provider's Facilities within County public rights-of-way incident to Provider's provision of service shall, regardless of who performs installation and/or construction, be and remain the responsibility of the Provider.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-152.1. Protection of underground utilitie</catch_line>
<text>
In connection with excavation in the Public Rights-of-Way, Providers, where applicable, shall comply with the requirements of Article XIII.5 of Chapter 21 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-153. Compliance with applicable laws and ordinances</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
All Providers shall at all times during the life of this chapter be subject to all lawful exercise of the police power by the County and to such reasonable regulation by the County as the County shall hereafter provide. All Providers shall comply with all laws, statutes, codes, ordinances, rules, or regulations applicable to its business. Specific and exact compliance to all zoning and building regulations shall be adhered to by Providers.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Except as may be specifically provided for in this chapter, the failure of the County or a licensee, upon more than one (1) occasion, to exercise a right or to require compliance or performance under this chapter shall not be deemed to constitute a waiver of such right or a waiver of compliance or performance in the future.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 01-109, § 5, 6-19-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-154. Right to use Easement and Streets Not Warranted</catch_line>
<text>
It is understood that there may be from time to time within the County various Public Rights-of-Way which the County does not have the unqualified right to authorize Providers to use; therefore, in granting a Communications Services Provider Registration or a Cable Service provider License, the County does not warrant or represent as to any particular easement, right-of-way, or portion of a right-of-way or easement, that it has the right to authorize Providers to Place or Maintain portions of its Facilities therein.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-155. Other Agreements, Permits and Easements Requirements</catch_line>
<text>
Nothing in this Article or with respect to the issuance of a Registration or License shall be construed to require the County to assume any responsibility for the securing of any right-of-way, easements, or other rights which may be required by a Provider for the installation of its Facilities, nor shall the County be responsible for securing any permits or agreements with other persons or utilities.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-156. No Property Rights Conveyed</catch_line>
<text>
Nothing in this Article or with respect to the issuance of a Registration or License shall grant to Providers any right of property in County-owned property or public rights-of-way, nor shall the County be compelled to maintain any of its property or public rights-of-way any longer than, or in any other fashion than in the County's judgment, its own business or needs may require.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-156.1 Reservation of rights</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The County reserves the right to amend this chapter as it shall find it necessary in the lawful exercise of its police powers.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The County reserves the right to amend this chapter as it existed prior to the effective date of this article, to the full extent permitted by state and federal law.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
This article shall be applicable to all facilities Placed or Maintained in the County's Rights-of-Way on or after the effective date of this article, to the full extent permitted by state and federal law.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The adoption of this article is not intended to waive any rights or defenses under any existing franchise, license or other agreements with a Provider.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 01-109, § 5, 6-19-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-157. County's Right to Inspect</catch_line>
<text>
The County shall have the right to inspect a Provider's Facilities located in the Public Rights-of-way and its installation, construction, and maintenance to insure compliance with the terms of this chapter and any requirements of the Public Works Department or applicable ordinances.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-158. Joint or common use of poles</catch_line>
<text>
Providers shall enter into agreements for the joint or common use of poles or other wire holding structures where poles or other wire holding structures already exist for the use in serving the County or serving the public convenience. No location of any pole or wire holding structure of the Provider shall be a vested interest, and such pole or structure shall be removed or modified by the licensee at its own expense whenever the County determines it to be necessary in conjunction with a County project.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-159. Location/Relocation of Facilities</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Unless controlling law provides otherwise, a Provider's system shall be installed underground in areas where existing power or telephone facilities are underground. If both power and telephone facilities are installed above ground, the Provider shall install its facilities underground at the request of a resident or property owner when the resident or property owner agrees to pay the additional cost of such installation.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Provider shall not place any fixtures or equipment where the same will interfere with any existing gas, electric, cable system, telephone, sewer, drainage, or water lines, fixtures or equipment. The Provider shall locate its lines and equipment in such a manner as not to interfere unnecessarily with the usual travel on streets; with the installation or operation of gas, electric, Cable System, telephone, water, drainage, or sewer line equipment, or with the rights of owners of property which abuts any Public Right-of-Way.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Unless controlling law provides otherwise, Providers shall relocate any above ground portion of their systems underground in any easement or right-of-way area where existing power or telephone facilities are hereafter so relocated. Any such relocation shall be at the Provider's expense, and such relocation shall be accomplished concurrently with relocation of any such power and telephone facilities.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Provider shall have the authority to trim trees upon or overhanging streets, alleys, sidewalks and public ways and places of the County so as to prevent the branches of such trees from coming in contact with the wires and cables of the Provider, in a manner approved by and acceptable to the County. When the County determines such trimming is necessary to protect the health safety and welfare of the public, such trimming may be done by it or under its supervision and direction at the expense of the Provider, if prior notification has been given to the Provider and the Provider thereafter failed to respond.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
A Provider shall promptly and at the Provider's own expense protect, support, temporarily disconnect, remove, modify or relocate any part of their system when required by the County by reason of traffic conditions, public safety, road construction, change of street grade, installation of sewers, drains, water pipes, power lines, signal devices, tracks, any other type of County improvement project, or to accommodate the abandonment of any street. Such work shall be completed no later than 30 days after receiving notice from the County or such longer period as may be agreed to by the County. In the event such contingency occurs, and the Provider fails to remove or modify its system, the County may, upon notice to the Provider, make the necessary removals and charge the Provider for the cost. Nothing in this Section shall be construed to waive any rights the Provider may have under state or federal law to be reimbursed for relocation expenses.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Each Provider shall, on the request of any person holding a building moving permit issued by the County, temporarily remove, raise or lower its wires to permit the moving of buildings. The expense of such temporary removal or raising or lowering of wires shall be paid by the person requesting same, and the Provider shall have the authority to require such payment in advance. The Provider shall be given not less than seven (7) days advance notice to arrange for such temporary wire changes.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
When placed underground, all service lines, drops, or laterals that connect the end user customer to the Provider's distribution system shall be buried as follows: (a) on easements and public rights-of-way at the depth as established by the Public Works manual or regulations; and (b) on private property at a sufficient depth so that no portion of the line is exposed. The County may impose a specific depth requirement for such lines on private property.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Except for relocation expenses when authorized by state or federal law, the Provider shall not be entitled to any compensation for damages from the County as a result of having to remove or relocate its property, lines and cable from such public property or public rights-of-way in the event the County determines that a necessity exists for such removal or relocation.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 01-109, § 5, 6-19-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-160. Work in the right-of-way</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Provider must obtain any required permits before causing any damage or disturbance to public rights-of-way, easements or thoroughfares as a result of its construction or operations and must restore to their former condition such property in a manner approved by the County. If such restoration is not satisfactorily performed within a reasonable time, the County, after prior notice to the Provider, may cause the repairs to be made at the expense of the Provider. All additional or reoccurring repairs required as a result of the Provider's work may also be made at the expense of the Provider.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Providers granted Permits to Place or Maintain Facilities in the Public Rights-of-Way or utility easements shall provide at least seven (7) days' prior written notice to the residents of an area that Provider's construction or maintenance crews will be working in the area by mail and/or through the placement of notices on the front door knobs of the residents in the area, with such notices providing the provider's name and telephone number. Such notice shall be provided to residents whose property is directly affected, or adjacent to, the Public rights-of-way or utility easement impacted by the Provider's construction or maintenance. Such notice will inform customers that construction will take place and contain the anticipated duration, a brief and accurate statement of Provider's property and rights-of-way restoration obligations, name of contractor, if any, and list the telephone number of the Consumer Services Department if residents have complaints regarding construction, maintenance and/or restoration. The Director shall promulgate a model notice form. Use of that form, while not required, will constitute per se compliance with this notice requirement. The notice requirement in this Section shall not apply to service drops or emergency maintenance which is defined for purposes of this Section to mean repairs necessary to restore service or system performance as a result of an incident outside of the provider's control.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All vehicles utilized by Providers and subcontractors working for Providers in the construction, installation or maintenance of the Provider's system shall be clearly marked, providing the licensee's name and telephone number, and, if applicable, the CC# as required by Section 10-4 of the Miami-Dade County Code. Subcontractors working for multiple Providers may place magnetic signage on their vehicle(s) to meet the requirements of this subsection; provided, however, this provision does not affect the subcontractors Section 10-4 requirements. All personnel employed or subcontracted by Providers in the construction of the Provider's system shall possess identification providing the employee's name and the provider's name and telephone numbers.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Providers shall join and maintain a continuous membership in Sunshine State One Call of Florida, Inc. or other bona fide underground notification program accepted by Miami-Dade County and use its services prior to construction or maintenance. Only certified contractors may be utilized for the construction or maintenance.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
All new pedestals, amplifiers and power supplies installed or worked on by the Provider shall be marked with the name of the Provider. The Provider will make all reasonable efforts to ensure that all existing pedestals, amplifiers and power supplies shall be marked during the normal course of business.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 01-109, § 5, 6-19-01; Ord. No. 03-122, § 3, 5-6-03)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-161. Safety</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Providers' work performance, equipment, and job sites shall be in compliance with all applicable County, State and federal requirements and shall conform to the provisions of the public works manual. Provider's work, while in progress, shall be properly protected at all times with suitable barricades, flags, lights, flares or other devices as are required by the Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices (FDOT), Roadway and Traffic Design Standards (FDOT) and/or any requirements of the Public Works Department to protect all members of the public having occasion to use the portion of the streets involved or adjacent property.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Provider shall at all times employ due care and shall install, maintain and use commonly accepted methods and devices for preventing failures and accidents which are likely to cause damage, injuries or nuisances to the public. All of Provider's structures and all lines, equipment and connection in, over, under and upon the public rights-of-way of the County wherever situated or located shall at all times be kept and maintained in a safe, suitable, substantial condition, and in good order and repair.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 01-109, § 4, 6-19-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-162. Technical Standards</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
All construction, installation, grounding, and maintenance shall comply with the current versions of the National Electrical Safety Code and the National Electrical Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Underground construction in streets shall be of such quality as to assure continuity of service without the necessity of frequent street or pavement cutting.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All cables and wires shall be installed, where possible, parallel with electric and telephone lines.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 01-109, § 5, 6-19-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-163. Unauthorized Work</catch_line>
<text>
Any conduits, cables or pole lines installed or placed without first having obtained the Permits herein before provided for shall be removed within ten (10) days following written notice by the County. Failure to comply following written notice may result in the removal of the conduits, cables or poles by order of the Public Works Department and the cost of removal shall be borne and paid by the Provider. When permits are required, all work done without permits will cease until all permits are pulled.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-164. Protection of County Property</catch_line>
<text>
The Provider shall not in any way displace, damage or destroy any sewer, water main, pipe or any other facilities belonging to the County without the consent of the County; and the Provider shall be liable to the County for the cost of any repairs made necessary by any such displacement, damage or destruction and shall pay such costs upon demand.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-165. Emergency, liability, indemnification; liability in case of emergency</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
In an emergency that affects the public safety, as determined by the County, when the Provider or its representative is immediately unavailable or unable to provide the necessary immediate repairs to any portion of the Public Rights-of-Way that is damaged due to any faults or settled or sunken areas that may develop in any area over, around or adjacent to same, the County, when apprised of such an emergency, shall have the right to make the repairs with the total cost of same being charged to the Provider.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
If, at any time in case of fire, police action, disaster, or other emergency, it shall appear necessary in the reasonable judgment of the County to cut, move or otherwise interfere with any of the wires, cables, amplifiers, appliances or appurtenances thereto of the Provider the County shall not be liable for any injury or damage to such property and equipment of the Provider as a result of such cutting, moving or interference.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 01-109, § 5, 6-19-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-166. Abandonment of Facilities</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Upon abandonment of a Facility owned by a Provider in the Public Rights-of-Way, the Provider shall notify the Director within ninety (90) days. The Director may direct the Provider by written notice to remove all or any portion of such Abandoned Facility at the Provider's sole expense if the County determines that the Abandoned Facility's presence interferes with the public health, safety or welfare, which shall include, but shall not be limited to, a determination that such Facility: (a) compromises safety at any time for any Public Rights-of-Way user or during construction or maintenance in Public Rights-of-Way; (b) prevents another Person from locating facilities in the area of Public Rights-of-Way where the Abandoned Facility is located when other alternative locations are not reasonably available; or (c) creates a maintenance condition that is disruptive to the Public Rights-of-Way's use. In the event of (b), the County may require the third Person to coordinate with the Provider that owns the existing Facility for joint removal and placement, where agreed to by the Registrant.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Reserved.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
In the event that the County does not direct the removal of the Abandoned Facility, the Provider, by its notice of Abandonment to the County, shall be deemed to consent to the alteration or removal of all or any portion of the Facility by the County or another Person at such third party's cost.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
If the Provider fails to remove all or any portion of an Abandoned Facility as directed by the County within a reasonable time period as may be required by the County under the circumstances, the County may perform such removal and charge the cost of the removal against the Provider.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 01-109, § 5, 6-19-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-167. Removal and restoration; removal required</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
To the extent that it is determined to be in the interest of the health, safety, and welfare of the public a Provider shall, upon notice, promptly remove from the public rights-of-way all portions of the system and poles of such system.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
In the event that a communications facility has been installed in any street without complying with the requirements of this article, the Provider, within thirty (30) days after written notice by the County, shall commence removal from the streets of all such property as the County may require.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 01-109, § 5, 6-19-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8AA-168. Restoration Required</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
In the event of such removal as referenced herein, the Provider shall promptly and reasonably restore the street or other area from which such property was removed to the condition existing prior to the disruption of the street or other area.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
If a Provider fails to properly and promptly restore the area, the County, at its election, may restore the area and cause forfeiture of the permanent performance bond in order to reimburse the County for any costs and expenses it incurs for restoring the area.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 01-109, § 5, 6-19-01)</history>
</law>
