<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXIV._BU-1_NEIGHBORHOOD_BUSINESS</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-237. Purpose</catch_line>
<text>
The purpose of the BU-1, Neighborhood District, is to provide for retail and service convenience facilities which satisfy the essential and frequent needs of the adjacent residential neighborhood.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-238. Uses permitted</catch_line>
<text>
No land, body of water or structure shall be used or permitted to be used and no structure shall be hereafter erected, constructed, moved, reconstructed or structurally altered or maintained in any BU-1 District, which is designed, arranged or intended to be used or occupied for any purpose, except for one (1) or more of the following uses:
<section prefix = "1">
Residential uses may be permitted as a combination of permitted business uses and residential uses housed in the same building; the floor area of the residential use shall not exceed fifty (50) percent of the floor area of the building.
(1.1)
Workforce housing units in compliance with the provisions of this section and Article XIIA of this code.
(1.2)
Allied health care clinical colleges/universities.
(1.3)
Adult day care center.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Antique shops.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Apparel stores selling new and/or used merchandise, provided such establishments offering used merchandise contain not more than four thousand (4,000) square feet of gross floor area. The incidental sales of used jewelry, used toys, and used furniture shall be permitted in conjunction with the sales of used apparel, provided that the floor area devoted to the display of those incidental sales items does not exceed thirty (30) percent of the total gross floor area of the apparel store.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Art good stores, artist studios and photograph shops and galleries.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Attended, nonmotorized donation collection vehicles as described in Section 33-19; provided, however, that such attended non-motorized donation collection vehicles are placed only on improved property on sites of not less than one-half acre in size, in compliance with required setbacks, and not in required landscape areas or required parking areas and not in an area which would impede traffic circulation. It is further provided, that no attended non-motorized donation collection vehicle shall be placed within twenty-six hundred (2600) feet of another non-motorized donation collection vehicle; the distance shall be measured by following a straight line from the nearest property line where the proposed attended, non-motorized donation collection vehicle is to be located to the nearest property line of an existing attended, non-motorized donation collection vehicle. Notwithstanding any ordinance, resolution or administrative order to the contrary no fee shall be charged for the issuance of a certificate of use and occupancy.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Banks, excluding drive-in teller service.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Beauty parlors.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Bakeries, retail only (baking permitted on premises).
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Barber shops.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Bicycle sales, rentals and repairs (nonmotorized).
(10.1)
Computer, video, videogame and DVD stores, including the retail sale or rental of new hardware, software, players, videotapes and videogames, consoles, and related computer, video, videogame and DVD products, and the ancillary resale or exchange of pre-played computer, video, videogame and DVD products, provided such establishments contain not more than four thousand (4,000) square feet of floor area.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Confectionery, ice cream stores and dairy stores.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Conservatories and music and dance schools, provided no such establishment is located within five hundred (500) feet of any RU, or EU District except after approval after public hearing.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Dairy stores.
(13.5)
Drugstores.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
Donated goods centers for the acceptance only of new or used merchandise, upon compliance with the following conditions:
<section prefix = "a">
The portion of the donated goods center which is open to the public shall not exceed 2000 square feet;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A solid wall shall separate the public area of the donated goods center from the balance of the said center and shall prevent public access to the balance of said center;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The donated goods center must be operated by an organization which has been incorporated as a not-for-profit organization under the laws of the State of Florida for a charitable purpose and which has been declared exempt from the payment of federal income taxes by the United States Internal Revenue Service;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The donated goods must be accepted by personnel directly employed by or volunteers for the not-for-profit organization;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The monetary proceeds resulting from the sale of donations collected at a donated goods center must be used in accordance with the organization's charitable purpose pursuant to Section 33-238(14)(c) to benefit persons within the boundaries of Miami-Dade County or outside of Miami-Dade County to provide emergency relief for victims of natural, manmade or economic disasters;
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The operation of the donated goods center, the collection and use of donations and proceeds thereof must be conducted by said not-for-profit organization and not by a licensee, subcontractor or agent of the not-for-profit organization;
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
A declaration of use in a form meeting with the approval of the Director shall be submitted to the Department prior to the issuance of a certificate of use and occupancy specifying compliance with the foregoing conditions. Said declaration of use shall include a floor plan for the intended use as required by the Department.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
Florist shops.
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
Grocery stores, fruit stores, health food stores, delicatessen, meat and fish markets and other similar food stores, provided such establishments contain not more than four thousand (4,000) square feet of floor area.
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
Hardware stores.
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
Information booth, gate house and security station. The structure housing these uses shall comply with principal building setback requirements but need not comply with any minimum square foot requirements for the districts.
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
Interior design shops, office and display only.
</section>
<section prefix = "20">
Jewelry stores, including incidental sales and purchases of used jewelry.
</section>
<section prefix = "21">
Leather goods and luggage shops.
</section>
<section prefix = "22">
Mail order offices, without storage of products sold.
(22.1)
Museum.
</section>
<section prefix = "23">
Newsstand.
</section>
<section prefix = "24">
Office buildings.
</section>
<section prefix = "25">
Optical stores.
(25.1)
Outdoor dining as an ancillary use in conjunction with restaurants, snack shops and other food service facilities where the primary use is the preparation of food for consumption on premises shall be permitted, subject to the following restrictions:
<section prefix = "a">
The outdoor dining area shall be managed, operated and maintained as an integral part of the immediately adjacent food service facility; and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The outdoor dining area shall not reduce required parking or landscaping for the site; and
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The outdoor seating area shall be included in the calculations for required parking; and
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
There shall be no outdoor cooking or food preparation; and
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
No outdoor dining area shall obstruct or impede pedestrian traffic; and
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The outdoor dining area shall comply with handicapped accessibility requirements; and
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
No outside public address system shall be permitted. Unamplified music shall be permitted in the outdoor dining area, subject to compliance with Section 21-28 of this Code; and
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Blinking and flashing type lighting shall be prohibited; and
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Alcoholic beverages may be served where such service is strictly incidental to the service of food and is from a service bar only, subject to compliance with the regulations specified in Article X (Alcoholic Beverages) of this chapter; and
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
The use shall be subject to plan review and approval through the building permit review process. The plans for such use shall include all restrooms, furniture, umbrellas, lighting, and other related services and functions associated with the proposed use, together with all required and provided parking calculations. Plans shall be subject to all the applicable building and zoning code regulations; and
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
The use shall require a Certificate of Use which shall be renewed annually and shall be subject to revocation upon violation of any applicable building and zoning code regulations, or when a continuation of the permit would constitute a hazard or nuisance.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "26">
Paint and wallpaper stores.
</section>
<section prefix = "27">
Photograph galleries.
</section>
<section prefix = "28">
Pottery shops.
</section>
<section prefix = "29">
Restaurants and coffee houses or dining room where kitchen is screened or located altogether within an enclosed building or room and with ample provisions for carrying away or dissipating fumes, odors, smoke or noise and where premises are so arranged and the business is so conducted as not to be offensive or obnoxious to occupants of adjoining premises or to passersby. Restaurants and outdoor (where approved by public hearing) cafes may serve alcoholic beverages where such service is strictly incidental to the service of food and from a service bar only provided no entertainment of any kind is furnished. No sign of any type or character shall be exhibited or displayed to the outside denoting that alcoholic beverages are obtainable within.
(29.1)
Religious facilities located inside the Urban Development Boundary. Religious facilities outside the Urban Development Boundary will be permitted only upon approval after public hearing.
</section>
<section prefix = "30">
Schools, subject to compliance with the requirements of Sections 33-151.11 through 33-151.22 of this code.
</section>
<section prefix = "31">
Self-service post office which contains mechanical or computer equipment designed to provide limited postal service for walk-up trade.
</section>
<section prefix = "32">
Shoe stores and shoe repair shops.
</section>
<section prefix = "33">
Sporting goods stores.
</section>
<section prefix = "34">
Tailor shops, provided such establishments contain not more than four thousand (4,000) square feet of floor area.
</section>
<section prefix = "35">
Tobacco shops.
</section>
<section prefix = "36">
Variety stores, provided such establishments contain not more than four thousand (4,000) square feet of floor area.
</section>
<section prefix = "37">
Any property in a BU District may be used as access for egress and ingress only to property zoned in any BU classification or in any IU classification provided that both properties are under the same ownership.
</section>
<section prefix = "38">
Outside walk-up window service (no outside stools, chairs or tables), in connection with establishments where the principal use is selling food and drink products, and where a sidewalk of at least seven (7) feet in width abuts the store unit concerned.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-239. Setbacks, cubic content, yard area, etc</catch_line>
<text>
Setbacks, cubic content, yard area, lot sizes, etc., shall be as specified in article II of this chapter.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-240. Height</catch_line>
<text>
The maximum height of a building shall be two (2) stories and shall not exceed thirty-five (35) feet in height.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-241. Floor area ratio and lot coverage</catch_line>
<text>
The floor area ratio shall be forty-one-hundredths (0.40) at one (1) story and shall be increased by eleven-one-hundredths (0.11) for each additional story. Structure parking shall not count as part of the floor area, but shall be counted in computing building height and number of stories. The total lot coverage permitted for all buildings on the site shall not exceed forty (40) percent of the total lot area. Enclosed or nonenclosed mall areas shall not count as part of the floor area, for floor area ratio computation purposes, nor as part of the lot coverage.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-242. Landscaped open space</catch_line>
<text>
The minimum landscaped open space at one (1) story shall be in accordance with the following table:
<section prefix="1" type="table">
<table class="thead1 table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="66.66666666666667%" /> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class=""> <i>  Size of the</i> <br /><i>Total Lot Area</i> </td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class=""> <i>Percent of the</i> <br /><i>Total Lot Area</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Up to one (1) acre</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">18.0%</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than one (1) acre and up to five (5) acres</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">16.0%</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than five (5) acres and up to twenty-five (25) acres</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">14.0%</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than twenty-five (25) acres</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">12.0%</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 

The minimum landscaped open space shall be increased by one and one-half (1.5) percent for each additional story or part thereof. For the purpose of computing the amount of required landscaped open space where the building height varies, the number of stories shall be equal to the sum of the products of the number of stories of each part of the building(s) of a different height times its floor area divided by the sum of the floor area of all parts of the building(s). Said open space shall be extensively landscaped with grass, trees and shrubbery. Water areas may be used as part of the required landscaped open space provided such water areas do not exceed twenty (20) percent of the required landscaped open space. The specific areas within enclosed or nonenclosed malls which are landscaped with grass, trees and/or shrubbery, water areas therein, and areas therein with permanent art display may be used as part of the required landscaped open space provided such areas do not exceed ten (10) percent of the required landscaped open space. Landscaping and trees shall be provided in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-243. Prohibited uses</catch_line>
<text>
Sale of fruit or merchandise from trucks, wagons or other vehicles parked on or along public or private streets shall be prohibited.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-244. Enclosed uses</catch_line>
<text>
All uses shall be conducted within completely enclosed buildings, unless otherwise specifically provided herein. All materials and products shall be stored within the building or within an area completely enclosed with walls which have a life expectancy of twenty (20) years or more from the date of installation of said walls. Storage shall not be made above the height of the walls.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-245. Business property adjacent to residential districts</catch_line>
<text>
Where a business lot abuts an AU, GU, RU or EU zoned property, a decorative masonry wall at least five (5) feet in height shall be erected on the business lots along the common property line separating the two (2) districts. Where a dedicated alley separates the two (2) districts, the five-foot decorative masonry wall shall be erected along the business lots adjacent to the alley, permitting only openings for egress and ingress purposes with the smallest width possible for this purpose. Where the business property is a through lot, and the rear of the business lot lies across the street right-of-way from AU, GU, RU or EU zoned property, said wall shall be located on the business lot ten (10) feet in from the official right-of-way line at the rear of the lot, and the ten-foot strip shall be substantially landscaped. The Director shall determine which part of the lot is the rear property line. No wall will be required along the front property line of the business lot where the same is separated from a residential zone by a street. Where the common property line between the two (2) districts is an interior side property line, the required wall shall extend only to a point fifteen (15) feet from the official front property line.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-245.1. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Section 33-245.1, pertaining to expansion of existing commercial structures, has been deleted as obsolete. It was derived from Ord. No. 74-22, § 1, adopted April 16, 1974.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-245.2. Plan review standards</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
The Department shall review plans for compliance with zoning regulations and for compliance with the site plan review criteria. The decision of the Department in relation to the site plan review criteria may be appealed by the party(ies) which filed the application for the project to the appropriate Community Zoning Appeals Board within thirty (30) days of the date the project was denied approval in writing. Appeals will be heard as expeditiously as possible. The purpose of the site plan review is to encourage logic, imagination and variety in the design process and thereby insure the congruity of the proposed development and its compatibility with the surrounding area. All final plans submitted for building permits shall be substantially in compliance with plans approved under the plan review procedure herein established.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Exhibits which the applicant shall submit to the Department of Planning and Zoning shall include, but not be limited to the following:
<section prefix = "1">
Schematic site plans at a scale of not less than one (1) inch equals one hundred (100) feet containing the following information:
<section prefix = "a">
Proposed commercial floor area.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Height, size, shape and location of existing and proposed buildings.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Parking layouts.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Proposed grades if significantly altered.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Existing and proposed fences, walls, signs, architectural accents, street furniture and locations of advertising or graphic features.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Landscaping and trees shall be provided in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Schematic building plans including elevation and/or sections of major structures.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Isometrics or perspective and/or model(s) of the proposed development.
The Director shall have the right to waive any of the items required because of the nature or timing of the development or because the information cannot be furnished at the time of this review.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
The following checklist of criteria shall be utilized as a guide by the Department and by the appropriate board, upon appeal, in the review process:
<section prefix = "1">
Planning studies. Design or planning studies completed by the Department and submitted to the County Commission that include recommendations for development patterns or site plan criteria which would apply to the development proposal under review shall be utilized in the site plan review process.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Exterior spatial relationships. The three-dimensional air-space volume created by the arrangement of structures and landscape shall produce spatial relationships that function with the intended use of the project and are compatible with the development or zoning in the adjoining area.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Landscape. Landscape shall be preserved in its natural state insofar as practicable by minimizing tree removal. Landscape treatment shall be provided to enhance architectural features, strengthen vistas and important axes and provide shade.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Buffers. Buffering elements that provide a logical transition to adjoining, existing or permitted uses shall be provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Scale. Scale of proposed structures shall be compatible with surrounding existing or permitted uses or shall be made compatible by the use of the buffering element.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Signs and outdoor lighting. All outdoor lighting, signs or permanent outdoor advertising or identification features shall be designed as an integral part of and be harmonious with building design and the surrounding landscape.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Roof installation and facilities. All permitted installations housing mechanical equipment located on the roof shall be screened from ground view and from view at the level in which the installations are located, and shall be designed as an integral part and be harmonious with the building design.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Circulation. Pedestrian and auto circulation shall be separated insofar as practicable and all circulation systems shall adequately serve the needs of the project and be compatible and functional with circulation systems outside the development. When head-in parking is located directly adjacent to a storefront an anti-ram fixture with a minimum Department of State protection rating of K4 shall be placed along the outer edge of the sidewalk to visually and physically separate the vehicular and pedestrian areas. Installations must include a landscaping/planting component to mitigate the visual impacts of the anti-ram fixture. The anti-ram fixture shall be continuous with reasonable breaks provided to allow for pedestrian access and compliance with the Americans with Disabilities Act.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Parking areas. Building wall extensions, plantings, berms or other innovative means shall be used as a means of minimizing the adverse effect of the visual impact of parking areas. This requirement is in addition to the requirements of the landscape regulations of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Service areas. Service areas which may be provided shall be screened and so located as not to be visible from view.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Visual screening for decorative walls: In an effort to prevent graffiti vandalism, the following options shall be utilized for walls abutting zoned or dedicated rights-of-way:
<section prefix = "a">
Wall with landscaping. The wall shall be setback two and one-half (2½) feet from the right-of-way line and the resulting setback area shall contain a continuous extensively landscaped buffer which must be maintained in a good healthy condition by the property owner, or where applicable, by the condominium, homeowners or similar association. The landscape buffer shall contain one (1) or more of the following planting materials:
<section prefix = "1">
Shrubs. Shrubs shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Hedges. Hedges shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Vines. Climbing vines shall be a minimum of thirty-six (36) inches in height immediately after planting.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Metal picket fence. Where a metal picket fence abutting a zoned or dedicated right-of-way is constructed in lieu of a decorative wall, landscaping shall not be required.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Window Height. When head-in parking is located directly adjacent to a storefront, ground floor windowsills shall be placed at a minimum height of 24 inches and a maximum of 48 inches above grade.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 74-22, § 1, 4-16-74; Ord. No. 95-19, § 9, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 95-223, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-127, § 14, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 98-125, § 21, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 99-38, § 10, 4-27-99; Ord. No. 12-47, § 1, 7-3-12)</history>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (29) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 74-22, § 1, adopted April 16, 1974, amended Art. XXIV, pertaining to the BU-1 District, to read as set out in §§ 33-327—33-245.2. Formerly Art. XXIV, §§ 33-237—33-245, was derived from Ord. No. 57-19, § 18(A)—(C), (E)—(G), adopted Oct. 22, 1957; Ord. No. 62-18, § 1, adopted April 17, 1962; Ord. No. 64-19, § 6, adopted May 5, 1964; and Ord. No. 69-54, § 1, adopted Sept. 17, 1969. (Back)
Section 4 of said Ord. No. 74-22 provides: (Back)
"Section 4. The provisions of this ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days from date of its enactment. However: (Back)
"Provisions of this ordinance shall not apply to those buildings for which a building permit has been issued and is in effect or for which proper and complete applications and plans have been submitted for building permits within sixty (60) days from the effective date of this ordinance provided that the construction under the permit shall be commenced and progressively carried to a conclusion within the time limitations for permits established by the Building Code. As to all such buildings, the pertinent zoning regulations in effect prior to the effective date of this ordinance shall be applicable. Where a development or project site plan has been approved prior to the adoption of this ordinance by resolution of the Zoning Appeals Board or Board of County Commissioners, or prior to the adoption of this ordinance, an agreement, letter of intent, or performance standards encompassing all of the basic items constituting a site plan has been recorded or adopted by resolution of the Zoning Appeals Board or the Board of County Commissioners, this ordinance shall not be applicable thereto so long as the following conditions are met: (Back)
(1)This exception shall apply only to those properties covered by that specific site plan, letter of intent, performance standards, or agreement. (Back)
(2)Such project is developed in accordance with the approved site plan or agreement letter of intent or performance standards and in accordance with pertinent regulations in effect prior to the effective date of this ordinance. (Back)
(3)Such development or project shall be commenced on or before the expiration of nine (9) months from the effective date of this ordinance. Site preparation, such as filling or excavating as well as commencement of construction of buildings, shall, for the purpose of this section, constitute commencement of work. (Back)
(4)Such project is under continual construction unless acts of God cause an interruption in construction. Any cessation of construction for a period of nine (9) months shall be conclusive presumption of an abandonment of the approved project or development and the uncompleted portion of said project or development shall be subject to terms and conditions of this ordinance." (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
