<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_II._BULK_SALES_OF_PLANTS_AVOCADO</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-51. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
As used in this article:
<section prefix = "a">
Bulk means six (6) or more plants, or quantities of fruit in excess of one (1) bushel by weight or fifty-five (55) pounds.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Fruit means avocados, limes, and mangoes.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Grower means any person who grows said plants or fruit for sale in bulk.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Plants means trees, shrubs, vines, foliage, buds, bulbs, seeds, and all other plants and plant parts.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-52. Bulk sales, transportation or purchase without certificate, prohibited</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful for any person to sell, transport or purchase said fruit or plants in bulk without completing a certificate as hereinafter provided.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-53. Certificates—Distribution; contents</catch_line>
<text>
The Miami-Dade Police Director shall provide and distribute a certificate form, to be completed by growers, transporters and purchasers of said fruit or plants in bulk, which certificate form shall provide for information to be inserted indicating the date of the purchase from the grower, the name and address of the growers, transporters and purchaser, which of the said fruit or plants is sold, the quantity of said fruit or plants, if any, the origin of said fruit or plants and the license tag number of the vehicle, if any, used to transport said fruit or plants from the place of sale by the grower.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-54. Same—Grower, transporter and purchaser to fill out; certificate to accompany said fruit or plants during transportation; grower, transporter and purchaser to retain copy</catch_line>
<text>
Every grower, transporter and purchaser of said fruit or plants in bulk shall complete the certificate form provided and distributed by the Miami-Dade Police Director, indicating the date of the purchase from the grower, the name and address of the grower, transporter and purchaser, which of the said fruit or plants is sold, the quantity of said fruit or plants sold, the specific variety of said fruit or plants, if any, the origin of said fruit or plants and the license tag number of the vehicle, if any, used to transport said fruit or plants from the place of sale by the grower. Said certificate shall accompany said fruit or plants during the transportation thereof. Each grower, transporter and purchaser shall retain a carbon copy or duplicate of said completed certificate for a period of sixty (60) days following the date of purchase from the grower.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-55. Exemptions from article provisions</catch_line>
<text>
This article shall not apply:
<section prefix = "a">
To the transaction of said fruit or plants by the grower prior to sale; or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
To avocados and limes after inspection by the Florida State Department of Agriculture when accompanied by a certificate of inspection; or
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
To the transportation of said fruit or plants by license wholesale produce or nursery dealers; or
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
To said fruit or plants purchased outside Miami-Dade County, Florida; or
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
To the transportation of said fruit or plants between two (2) locations at which the transporter or his employer maintain a place of business; or
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
To persons growing said fruit or plants for personal consumption and not for the purposes of sale; or
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
To retail sales of said fruit or plants.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-56. Penalty for violations</catch_line>
<text>
Any person convicted of violating this article shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for a period not to exceed thirty (30) days, or by both such fine and imprisonment.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-57. Article provisions declared supplemental</catch_line>
<text>
The provisions of this article are not intended to and shall not be construed as changing, modifying, amending, repealing, superseding or conflicting with any provisions or sections of the Florida Statutes, but shall be construed as supplemental and additional thereto and not as a substitute therefor.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 8A-58—8A-64. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (2) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 66-23, §§ 1—9, enacted June 7, 1966, and effective thirty (30) days thereafter, amended the Code to add the provisions codified as Art. II, §§ 8A-51—8A-59. Ord. No. 71-28, § 1, enacted March 16, 1971 amended the article "to read as follows," replacing §§ 8A-51—8A-59 with §§ 8A-51—8A-57, thereby effecting a total revision of the article. (Back)
State Law reference— Florida Avocado, Mango and Lime Sales Law, F.S. § 570.55. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
