<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXII._PUBLIC_LIBRARY_ADVISORY_BO</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-192. Short title</catch_line>
<text>
This article shall be known and may be cited as the "Miami-Dade County Public Library Advisory Board Ordinance".
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-193. Declaration of legislative intent</catch_line>
<text>
It is the purpose and intent of the Board of County Commissioners, in enacting this article under and pursuant to the provisions of Section 4.08 of the Home Rule Charter, to create and establish an Advisory Board of official status composed of outstanding citizens with representative interests and geographical distribution, who are dedicated to the purposes of providing a feasible, adequate Public Library system for this entire metropolitan area in cooperation with all other governmental entities, and that will be in a position to furnish information, advice and counsel to the Board of County Commissioners in respect to the appropriate means and methods by which adequate Public Library facilities and services may be provided within the framework of the County government on a sound financial basis for the use and benefit of all residents and visitors of this metropolitan area, and to work towards the development and implementation of sound programs for public libraries through the mutual cooperation between the State, County and municipal governments and agencies and coordination with non-governmental organizations interested in library facilities and services. This article shall not be construed as delegating to such advisory board or its members any power or authority of a governmental, legislative or administrative nature, but as the establishment of an official instrumentality by which the Board of County Commissioners may obtain the benefit of accurate, comprehensive information, advice and counsel concerning all matters relating to public libraries and other cultural facilities and programs which may be necessary for appropriate action by the Board of County Commissioners.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-194. Creation of Advisory Board</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created and established in Miami-Dade County, Florida, an Advisory Board to be known as the Miami-Dade County Public Library Advisory Board.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-195. Membership; vacancies; qualifications; term</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Membership. The Miami-Dade County Public Library Advisory Board shall consist of eleven (11) members appointed by the County Commission. Eight (8) members shall be residents of the Library Taxing District and three (3) members shall be residents of the City of Miami and members of the City of Miami's Library Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Vacancies.
<section prefix = "1">
Library taxing district members. In filling any vacancy the County Commission shall select the replacement board member from a list of three (3) candidates to be submitted by the remaining members of the Board; provided that the City Manager of the City of Miami Beach may recommend to the Library Board candidates for two (2) membership positions. In the event that none of the three (3) candidates suggested meets with commission approval, the Board shall submit another and entirely different list for commission consideration. This process shall continue until a replacement has been appointed.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
City of Miami members (if City Library Board abolished). If the City of Miami's Library Board is abolished, then vacancies from among the aforesaid three (3) members who are residents of the City of Miami shall be filled as follows:
<section prefix = "a">
The Board shall submit a list of three (3) candidates to the City Commission.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The City Commission shall select one (1) of the candidates to submit to the County Commission; however, in the event that none of the three (3) candidates suggested meets with City Commission approval, the Board shall submit three (3) different names to the City Commission for its consideration.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The County Commission shall appoint the suggested candidate to the Board; however, in the event that the candidate suggested does not meet with County Commission approval, the City Commission shall either submit one (1) of the remaining candidates to the County Commission or request three (3) different names from the Board.
This process shall continue until a replacement has been appointed.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Qualifications. Each member shall be a qualified elector of Miami-Dade County, and shall possess a reputation for civic pride, integrity, responsibility, and business or professional ability, and shall have demonstrated an active interest in Public Library facilities and services. As far as practicable, the membership of the Board shall be representative of the various interests of this metropolitan area in respect to geographic and economic factors.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
Terms. The term of office of the membership shall be one (1) year for three (3) members, two (2) years for three (3) members and three (3) years for three (3) members; and effective October 1, 1986, the Board of County Commissioners shall appoint the tenth member to a two (2) year term and the eleventh member to a three (3) year term with appointments thereafter to be for a term of three (3) years for each of the eleven (11) members. Appointments to fill any vacancy on the Board shall be for the remainder of the unexpired term of office. Terms of office of members of the Board appointed by the Board of County Commissioners, which would normally expire on or between the dates of January 1 through June 30, or July 1 through December 31 of the termination year, shall be deemed ended and expired as of March 31 or September 30 thereof respectively; and the position thereon vacated may be refilled by the Board of County Commissioners. Prior to October 1, 1989, the Board of County Commissioners shall review the composition of the Public Library Advisory Board.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 63-27, § 4, 7-2-63; Ord. No. 63-29, § 1, 7-16-63; Ord. No. 64-39, § 5, 9-1-64; Ord. No. 71-78, § 1, 9-22-71; Ord. No. 73-20, § 1, 3-8-73; Ord. No. 77-81, § 1, 11-15-77; Ord. No. 86-65, § 1, 9-16-86; Ord. No. 86-84, § 1, 10-28-86)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-196. Removal of members</catch_line>
<text>
Any member of the Board who ceases to be a qualified elector of Miami-Dade County shall immediately forfeit his office. Should a vacancy result from such forfeiture, or should any member of this Board fail to attend three (3) consecutive meetings of the Board without due cause, the Chairman of the Board shall certify the same to the County Commission, who shall fill the vacancy created thereby by appointment. Any member of the Board may be removed from office without cause by two-thirds vote of the entire membership of the County Commission.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-197. Organization of Board; quorum; meetings; clerical personnel</catch_line>
<text>
The members of the Board, or a majority thereof, shall select a Chairman and such other officers as may be deemed necessary or desirable, who shall serve at the will of the Board. A majority vote of the entire membership of the Board shall be necessary to take any action. A majority of the members of the Board shall constitute a quorum necessary to hold a meeting or take any action. The Chairman may call meetings of the Board, and meetings may be called by written notice signed by four (4) members of the Board, and the Board at any meeting may fix and call a meeting for a future date. Minutes shall be kept of all meetings of the Board. All meetings shall be public. The County Manager shall provide adequate and competent clerical and administrative personnel as may be reasonably required by the Board for the proper performance of its duties and functions, subject to budget limitations as fixed by the County Commission.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-198. Compensation; expenses</catch_line>
<text>
Members of the Public Library Advisory Board shall serve without compensation, salary or remuneration of any nature, but the County Commission may provide in the annual County budget sufficient funds for the reasonable and necessary expenses incurred by the Board in performance of its duties and functions prescribed by the provisions of this article.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-199. Duties and functions</catch_line>
<text>
The Public Library Advisory Board shall have the following duties, functions and responsibilities:
<section prefix = "a">
To serve in an advisory capacity to the County Commission in respect to all matters pertaining to Public Library and other cultural facilities, and to make periodic reports and recommendations in respect to such matters.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
To make a continuing study of all existing Public Library facilities and services in this metropolitan area, and the future needs of this community in respect to Public Library facilities and services.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
To formulate plans and programs for the coordination of the activities of all governmental entities, and nongovernmental agencies, relating to Library facilities and services.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
To formulate comprehensive, feasible plans and programs for providing adequate Public Library facilities and services necessary to fulfill the present and future needs of this metropolitan area.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
To devise means and methods by which existing and future Library facilities and services may be improved and more fully utilized to provide better service and availability to the general public.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
To make a continuing study and periodic reports and recommendations for a sound, feasible program for financing the costs of improving existing Library facilities and services and providing additional Public Library facilities and services.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
To review all laws, regulations and requirements governing Public Libraries and make recommendations concerning appropriate actions that may be taken to achieve the objective of providing adequate Public Library facilities and services for this metropolitan area, and to devise programs by which financial assistance from other governmental entities may be utilized to the fullest extent.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
To perform and carry out such other duties and functions of an advisory nature as may be assigned to the Board by the County Commission.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-200. Limitation on powers of Board</catch_line>
<text>
The Public Library Advisory Board shall have no power or authority to commit the County Government to any policies or to incur any financial obligation or to create any liability on the part of the County. No actions or recommendations of this Board shall be binding upon the County until approved or adopted by the County Commission. This Board shall not infringe upon any of the powers granted by law to any other duly constituted Board relating to matters involving Public Library facilities and services.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-201—2-203. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (39) ---
Editor's note— This article is derived from Ord. No. 63-27, adopted on July 2, 1963. Section 10 of said ordinance declared it to be the intention of the County Commission that the provisions of the ordinance, including the recitations contained in the "whereas" clauses, become a part of this Code of Ordinances. The "whereas" clauses read as follows: (Back)
 "WHEREAS, it is recognized that the establishment, maintenance and administration of adequate Public Library facilities to which the general public has free access as places of resort to seek quiet study, educational pursuits and enjoyment constitute joint functions and responsibilities of the State, County and municipal government; and (Back)
 "WHEREAS, it is apparent that increased and expanded Public Library facilities and services, and the coordination of existing Public Library facilities and services, are urgently required in order to meet the needs of the ever increasing population of this metropolitan area. This may be accomplished only by appropriate planning based upon accurate factual data and information and sound financial feasibility; and (Back)
 "WHEREAS, the planning and accomplishment of a sound, feasible and adequate Public Library system for the use and benefit of all the residents and visitors of this metropolitan area constitutes a governmental function or service that is susceptible to, and may be most effectively performed, under a uniform plan and program applicable to and embracing this entire metropolitan area; and (Back)
 "WHEREAS, the general laws of the State of Florida grant to the Boards of County Commissioners of the several counties the permissive power to establish, operate and maintain free public libraries, and prescribe the methods and procedures by which such power shall be exercised. The general laws further authorize certain types of grants of financial assistance to counties meeting regulations established by the State Library Board. The general laws also grant to the governing bodies of municipalities the power and authority to establish, maintain and operate public libraries in accordance with the prescribed statutory procedures. The Home Rule Charter of Government for Miami-Dade County, Florida, empowers the Board of County Commissioners to provide libraries and other cultural facilities and programs, to create by ordinance such Boards as may be deemed necessary, and to carry on a central metropolitan government and perform such acts as may be required in the common interest of the people; and (Back)
 "WHEREAS, the coordination and reconciliation of the applicable and controlling requirements of law, the coordinate and feasible utilization of existing facilities and services, and the appropriate planning for additional facilities and services, relating to public libraries, may be best accomplished through the medium of an advisory Board composed of outstanding qualified citizens, (Back)
 "NOW, THEREFORE BE IT ORDAINED BY THE BOARD OF COUNTY COMMISSIONERS OF Miami-Dade County, FLORIDA:" (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
