<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XII._Miami-Dade_POLICE_DEPARTMEN</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-91. Established; Director as head, appointment, term; organization and operating procedures; appointment, compensation of personnel; psychological testing of personnel</catch_line>
<text>
Sec. 2-91. Established; Director as head, appointment, term; organization and operating procedures; appointment, compensation of personnel; psychological testing of personnel.
<section prefix = "a">
A Miami-Dade Police Department is hereby established.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The head of this Department shall be the Miami-Dade Police Director who shall also be known by the title of Metropolitan Sheriff. The Director shall be appointed by and serve at the will of the Manager.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The organization and operating procedures of the Department shall be described in administrative orders and regulations of the Manager.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The Manager shall appoint such employees and other personnel as may be necessary to operate the Department. The salaries and compensation of all personnel, except employees within the classified service, shall be fixed by the County Commission upon recommendation of the Manager.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The County Manager, or his designee, shall within a reasonable time adopt rules or regulations for the formulation and implementation of valid and relevant psychological testing to be required of all applicants for employment as Police Officers in the Miami-Dade Police Department, and said rules or regulations shall further authorize such psychological testing of officers presently employed as shall be considered by the Manager upon the advice of the Miami-Dade Police Department and Director to be conducive to effective law enforcement and sound community relations.
</section>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 80-5, § 1, adopted Jan. 22, 1980, did not expressly amend this Code. For purposes of classification, and at his discretion, the editor has added subsection designations (a)—(d) to § 2-91 as derived from Ord. No. 58-15 and added § 1 of Ord. No. 80-5 as § 2-91(e).
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-92. Powers and duties generally</catch_line>
<text>
The Miami-Dade Police Department shall:
<section prefix = "a">
Preserve the public peace, prevent crime, detect and arrest offenders, protect the rights of persons and property, and regulate and control traffic in accordance with the laws of this State and the ordinances of this County.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Have all powers and perform all duties, powers and functions formerly exercised by the Sheriff of this County.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Reserved.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Recruit and provide training for Department personnel.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Provide central records, investigation, and communications of police protection and require each municipality to furnish the department with all police records prescribed by the Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
[Reserved].
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Provide police protection in the unincorporated areas of the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Perform such additional duties as may be prescribed by ordinance or by administrative orders and regulations of the Manager.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Charge and collect a fee for administrative services rendered for or on behalf of any person by furnishing copies of background investigations, photographs taken or processed by it, accident reports, and any other reports authorized to be furnished to members of the public; provided that a schedule of the type and amount of fees to be charged will be established in accordance with an administrative order governing the setting of such fees pursuant to Section 4.02 of the Miami-Dade County Charter. Any and all fees charged and collected by the Miami-Dade Police Department prior to enactment of this subsection [May 21, 1975], for the furnishing of those items enumerated in this subsection are hereby ratified, approved and declared to have been legal, proper and authorized.

</section>
</text>
The Miami-Dade Police Department shall:
<section prefix = "a">
Preserve the public peace, prevent crime, detect and arrest offenders, protect the rights of persons and property, and regulate and control traffic in accordance with the laws of this State and the ordinances of this County.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Have all powers and perform all duties, powers and functions formerly exercised by the Sheriff of this County.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Reserved.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Recruit and provide training for Department personnel.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Provide central records, investigation, and communications of police protection and require each municipality to furnish the department with all police records prescribed by the Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
[Reserved].
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Provide police protection in the unincorporated areas of the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Perform such additional duties as may be prescribed by ordinance or by administrative orders and regulations of the Manager.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Charge and collect a fee for administrative services rendered for or on behalf of any person by furnishing copies of background investigations, photographs taken or processed by it, accident reports, and any other reports authorized to be furnished to members of the public; provided that a schedule of the type and amount of fees to be charged will be established in accordance with an administrative order governing the setting of such fees pursuant to Section 4.02 of the Miami-Dade County Charter. Any and all fees charged and collected by the Miami-Dade Police Department prior to enactment of this subsection [May 21, 1975], for the furnishing of those items enumerated in this subsection are hereby ratified, approved and declared to have been legal, proper and authorized.

Annotation—AO's 4-32, 4-33.
</section>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-92.1. Docketing and service of process in civil cases, surfees</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
The Miami-Dade Police Department in civil cases shall charge fixed surfees for docketing and service of process as prescribed by State statute, as may be amended from time to time.
<section prefix = "1">
Evictions: As permitted by State statute 83.62, in addition to prescribed State fee, a fee shall be established by the Miami-Dade Police Department and charged for service of each writ of possession for the first one-half hour during which a police officer must remain at the location of the eviction while the personal property of the tenant is removed. A charge for additional time of the police officer shall also be established by the Miami-Dade Police Department, and charged when the officer remains beyond the one-half hour period.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
All surfees established by this section shall be nonrefundable and shall be deposited monthly into the fine and forfeiture fund of the County, in accordance with Section 30.231(4) and (5), Florida Statutes.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 77-82, §§ 1, 2, 11-15-77; Ord. No. 81-87, § 1, 7-21-81; Ord. No. 90-41, § 1, 5-1-90; Ord. No. 99-113, § 1, 9-9-99)</history>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 77-82, §§ 1, 2, adopted Nov. 15, 1977, did not expressly amend the Code; hence, inclusion herein as § 2-92.1 is at the discretion of the editor.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-92.2. Availability of records to public</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Files of internal investigations; procedures generally. The Miami-Dade Police Department shall designate a place where records or files of investigations conducted by the internal review section of the Miami-Dade Police Department shall be kept and maintained; the location thereof shall be disseminated to the public, and the public shall have free access thereto during normal business hours. Sufficient qualified personnel shall be assigned to such location to assist in locating and producing any such record or file for inspection or copying by any person making request therefor. Photographic copies of any such file or record, or portion thereof, shall be provided to any person upon request and upon payment by such person of the actual cost of duplication. All other expenses shall be borne by the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Officer profiles. The Miami-Dade Police Department shall compile a profile on each officer in alphabetical order by name. Such profile shall indicate each and every commendation received by each officer and shall identify every complaint against the officer where the identity of the complainant is known. Such complaints shall be identified by the name of the complainant, nature of the complaint and case file number and indicate the disposition. This profile shall be available to the public pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Records not available. All public records exempt from statutory disclosure requirements by Florida Statutes, subsections 119.07(3), (4), and (5), as defined by Florida Statutes, subsections 119.011(3) and (4), shall be exempt from provisions of subsection (a) of this section.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 80-4, § 3, 1-22-80; Ord. No. 81-87, § 1, 7-21-81)</history>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 80-4, §§ 1—3, adopted Jan. 22, 1980, did not expressly amend this Code; hence, codification as § 2-92.2 is at the discretion of the editor.

State law reference— Public records, F.S. Ch. 119.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-93. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Section 2-93 has been deleted as obsolete. Such section abolished the Office of County Sheriff and transferred the powers, duties, etc., of same to the Miami-Dade Police Department. Such section was derived from Ord. No. 58-15, § 6.03, adopted May 6, 1958 and Ord. No. 81-87, adopted July 21, 1981.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-94. Consolidation of County departments</catch_line>
<text>
The Miami-Dade Police Department shall be vested with sole and exclusive responsibility for performance of the powers, duties and functions hereinabove enumerated except as otherwise provided by Section 2-95 of the Code of Miami-Dade County. All such powers, duties and functions heretofore performed by other County departments, agencies and officials are hereby transferred to the Miami-Dade Police Department, and all County departments and agencies whose activities are confined solely to performance of the powers, duties and functions hereby vested exclusively in the Miami-Dade Police Department are hereby abolished and all their equipment transferred to this Department.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-94.1. Law Enforcement Services Regarding Investigations of Criminal Violations of Law by the County Mayor and County Commissioner and Investigations of Public Corruption By Non-elected County Officials and Employees</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Upon the execution of a memorandum of understanding (MOU) with the Miami-Dade State Attorney's Office, the Florida Department of Law Enforcement ("FDLE") or other appropriate law enforcement agency, the Miami-Dade Police Department ("MDPD") shall make its personnel and financial resources available to the Miami-Dade State Attorney's Office, the FDLE or other appropriate law enforcement agency to conduct investigations of the violation of criminal law by the County Mayor and/or County Commissioners subject to the limitations imposed herein;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
"violation of criminal law" as used herein shall be defined as the violation of any of the laws of the United States, the State of Florida or the Ordinances of Miami-Dade County that provide for a criminal penalty including but not limited to violations of law that constitute public corruption as defined herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
"Public corruption" as used herein shall be defined to include:
<section prefix = "1">
a "breach of the public trust" as defined in §112.312(3), Florida Statutes;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
all of the crimes within the definition of "specified offense" set forth in §112.3173, Florida Statutes; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
a violation of the Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance codified at Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The term "County Mayor" and "County Commissioners" as used herein shall be defined in the same manner as the term "commissioners" is defined in Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The term "employees" and "officials" as used herein shall be defined to include:
<section prefix = "1">
the following persons as defined in Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County:
<section prefix = "a">
"autonomous personnel",
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
"quasi-judicial personnel",
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
"advisory personnel",
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
"departmental personnel", and
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
"employees"; and
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
the President, Board of Trustees and employees of the Public Health Trust of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The MDPD Director is hereby authorized and directed to negotiate memoranda of understanding (MOU) with the Miami-Dade State Attorney's Office, the FDLE or other appropriate law enforcement agency that provides for such agency other than MDPD to: (1) serve as the lead investigative law enforcement agency to investigate the violation of criminal law by the County Mayor or Commissioners, and (2) to participate in MDPD public corruption investigations of County employees and officials. Upon completion of such negotiation, the MDPD Director shall present such MOU to the Board of County Commissioners for approval by the Board of County Commissioners and, if approved, for execution by the Mayor.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Upon the execution of an MOU with the Miami-Dade State Attorney's Office, the FDLE or other appropriate law enforcement agency as authorized herein, if MDPD is requested to investigate a violation of criminal law involving the County Mayor or Commissioners or otherwise becomes aware of a possible violation of criminal law involving the County Mayor or Commissioners, MDPD shall refer such matter to the Miami-Dade State Attorney's Office, the FDLE or other appropriate law enforcement agency pursuant to such MOU. In such event, MDPD shall make its personnel and financial resources available to the Miami-Dade State Attorney's Office, the FDLE or other appropriate law enforcement agency pursuant to such MOU, but MDPD shall not be the lead investigative agency responsible for the manner in which such investigation is conducted and concluded.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Upon the execution of an MOU with the Miami-Dade State Attorney's Office, the FDLE or other appropriate law enforcement agency as authorized herein, if MDPD is requested to investigate otherwise becomes aware of a possible public corruption matter involving County officials or employees, MDPD shall be required to include the Miami-Dade State Attorney's Office, the FDLE or other appropriate law enforcement agency as a participant in such investigation pursuant to such MOU.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
The requirements of this section shall only apply to investigations commenced after the effective date of this section.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 07-48, § 2, 3-8-07)</history>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 07-48, § 1, adopted March 8, 2007, amended the Code with the addition of a new § 2-95. In order to avoid duplication of section numbers, the provisions of said ordinance have been included herein as § 2-94.1 at the discretion of the editor.

</EditorsNote>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (23) ---
Editor's note— Section 1 of Ord. No. 81-87, adopted July 21, 1981, changed the name of the public safety department to the Miami-Dade Police Department. (Back)
Annotations—AO's 7-9, 9-1 (Back)
Cross reference— Police relief and pension fund, § 23-11 et seq. (Back)
State Law reference— Law enforcement training, F.S. § 943.085 et seq. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
