<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="2">ARTICLE_LXXXIV._MIAMI-DADE_COUNTY_CITIZE</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1161. Creation of Miami-Dade County Citizens' Transportation Oversight Committee</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created an advisory and oversight committee to be known as the Miami-Dade County Citizens' Transportation Oversight Committee ("Oversight Committee").
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1162. Composition and appointment</catch_line>
<text>
The Oversight Committee shall consist of sixteen (16) members. Thirteen (13) members shall be selected by the Board of County Commissioners from a slate of candidates submitted by a nominating committee as provided in Section 2-1162(a). The additional three (3) members shall be appointed as provided in Section 2-1162(b).
<section prefix = "a">
Nominating Committee. Thirteen (13) members of the Oversight Committee shall be appointed in the manner set forth in this subsection. A nominating committee ("Nominating Committee") comprised of at least twenty-two (22) members shall be appointed as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
The Mayor of Miami-Dade County shall appoint one (1) member of the Nominating Committee;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Chief Judge of the Eleventh Judicial Circuit shall serve as a member of the Nominating Committee;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Mayor of each municipality with a population of 50,000 or more residents shall serve as a member of the Nominating Committee;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The Executive Director of the Miami-Dade League of Cities shall serve as a member of the Nominating Committee;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The Greater Miami Chamber of Commerce ("Greater Miami Chamber") shall appoint one (1) member of the Nominating Committee who shall be the Chairperson of the Greater Miami Chamber or one (1) of its members;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
The Camara de Comercio Latina de los Estados Unidos ("CAMACOL") shall appoint one (1) member of the Nominating Committee who shall be the President of CAMACOL or one (1) of its members;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
The North Dade Regional Chamber of Commerce ("North Dade Chamber") shall appoint one (1) member of the Nominating Committee who shall be the Chairperson of the North Dade Chamber or one (1) of its members;
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
The Chamber South shall appoint one (1) member of the Nominating Committee who shall be the Chairperson of Chamber South or one (1) of its members;
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
The Miami-Dade Chamber of Commerce shall appoint one (1) member of the Nominating Committee who shall be the President of the Miami-Dade Chamber of Commerce or one (1) of its members;
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
The President of Florida International University or his or her designee shall serve as a member of the Nominating Committee;
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
The President of Miami-Dade Community College or his or her designee shall serve as a member of the Nominating Committee;
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
The President of the Trust for Public Land or his or her designee shall serve as a member of the Nominating Committee;
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
The Chairperson of the United Way or his or her designee shall serve as a member of the Nominating Committee;
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
The Chairperson of the Champion Our Children Initiative or his or her designee shall serve as a member of the Nominating Committee;
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
The Chairperson of the Cultural Affairs Council or his or her designee shall serve as a member of the Nominating Committee;
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
The Chairperson of the Greater Miami Visitors and Convention Bureau or his or her designee shall serve as a member of the Nominating Committee;
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
The Chairperson of the Urban Economic Revitalization Task Force or his or her designee shall serve as a member of the Nominating Committee;
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
The Chairperson of the Citizen's Transportation Advisory Committee shall serve as a member of the Nominating Committee; and
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
The Hialeah Chamber of Commerce and Industries ("Hialeah Chamber") or the Hialeah-Miami Springs Northwest Dade Area Chamber of Commerce ("Hialeah-Miami Springs Chamber") shall appoint one (1) member of the Nominating Committee. The Board of County Commissioners shall by resolution determine whether the Hialeah Chamber or the Hialeah-Miami Springs Chamber shall appoint one (1) member of the Nominating Committee.
The Nominating Committee shall submit a slate of four (4) candidates from each Commission District to the Board of County Commissioners for selection. The Board must select from the slate submitted by the Nominating Committee; however, the Board may request additional nominations.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Additional members. In addition to the thirteen (13) members of the Oversight Committee appointed pursuant to Subsection (a), the following persons shall serve on the Oversight Committee:
<section prefix = "1">
The Chairperson of the Miami-Dade County Commission on Ethics and Public Trust shall serve as a member of the Oversight Committee;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Chairperson of the Alliance for Ethical Government shall serve as a member of the Oversight Committee; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
One (1) member of the Efficiency and Competition Commission shall serve as a member of the Oversight Committee. Said member shall be appointed by the Mayor of Miami-Dade County and shall not be an elected official.

Members shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties. The provisions of Section 2-11.38 which provide that no member of a county board shall become a candidate for elective political office during his or her term shall not apply to members of the Nominating Committee appointed pursuant to Section 2-1162(a)(3).
</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1163. Additional qualifications</catch_line>
<text>
Each member of the Oversight Committee shall be a United States citizen, resident of Miami-Dade County and shall be of outstanding reputation for integrity, responsibility and commitment to serving the community. The members of the Oversight Committee shall have no financial interest in the implementation of the transportation and nontransportation components of the Mayor's Transportation Plan, as stated in the ballot question presented to the voters on July 29, 1999, Ordinance No. 99-68 and any amendments thereto, and the use of funds generated by the 1999 Transit Surtax, MDTA general fund subsidy moneys, MDTA revenue and the three (3) cents local option gas tax dedicated for transit. The members of the Oversight Committee should be representative of the community-at-large and should reflect the racial, gender and ethnic make-up of the community.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1164. Applicability of Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance</catch_line>
<text>
The Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance, Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall be applicable to members of the Oversight Committee.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1165. Term of service</catch_line>
<text>
At the first meeting of the Oversight Committee, a blind lottery shall be held to determine the initial staggered terms of the sixteen (16) members. These initial terms shall be: five (5) members shall serve for a period of one (1) year; five (5) members shall serve for a period of two (2) years; and six (6) members shall serve for a period of three (3) years. Upon expiration of each initial term, all appointments shall serve a two-year term. Appointments to fill any vacancy on the Oversight Committee shall be for the remainder of the unexpired term of office.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1166. Organization of the Oversight Committee</catch_line>
<text>
The Mayor of Miami-Dade County shall appoint the Chairperson of the Oversight Committee who shall be one (1) of the members appointed pursuant to Section 2-1162. The Oversight Committee shall hold regular meetings. All meetings of the Oversight Committee shall be public and written minutes of the proceedings thereof shall be maintained by the Oversight Committee. All actions taken at the meetings of the Oversight Committee shall be promptly and properly recorded. Copies of all minutes and resolutions of the Oversight Committee shall be forwarded to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners no later than thirty (30) days subsequent to any meeting of the Oversight Committee.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1167. Powers, duties and jurisdiction</catch_line>
<text>
The Oversight Committee shall have the following duties, functions, powers, responsibilities and jurisdiction:
<section prefix = "a">
To audit, investigate, monitor, oversee, inspect and review the implementation of the transportation and nontransportation components of the Mayor's Transportation Plan, as stated in the ballot question presented to the voters on July 29, 1999, Ordinance No. 99-68 and any amendments thereto, and the use of funds generated by the 1999 Transit Surtax, MDTA general fund subsidy moneys, MDTA revenue and the three (3) cents local option gas tax dedicated for transit;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
To require reports from the Mayor, County Commission, Manager, County agencies and instrumentalities regarding the implementation of the transportation and nontransportation components of the Mayor's Transportation Plan, as stated in the ballot question presented to the voters on July 29, 1999, Ordinance No. 99-68 and any amendments thereto, and the use of funds generated by the 1999 Transit Surtax, MDTA general fund subsidy moneys, MDTA revenue and the three (3) cents local option gas tax dedicated for transit;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
To file a report, including any recommendations, with the Mayor and the County Commission on a quarterly basis regarding the implementation of the transportation and nontransportation components of the Mayor's Transportation Plan, as stated in the ballot question presented to the voters on July 29, 1999, Ordinance No. 99-68 and any amendments thereto, and the use of funds generated by the 1999 Transit Surtax, MDTA general fund subsidy moneys, MDTA revenue and the three (3) cents local option gas tax dedicated for transit; and
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
To review any proposed amendments to Ordinance No. 99-68 prior to adoption by the County Commission, and to file a report with the Mayor and the County Commission regarding such proposed amendments.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1168. Staff support</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager shall provide appropriate staff support to the Oversight Committee.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1169. Inspector General</catch_line>
<text>
The Inspector General shall be charged with the responsibility of overseeing the activities of the Oversight Committee. In order to perform his or her oversight function, the Inspector General shall, pursuant to Section 2-1076 of the Code, be empowered to, among other things, require reports from the Oversight Committee, perform audits, subpoena witnesses, administer oaths and require the production of records. The Inspector General or his or her designee shall attend all meetings of the Oversight Committee. The Office of the Inspector General shall, on at least an annual basis and subject to budgetary limitations, audit the implementation of the transportation and nontransportation components of the Mayor's Transportation Plan, as stated in the ballot question presented to the voters on July 29, 1999, Ordinance No. 99-68 and any amendments thereto, and the use of funds generated by the 1999 Transit Surtax, MDTA general fund subsidy moneys, MDTA revenue and the three (3) cents local option gas tax dedicated for transit. The Office of the Inspector General shall provide the Oversight Committee with a copy of each audit report.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-1170—2-1190. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (96) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 99-87, § 1, adopted July 27, 1999, added a new article LXXX, pertaining to the Miami-Dade County Citizens' Transportation Oversight Committee. However, in order to avoid duplication of articles, said article has been redesignated as article LXXXIV at the discretion of the editor. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
