<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_IV._COMMUNITY_ANTENNA_TELEVISION</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-125. Intent and application</catch_line>
<text>
It is the intent of this article to provide for the control of community antenna television service in all unincorporated and incorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, to provide for its safe and orderly installation, to establish fees and service charges for its use, and to establish a system of licensing, inspection and charges by Miami-Dade County. The application of this section is also intended to encompass those Licensees who are required, pursuant to Section 8A-127, to obtain a permit.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-126. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
CATV (community antenna television system) shall mean any facility that, in whole or in part, receives directly, or indirectly over the air, and amplifies or otherwise modifies the signals transmitting programs broadcast by one (1) or more television or radio stations and distributes such signals by wire or cable to subscribing members of the public who pay for such service, but such terms shall not include:
<section prefix = "1">
Any such facility that serves fewer than fifty (50) subscribers, or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Any such facility that serves only the residents of one (1) or more apartment dwellings under common ownership, control, or management, and commercial establishments located on the premises of such an apartment house.
CATV shall be deemed to include all transmission and distribution facilities located in, under, over, along, across or upon any highway, street, alley, right-of-way, easement or any public property.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
County shall mean Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Commission shall mean the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, or its representative.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
License shall mean the License granted to the applicant for permission to install and operate CATV systems in Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Distribution System shall include all means of transmission of all signals.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Lead-in shall be the individual lead wire or cable from the distribution system to each individual household or connection.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Licensee shall be the corporation, partnership, individual, or other entity granted a License for CATV by the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
County Manager shall mean the Miami-Dade County Manager, as appointed by the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Gross Receipts shall mean all revenue derived directly or indirectly by the Licensee, its affiliates, subsidiaries, parents and any person in which the Licensee has a financial interest, from or in connection with the furnishing of regular subscriber services, the carriage of broadcast signals and required nonbroadcast services. Gross Receipts may include all revenues from services upon which the FCC's regulations allow application of percentage franchise fees.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Federal Communications Commission (FCC) shall mean that agency as presently constituted by the United States Congress, or any successor agency.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Priority Service Area shall mean that area of the County assigned by the Commission wherein the Licensee is authorized to provide CATV service. The Priority Service Area need not include all licensed areas.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 74-88, §§ 2, 4, 10-15-74; Ord. No. 82-66, § 1, 7-20-82)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-127. License required</catch_line>
<text>
A License may be issued to a Licensee, its successors and assigns, granting the nonexclusive right, privilege and permit for a period of fifteen (15) years, to install, maintain and operate transmission and distribution facilities and additions thereto in, under, over, along, across and upon the present and future highways, streets, alleys, rights-of-way, easements and public property in the unincorporated and incorporated areas of Miami-Dade County for the purpose of transmission and distribution by cable of audio and video signals by means of electrical impulses for sale to inhabitants of said County. The Licensee may, at the Commissioner's option and in its discretion and after a full public hearing affording due process, be renewed for additional periods of at least ten (10) years' duration. No person, corporation or other entity shall install or operate CATV facilities within any unincorporated or incorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, without first having received a License from Miami-Dade County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-128. Application procedure; information required</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
License applications shall contain or be accompanied by the following information:
<section prefix = "1">
Name, address and telephone number of applicant.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Names of all officers and directors of corporate applicant.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Copy of contract to be utilized for individual customer service which shall include all fees, charges, rentals, etc., during the first five (5) years of operation.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Estimated date installation of main distribution system will be commenced.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Locations of antennae and transmitter.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Certificates of liability insurance coverage in the minimum amounts specified by this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Performance bond as required by Section 8A-137(d) of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Information on the applicant's past experience in the cable television industry.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Audited financial statements of the applicant for the past two (2) years.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Financial forecasts of the proposed system.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Any other information deemed necessary by the County Manager in order to evaluate the application.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Except for applications specified in subparagraph (c) below, License applications may only be filed during the months of January and July of each year.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Applications from applicants which have been issued a municipal License, franchise or permit may be filed and processed at any time provided that:
<section prefix = "1">
The application does not seek to provide service in areas located in the unincorporated areas of the County; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The municipal License was granted after an investigation and public hearing process comparable to that process provided for in this article.
The County Manager may, after verifying that an application meets the requirements of this paragraph, waive the notice and comment requirements specified in subparagraph (e) below.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Each application shall be accompanied by a nonrefundable fee of one thousand dollars ($1,000.00) to cover the cost of initial processing.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The County Manager or his designee shall investigate all applications to ensure that all information provided is correct, that the applicant has the financial, technical and managerial background and resources to provide the proposed services. Upon receipt of any application, the Manager shall publish notice thereof, which notice shall request written comments regarding the application. All such written comments shall be submitted at least sixty (60) days before the public hearing required by subparagraph (f) below.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The County Manager or his designee shall prepare a report to the Commission regarding the application, which report shall consider and respond to any comments received and shall contain the County Manager's recommendations concerning the application. The Manager shall schedule a public hearing before the Commission to consider the application and the Manager's report. Notification of any License hearing must be published one (1) time each for two (2) successive weeks in a newspaper of general Miami-Dade County circulation. The County Commission then will approve, disapprove or take any other action it finds to be in the public interest. The Commission may, by resolution, assign a priority service area to the Licensee.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Upon the issuance of a nonexclusive License by the County Commission the Licensee shall pay all reasonable costs, fees and other obligations incurred by the County and which the County may legally be required to pay in the examining, preparing, advertising and awarding of the License. These costs, fees and other obligations shall include, but shall not be limited to, reasonable consulting fees, printing, advertising and other costs as deemed appropriate by the County Manager. With the exception of stated consulting fees and expenses which are not excessive and can be shown as direct costs to the County, amounts paid to the County by the Licensee in reimbursement of these expenses shall be amortized over the term of the License and shall be applied as a credit against the annual percentage fee specified in Section 8A-129 for that year.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 74-88, §§ 2, 6, 10-15-74; Ord. No. 77-91, § 2, 12-20-77; Ord. No. 82-66, § 1, 7-20-82)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-128.1. Regulation</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager is hereby vested with the power, authority and jurisdiction to regulate and control cable antenna television systems, as defined herein, and shall exercise the powers and perform the duties and functions prescribed by this chapter under the direct jurisdiction and legislative control of the Board of County Commissioners.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-128.2. Evaluation</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager may designate qualified individuals to assist in the evaluation of franchise applicants and Licensee performance. No member designated by the County Manager shall be employed by or connected with any privately owned CATV system in Miami-Dade County or have any special financial interest, directly or indirectly, in any such CATV system operating in Miami-Dade County. This does not preclude members from the private and public broadcasting industry from being selected.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-128.3. Organization</catch_line>
<text>
The County Public Works Department or other agency designated by the County Manager, shall provide staff support to the County Manager for proper regulation of Licensee performance in Miami-Dade County, insuring quality service for all subscribers. The County Attorney shall serve as legal counsel to the County Manager in all matters relating to CATV.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-128.4. Rules and regulations</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager shall make and prescribe such rules and regulations reasonably necessary and appropriate for the proper administration and enforcement of the provisions of this article. Such rules and regulations shall establish a procedure for the Manager's approval of the installation of CATV distribution systems, which procedure shall provide for the orderly, logical progressive expansion or extension of CATV systems throughout the entire County. Such rules and regulations shall conform to the provisions of this article and shall not conflict with the Constitution and General Laws of the State of Florida, and the Constitution and laws of the United States, and the rules and regulations of any agency, State or federal, having jurisdiction, including, but not limited to, the Federal Communications Commission. Rules and regulations promulgated by the County Manager shall insure fair and equitable treatment for all municipalities affected by cable service, particularly [those rules] concerning utilization of local government use channels. No such rules and regulations shall become effective until a public hearing has been held upon the proposed rules and regulations, and any amendments or modifications thereto, and the same have been approved by resolution by the County Commission and filed with the Clerk of the Commission. Upon approval by the Commission, such rules and regulations shall prescribe forms for use by Licensees in compliance with the provisions of this chapter. Any member of the County Manager's staff, so designated by the County Manager, may administer oaths, certify to official acts, issue subpoenas, and compel the attendance of witnesses and the production of papers, account books, contracts, documents and other records, data or information, when necessary, convenient, or appropriate in the discharge of the duties of the Office. The County Manager, or duly authorized representatives of the County Manager, may during all reasonable hours enter upon any premises or property owned, operated or occupied by any Licensee as defined herein, and may set upon and use thereon all necessary apparatus and appliances for the purpose of making investigations, inspections, examinations and tests, and of exercising any of the powers conferred upon the County Manager by this article; provided, however, that such Licensee shall have the right to be notified of and be represented at the making of such investigations, inspections, examinations or tests. Should the State of Florida or the Federal Communications Commission require the Licensee to deliver any signals in addition to those required by this article, or perform or refrain from performing any act the performance or nonperformance of which is inconsistent with any of the provisions of this article or the License, the County Manager shall institute immediate action, which shall not be more than thirty (30) days in time, to recommend to the Commission appropriate action concerning the article or License. Licensee shall be subject to and bound by the FCC modification of the franchise fee limitation specified in Section 76.31 of the Federal Communications Commission Rules or any successor rule thereto.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-128.5. Jurisdiction and powers</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager shall exercise jurisdiction and have the power and authority to regulate and supervise each License as defined herein in respect to service and Service Areas within Miami-Dade County, in accordance with the standards set by the provisions of this article. This jurisdiction shall be exclusive and superior to that of all other boards, agencies, commissions, political subdivisions, and municipalities in Miami-Dade County, Florida, and in case of conflict all lawful acts, orders, rules and regulations of the County Manager shall in each instance prevail, subject to the Constitution and General Laws of the State of Florida. In the exercise of such jurisdiction, the County Manager shall be vested with the power, and it shall be the County Manager's duty, to prescribe classifications, standards of quality and measurement and redundancy factors, and service rules and regulations to be observed and complied with by each Licensee embraced within the terms of this article, with the exception of the public access channels, to prescribe uniform systems and classifications of accounts for each CATV Licensee, as defined herein, which, among other things, shall set up adequate, fair and reasonable depreciation rates and schedules; to require each Licensee to furnish and file periodic reports and other reasonable information and data for the proper administration and enforcement of the provisions of this article; to require appropriate administrative personnel or departments of the County government to perform the work of compiling factual data and information necessary or reasonably required by the County Manager for the proper performance of the duties and functions imposed upon it by the provisions of this article; and to take such actions necessary for the protection and preservation of the public safety and welfare in respect to the transmission of CATV systems furnished within Miami-Dade County, Florida, in accordance with the terms and provisions of this article. The County Manager shall further insure that the Licensee serve the best interest of the total community in Miami-Dade County, Florida, and provide full television service to the extent permitted by the FCC.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-128.6. Review of the County Manager's decisions</catch_line>
<text>
All decisions of the County Manager shall be subject to review by the Miami-Dade County Commission. Appeals from the Commission's decisions shall be by compliance with the appropriate Florida Appellate Rules. Service on the County Manager may be made by serving the County Manager or other party designated by him to accept service and serving a copy of said service with the County Attorney.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-129. License fee and public property charge</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Each Licensee shall pay to Miami-Dade County a quarterly License fee based upon the Licensee's gross receipts (as defined in Section 8A-126 of this article) during the preceding quarter in the following amounts:
<section prefix = "i">
Four (4) percent of gross revenues derived from the unincorporated areas of the County; and
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
One (1) percent of gross revenues derived from the incorporated areas in the County.
The Licensee shall be allowed a credit for any payments to the County in reimbursement of expenses as provided in Section 8A-128(g) of this article.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Reserved.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
In the event the total of the payments due from a Licensee to the County pursuant to Section 8A-129(a)(ii) above and the payments due a municipality pursuant to a municipal License or franchise exceeds five (5) percent of the Licensee's Gross Receipts, then the municipal License or franchise shall be superseded to the extent necessary to reduce the total payment to five (5) percent of the Licensee's Gross Receipts, within the one (1) percent required by Section 8A-129(a)(ii) being paid to the County and the balance being paid to the municipality.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
For purposes of this Section 8A-129 "franchise fees" means any tax, fee or assessment of any kind imposed by a municipality on a Licensee solely because of its status as a CATV Licensee and does not include nonmonetary requirements such as, by way of example, services, facilities, or equipment, imposed by the municipal License or franchise; any taxes, fees, or assessments of general applicability; and any payments or capital costs for municipal public, educational, or governmental access facilities.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Nothing herein shall be construed, directly or indirectly, to authorize or direct any changes in existing municipal franchises or Licenses which would require the payment of additional franchise fees to municipalities.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The four (4) percent License fee specified in Section 8A-129(a)(i) above shall remain in effect with respect to each existing County License for the remainder of the particular License term. The County License fee in the unincorporated area of the County for all Licenses issued after December 1, 1985, and all renewals of existing Licenses shall be the maximum fee allowed by law.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
All municipal ordinances, franchises and Licenses in conflict with this Section 8A-129 are hereby repealed to the extent of such conflict.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 74-88, §§ 2, 13, 10-15-74; Ord. No. 85-68, § 1, 9-18-85)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-130. Service charges</catch_line>
<text>
The rates charged by the Licensee shall be filed annually with the County Manager. No increase in established rates by the Licensee shall become effective until at least thirty (30) days' written notice is given to the Miami-Dade County Manager and to all customers served by the Licensee. The Licensee may at any time reduce the established rate.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-131. Number of channels, channel reservation</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Licensee shall provide minimum requirements in accordance with Section 76.252 of the Federal Communications Commission Rules.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Licensee shall agree to provide one (1) outlet CATV service without charge to each public school and recognized public institution of higher learning. This does not include commercial educational enterprises (computer schools, beauty schools, etc.).
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Licensee shall provide without charge, subject to the rules and regulations of the FCC, public emergency broadcast capabilities whereby, at the request of designated County official(s) service on all channels may be interrupted in order to make such public emergency broadcasts.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The Licensee shall provide, to the extent not inconsistent with FCC requirements, facilities capable of allowing each subscriber's standard television receiver to receive all standard broadcast television signals and all regular, required nonbroadcast services at no additional charge above the standard monthly rate.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The Licensee shall provide and maintain at least one (1) specially designated and noncommercial public access channel which shall be operated in accordance with prevailing federal regulations.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The Licensee shall provide and maintain, without charge, at least four (4) specially designated channels for use and programming by local tax supported educational authorities in the elementary, secondary and college level fields, as well as instructional television for adults. This does not include commercial educational enterprises (computer schools, beauty schools, etc.). Initially, only one (1) such channel shall be required from the Licensee, unless and until the County Manager determines the need for additional educational channels does exist and so notifies the Licensee. The Licensee, after such notification by the County Manager, shall provide such required channels forthwith.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
The Licensee shall provide and maintain, without charge, at least one (1) specially designated channel for local government use.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
At those daily time segments during which no signals are transmitted over public access channels or local government channels the Licensee may utilize such channels for any purpose consistent with the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
The Licensee may be required to interconnect its system with other cable systems operating in Miami-Dade County, to the extent that such interconnection is done at the request of and in conjunction with County and local school officials who seek such interconnection to foster educational goals.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
The Licensee shall provide two-way capability pursuant to the rules and regulations of the FCC and shall provide the following at no charge to Miami-Dade County:
<section prefix = "1">
Two-way capability to be made available without charge to the Miami-Dade County School Board to be used and programmed as desired by such School Board. The system shall provide interconnecting terminals to provide signal into the system at locations designated by the Board. Public tax-supported institutions of higher education also shall be provided with such two-way capability. The two-way capability referred to here applies to those channels required by Section 8A-131(f).
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Two-way channel of secure, wideband capability for local governmental use, as provided in Section 8A-131(g), at no additional charge, except for such special terminal devices (converters) as may be required. The Licensee shall provide the interconnecting terminals to provide entrance into the system, but the County shall provide the programming and programming equipment necessary to use the service of this channel.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
The Licensee shall provide that the signal of each television station carried shall be received at a designated place on the subscriber's channel selector as prescribed by the County Manager, which shall be uniform for every CATV system in the County insofar as technology permits.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 74-88, §§ 2, 15, 10-15-74; Ord. No. 77-91, § 6, 12-20-77)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-132. Prohibition of certain activities</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Licensee shall not engage in the following activities without prior approval of the Commission:
<section prefix = "1">
Sale or service of television sets.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Recommendations, by Licensee or his employees, of specific television appliance dealers or servicemen for sales or service.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
No property owner:
<section prefix = "1">
Shall charge any fees for the installation and service of a CATV system without prior approval of the County Manager.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Can deny any individual who occupies said property the right to have installed a system and have it serviced by a Licensee.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Charge any fee to a Licensee without prior approval of the County Manager.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 74-88, §§ 2, 16, 10-15-74)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-133. Minimum reception standards</catch_line>
<text>
The Licensee shall establish and guarantee minimum technical reception standards at the terminals of each television set services, said standards to be approved by the Commission. The following minimum technical reception standards are herewith established:
<section prefix = "a">
The Licensee shall maintain and operate the system in accordance with technical and measurement standards currently in effect under the rules and regulations of the Federal Communications Commission and the rules and regulations of the County Manager.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Licensee shall maintain and operate the system and render efficient service in accordance with the rules and regulations established or to be established by the Commission. Provided, however, the Licensee shall not exceed the radiation limits established in Section 76.605 of the Federal Communications Commission Rules adopted February 2, 1972, thereby operating the system so as to cause the least amount of interference with television reception, radio reception, telephone communications or other installations which are now or may hereafter be installed and in use in the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The television signals carried by the Licensee at no time shall be altered, interrupted, or blacked out in any way by the Licensee except as authorized by appropriate law or regulation and as may be necessary for technical adjustments or for the signal changes provided by such equipment as set-top converters.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The Licensee shall provide and make available accurately calibrated test equipment for the testing of all service and operational standards outlined herein and shall conduct tests as requested by the County under the supervision of a County representative in order to establish the level of performance of the system.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The Licensee shall provide a local service channel in addition to the six (6) channels required by Section 8A-131 herein. The local service channel shall provide local weather information and time with continuous FM background music. Further use for public service, civic organizations, and charitable causes is also hereby authorized.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The Licensee shall render efficient service, make repairs promptly, and interrupt service only for good cause and for the shortest time possible. Such interruption insofar as possible shall be preceded by notice and shall occur during periods of minimum use of the system.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
The Licensee shall maintain an office in the County which shall be open during all usual business hours, have a listed telephone, and be so operated that complaints and requests for repairs or adjustment may be received at any time. The Licensee shall respond to all service calls promptly and correct malfunctions as promptly as possible, but in any event within forty-eight (48) hours after notice thereof, except where the cause and extent of failure-causing damage is beyond the control of the Licensee.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-134. Installation of Distribution System</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The entire Distribution System of the Licensee, including poles, wires, cables, appurtenances and facilities, shall be located or relocated and so erected as not to interfere with travel over, in, on or under any public way and with reasonable ingress and egress to abutting property. All installations shall be in accordance with County standards and specifications and under permit issued by the Public Works Department. The construction, operation and maintenance of the system by the Licensee shall be in accord with good engineering practices and shall be in full compliance with the National Electric Safety Code and applicable laws, regulations and ordinances and as from time to time such are amended and revised.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
When any portion of any public way within the unincorporated or incorporated areas of the County is required to be excavated for the purpose of installing any portion of the Licensee's Distribution System or lead-in system, such excavation shall be at the expense of the Licensee and under inspection by the County appropriate governmental agency having jurisdiction. Repair and replacement of the property so excavated shall not be restricted to the actual trench, ditch or path excavated but shall include any and all portions of the public way disturbed, including pavement, curbing, sidewalks, drainage facilities, swales, parkways, and grassed areas, and shall conform to the standards prescribed by the manual of public works construction.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The conditions on street occupancy shall be as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
All transmissions and distribution structures, poles, fixtures, lines, and equipment erected by the Licensee within the County shall be so located as to cause minimum interference with the proper use of streets, alleys, and other public ways and places, and to cause minimum interference with the rights and reasonable convenience of property owners who may join any of the said streets, alleys or other public ways and places. All facilities shall be placed in such a manner as will not interfere with the usual travel on any public way.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
In case of disturbance of any street, sidewalk, alley, public way, or paved area, the Licensee shall, at its own cost and expense and in a manner approved by the appropriate governmental agency having jurisdiction replace and restore such street, sidewalk, alley, public way, or paved area in as good a condition as before the work involving such disturbance was done.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
If at any time during the period of the License any appropriate governmental agency having jurisdiction shall lawfully elect to alter or change the grade of any street, sidewalk, alley, or other public way, the Licensee, upon reasonable notice by such governmental agency, shall move, remove, or adjust its poles, wires, cables, underground conduits, manholes, and other fixtures at its own expense. However, if such activities as are delineated in this subsection are undertaken pursuant to any urban renewal projects, then the Licensee shall be treated in a manner similar to other utilities with regard to responsibility for payment for such removal, adjustments of poles, wires, etc., as may be required.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The Licensee shall, on the request of any person holding a building moving permit issued by any appropriate governmental agency having jurisdiction, temporarily raise or lower its wires to permit the moving of buildings. The expense of such temporary removal or raising or lowering of wires shall be paid by the person requesting the same, and the Licensee shall have the authority to require such payment in advance. The Licensee shall be given forty-eight (48) hours advance notice to arrange for such temporary wire changes.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The Licensee shall have the authority to trim trees upon, and overhanging, streets, alleys, sidewalks, and public ways and places of the County so as to prevent the branches of such trees from coming in contract with the wires and cables of the Licensee. Such trimming work shall be done by the Licensee at its own expense, and it shall be subject to the prior approval and inspection of the appropriate governmental agency having jurisdiction.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
In all sections of the County where the cables, wires or other like facilities of public utilities are placed underground, either by voluntary action on the part of any utility or by requirement of an existing or subsequent statute, ordinance or other enactment of law the Licensee shall place its cables, wires, or other like facilities under- ground, without cost to Miami-Dade County and without right to any reimbursement from Miami-Dade County for any costs incurred by the Licensee.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 74-88, §§ 2, 18, 10-15-74; Ord. No. 77-91, § 8, 12-20-77)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-135. Termination of service; refunds</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
If any subscriber of the Licensee of less than three (3) years terminates his subscription because of the Licensee's failure to render service of the type and quality provided for herein, or if the Licensee terminates service to a subscriber of less than three (3) years without good cause or because the Licensee ceases to operate the CATV business authorized hereunder for any reason except expiration of a License granted hereunder, the Licensee shall refund to such subscriber that portion of the initial tap-in and connection charges paid by the subscriber representing the unused remainder of the three-year period, determined by prorating to the date of notice of termination on a month-unit basis. Said refund shall be subject to approval by the County Manager.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Upon termination of service to any subscriber the Licensee shall promptly remove all its facilities and equipment from the premises of the subscriber upon request.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 74-88, §§ 2, 19, 10-15-74)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-136. Flow-through of refunds</catch_line>
<text>
If during the term of a License granted hereunder, the Licensee receives refunds of any payments, it shall without delay notify the County Manager, suggest a plan for flow-through of the refunds to its subscribers and retain such refunds pending order of the County Manager. After considering the plan submitted by the Licensee, the County Manager shall order the flow-through of the refunds to the Licensee's subscribers in a fair and equitable manner.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-137. Liability and indemnification</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Licensee shall pay all reasonable damages and penalties which the County or other governmental entity may legally be required to pay as a result of the License granted hereunder. These damages or penalties shall include, but shall not be limited to, damages arising out of copyright infringements and all other damages arising out of the installation, operation, or maintenance of the CATV system authorized herein, whether or not any act or omission complained of is authorized, allowed or prohibited by this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Licensee shall pay all reasonable expenses incurred by the County or other governmental entity in defending itself with regard to all damages and penalties mentioned in (a) above. The expenses shall include all incidental expenses, including attorney fees, and shall also include the reasonable value of any services rendered by the County Attorney or his assistants or by any employee of the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Licensee shall maintain and pay for liability insurance insuring the County and the Licensee with regard to all damages charged against the County and the Licensee resulting from the installation, development, maintenance or expansion of the CATV system authorized by this article in the following minimum amounts:
<section prefix = "1">
One hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00) for bodily injury or death to any one (1) person with an aggregate limit for any one (1) occurrence of five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000.00) for bodily injury or death.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
One hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00) property damage resulting from any one (1) accident.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Automobile liability insurance covering all owned, nonowned and hired vehicles used in connection with the Licensee's work in amounts as indicated in (1) and (2) above.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Contractual liability insurance covering all liability arising out of the terms of the License agreement.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Worker's compensation insurance as required by Chapter 440, Florida Statutes.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The Licensee shall maintain throughout the term of its License a faithful performance bond with a surety approved by the County, in the penal sum of one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00) upon the condition that the Licensee shall truly observe, fulfill and perform each term and condition of this article and its License and that in case of any breach of condition of the bond, the amount thereof shall be recoverable from the principal and surety thereof by the County for all damages resulting from the failure of the Licensee to well and faithfully observe and perform any provision of this article or the License issued hereunder.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
All insurance policies required above shall be issued in companies authorized to do business under the laws of the State of Florida and have been approved by the Risk Management Division of Miami-Dade County. The Licensee shall furnish certificates of insurance to the County prior to commencing any operations under the License agreement, which certificates shall clearly indicate that the Licensee has obtained insurance in the type, amount and classifications in strict compliance with this section. No material change or cancellation shall be permitted without thirty (30) days prior notice to the County.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 74-88, §§ 2, 21, 10-15-74; Ord. No. 77-91, § 9, 12-20-77)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-138. Time limitations</catch_line>
<text>
The Licensee shall, within sixty (60) days after the issuance of said License, apply to the Federal Communications Commission for any required permits or Licenses and shall begin service within one (1) year thereafter. Following the receipt of all required permits and Licenses and other necessary approvals, the Licensee shall accomplish significant construction of its cable television system and shall thereafter reasonably and equitably extend energized trunk cable to twenty (20) percent of the Licensee's County-franchised area each year, until service is available to substantially all residents of such area. Additional time to complete construction may be granted by the County Manager for good cause shown upon request of the Licensee. Licensee need not, but may, at its option, provide service to areas having fewer than sixty (60) homes in front of each linear mile of trunk line cable.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-139. Nonexclusive License</catch_line>
<text>
No License issued hereunder shall be construed or considered an exclusive License, nor shall the same vest any exclusive rights in any Licensee.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-140. Ownership, control, transfer of License</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Licensee shall at all times be the sole owner or lessee of all the facilities and property, real and personal, of the CATV business operating under License issued by Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Any change of thirty (30) percent or more of the ownership of the Licensee's business or transactions which may later affect the transference of the ownership shall be submitted to the County Manager for prior approval. By its acceptance of a License under this article the Licensee specifically acknowledges and agrees that any such change in ownership and control occurring without prior approval of the County Manager shall constitute a violation of the terms of the License, and render it subject to cancellation at the discretion of the County Manager.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Upon the foreclosure or other judicial sale of all or a substantial part of the system, or upon termination of any lease covering all or a substantial part of the system, the Licensee shall notify the Commission of such fact, and such notification shall be treated as a notification that a transfer of License has taken place, and the provisions of Section 8A-140(d) of this Code governing the consent of the County Manager to such transfer of License shall apply.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
No assignment of any License granted hereunder shall be valid and effective to transfer any interest or to bind the County without prior approval of the County Manager. In considering any request for transfer of License the County Manager may require such information, records, books of accounts, or other data as it may deem necessary and proper to evaluate the qualifications of the proposed assignee.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 74-88, §§ 2, 24, 10-15-74; Ord. No. 77-91, § 11, 12-20-77)</history>
Sec. 8A-141. Audit, books and records.
<section prefix = "a">
The Licensee hereunder shall maintain books or records of accounts, which shall be annually audited by a certified public accountant, and said audit shall be submitted to the County Manager. The County Manager shall have the right, at any time, at the expense of the County, to cause an audit to be made of the said Licensee, within the public interest.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Licensee shall file with the Public Works Department true and accurate maps or plats of all existing and proposed installations.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Licensee shall file annually with the County Manager not later than sixty (60) days after the end of the Licensee's fiscal year a copy of its report to its stockholders, as well as so much of the books of account of the Licensee as are necessary for independent ascertainment of the gross income from operations of the Licensee by the County or its agent.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The Licensee shall keep on file with the County Manager a current list of its shareholders and bondholders, if a corporation. If not a corporation, then a record of the appropriate ownership percentages in the Licensee shall be so filed.
</section>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-142. Filing and communications with regulatory agencies</catch_line>
<text>
Copies of all petitions, applications and communications submitted by the Licensee to the Federal Communications Commission, Securities and Exchange Commission, or any other federal or State regulatory Commission or agency having jurisdiction in respect to any matters affecting CATV operations authorized pursuant to a License granted under this article, shall also be submitted simultaneously to the County Manager.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-143. Forfeiture of License</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
In addition to all other rights and powers of the County by virtue of a License granted under this article or otherwise, the County reserves the right to terminate and cancel a License granted under this article and all rights and privileges of the Licensee hereunder in the event that the Licensee:
<section prefix = "1">
Materially violates any provision of a License granted hereunder, or any rule, order or determination of the County Manager or the Commission made pursuant to a License granted under this article, except where such violation, other than under Section 8A-140 or subsection (b) below, is without fault of the Licensee or occurs through excusable neglect.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Becomes insolvent, unable or unwilling to pay its debts or is adjudged bankrupt.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Attempts to dispose of any of the facilities of property of its CATV business to prevent the County from recovering any payments due or any losses or damages arising out of the License.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Attempts to evade any of the provisions of a License granted hereunder or practices any fraud or deceit upon the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Fails to begin, or to complete, construction under a License granted hereunder before such time limitation established herein.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
After a License is granted under this article and if Licensee fails to maintain the minimum reception standards as herein set forth or fails to abide by the terms and conditions of this article, after reasonable notice by the County Manager, said Licensee may be subject to having its License cancelled by the Commission who shall notify the Licensee of the time and place of a meeting of the Commission at which the cancellation of said License shall be considered. The Licensee shall have an opportunity, in person or by attorney, to defend or explain its position to said Commission and may offer witnesses or evidence in support of its position.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Termination and cancellation of License shall be by resolution and shall in no way affect any of the County's rights under a License granted under this article or any provision of law.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The Commission shall have the right to cancel a License one hundred twenty (120) days after the appointment of a receiver, or trustee, to take over and conduct the business of the Licensee, whether in receivership, reorganization, bankruptcy, or other action or proceeding, unless such receivership or trusteeship shall have been vacated prior to the expiration of the one hundred twenty (120) days, or unless:
<section prefix = "1">
Within one hundred twenty (120) days after election or appointment such receiver or trustee shall have fully complied with all of the provisions of this chapter and remedied all defects thereunder; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Such receiver or trustee, within one hundred twenty (120) days shall have executed an agreement, duly approved by the court having jurisdiction in the premises, whereby such receiver or trustee assumes and agrees to be bound by each and every provision of this chapter and License granted to the Licensee.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 74-88, §§ 2, 27, 10-15-74; Ord. No. 77-91, § 12, 12-20-77)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-144. County's right of intervention</catch_line>
<text>
The Licensee shall agree not to oppose intervention by the County in any suit or proceeding to which the Licensee is a party.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-145. Further agreement and waiver by Licensee</catch_line>
<text>
The Licensee shall agree to abide by all provisions of a License granted under this article and further that it will not at any future time set up against the County or the County Manager the claim that the provisions of the License are unreasonable, arbitrary or void.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-145.1. Modifications to federal regulations</catch_line>
<text>
All Licenses shall be subject to the applicable provisions of the Federal Communications Commission Regulations, and any modifications to those regulations shall be considered a part of the License within one (1) year of the adoption of the modification or at the time of License renewal, whichever occurs first.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-145.2. Severability</catch_line>
<text>
If any section, subsection, clause or provision of the article is held invalid, the remainder of this article shall not be affected by such invalidity.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-146. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 77-91, § 14, adopted Dec. 20, 1977, repealed former § 8A-146, which section provided a specific penalty for violations of the article; said former section was derived from Ord. No. 74-88, §§ 2, 32, adopted Oct. 15, 1974.

</EditorsNote>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (5) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 74-88, § 1, enacted Oct. 15, 1974, repealed former Art. IV, §§ 8A-125—8A-146, relative to community antenna television systems. Sections 2-32 of said Ord. No. 74-88 enacted a new Art. IV as herein set out. (Back)
 Former Art. IV was derived from Ord. No. 70-75, §§ 1—22, adopted Sept. 29, 1970, and Ord. No. 73-54, §§ 1—8, adopted May 15, 1973. (Back)
Cross reference— Cable television regulations, Ch. 8AA. (Back)
State Law reference— CATV franchises, F.S. § 166.046. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
