<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XIX._Miami-Dade_TRANSIT_AGENCY</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-145. Created and established; administrative direction and supervision; functions</catch_line>
<text>
The Miami-Dade Transit Agency is hereby created and established. The County Manager is hereby empowered and shall have the duty and responsibility to provide the administrative direction and supervision of the Miami-Dade Transit Agency, in accordance with policies adopted and promulgated by the Board of County Commissioners. The Miami-Dade Transit Agency shall perform the following functions:
<section prefix = "a">
Routes, schedules and operations. Develop and maintain a system of routes consonant with the needs of the riding public and extend, discontinue or adjust such routes based upon studies relating to population distribution, business activity, employment, origin and destination of trips, traffic conditions, load analyses, schedules, or other such factors which would show the practicability, feasibility or general public benefit of such changes; make and adjust schedules; carry on safety and training activities; maintain an information service; conduct passenger traffic route change and marketing studies; and market the services of the transit system.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Maintenance of the fleet. Maintain, repair or modify the rolling stock of the fleet including engines, electrical systems, air conditioning systems, bodies, chassis, painting, and other mechanical components; conduct a preventative maintenance program; and keep such equipment cost accounts and records as may be necessary to determine the life, effectiveness, or usefulness of the equipment.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Damage claims. Investigate, adjust, compromise, settle or defend all damage claims arising from operation of the system in accordance with the procedures established by the County Manager pursuant to Section 2-148 of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Sale of advertising space. Promote the sale of advertising space in or on the buses, stations, shelters, or other suitable facilities of the system on a nondiscriminatory basis.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Providing public transportation services and facilities for the physically disabled. Such services and facilities, in addition to other services and facilities for the disabled, shall be provided through the purchase and operation of buses equipped with appropriate devices (specifically including wheelchair lifts) to facilitate transportation of the physically disabled. The anticipated capital and operating expenditures for each fiscal year shall be determined and budgeted by the Manager in accordance with established budgetary procedures. For the purposes of this subsection, "buses" are defined as buses with a maximum capacity of forty-five (45) passengers.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-146. Functions of County Manager in relation to Agency</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager is hereby empowered and shall have the duty and responsibility to perform the following functions:
<section prefix = "a">
Appoint a Director of the Miami-Dade Transit Agency, who shall serve at the will of the County Manager.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Prescribe, by administrative order, the organization and operating procedure of the Agency.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Appoint such employees and other personnel as may be necessary to operate the Agency.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
May establish a special fund for the payment of damage claims against the Agency and designate those County employees authorized to issue drafts thereon. All drafts shall bear at least two (2) authorized signatures thereon.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-147. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Section 2-147, pertaining to the transfer of salaried officers and employees from the Transit Authority to the Transit Agency, has been deleted as obsolete. The section was derived from Ord. No. 74-92, § 1, adopted Oct. 15, 1974.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-148. Authority of County Attorney to adjust, compromise or settle damage claims arising out of operation of Agency</catch_line>
<text>
Notwithstanding anything in Section 2-15, Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, to the contrary, the County Attorney shall be and is hereby authorized to adjust, compromise, or settle all damage claims against Miami-Dade County arising out of the operation of the Miami-Dade Transit Agency, provided that the County Attorney shall first determine that said adjustment, compromise, or settlement is in the best interest of the taxpayers of Miami-Dade County after taking into regard the legal liability of the Agency, the amount of damages claimed, potential litigation expenses and the potential financial exposure of the County; provided further, that any proposed adjustment, compromise, or settlement in excess of two thousand five hundred dollars ($2,500.00) per claimant shall also require the prior approval of the County Finance Director: and provided further, that any proposed adjustment, compromise, or settlement in excess of five thousand dollars ($5,000.00) per claimant shall require the prior approval of both the County Manager and the County Finance Director.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-149. Rules and regulations</catch_line>
<text>
The Director of the Transit Agency shall prepare and submit to the County Manager such rules and regulations as may be necessary to perform the duties and functions conferred or imposed upon him by this article or as are required to properly govern the use, operation and maintenance of the system. Such rules and regulations, when approved by the County Commission shall have the force and effect of law.
</text>
The Director of the Transit Agency shall prepare and submit to the County Manager such rules and regulations as may be necessary to perform the duties and functions conferred or imposed upon him by this article or as are required to properly govern the use, operation and maintenance of the system. Such rules and regulations, when approved by the County Commission shall have the force and effect of law.
<catch_line>Sec. 2-150. Fixing and changing fares, service, rates or charges</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Except as provided in Section 2-150(c), the County Commission shall have the authority to make service changes and fix all fares, rates or charges for the use of the transit system, provided however, that those fares, rates or charges in force on the effective date of this article shall continue in full force and effect until changed or modified by the County Commission.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Approved by County Commission after public hearing. The County Manager may recommend the following changes or modifications to service, fares, rates or charges, which changes may be adopted by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners after a public hearing:
<section prefix = "1">
Any fare, rate or charge for transit service or for service ancillary to transit;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Any change in service of twenty-five (25) percent or more of the number of route miles of a route;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
If, in a fiscal year, the cumulative changes on a route add up to twenty-five (25) percent or more change in the number of route miles of a route;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
A change in the interval between peak period transit services on a route of more than ten (10) minutes;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
A change in the interval between off-peak period transit services on a route of more than thirty (30) minutes; or
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
A new transit service is established or an existing service is abolished.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Approved by County Manager. The following transit fare or service changes may be approved administratively by the County Manager, or his or her designee, and shall not require a public hearing:
<section prefix = "1">
Institution of reduced or free promotional fares for up to one hundred and eighty (180) days;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Service changes which are seasonal in nature;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
During an emergency for a period up to one hundred eighty (180) days;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
When the designation of a route (i.e., route name, number or letter) is changed;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Institution of experimental service changes or demonstration routes/service changes for the duration of the experiment or demonstration;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Any scheduling or service change which does not require a public hearing as described in Section 2-150(b).
The Agency shall provide public notice of such passenger fare and service changes in such a manner as to inform the public thereof.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The County Manager or his designee is delegated the authority to change service or modify or waive fares, rates or charges for special events not to exceed sixty (60) days. These short-term program changes, modifications or waivers will be exempt from public hearing requirements.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 74-92, § 1, 10-15-74; Ord. No. 84-91, § 1, 12-4-84; Ord. No. 98-162, § 1, 11-5-98)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-150.1. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 98-162, § 1, adopted Nov. 5, 1998, repealed section 2-150.1 in its entirety. Former section 2-150.1 pertained to public hearing for services changes and derived from Ord. No. 86-32, § 1, adopted April 15, 1986.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-151. Compliance with safety regulations, etc</catch_line>
<text>
In the operation of transit facilities, the Agency and any corporation, association, employee or individual acting for the Agency, shall comply with safety regulations, County ordinances, State laws or regulations, and federal regulations applicable to comparable street, railway and bus systems.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-152. Rights of employees of transit systems acquired by County</catch_line>
<text>
Whenever the County acquires existing transit systems or facilities from a publicly owned public utility, to the extent necessary or feasible for the economic operation of such facilities, all of the employees of such acquired transit system whose duties pertain to the facilities acquired shall be employed in comparable positions in the County service and the pay status, seniority, vacation and sick leave rights shall be preserved and maintained to the fullest possible extent.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-153—2-170. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (34) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 74-92, §§ 1, 2, adopted Oct. 15, 1974, repealed former Art. XIX, §§ 2-145—2-167, pertaining to the Transit Authority, and enacted in lieu thereof a new Art. XIX, §§ 2-145—2-152, as herein set out. (Back)
Former Art. XIX was derived from Ord. No. 60-23, §§ 1—3, adopted Aug. 2, 1960; Ord. No. 61-22, § 1, adopted May 23, 1961; Ord. No. 62-49, §§ 1, 2, adopted Dec. 4, 1962; Ord. No. 64-39, § 14, adopted Sept. 1, 1964; Ord. No. 71-32, § 1, adopted March 30, 1971; and Ord. No. 74-26, § 1, adopted April 16, 1974. (Back)
Annotation—AO 9-1 (Back)
Case law annotation— State v. Miami-Dade County, 142 So. 2d 79 (Fla. 1962), arising out of proceedings to validate a Transit System revenue bond issue to be issued by Miami-Dade County, the Supreme Court held that the County could acquire by purchase all the capital stock of transportation systems in the County, and issue revenue bonds payable solely from earnings of such system, that the purchase would not impair any legal rights of municipalities involved, and that the sale of the common stock of the transportation system was not a sale condemned by the constitution. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
