<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XCIX._SOCIAL_AND_ECONOMIC_DEVELO</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1441. Creation of Board</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created and established in Miami-Dade County an advisory board to be known as the Dr. Antonio Jorge Social and Economic Development Council for Miami-Dade County ("Council").
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1442. Membership</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Council shall consist of at maximum twenty-two (22) voting members. The Council, by a majority vote of members present, shall appoint its own members and its own chairperson and vice-chairperson. The SEDC may review the credentials of any person interested in serving as an SEDC member.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The provisions of Section 2-11.38.2(b) of the Code of Miami-Dade County shall not apply to current voting members of the Social and Economic Development [Council] as of September 30, 2009.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 02-120, § 2, 7-9-02; Ord. No. 08-117, § 1, 10-7-08; Ord. No. 09-99, § 1, 11-3-09; Ord. No. 11-78, § 2, 10-4-11)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1443. Organization</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Five (5) members of the Council shall constitute a quorum. The Council shall adopt a schedule of regular meetings. Special meetings of the Council may be called by the Chairperson or upon the written request of five (5) members. All meetings of the Council shall be public and written minutes shall be maintained.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Ex officio members. The Council may, from time to time appoint ex officio, non-voting members to the Council. The ex officio members shall not count towards a quorum. The Council may remove any ex officio member, with or without cause. The Council may appoint whatever number of ex officio members the Council deems necessary. There shall be no attendance requirement for ex officio members.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 02-120, § 3, 7-9-02; Ord. No. 08-117, § 2, 10-7-08; Ord. No. 11-78, § 3, 10-4-11)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1444. Duties and Functions</catch_line>
<text>
The Council shall be charged with the following duties, functions and responsibilities and will report biannually to the Economic Development and Housing Committee:
<section prefix = "a">
To suggest and recommend to the Mayor and Commissioners of Miami-Dade County the appropriate short-run policies and measures to reactivate the economy of the County, with special attention to the needs of low income segments of the population;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
To actively participate in and coordinate the efforts for the conceptualization, formulation and implementation of a long-run strategy for the acceleration of the social and economic development of Miami-Dade County. The resulting socioeconomic plan should aim at the rapid increase in the per-capita income of the general population as well as at the diversification of the local economy and the substantial reduction in the prevailing rates of poverty in the County;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
To provide a forum and medium for governmental officers and community leaders to study and address the socioeconomic consequences of the terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
To make findings and recommendations on a quarterly basis to the Mayor of Miami-Dade County and the Board of County Commissioners regarding the necessary measures to ensure full recovery and future socioeconomic development.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1445. Staff Support</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager shall provide adequate departmental staff support and access to the necessary resources to enable the Council to carry out its duties, functions and responsibilities.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-1446—2-1460. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (108) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 02-120, §§ 1—5, adopted July 9, 2002, did not specifically amend the Code. Hence, its inclusion herein as article XCIX, §§ 2-1441—2-1445, was at the discretion of the editor. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
