<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 29 TAXATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_V._TOURIST_DEVELOPMENT_ROOM_TAX</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-51. Levy and imposition</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
There shall be levied and imposed throughout the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, Florida, except within the municipal limits of Miami Beach, Bal Harbour and Surfside: (1) a tourist development room tax; (2) a professional sports franchise facility tax; and (3) a homeless and spouse abuse tax. The tourist development room tax shall be imposed at a rate of two (2) percent, and the professional sports franchise facility tax shall be imposed at a rate of one (1) percent, of each whole and major fraction of each dollar of the total rental charged every person who rents, leases or lets for consideration any living quarters or accommodations in any hotel, apartment hotel, motel, resort motel, apartment, apartment motel, rooming house, mobile home park, recreational vehicle park, or condominium for a term of six (6) months or less. When receipt of consideration is by way of property other than money, the tax shall be levied and imposed on the fair market value of such nonmonetary considerations. An oral lease, payable weekly, monthly or otherwise, shall not be subject to the tax where the tenant occupies a residential unit located in a facility in which the residential units are leased primarily as permanent residences. Living quarters or accommodations which are exempt according to the provisions of Chapter 212, Florida Statutes, shall also not be subject to the tax.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
There shall also be levied and imposed throughout the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, Florida, except within the municipal limits of those municipalities presently imposing a municipal resort tax pursuant to Chapter 67-930, Florida Statutes, a tourist development surtax at a rate of two (2) percent of each whole and major fraction of each dollar of the total amount charged every person for the purchase of food, beverages or alcoholic beverages in any hotel or motel. When receipt of consideration is by way of property other than money, the tax shall be levied and imposed on the fair market value of such nonmonetary consideration.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
In addition to the tourism development room tax, the professional sports franchise facility tax and the tourism development surtax, there shall be levied and imposed throughout the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, except within the municipal limits of those municipalities presently imposing a municipal resort tax pursuant to Chapter 67-930, Florida Statutes, a homeless and spouse abuse tax. The homeless and spouse abuse tax shall be imposed at the rate of one (1) percent on each whole and major fraction of each dollar charged every person for the purchase of food, beverages or alcoholic beverages in establishments that are licensed by the State of Florida to sell alcoholic beverages for consumption on the premises, except hotels and motels. The tax shall not apply to: (1) any item sold by the package for off premises consumption; (2) sales of food, beverages or alcoholic beverages in establishments licensed by the state to sell alcoholic beverages for consumption on the premises which during the previous calendar year, calculated from July 1 until the following June 30, had gross annual revenues of four hundred thousand dollars ($400,000.00) or less; (3) food, beverage and alcoholic beverage sales in any veterans, fraternal, or other chartered or incorporated club licensed under Section 565.02(4), Florida Statutes; and (4) all sales or transactions which are exempt from the state sales tax.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The tourist development room tax, the professional sports franchise facility tax, the tourist development surtax, and the homeless and spouse abuse tax shall be in addition to any other tax imposed pursuant to Chapter 212, Florida Statutes, and in addition to all other taxes, fees and the considerations for the rental or lease of living quarters or accommodations as described in Section 29-51(a), or for the purchase of food, beverages and alcoholic beverages from the establishments described in Section 29-51(b).
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The tourist development room tax and the professional sports franchise facility tax shall be charged by the person receiving the consideration for the lease or rental, and it shall be collected from the lessee, tenant or customer at the time of payment of the consideration for such lease or rental. The tourist development surtax and the homeless and spouse abuse tax shall be charged by the person receiving the consideration for the food, beverages or alcoholic beverages, and it shall be collected at the time of payment for such food, beverage or alcoholic beverage.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 78-62, § 1, 10-4-78; Ord. No. 84-88, § 1, 11-6-84; Ord. No. 90-33, § 1, 4-3-90; Ord. No. 90-116, § 1, 10-16-90; Ord. No. 93-75, § 1, 7-27-93)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-51.1. Remittance and administration</catch_line>
<text>
The person receiving the consideration for rentals, leases, food, beverages or alcoholic beverages taxable under this article shall receive, account for, and remit the tax to the Miami-Dade County Tax Collector in accordance with the following procedure:
<section prefix = "a">
The taxes levied hereunder shall be due and payable monthly on the first day of each month, and for the purpose of ascertaining the amount of tax payable under this article, it shall be the duty of all lessors to make a return, on or before the twentieth day of the month, to the County Tax Collector, upon forms prepared and furnished by the County, showing all rentals during the preceding calendar month; however, the County may authorize a quarterly return and payment when the tax remitted by the lessor for the preceding quarter did not exceed twenty-five dollars ($25.00). The County or its designated agent shall accept returns if postmarked on or before the twentieth day of the month; if the twentieth day falls on a Saturday, Sunday, or federal or State legal holiday, returns shall be accepted if postmarked on the next succeeding work day. Each lessor shall file a return for each tax period even though no tax is due for such period.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The same duties, privileges, enforcement procedures and penalties imposed by Chapter 212, Florida Statutes, upon dealers in tangible property respecting the remission and collection of tax, the making of returns, the keeping of books, records and accounts, and compliance with the rules of the Florida Department of Revenue in the administration of said chapter, to the extent that such provisions of said Florida Statutes and Department of Revenue regulations are not in conflict with the provisions of this article, shall apply to and be binding upon all persons and entities who are subject to the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
(1)  Every lessor upon whose premises the tourist development room tax and the professional sports franchise facility tax are levied and every person selling food, beverages or alcoholic beverages taxable under this article shall have the duty to maintain adequate records to show gross collections from all such taxable transactions and the amount of tax due and paid hereunder. It shall be their duty, moreover, to keep and preserve, for a period of three (3) years, all invoices and other records of leases, rentals and sales of food, beverages and alcoholic beverages under this article, and all such books, invoices, and other records shall be open to examination at all reasonable hours to the County or its designated agent.
<section prefix = "2">
For the purpose of this subsection, if a lessor or other person collecting the taxes under this article does not have adequate records of his rentals or sales of food, beverages and alcoholic beverages, the County or its designated agent, may, upon the basis of test or sampling of the lessor's or person's available records or other information relating to the rentals or sales made by such lessor or person, for a representative period, determine the proportion that taxable transactions bear to total transactions. This subsection does not affect the duty of any lessor or person to collect, or the liability of any tenant or purchaser to pay, any tax imposed by or pursuant to this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
If the records of a lessor or other person collecting the taxes under this article are adequate but voluminous in nature and substance, the County or its designated agent may statistically sample such records and project the audit findings derived therefrom over the entire audit period to determine the proportion that taxable transaction amounts bear to total transaction amounts, provided, the lessor or other person and the County have entered into an agreement which provided for the use of statistical sampling and projections and the means and methods to be used. The agreement shall be binding on the lessor or person and the County.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
(1)  The County is authorized to audit or inspect the records and accounts of such lessors and persons and correct by credit any overpayment of tax; and, in the event of a deficiency, an assessment shall be made and collected. No administrative finding of fact is necessary prior to the assessment of any tax deficiency.
<section prefix = "2">
In the event any lessor or person charged herein fails or refuses to make his records available for inspection so that no audit or examination has been made of the books and records of such lessor or person, fails or refuses to register as a lessor or other person collecting the taxes under this article, or fails to make a report and pay the taxes as provided by this article, or makes a grossly incorrect report, or makes a report that is false or fraudulent, then, in such event, it shall be the duty of the County to make an assessment from an estimate based upon the best information then available to it for the taxable period of retail sales of such lessor or other person collecting the taxes, the gross proceeds from rentals or sales of food, beverages and alcoholic beverages, together with interest plus penalty, if such have accrued, as the case may be. Then the County shall proceed to collect such taxes, interest, and penalty on the basis of such assessment, which shall be considered prima facie correct; and the burden to show the contrary shall rest upon the lessor or other person collecting the taxes.

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-51.2. Tax Collector's powers and duties</catch_line>
<text>
The Tax Collector shall maintain accurate books, records and accounts reflecting the collection, administration and disbursement of the taxes levied and imposed under this article. The Tax Collector shall prescribe and publish such forms as may be necessary to effectuate the local collection of the tourist development room tax, the professional sports franchise facility tax, the tourist development surtax and the homeless and spouse abuse tax. For the purpose of collecting the tourist development room tax, the professional sports franchise facility tax, the tourist development surtax and the homeless and spouse abuse tax, the Tax Collector shall have the same duties and powers as those vested in the Florida Department of Revenue under Chapter 212, Florida Statutes.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-51.3. Costs of administration</catch_line>
<text>
The Tax Collector may retain a portion of the taxes collected for costs of administration in an amount not to exceed three (3) percent of collections.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-51.4. Dealer's credit</catch_line>
<text>
The same duties and privileges imposed upon dealers by Chapter 212, Florida Statutes, apply under this article. To compensate dealers for keeping of prescribed records and the proper accounting and remitting of taxes by them, dealers shall be allowed three (3) percent of the first one thousand dollars ($1,000.00) of the amount of taxes due and accounted for and remitted to the Tax Collector and one percent of all amounts in excess of one thousand dollars ($1,000.00) on each tax return to the Tax Collector. The collection allowance may not be granted nor may any deduction be permitted, if the tax is delinquent at the time of payment. The Tax Collector may reduce the collection allowance by ten (10) percent or fifty dollars ($50.00), whichever is less, if taxpayer files an incomplete return.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-51.5. Procedures for confidentiality</catch_line>
<text>
All information contained in returns, reports, accounts, or declarations received from dealers, and from the Department of Revenue, including investigative reports and information, is confidential except for official purposes and subject to the provisions of Section 213.053, Florida Statutes. Miami-Dade County and its officers and employees having access to information regarding the tourist development room tax, the professional sports franchise facility tax, the tourist development surtax or the homeless tax shall accord such information, documents, names, and addresses, the same confidentiality as required by said statute. All Miami-Dade County officers and employees having access shall be made aware of those requirements and the penalties for their violation.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-52. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-53. Enforcement of collections</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Failure to charge and collect tax. Any person who is taxable hereunder who fails or refuses to charge and collect from the person paying any rental or lease or purchasing any food, beverage or alcoholic beverage the taxes herein provided, either by himself or through his agents or employees, shall be, in addition to being personally liable for the payment of the tax, guilty of a violation of the second degree, punishable as provided in Section 775.082, Section 775.083 or Section 775.084, Florida Statutes. Each occasion upon which such person fails to charge and collect the taxes herein provided shall constitute a separate offense.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Advertisement or holding out to public that tax not required to be paid by renter or lessee, etc. No person shall advertise or hold out to the public in any manner, directly or indirectly, that he will absorb all or any part of the taxes herein provided, or that he will relieve the person paying for a rental, lease, food, beverage or alcoholic beverage of the payment of all or any part of the tax, or that the tax will not be added to the rental or lease consideration or the consideration of food, beverage or alcoholic beverage, or when added, that it or any part thereof will be refunded or refused, either directly or indirectly, by any method whatsoever. Any person who willfully violates any provision of this subsection shall be guilty of a violation of the second degree, punishable as provided in Section 775.082, Section 775.083 or Section 775.084, Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Lien status of levy. The tourist development room tax and the professional sports franchise facility tax hereby levied shall constitute a lien on the property of the lessee, customer, or tenant in the same manner as, and shall be collectible as are, liens authorized and imposed by Sections 713.67, 713.68 and 713.69, Florida Statutes.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 78-62, § 5, 10-4-78; Ord. No. 90-33, § 7, 4-3-90; Ord. No. 90-116, § 5, 10-16-90)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-54. Disposition of revenues; review of expenditures</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Tourist development room tax.
<section prefix = "1">
Collections received by the Tax Collector from the tourist development room tax, less costs of administration, are to be deposited in the "Miami-Dade County Tourist Development Trust Fund," herewith established, and used in accordance with the Miami-Dade County Tourist Development Plan, which provides for the allocation of funds as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
To fund the Greater Miami Convention and Visitors Bureau (sixty (60) percent less the following amounts, the allocation of which shall be made by the Board of County Commissioners after receipt of the recommendations of the Miami-Dade County Tourist Development Council: (i) $550,000.00 in 1993-94; (ii) $575,000.00 in 1994-95; and (iii) $600,000.00 in 1995-96 and each year thereafter.) Funds allocated pursuant to the recommendations of the Tourist Development Council shall be for the tourism purposes described in the following subparagraph 2.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To promote Miami-Dade County tourism by sponsoring tourist-oriented culture, cultural and special events such as visual and performing arts including theater, concerts, recitals, opera, dance, art, exhibitions, festivals and other tourist-related activities. (Twenty (20) percent). In determining expenditures from the twenty (20) percent portion of this allocation the County Commission may consider the recommendations of the Miami-Dade County Cultural Affairs Council.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
To promote tourism, to fund tourist-related facilities as allowed by law, and to fund tourist-oriented events located within the municipal boundaries of the City of Miami, as determined by the Board of the County Commissioners and for fiscal year 2012-13, to finance within the County beach park facilities or beach improvement, maintenance, renourishment, restoration, and erosion control, including shoreline protection, enhancement or cleanup, as those uses relate to the physical preservation of the beach or shoreline, or for any other uses within the County's boundaries permitted by law. (Twenty (20) percent).
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
To use as a secondary pledge to pay debt service on bonds issued to finance the construction, reconstruction, or renovation of professional sports franchise facilities (the "Professional Sports Franchise Facilities Tax Revenue Bonds"), if and only to the extent that the primary pledge of revenues are not sufficient to pay amounts due on said Professional Sports Franchise Facilities Tax Revenue Bonds.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The duties of the Tourist Development Council shall be described in the enabling act [Section 125.0104, Florida Statutes] and in Ordinance No. 78-28 [Sections 2-248 through 2-253.1] passed by the Board of County Commissioners on April 4, 1978. The Council shall also, from time to time, make recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners for the effective operation of the special projects or uses of the tourist development room tax revenue and may perform such other duties or functions as may be prescribed by ordinance or resolution.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Tourist Development Council shall continuously review expenditures of revenues from the Tourist Development Trust Fund and shall receive at least quarterly expenditure reports from the Board of County Commissioners or the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners. Expenditures which the Council believes to be unauthorized shall be reported to the Board of County Commissioners and the Florida Department of Revenue. The County Commissioners and the Florida Department of Revenue shall review the Council's findings and take appropriate administrative or judicial action to ensure compliance with this article and the provisions of Section 125.0104, Florida Statutes.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Professional sports franchise facility tax. Collections received by the Tax Collector from the professional sports franchise facility tax, less costs of administration, shall be used to pay debt service on bonds issued to finance the construction, reconstruction, or renovation of a professional sports franchise facility.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Tourist development surtax. Collections received by the Tax Collector from the tourist development surtax, less costs of administration, are to be deposited to the Miami-Dade County Tourist Development Surtax Trust Fund, herewith established, and disbursed in the following manner:
<section prefix = "1">
The proceeds of the tourist development surtax shall be allocated to the Countywide Convention and Visitors Bureau which, by interlocal agreement and contract with the County, has been given primary responsibility for promoting the County and its constituent cities as a destination site for conventions, trade shows, and pleasure travel.
<section prefix = "a">
All tax proceeds allocated to the Convention and Visitors Bureau shall be used only for the following purposes:
<section prefix = "i">
To promote and advertise tourism in the State of Florida and nationally and internationally; and
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
To fund convention bureaus, tourist bureaus, tourist information centers and news bureaus, either as County agencies or by contract with the Chambers of Commerce or similar associations in the County.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The County shall regulate by separate agreement with the Convention and Visitors Bureau the manner in which the tax proceeds shall be distributed to the Convention and Visitors Bureau, the specific purposes for which the proceeds shall be expended, and the manner in which the County shall review the administration of tax proceeds by the Convention and Visitors Bureau.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
In the event the County is no longer a party to an interlocal agreement and contract with a Countywide Convention and Visitors Bureau, the County shall allocate directly the proceeds of the tax for the purposes described in subsection (b)(1)(a)(i) and (ii).
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Homeless and spouse abuse tax.
<section prefix = "1">
The County adopts as its controlling policy and plan for addressing the needs of persons who have become or are about to become homeless, the Miami-Dade County Community Homeless Plan prepared by the Miami-Dade County Task Force on the Homeless, attached as exhibit A. This plan shall govern the expenditure of that portion of the homeless and spouse abuse tax dedicated to assisting the homeless.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
All funds collected by the Tax Collector from the homeless tax shall be placed into the Homeless Tax Trust Fund and used in the following manner:
<section prefix = "a">
For the first twelve (12) months funds placed into the Homeless Tax Trust Fund shall be used by the County to assist persons who have become or are about to become homeless only in accordance with the Miami-Dade County Community Homeless Plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Thereafter not less than fifteen (15) percent of the funds generated by the homeless and spouse abuse tax shall be made available for the construction and operation of a spouse abuse emergency treatment and shelter facility.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
During the existence of the homeless and spouse abuse tax, Miami-Dade County shall continue to contribute each year at least eighty-five (85) percent of the average annual aggregate general fund expenditures devoted to operating homeless shelter services in the two (2) fiscal years preceding the effective date of this Ordinance No. 93-75.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 78-62, § 3(C), (D), 10-4-78; Ord. No. 90-33, § 8, 4-3-90; Ord. No. 90-116, § 6, 10-16-90; Ord. No. 92-138, § 1, 11-5-92; Ord. No. 93-75, § 4, 7-27-93; Ord. No. 94-02, § 1, 1-18-94; Ord. No. 06-57, § 1, 4-27-06; Ord. No. 12-74, § 25, 9-20-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-55. Modification of Tourist Development Plan</catch_line>
<text>
The Tourist Development Plan adopted under the provisions of this article may not be substantially amended except by ordinance enacted by an affirmative vote of a majority plus one additional vote of the Board of County Commissioners, pursuant to the enabling act.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-56. Powers, duties and responsibilities not specifically conferred</catch_line>
<text>
Any powers, duties or responsibilities not specifically conferred on the Tourist Development Council or the Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners by this article but authorized to be conferred by the State enabling act, as amended from time to time, shall be deemed to be conferred by this article upon the Tourist Development Council or the Board of County Commissioners, as the case may be.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-57. Effective date</catch_line>
<text>
That part of this article pertaining to the tourist development room tax shall become effective the first day of the month following its being approved at referendum.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 29-58, 29-59. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (5) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 78-62, §§ 1, 2, 3(C), (D), 4, 5, 7, 8, and 11, adopted Oct. 4, 1978, and approved at referendum on Nov. 7, 1978, did not expressly amend the Code; hence, inclusion herein as Art. V of Ch. 29, §§ 29-51—29-56, is at the discretion of the editor. (Back)
Cross reference— Metropolitan Dade County Tourist Development Council, § 2-248 et seq. (Back)
State Law reference— Tourist development tax, F.S. § 125.0104. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
