<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="2">ARTICLE_LVII._MIAMI-DADE_COUNTY_ADVISORY</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-701. Created; composition; terms; compensation</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created a Miami-Dade County Advisory Board for Minority and Women-Owned Businesses consisting of 15 members, one member to be appointed by each County Commissioner and two members to be appointed by the County Manager. No less than seventy-five (75) percent of the members appointed shall be members of those groups affected by the Minority and Women-Owned Business Discrimination Study prepared by MRD Consulting, dated November 29 and December 16, 1993. The terms of each commissioner appointed member shall be coterminous with the term of the appointing Commissioner. The terms of each County Manager appointed member shall be at the will and discretion of the County Manager. In no event shall a Board member serve more than four (4) consecutive years. Members shall serve without compensation.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-702. Purpose and intent; report; staff</catch_line>
<text>
The Advisory Board is created for the purpose of reviewing County set-aside programs for minority-owned and women-owned businesses, and for making recommendations concerning said programs to the Board of County Commissioners on all matters pertaining to these programs. The Advisory Board is also intended to operate as a focal point for the public. The Advisory Board, with the assistance of the County Manager, will collect, input, and disseminate information related to economic opportunities within Miami-Dade County government for women and minority business owners. The Board shall submit an annual written report to the County Commission on ways to improve such communication. The Board may submit interim reports as it deems appropriate. The County Manager, County Attorney, and Clerk of the Board shall provide appropriate staff support.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-703. Conflict of interest waiver</catch_line>
<text>
Sections 2-11.1(c) and (d) of the Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance of Miami-Dade County are waived for advisory board members for transactions arising from the exercise of those powers given the advisory board by this ordinance.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-704—2-720. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 07-17, § 1, adopted Feb. 6, 2007, repealed section 2-704 in its entirety. Former section 2-704 pertained to the Miami-Dade County flood management task force, and derived from Ord. No. 01-70, § 1, adopted April 10, 2001.

</EditorsNote>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (76) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 94-31, adopted Feb. 1, 1994, amended the Code by the addition of provisions which have been included herein at the discretion of the editor as Art. LVII, §§ 2-701, 2-702 (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
