<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 30A URBAN RENEWAL</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_VI._TASK_FORCE_ON_URBAN_ECONOMIC</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 30A-128. Creation of the task force on urban economic revitalization</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created and established as an agency and instrumentality of Miami-Dade County a revocable trust which shall be named and known as a Task Force on Urban Economic Revitalization hereinafter referred to as "the Task Force." The Task Force shall be a public body through which its governing body may exercise all those powers either specifically granted herein or necessary in the exercise of the powers herein enumerated.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30A-129. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
For the purposes of this section the following definitions shall be effective:
<section prefix = "1">
Urban Economic Revitalization means the undertakings and activities of Miami-Dade County and its residents in implementing comprehensive economic development strategies to create jobs, cause an increase in the tax base, and promote business activity in Targeted Urban Areas located in Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Targeted urban areas means those geographical areas commonly known as: Liberty City, Model City/Brownsville, Carol City, Goulds, Overtown, Little Haiti, Opa-locka, Richmond Heights, Homestead, Florida City, Coconut Grove, Northwest 27th Avenue Corridor, Northwest 183rd Street Corridor, West Little River, Princeton/Naranja, Leisure City, South Miami, Perrine and the following City of North Miami Districts: 7th Avenue District, Downtown District, West Dixie Highway District and Biscayne Boulevard District. Any geographic locations in Miami-Dade County which are designated by the Federal Government as empowerment zones shall be included in the definition of targeted urban areas at the time of such designation. Maps or street descriptions setting forth the contiguous boundaries of the targeted urban areas, which are more fully described in Exhibit A that is attached to this ordinance [Ord. No. 11-05], are hereby incorporated herein by reference. Exhibit A shall replace any prior maps describing the target urban areas, which are currently on file with the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners. The Clerk of the Board is directed to file Exhibit A upon the effective date of this ordinance [February 11, 2011].
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
County funds means funds received by the County from any source, and shall include but not be limited to, general funds, omnibus reserve funds, state or federal grant funds, and any empowerment zone funding granted to Miami-Dade County before and after the effective date of this article

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30A-130. Governing body</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Membership; compensation. The governing body of the Task Force shall be a Board of Directors composed of twenty-three (23) voting members. Members shall serve without compensation but shall be entitled to reimbursement for necessary expenses incurred in the discharge of their duties.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Composition. The voting membership of the Board of Directors shall be ethnically, racially, geographically and gender balanced and shall be composed of the following members:
<section prefix = "1">
One (1) member representing the financial or banking community;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
One (1) member representing the legal community;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
One (1) member nominated by the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioner's Committee which has jurisdiction over community and economic development;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
One (1) member with a background in public sector budgeting and finance;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
One (1) member nominated by the Beacon Council;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
One (1) member representing the civic and private sector business community which shall be nominated by the Greater Miami Chamber of Commerce;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
One (1) member representing the civic and private sector business community which shall be nominated by the Miami-Dade Chamber of Commerce;
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
One (1) member nominated by the Metro-Miami Action Plan Trust
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Two (2) members of the Florida Legislature, one (1) from the House and one (1) from the Senate, who were elected from districts which are located, wholly or partially, within a targeted urban areas;
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
One (1) member nominated by the Urban Bankers Association, Inc.;
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
One (1) member nominated by the Black Lawyers Association Inc.;
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
One (1) member nominated by the Black Business Association;
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
One (1) member nominated by Tools for Change;
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
One (1) member nominated by a community development organization which allows the community to vote on its Board membership;.
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
Four (4) members of the Board of County Commissioners whose districts constitute the largest part of the Targeted Urban Areas shall each designate one (1) member of the Task Force who shall be residents of targeted urban areas or who are business owners who have places of business within targeted urban areas.
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
One (1) member representing the Commercial/Industrial Development Community;
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
One (1) member nominated by the Coalition of Community Development Corporations;
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
One (1) member representing the investment banking community;
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
One (1) member representing the insurance community;
Members of the Board of County Commissioners who were elected from districts which are located, wholly or partially, in the targeted urban areas, shall serve as ex-officio, non-voting advisors to the Task Force. These advisors shall not count towards a quorum.
Vacancies on the Board of Directors shall be filled in the same manner by which the original members were appointed, with a special emphasis on choosing persons representative of the gender, racial and ethnic composition of the entire community.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 97-33, § 3, 4-15-97)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 30A-131. Terms of office, tenure and removal of Directors</catch_line>
<text>
All non-ex officio members shall serve staggered terms of three (3) years each; provided, however, of the original Board of Directors, the Mayor of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County shall select five (5) members for a term of one (1) year, and five (5) members for a term of two (2) years and the remaining non-ex officio members for a term of three (3) years. No member, with the exception of ex-officio members and advisors, shall be permitted to serve more than two (2) consecutive and complete terms of three (3) years each unless so authorized by the Mayor of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County. Members may be removed in accordance with the provisions of Section 2-11.38 of the Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30A-132. Qualifications</catch_line>
<text>
Each member of the Task Force must comply with the requirements of Section 2-11.38 of the Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30A-133. Organization and procedure</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Officers. The Task Force shall organize after the members thereof have qualified to serve. The Mayor shall appoint the initial Chairperson and Vice-Chairperson and officers of the Task Force as necessary. These officers shall hold such offices for an initial one-year term. After expiration of the initial term of office of such officers, the Task Force shall elect its officers from among its members. In addition, the Task Force shall make, adopt and amend bylaws, rules and regulations for its own governance.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Meetings. The Task Force shall hold regular meetings and such other meetings as it deems necessary. A majority of the members of the Task Force shall constitute a quorum. Minutes shall be kept of all meetings of the Task Force and all meetings shall be public.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Committees. The Task Force shall appoint any committees it deems necessary.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Applicability of County rules and procedures. The trust shall at all times operate under the Florida Open Government laws, including the "Sunshine Law," public meeting laws and public records laws and shall be governed by all state and County conflict of interest laws, as applicable, including the Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance, Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Voting requirements. Trustees may designate in writing alternates to attend meetings and/or vote on their behalf.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 97-33, § 6, 4-15-97)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 30A-134. Powers and duties</catch_line>
<text>
The powers and duties of the Task Force shall be as follows:
<section prefix = "a">
To serve in an advisory capacity to the Mayor and the Board of County Commissioners with respect to all issues affecting urban economic revitalization related to targeted urban areas;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
To develop and present to the Mayor and the Board of County Commissioners within ninety (90) to one hundred twenty (120) days from the first meeting of the Task Force, a "Plan" which shall:
<section prefix = "1">
Identify the goals of the Plan and identify specific, focused, achievable economic development projects and/or programs to be carried out wholly or partially within the targeted urban areas,
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Delineate the action steps necessary or desirable to accomplish goals of the Plan,
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Develop a plan for private sector fundraising to benefit Urban Economic Development within targeted urban areas; such plan should (1) identify persons and/or private entities to engage in fundraising to benefit Urban Economic Development within targeted urban areas and may propose to Miami-Dade County a contract with such persons and/or entities which would establish a public/private partnership, the goal of which would be to benefit Urban Economic Development within targeted urban areas; (2) include a component to involve residents of the targeted urban areas in fundraising in order to promote a sense of community ownership in the economic revitalization of the targeted urban areas, and (3) allow an opportunity for capital investment by residents of the targeted urban areas.

In order to develop the Plan, the Task Force shall:
<section prefix = "1">
Review, analyze and evaluate the funding expended in the targeted urban areas for economic development over the past ten (10) years.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Review, analyze and evaluate existing economic development plans and/or studies prepared on behalf of Miami-Dade County and prepared by community development corporations or community based organizations to determine which projects are achievable and feasible, including but not limited to plans and/or studies related to projects such as the Poinciana Industrial Park, the Seventh Avenue Corridor, Northside Shopping Center, the Northwest 183rd Street Shopping Center, the Community Development Bank, the Richmond Heights Old Shopping Center Project, the Perrine/Homestead Avenue Corridor, and the Goulds Shopping Center; provided, such plans or studies shall relate to projects or programs wholly or partially within targeted urban areas;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Review, analyze and evaluate successful Urban Economic Revitalization programs from other major urban areas, including but not limited to programs in Baltimore, Maryland, Harlem, New York; Washington, D.C. and Atlanta, Georgia;
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Review, analyze and evaluate the Community and Individual Investment Corporation Guide published by USHUD September, 1996;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Hold community meetings, coordinated by MMAP, to encourage public input in developing a focused, achievable and feasible plan and disseminate information regarding existing programs which aid the urban economic revitalization effort. The community input process utilized in the empowerment zone process may be used as a guide;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Identify new and existing federal, state and local sources of funding, if any, which could provide funding for Urban Economic Revitalization.

</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
To update the Plan on an annual basis;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
To study the feasibility of community based development entities' consolidating and forming alliances which could take advantage of economies of scale and promote efficiency in service delivery; and to recommend incentives to encourage the formation of such consolidations and alliances;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
To encourage employment of targeted urban area residents in major downtown developments, such as the Maritime Park Project and the Performing Arts Center;
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
To encourage and promote the development and growth of the new and existing businesses in the targeted urban areas; and
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
To review the Office of Community Development's ("O.C.D.'s") recommendations for Miami-Dade County Community Development Block Grant economic development category funding and Community Based Organization Funding, related to economic development, for the purpose of assuring that O.C.D.'s staff recommendations are in accordance with priorities established by the Plan and require O.C.D. to report the dollar amount being spent in targeted urban areas. To the extent the Board expends County Funds for economic development in targeted urban areas, recommendations of the Task Force made pursuant to this subsection shall be accepted and implemented by the Board of County Commissioners, unless the recommendation is disapproved by a two-thirds (2/3) vote of the entire membership of the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Work with the Mayor to identify and propose to the Board of County Commissioners a dedicated source of funding to implement the Urban Economic Revitalization Plan.
</section>
</text>
The powers and duties of the Task Force shall be as follows:
<section prefix = "a">
To serve in an advisory capacity to the Mayor and the Board of County Commissioners with respect to all issues affecting urban economic revitalization related to targeted urban areas;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
To develop and present to the Mayor and the Board of County Commissioners within ninety (90) to one hundred twenty (120) days from the first meeting of the Task Force, a "Plan" which shall:
<section prefix = "1">
Identify the goals of the Plan and identify specific, focused, achievable economic development projects and/or programs to be carried out wholly or partially within the targeted urban areas,
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Delineate the action steps necessary or desirable to accomplish goals of the Plan,
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Develop a plan for private sector fundraising to benefit Urban Economic Development within targeted urban areas; such plan should (1) identify persons and/or private entities to engage in fundraising to benefit Urban Economic Development within targeted urban areas and may propose to Miami-Dade County a contract with such persons and/or entities which would establish a public/private partnership, the goal of which would be to benefit Urban Economic Development within targeted urban areas; (2) include a component to involve residents of the targeted urban areas in fundraising in order to promote a sense of community ownership in the economic revitalization of the targeted urban areas, and (3) allow an opportunity for capital investment by residents of the targeted urban areas.

In order to develop the Plan, the Task Force shall:
<section prefix = "1">
Review, analyze and evaluate the funding expended in the targeted urban areas for economic development over the past ten (10) years.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Review, analyze and evaluate existing economic development plans and/or studies prepared on behalf of Miami-Dade County and prepared by community development corporations or community based organizations to determine which projects are achievable and feasible, including but not limited to plans and/or studies related to projects such as the Poinciana Industrial Park, the Seventh Avenue Corridor, Northside Shopping Center, the Northwest 183rd Street Shopping Center, the Community Development Bank, the Richmond Heights Old Shopping Center Project, the Perrine/Homestead Avenue Corridor, and the Goulds Shopping Center; provided, such plans or studies shall relate to projects or programs wholly or partially within targeted urban areas;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Review, analyze and evaluate successful Urban Economic Revitalization programs from other major urban areas, including but not limited to programs in Baltimore, Maryland, Harlem, New York; Washington, D.C. and Atlanta, Georgia;
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Review, analyze and evaluate the Community and Individual Investment Corporation Guide published by USHUD September, 1996;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Hold community meetings, coordinated by MMAP, to encourage public input in developing a focused, achievable and feasible plan and disseminate information regarding existing programs which aid the urban economic revitalization effort. The community input process utilized in the empowerment zone process may be used as a guide;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Identify new and existing federal, state and local sources of funding, if any, which could provide funding for Urban Economic Revitalization.

</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
To update the Plan on an annual basis;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
To study the feasibility of community based development entities' consolidating and forming alliances which could take advantage of economies of scale and promote efficiency in service delivery; and to recommend incentives to encourage the formation of such consolidations and alliances;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
To encourage employment of targeted urban area residents in major downtown developments, such as the Maritime Park Project and the Performing Arts Center;
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
To encourage and promote the development and growth of the new and existing businesses in the targeted urban areas; and
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
To review the Office of Community Development's ("O.C.D.'s") recommendations for Miami-Dade County Community Development Block Grant economic development category funding and Community Based Organization Funding, related to economic development, for the purpose of assuring that O.C.D.'s staff recommendations are in accordance with priorities established by the Plan and require O.C.D. to report the dollar amount being spent in targeted urban areas. To the extent the Board expends County Funds for economic development in targeted urban areas, recommendations of the Task Force made pursuant to this subsection shall be accepted and implemented by the Board of County Commissioners, unless the recommendation is disapproved by a two-thirds (2/3) vote of the entire membership of the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Work with the Mayor to identify and propose to the Board of County Commissioners a dedicated source of funding to implement the Urban Economic Revitalization Plan.
Sec. 30A-135. County spending in targeted urban areas to be in accordance with the Plan.
All County funds expended for Urban Economic Revitalization purposes on projects to be implemented partially or wholly within targeted urban areas, shall be spent in accordance with the priorities established by the Plan.
</section>
The powers and duties of the Task Force shall be as follows:
<section prefix = "a">
To serve in an advisory capacity to the Mayor and the Board of County Commissioners with respect to all issues affecting urban economic revitalization related to targeted urban areas;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
To develop and present to the Mayor and the Board of County Commissioners within ninety (90) to one hundred twenty (120) days from the first meeting of the Task Force, a "Plan" which shall:
<section prefix = "1">
Identify the goals of the Plan and identify specific, focused, achievable economic development projects and/or programs to be carried out wholly or partially within the targeted urban areas,
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Delineate the action steps necessary or desirable to accomplish goals of the Plan,
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Develop a plan for private sector fundraising to benefit Urban Economic Development within targeted urban areas; such plan should (1) identify persons and/or private entities to engage in fundraising to benefit Urban Economic Development within targeted urban areas and may propose to Miami-Dade County a contract with such persons and/or entities which would establish a public/private partnership, the goal of which would be to benefit Urban Economic Development within targeted urban areas; (2) include a component to involve residents of the targeted urban areas in fundraising in order to promote a sense of community ownership in the economic revitalization of the targeted urban areas, and (3) allow an opportunity for capital investment by residents of the targeted urban areas.

In order to develop the Plan, the Task Force shall:
<section prefix = "1">
Review, analyze and evaluate the funding expended in the targeted urban areas for economic development over the past ten (10) years.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Review, analyze and evaluate existing economic development plans and/or studies prepared on behalf of Miami-Dade County and prepared by community development corporations or community based organizations to determine which projects are achievable and feasible, including but not limited to plans and/or studies related to projects such as the Poinciana Industrial Park, the Seventh Avenue Corridor, Northside Shopping Center, the Northwest 183rd Street Shopping Center, the Community Development Bank, the Richmond Heights Old Shopping Center Project, the Perrine/Homestead Avenue Corridor, and the Goulds Shopping Center; provided, such plans or studies shall relate to projects or programs wholly or partially within targeted urban areas;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Review, analyze and evaluate successful Urban Economic Revitalization programs from other major urban areas, including but not limited to programs in Baltimore, Maryland, Harlem, New York; Washington, D.C. and Atlanta, Georgia;
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Review, analyze and evaluate the Community and Individual Investment Corporation Guide published by USHUD September, 1996;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Hold community meetings, coordinated by MMAP, to encourage public input in developing a focused, achievable and feasible plan and disseminate information regarding existing programs which aid the urban economic revitalization effort. The community input process utilized in the empowerment zone process may be used as a guide;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Identify new and existing federal, state and local sources of funding, if any, which could provide funding for Urban Economic Revitalization.

</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
To update the Plan on an annual basis;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
To study the feasibility of community based development entities' consolidating and forming alliances which could take advantage of economies of scale and promote efficiency in service delivery; and to recommend incentives to encourage the formation of such consolidations and alliances;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
To encourage employment of targeted urban area residents in major downtown developments, such as the Maritime Park Project and the Performing Arts Center;
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
To encourage and promote the development and growth of the new and existing businesses in the targeted urban areas; and
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
To review the Office of Community Development's ("O.C.D.'s") recommendations for Miami-Dade County Community Development Block Grant economic development category funding and Community Based Organization Funding, related to economic development, for the purpose of assuring that O.C.D.'s staff recommendations are in accordance with priorities established by the Plan and require O.C.D. to report the dollar amount being spent in targeted urban areas. To the extent the Board expends County Funds for economic development in targeted urban areas, recommendations of the Task Force made pursuant to this subsection shall be accepted and implemented by the Board of County Commissioners, unless the recommendation is disapproved by a two-thirds (2/3) vote of the entire membership of the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Work with the Mayor to identify and propose to the Board of County Commissioners a dedicated source of funding to implement the Urban Economic Revitalization Plan.
Sec. 30A-135. County spending in targeted urban areas to be in accordance with the Plan.
All County funds expended for Urban Economic Revitalization purposes on projects to be implemented partially or wholly within targeted urban areas, shall be spent in accordance with the priorities established by the Plan.
Sec. 30A-136. County spending in non-targeted urban areas not affected by ordinance.
It is the intention of the Board that areas which are not within the boundaries of targeted urban areas shall not be prejudiced with respect to the allocation of County Funds by virtue of the operation of this article. The Board reserves its discretion to allocate County Funds to areas inside and outside targeted urban areas.
</section>
<catch_line>Sec. 30A-137. Staff support</catch_line>
<text>
The Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners shall record all meetings of the Task Force. The County Manager and the County Attorney shall provide to the Task Force adequate staff and support services to enable the Task Force to carry out its duties and responsibilities.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30A-138. Liberal construction to effectuate public purpose</catch_line>
<text>
This article, being for public purpose and for the welfare of the citizens of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall be liberally construed to effect the purposes hereof.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 30A-139—30A-150. Reserve</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
</law>
