<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_VII._TAMPERING_WITH_UTILITY_FIXT</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-121. Tampering with utility fixtures</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
As used in this Section, "utility" means the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
It shall be unlawful for any person, without the written consent of the utility:
<section prefix = "a">
To alter, tamper or meddle with, injure, remove, bypass or otherwise hinder or disturb, or to cause, permit, suffer, let or allow to be altered, tampered or meddled with, injured, removed, bypassed or otherwise hindered or disturbed, any meters, meter seals, pipes, wire locks, lines, valves, mains, laterals, collectors, connections, interceptors, manholes, appliances, appurtenances or other apparatus or device used for or in connection with any water or sewer system belonging to the utility, in such a manner as to cause loss or damage or to prevent any meter installed for registering water from registering the quantity which otherwise would pass through the same; or to alter or break the wire lock or seal of any such meter; or in any way to hinder or interfere with the proper action or just registration of any such meter or device; or to use, waste, or suffer the waste, by any means, of water passing through any such meter, pipe, or fitting, or other appliance or appurtenance connected with or belonging to the utility, after such meter, pipe or fitting, or other appliance or appurtenance has been tampered with, injured, or altered; or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
To make or cause, permit, suffer, let or allow to be made any connection with mains, service pipes or other pipes, appliances, or appurtenances in such manner as to use, without the written consent of the utility, any water, or to cause to be supplied any service, water or sewer, from the utility to any person, firm or corporation through any orifice, faucet or other outlet whatsoever, without such service being reported for payment or such water passing through a meter provided by the utility and used for measuring and registering the quantity of water passing through the same; or
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
To use or receive the direct benefit from the use of the utility knowing, or under such circumstances as would induce a reasonable person to believe, that such direct benefits have resulted from any tampering with, altering of, or injury to any connection, meter, pipe, conduit, line, meter seal, valve, main, wire lock, lateral, collector, interceptor, manhole or other apparatus or device owned, operated, or controlled by the utility, for the purpose of avoiding payment.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-148, § 1, 10-19-99)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-122. Strict liability</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Whenever a violation of this chapter occurs or exists, any person, individually or otherwise who has a legal, beneficial or equitable interest in the device or instrumentality causing or contributing to the violation or who has a legal, beneficial, or equitable interest in the real property which is receiving the benefit of the utility service shall be jointly and severally liable for said violation regardless of fault and regardless of knowledge of the violation. This provision shall be construed to impose joint and several liability regardless of fault and regardless of knowledge of the violation, upon all persons, individually or otherwise, who, although no longer having any such legal, beneficial or equitable interest in said device or instrumentality or real property, did have such an interest at any time during which such violation existed or occurred or continued to exist or to occur. This provision shall be liberally construed and shall be retroactively applied to protect the public health, safety, and welfare and to accomplish the purposes of this Article. provided, however, that no owner of rental property shall be held liable under this section unless the County notifies, in accordance with Section 32-122(2) of the Miami-Dade County Code, said owner of the County's intent to impose liability.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Notice to Owners of Tampering at Rental Property
<section prefix = "a">
No citation, order, or action issued or filed pursuant to this Section arising out of tampering at any rental property shall be effective against the owner of said rental property unless that owner is first given notice of the County's intent to issue such citation, order, or action. Said notice shall be by certified mail, with return receipt requested, to the owner of the rental property as shown on the tax records of Miami-Dade County and shall be issued no less than thirty (30) days prior to the issuance or filing of any citation, order, or action pursuant to this Section against such owner. Said notice shall be deemed given upon mailing of said notice by the County, whether or not said notice is received.
Notwithstanding the foregoing, water and sewer service shall not be provided to the rental property until the citation, action, or order is resolved.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
In the event that a citation, action, or order is or has been filed or issued pursuant to any provision hereof against a tenant or other person using or occupying a rental property other than the owner of such property as listed on the tax records of Miami-Dade County, the County shall provide a reference to this earlier citation, action, or order in the notice to owners specified in this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
When used herein, the term "rental property" shall include any property, including a single family home, which is used or occupied, in whole or in part, by any person other than the owner of said property as shown on the tax records of Miami-Dade County, pursuant to a rental agreement, either written or oral, between the owner and a tenant
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-148, § 1, 10-19-99; Ord. No. 04-93, § 1, 5-11-04)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-123. Criminal penalty</catch_line>
<text>
If any person shall fail or refuse to obey or comply with, or violate any of the provisions of this chapter or any lawful order of the Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee, such person, upon conviction of such offense, shall be punished by a fine not to exceed Five Hundred Dollars ($500.00), or by imprisonment not to exceed sixty (60) days in the County Jail, or both, in the discretion of the Court. Each day of each continued violation shall be considered as a separate offense. This shall be cumulative and in addition to any other remedies provided for in this chapter or in Chapter 8CC of the Miami-Dade County Code.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-124. Enforcement; procedure; remedies</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
It is unlawful for any person to violate or to cause, permit, allow, let, or suffer any violation of: any of the provisions of this chapter; any lawful orders of the Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee; and consent agreements. In addition to any other judicial or administrative remedies provided by this chapter, the Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee, shall have the following judicial remedies:
<section prefix = "1">
To institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to seek temporary or permanent, prohibitory or mandatory injunctive relief to enforce compliance with or prohibit the violation of: Any of the provisions of this chapter; any lawful order of the Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department; or any consent agreement.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to impose and recover a civil penalty in an amount of not more than Twenty -Five Thousand Dollars ($25,000.00) for each violation of: Any of the provisions of this chapter; any lawful order of the Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee; or any consent agreement.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
To institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to seek restitution and other equitable relief to recover any sums expended and cost incurred for tracing, investigating, preventing, controlling, abating, or remedying violations of: This chapter, or any lawful order of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee; or any consent agreement.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
To institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to recover a monetary amount equal to three (3) times the amount of services unlawfully obtained or $1,000.00, whichever is greater. The Department may add damages and costs to enforce this Article which remain unpaid after sixty (60) days to the customer's bill and enforce a lien when and as authorized by Article VI of Chapter 32 of the County Code.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Each day during any portion of which such violation occurs or continues to occur constitutes a separate violation. The right of trial by jury shall be available in any court to determine both liability for and the amount of the civil penalty to be imposed and recovered hereunder.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
In addition to a civil penalty or court award of damages, any violator shall be liable for the reasonable costs and expenses incurred by the County in enforcing the provisions of this Article, including but not limited to the labor and materials costs (including overhead and fringe benefits) of enforcement actions, inspections, preparation of enforcement reports, photographs, title searches, postage, court or hearing attendance time, and other demonstrable administrative costs for enforcement and collection. All such sums shall become delinquent if not paid within thirty days after receipt by the violator of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department's bill itemizing the costs incurred in enforcing the provisions of this Article, or after a hearing officer or court order become final (the "due date"). All such delinquent sums shall bear interest at the rate of twelve (12%) percent per annum after the due date. Any sums remaining unpaid after sixty (60) days shall be added to the customer's bill for services and the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department shall record and enforce liens as authorized by Article VI of Chapter 32 of the County Code.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-148, § 1, 10-19-99)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-125. Authority to issue lawful orders</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Whenever evidence has been obtained or received establishing that a violation of this chapter has been committed, the Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department or the Director's designee, shall issue a notice to correct the violation or a citation to cease the violation and cause the same to be served upon the violator and/or the property owner of the place where the violation occurred by personal service or certified mail or by posting in a conspicuous place on the premises where the violation occurred. Such notice or citation shall briefly set forth the general nature of the violation and specify a reasonable time within which the violation shall be rectified or stopped, commensurate with the circumstances. Reasonable time herein means the shortest practicable time to rectify or stop the violation. If notice to correct the violation or citation to cease the violation is not obeyed within the time set forth therein, the Director or the Director's designee, shall have the power and authority to issue any lawful orders to enforce the provisions of this chapter. Any orders issued by the Director or the Director's designee may be enforced by suit brought by him in the appropriate court of competent jurisdiction.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Whenever a violation of this chapter has been committed, the Director or the Director's designee may initiate proceedings against the violator in the appropriate court for such violation, whether or not a notice to correct the violation or citation to cease the violation has been issued.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-148, § 1, 10-19-99)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-126. Remedies cumulative and independent</catch_line>
<text>
All the judicial and administrative remedies in this chapter, municipal ordinances, County ordinances, State laws, and rules and regulations, as all of same may be amended from time to time, are independent and cumulative.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-127. Attorneys' fees</catch_line>
<text>
Upon the rendition of a judgment or decree by any of the courts of this State against any person in favor of the Director of Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee, to enforce any of the provisions of this chapter, the trial court, or, in the event of an appeal in which the Director of Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee, prevails, the appellate court shall adjudge or decree against said person and in favor of the Director of Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee, a reasonable sum as fees or compensation for the attorney who prosecuted the suit in which the recovery was had. Where so awarded, compensation or fees of the attorney shall be included in the judgment or decree rendered in the case. This provision shall apply to all pending or prospective civil actions, legal or equitable, filed by the Director of Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee, to enforce the provisions of this chapter. Cessation, correction or remediation of any violation of the provisions of this chapter, prior to rendition of a judgment or of a temporary or final decree, or prior to execution of a negotiated settlement, but after an action is filed by the Director of Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee, to enforce the provisions of this chapter, shall be deemed the functional equivalent of a confession of judgement or verdict in favor of the Director of Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee, for which attorneys' fees shall be awarded by the trial court as set forth herein above.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-128. Consent agreements</catch_line>
<text>
The Director of Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee, in the Director's or his designee's discretion, may terminate an investigation or an action commenced under the provisions of this chapter upon execution of a written consent agreement between the Director of Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee, and the persons who are the subject of the investigation or action. The consent agreement shall provide written assurance of voluntary compliance by said persons with the applicable provisions of this chapter. The consent agreement may, in the discretion of the Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee, provide the following: Posting of a surety, bond, or other security to assure compliance; costs and expenses of Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department for investigation, enforcement, testing, monitoring, and litigation, including attorneys' fees; civil penalties; remedial or corrective action. An executed written consent agreement shall not be evidence of a prior violation of this chapter. Such consent agreement shall not be deemed to impose a limitation upon any investigation or action of the Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee, in the enforcement of this chapter. The consent agreement shall not constitute a waiver of or limitation upon the enforcement of any federal, State, or local laws and ordinances. Executed written consent agreements are hereby deemed to be lawful orders of the Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee. Each violation of any of the terms and conditions of an executed written consent agreement shall constitute a separate offense under this chapter, by the persons who executed the consent agreement, their respective officers, directors, agents, servants, employees, and attorneys; and by those persons in active concert or participation with any of the foregoing persons and who receive actual notice of the consent agreement. Each day during any portion of each such violation occurs constitutes a separate offense under this chapter.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 32-129—32-150. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
</law>
