<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="2">ARTICLE_IX._WELLS_(OPEN_IRRIGATION_HOLES</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-111. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
In construing the provisions hereof, each and every word, term, phrase or part of the definitions provided in Chapter 72-299 (see Section 373.303, Florida Statutes) Laws of Florida, as amended, and the following definitions shall apply:
<section prefix = "a">
Well (irrigation hole) means an excavation that is drilled or otherwise constructed when the intended use of such excavation is for irrigation purposes. The irrigation hole is generally drilled nine (9) inches in diameter and twenty (20) to twenty-five (25) feet in depth.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Abandoned well (irrigation hole) means a well (irrigation hole) whose use has been permanently discontinued.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-112. Abandoned wells</catch_line>
<text>
Any well not expected to be in continued use must be filled permanently with like materials that originally came out of the hole.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-113. Functional wells</catch_line>
<text>
Any well in a field open to the public must be covered with a cap sufficient to withstand three hundred (300) pounds in weight. Each cap shall be painted bright red. Any such well shall also be marked by a small, triangular, colored flag.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-114. Permit required to open self-harvest agricultural field; requirements and conditions prerequisite to issuance of permit</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful to open a self-harvest agricultural field to the public unless and until the owner or lessee of such field obtains a permit for such an enterprise. The County Manager or his designated agent is hereby empowered and directed to issue such permits upon proof of compliance with the following requirements and conditions:
<section prefix = "a">
That the applicant for such a permit is the owner or lessee of agricultural fields for which a permit is sought;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
That a survey or map of said field is presented showing the boundaries of the field and the location of all known "wells (irrigation holes)" located within the boundaries of said field;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
That an affidavit is presented and filed wherein the owner or lessee states under oath that all known wells (irrigation holes) have been marked and covered in compliance with the provisions of this article;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
That written permission is granted by said owner or lessee for the entrance to and for inspection of the permitted field by the County Manager or his designees to determine whether there is compliance with the requirements of this section; and
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
That payment of a one dollar ($1.00) fee to cover the cost of processing the permit is tendered. This permit shall be valid for six (6) months.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-115. Children under ten years of age prohibited from entering fields</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful for any parent or other person acting in loco parentis, or the owner or lessee of a self-harvest field open to the public to permit a child under ten (10) years of age to enter upon such field, unless said owner or lessee has a designed area specifically approved for children under ten (10) years of age, and unless said parent or other person acting in loco parentis accompanies said child. Said designated area shall be inspected annually by the County Manager or his designated agent and must at all times be roped off in a manner that would prevent a child from leaving said designated area. Upon payment of an annual twenty-five-dollar-fee, the County Manager or his designated agent shall conduct the inspection and if the designated area is properly and securely roped off, issue the permit. Notwithstanding any of the foregoing, the County shall not be liable for any injury caused by the owner or lessee failing to maintain the designated area properly.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-116. Posting of fields</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful to open a self-harvest agricultural field to the public unless and until the field is posted with at least four (4) red-lettered signs stating in a clear and conspicuous manner the following warning:
"Self-harvesting is very dangerous—Watch for hidden holes. Children under 10 years of age not permitted by law".

Areas covered by the permit that are closed to the public must be marked by at least four (4) red-lettered signs stating:
"This area closed to public—Keep out"

and marked with the well known danger symbol of a skull and cross-bones.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-117. Violations and penalty</catch_line>
<text>
Each known or plainly visible well (irrigation hole) left uncovered in violation of this article shall constitute a separate violation. Failure to post any warning sign required hereby shall constitute a separate violation for each sign not properly posted. All violations of this article shall be punished as provided by Section 1-5 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-118. Thefts of plants and fruits and trespass</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It is unlawful for any person, with the intent to injure or defraud, to take, carry away, or damage any plants, fruits, plant products, or nursery stock contained within any nursery or private or public property without the consent of the owner of the property or his agent.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
It is unlawful for any person to enter upon the premises of any nursery or upon private or public property with the intent to injure, damage, take or carry away any plant, fruit, plant product or nursery stock, without the written or oral consent of the owner of the property or his agent.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
It is unlawful for any person to enter the premises of any plant or fruit nursery, whenever the nursery is not open for business, without the written or oral consent of the owner of the nursery or his agent.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
All violations of this section shall be punished as provided by Section 1-5 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 76-66, § 1, 7-20-76)</history>
<catch_line>Secs. 21-119, 21-120. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (6) ---
Editor's note— Section 6 of Ord. No. 74-9, enacted Feb. 25, 1974, provided that said ordinance be included in this Code, but did not specify the manner of inclusion. Codification of §§ 1—3 of said Ord. No. 74-9 as Art. IX, §§ 21-111—21-113, was at the discretion of the editors. (Back)
Cross reference— Potable water wells, § 24-12.1. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
