<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_III._HEIGHT_OF_BUILDINGS</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-52. Maximum height in all districts; exceptions</catch_line>
<text>
Except where a greater height may be approved as a result of a public hearing, the maximum height of a building shall be thirty-five (35) feet, two (2) stories, except as specified in each district and as specified elsewhere in the Code. No accessory building, garage or servants' quarter in RU and EU-M Districts shall exceed one (1) story in height unless the principal residence on the lot is two (2) stories in height and there are two (2) or more two-story residences on other lots in the block.
</text>
Except where a greater height may be approved as a result of a public hearing, the maximum height of a building shall be thirty-five (35) feet, two (2) stories, except as specified in each district and as specified elsewhere in the Code. No accessory building, garage or servants' quarter in RU and EU-M Districts shall exceed one (1) story in height unless the principal residence on the lot is two (2) stories in height and there are two (2) or more two-story residences on other lots in the block.
<catch_line>Sec. 33-53. Cornice height in specific districts</catch_line>
<text>
The minimum cornice height of buildings in EU-M and RU-1 Districts shall be fifteen (15) feet above the sidewalk or, in lieu of a sidewalk, the average elevation of the plot covered by the structure elevation adjacent to the lot on which said building is placed, in the following Districts: EU-M, RU-1, RU-2 and RU-3.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-54. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-55. Certain structures exempt</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The provisions of this article regarding building height shall not apply to: airplane beacons, belfries, chimneys, church spires/steeples, conveyors, cooling towers, cupolas, domes, elevator bulkheads and shafts and enclosures for mechanical equipment shall not be considered a part of a building for height calculations, fire towers, flag poles, monuments, parapet wall extending not more than five (5) feet above the limited height of the building on which it rests, radio and television towers, roof structures used only for ornamental purposes providing they do not exceed ten (10) percent of the roof area on which they stand, smokestacks, stage towers or scenery lofts, tanks, bins and silos used for purpose of storing grain or feed products such as silage in connection with agricultural production, water towers, and structures used in connection with screening of Antennas.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The provisions of this article III regarding building height shall not apply to active and passive recreational facilities which may be provided on the roof of a building, provided that the enclosed portion of such facilities shall not exceed sixty (60) percent of the total area of such roof, and provided that the same does not exceed one (1) story or twenty (20) feet in height.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 57-19, § 29(D), 10-22-57; Ord. No. 69-28, § 1, 4-15-69; Ord. No. 73-5, § 1, 1-9-73; Ord. No. 87-8, § 3, 3-3-87; Ord. No. 01-02, § 4, 1-23-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-56. Compliance with FAA rules</catch_line>
<text>
All buildings, structures and improvements to be constructed shall conform to and comply with the prevailing criteria and requirements of the Federal Aviation Administration and the Miami-Dade County Airport Zoning Regulations where applicable, regulations contrary thereto contained herein notwithstanding. The Director shall process applications for permits through the County Port Authority and Federal Aviation Administration whenever he deems it advisable.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-57. Setback when height exceeds limit</catch_line>
<text>
Any portion of a building in the BU-2, BU-3, IU-1, IU-2 and IU-3 Districts which is between thirty-five (35) and forty (40) feet in height shall be setback at least twenty-five (25) feet from the lot line adjacent to any street or thoroughfare. Thereafter one (1) additional foot of setback shall be provided for each five (5) feet of additional height.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-58. Height of building limited to width of street in certain districts</catch_line>
<text>
No building in IU-C, IU-1, IU-2 or IU-3 Districts shall be of a height greater than the width of the widest street upon which such building abuts, except after application is made and permit issued as a result of public hearing.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-59. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 02-255, § 4, adopted Dec. 3, 2002, repealed section 33-59 in its entirety. Former section 33-59 pertained to fire resistive construction of building over fifty-five feet and derived from Ord. No. 57-19, § 29(H), adopted Oct. 22, 1957.

</EditorsNote>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (5) ---
Cross reference— Definition of building height, § 33-1(17); towers, poles and masts, § 33-60 et seq. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
