<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="2">ARTICLE_CXV._GUIDELINES_FOR_ACHIEVING_MA</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1751. Legislative Findings and Purpose</catch_line>
<text>
It is in the best interest of the County to ensure to the greatest extent possible that the County evaluates, utilizes and participates in all systems, programs or other vehicles available for maximizing its receipt of federal matching funds in accordance with the Local Funding Revenue Maximization Act.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1752. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
The terms used in this Ordinance shall have the following meaning, unless the context clearly implies a different intent:
<section prefix = "a">
County shall mean Miami-Dade County and all of its departments, offices, agencies and instrumentalities.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Act shall mean the Local Funding Revenue Maximization Act, Section 409.017, Fla. Stat. (2003), as amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Federal Funds Maximization Program shall mean the County's program for maximizing federal matching funds under the Act.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
State shall mean the State of Florida and its agencies or departments that are involved in providing programs for health, social and human services, including, but not limited to, the Agency for Health Care Administration, the Agency for Workforce Innovation, the Department of Children and Family Services, the Department of Elderly Affairs, the Department of Juvenile Justice and the Florida Board of Education.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
All other terms used in this Ordinance shall have the same meaning as such terms have in the Act.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1753. Participation in State Programs for Federal Matching Funds</catch_line>
<text>
The County shall:
<section prefix = "a">
participate to the greatest extent possible in all programs and mechanisms established by the State pursuant to the Act;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
identify all certified local funds of the County (whether County funds or, to the extent provided or allowed by federal law, private funds) which are available, or potentially available, for utilization in maximizing the County's receipt of federal matching funds; and
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
submit proposals to the State in accordance with the Act and the Federal Funds Maximization Program.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1754. Responsibility of County Manager; Administrative Orders</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager shall develop policies for the Federal Funds Maximization Program through an administrative order which shall include, but not be limited to, the following:
<section prefix = "i">
identification of federal matching fund opportunities and State programs available for maximizing federal matching funds;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
creation and maintenance of an inventory of all available local funds (including private funds to the extent provided by federal law) that may qualify as certified local funds pursuant to the Act and periodic review of this inventory;
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
development and submittal of proposals that comply with the rules, regulations and other requirements promulgated by the State;
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
seeking and monitoring State approval of the proposals, provided that the Commission shall approve all County proposals prior to their being submitted to the State;
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
implementation and monitoring of State-approved County programs which have been awarded revenue maximization funds;
</section>
<section prefix = "vi">
maintenance of the documentation, records, information and databases necessary to maximize federal matching funds in subsequent years; and
</section>
<section prefix = "vii">
submittal of quarterly reports to the Commission regarding the Federal Funds Maximization Program which shall include, but not be limited to, information on funds received and disbursed, problems encountered and recommendations.

Based upon the availability of State programs related to health services, the County Manager's first priority shall be to maximize federal matching funds for health services.
All entities, such as community-based organizations, other municipalities, special districts and instrumentalities of the County, that receive County funds for health, social or human services shall provide such documentation, records, information and data required by the County Manager to assist the County Manager in fulfilling his or her responsibilities hereunder.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1755. Receipt of Federal Matching Funds</catch_line>
<text>
Funds received by the County through the Federal Funds Maximization Program shall be disbursed by the Commission by a resolution in a manner that benefits the greatest number of Miami-Dade County residents in need of health, social and human services. The County shall maintain autonomy of revenue maximization funds for which it is awarded.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-1756—2-1760. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (124) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 04-26, §§ 1—5, adopted Feb. 3, 2004, did not specifically amend the Code. Hence, its inclusion herein as article CXV, sections 2-1751—2-1755, was at the discretion of the editor. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
