<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_LXVIII._AGRICULTURAL_PRACTICES_A</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-931. Creation; purpose; duties</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created and established an advisory board to be known as the Agricultural Practices Advisory Board. Its purpose shall be to review proposed or existing regulations or legislation pertaining to agricultural practices in Miami-Dade County, and to provide recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners with regard to such regulations and legislation.
The duties of the Board shall be to:
<section prefix = "a">
Evaluate on an ongoing basis all pertinent existing or proposed federal, state, regional and local regulations, statutes, ordinances and policies concerning or impacting the agricultural industry in Miami-Dade County;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Provide recommendations for eliminating or reducing duplication of effort when two (2) or more governmental entities administer similar regulatory programs;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Provide recommendations for eliminating or modifying language in the Code of Miami-Dade County and/or regulatory activities that have mutually exclusive or contradictory criteria or goals;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Provide recommendations for eliminating or modifying language in the Code of Miami-Dade County and/or regulatory activities that create undue burden or hardship on the agricultural industry;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Provide recommendations for modifying or implementing provisions from any future or previously conducted study or plan that has the ability to impact the agricultural industry; and
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Prepare draft language to the Board of County Commissioners amending relevant sections of the Code of Miami-Dade County.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-932. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
For the purposes of this article, the following definitions apply:
Allied Agribusiness. A proprietorship, partnership, or other firm that provides goods, services, or supplies to those actively engaged in bona fide agriculture.
Board. The Agricultural Practices Advisory Board.
Director. The Director of the Department of Planning and Zoning or his or her designee.
Legislation. Statutes, ordinances, resolutions, and policies.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-933. Membership; qualifications</catch_line>
<text>
There shall be a total of thirteen (13) members appointed by the Board of County Commissioners as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
Two (2) representatives from the Tropical Fruit Crops Industry of Miami-Dade County, one (1) recommended by the Florida Avocado Committee, and one (1) recommended by the Tropical Fruit Growers of South Florida, Inc.;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Two (2) representatives from the nursery industry, recommended by the Miami-Dade County Chapter of the Florida Nursery Growers and Landscape Association;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Two (2) representatives from the vegetable industry, recommended by the Dade County Farm Bureau;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
One (1) representative of the aquaculture industry, recommended by the Ornamental Aquaculture Association of South Florida;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
One (1) representative of a citizens' association supportive of agriculture, recommended by the Redland Citizens' Association;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
One (1) representative of allied agribusiness recommended by the Dade AgriCouncil;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
One (1) representative of agri-banking, agri-financial consulting, or agri-lending recommended by the Homestead-Florida City Chamber of Commerce;
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
One (1) representative of Farm Labor, recommended by Coalition of Florida Farmworkers Organizations;
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
One (1) representative of the South Dade Soil and Water Conservation District, recommended by the South Dade Soil and Water Conservation District; and
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
One (1) at large representative recommended by the Miami-Dade Agricultural Practices Advisory Board.

Members shall have a majority of their income from or work time devoted to production agriculture in Miami-Dade County, hold membership in recognized agricultural organizations, or have a demonstrated interest in the agricultural industry in Miami-Dade County.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-934. Terms</catch_line>
<text>
Notwithstanding anything in the Code to the contrary, members shall be appointed for terms of four years without term limits. A member may serve until his or her successor has been duly appointed and qualified.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-935. Vacancies; election of officers; committees; meetings and records</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Vacancies. If a vacancy occurs, it shall be filled by the Board of County Commissioners. The designated organizations listed in Section 2-933 shall submit at least one nominee from their respective organizations, including the nominee's resume and the minutes of the board meeting approving the nominee to the County Manager, who shall forward the nominee to the Board of County Commissioners in a timely manner. In the case where a member organization fails to submit a nomination for a replacement member within 45 days of notification of a vacancy, the Board shall propose a nominee to fill the vacancy. The nominee shall be approved at a meeting of the Board, and the Board shall forward the minutes approving such nominee, together with the nominee's resume, to the County Manager, who shall forward the nominee to the Board of County Commissioners in a timely manner.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Election of officers. The Board shall annually elect a Chairperson and Vice-Chairperson from among its members at the Board's last meeting of each calendar year, or at the first Board meeting after a vacancy may occur in such positions. The Chairperson shall preside at all meetings at which he or she is present. The Vice-Chairperson shall act as Chairperson in the absence or inability of the Chairperson.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Committees. The Board may establish or eliminate committees at its discretion; however, only two such committees may be in existence at any time. In no instance shall the authority to act or speak in the name of the Board be delegated to any committee. The Chairperson shall nominate and appoint the chairperson and members of such committees as the Board shall find helpful to their mission. The committee chairperson shall schedule committee meetings, set the agenda, establish guidelines for discussion at committee meetings, and ensure that committee meeting minutes are properly recorded. Committees shall consist of at least three (3) members appointed by the Chairperson. Fifty-one percent of a committee's membership shall constitute a quorum.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Meetings. The Board shall hold regular meetings at least bimonthly and at other times in consultation with the Director.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 08-101, § 2, 9-2-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-936. Staff support</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
The Director shall designate representatives from the Department of Planning and Zoning to prepare meeting agendas, advertise meeting dates, record minutes from meetings of the Board, reserve meeting locations, arrange for speakers, administer the filling of vacancies, prepare and forward resolutions adopted by the Board to the County Manager, and provide the Board with a monthly update of the progress of such resolutions as they move through the legislative process.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Representatives from the Department of Planning and Zoning shall prepare draft ordinances and correspondence.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 08-101, § 2, 9-2-08)</history>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-937—2-950. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (87) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 95-03, adopted Jan. 17, 1995, amended the Code by the addition of provisions which have been included herein at the discretion of the editor as Art. LXVIII, §§ 2-931—2-933. (Back)
Section 1 of Ord. No. 08-101, adopted Sept. 2, 2008, amended Art. LXVIII, Agricultural Practices Study Advisory Board, to read as herein set out. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
