<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XVI._MIAMI-DADE_COUNTY_MOVING_OR</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-325. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
Sec. 8A-325. Definitions.
<section prefix = "a">
Accessorial services shall mean any service performed by a mover which results in a charge to the shipper and is incidental to the transportation service, including, but not limited to, preparation of a written inventory, packing, unpacking, or crating of articles, hoisting or lowering, waiting time, overtime loading and unloading, reweighing, disassembly or reassembly, elevator or stair carrying, boxing or servicing of appliances, and furnishing of packing or crating materials. Accessorial services include services not performed by the mover but by a third party at the request of the shipper or mover if the charges for such services are to be paid to the mover prior to or at the time of delivery.
(a.5)
Advertise shall mean to advise, announce, give notice of, publish or call attention by use of oral, written or graphic statement made in a newspaper or other publication or on radio or television, any electronic medium, or contained in any notice, handbill, sign (including signage on vehicle), flyer, catalog, or letter, or printed on or contained in any tag or label attached to or accompanying any good.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Article shall mean Article XVII of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and any rules, regulations and standards promulgated pursuant to this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Commission shall mean the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Compensation shall mean money, fee, emolument, quid pro quo, barter, remuneration, pay, reward, indemnification or satisfaction.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Contract for service or bill of lading shall mean a written document prepared by the mover and approved by the shipper in writing, prior to the performance of any service, that authorizes services from a named mover and lists the services and costs associated with the transportation of household goods and accessorial services.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Customer shall mean a person who inquires about, makes a request for or enters into a contract for service.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Director shall mean the Director of the Consumer Services Department or his/her designee. This definition shall apply to Section 8A-82.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, when utilizing the provisions of this article.
(g.5)
Equipment shall mean those items utilized by the mover to secure, deliver, transport and/or protect the shipper's household goods. Such equipment includes, but is not limited to, dollies, hand trucks, pads, blankets, and straps.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Estimate shall mean a written statement given by the mover to the shipper which sets forth the total cost of and the basis of the charges related to a shipper's move, such as, but not limited to, transportation or accessorial services.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Household goods shall mean personal effects, or other personal property, found in a home or personal residence, or found in a storage facility owned or rented by the shipper, where the shipper is the owner or the agent of the owner of the items. This definition does not include freight or personal property moving to or from a factory or store or other place of business.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Mover shall mean any person who engages in the transportation of household goods for compensation or any person who holds himself or herself out to the general public as engaging in the transportation of household goods for compensation.
(j.5)
Packing material shall mean the container utilized by a mover to package, deliver, transport, and/or protect the shipper's household goods. If a mover charges for packing material, the mover shall only charge for such material on a per container basis. This container charge shall include the cost for each container and any wrap, tape or other materials utilized by mover to pack the container.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Person shall mean any natural person, individual, public, or private corporation, trust, firm, association, joint venture, partnership, municipality, governmental agency, political subdivision, public officer, or any other entity whatsoever, or any combination of the foregoing, jointly or severally.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Registration or registration certificate shall mean the authorization by the Director required by this article before a person is authorized to engage in business in Miami-Dade County as a mover of household goods.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
Shipper shall mean any person who contracts with a mover for the transportation of household goods. This term shall include any other person whom the shipper designates in writing.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-326. Intent and application</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The provisions of this article shall be construed liberally to promote the following policies:
<section prefix = "1">
To establish the law governing moving practices within this county with regard to the transportation of household goods.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To address moving practices in this county in a manner that is not inconsistent with federal law and the laws of this state relating to consumer protection and moving.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The provisions of this article apply to the operations of any mover engaged in the intrastate transportation of household goods, except that this article shall not be construed to include shipments contracted by the United States, the state, or any local government or subdivision thereof. The provision of this article shall only apply to the transportation of household goods originating in Miami-Dade County and terminating in Miami-Dade County, Broward County or Palm Beach County, or originating in Broward County or Palm Beach County and terminating in Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
It is the intent of this article to seek to secure the satisfaction and confidence of customers and members of the public when utilizing a mover. This article shall be effective in the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County and shall be liberally construed to effectuate the purposes set forth herein and to protect the public. This article shall be known and cited as the "Miami-Dade County Moving Ordinance."
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Nothing in this article shall be construed to remove the authority or jurisdiction of any state or local agency with respect to goods or services regulated or controlled under other provisions of law or ordinance.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
This article is not applicable to an act or practice required or specifically permitted by federal law or the law of this state.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The provisions of this article shall be deemed supplemental to all county and municipal ordinances. In the event of a conflict between any of the provisions of this article and any provision of any county or municipal ordinance, the provision which establishes the most stringent standard shall prevail.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 94-136, § 1, 7-12-94)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-327. Registration required</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
No person shall engage in business or advertise to engage in the business of moving or offer to move any person in this county as a mover of household goods without first obtaining a registration certificate from the Director pursuant to this article and maintaining such registration certificate as required herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Each mover shall register every year with the Director and, where applicable, provide to the Director: its legal business and trade name, current mailing address, and current business location for each place from which the mover operates either a main or branch office; a designation of which location constitutes its principal place of business; the full names, current mailing addresses, current telephone numbers, and social security numbers or federal tax identification numbers of its owners or corporate officers and directors; the Florida registered agent of the corporation; a statement listing the names of any other corporations, entities, or trade names through which any owner or director of the registrant was known or did business as a mover within the five (5) calendar years immediately preceding the date upon which the mover is submitting the application for registration; proof of vehicle liability insurance and general liability insurance; vehicle identification numbers; motor vehicle license tag numbers; gross weight of each commercial motor vehicle; the number of employees who are currently employed; proof of workers' compensation insurance coverage, as required by Chapter 440 of the Florida Statutes, or a State certificate of exemption, or a letter from the registrant affirming that such coverage is not required by law; proof of all insurance and liability coverage required by Section 8A-329 of this Code; a printed copy of each of the documents, instruments, forms, contracts, or other materials used by the registrant when dealing with the public with respect to the shipment of household goods, including, but not limited to bills of lading, contracts and disclosure statements; and other information and items as the Director shall require to enforce the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Any mover desiring to change its registered name, business location, or registered agent shall notify the Director of such change. No registration shall be valid for any mover under any other name or at any place other than that designated in the registration unless the Director is notified in writing within thirty (30) days of the change.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The Director shall require any person desiring to obtain a registration as a mover to do so on forms prescribed by the Director. Renewal of registrations may be staggered over the annual period by the Director to facilitate the workload. When obtaining a registration or renewing a registration as required by this article, each mover shall furnish to the Director a registration fee, to be established by administrative order of the County Manager. Said fee shall be effective upon approval by the Commission. All fees collected shall be deposited in a separate county fund to be utilized solely for the administration and enforcement of this article. No part of said fund shall be used for purposes other than the aforesaid.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The Director shall issue to each registrant a registration certificate in the form and size as prescribed by the Director. Such certificate shall be prominently displayed to the public in the mover's primary place of business. The registration number appearing on the registration certificate shall appear on all advertisements, forms, and commercial motor vehicles of the mover. For the purposes of this section, any advertisement shall be defined to include any announcement, listing, display, entry or other written statement of whatever nature or kind, and specifically to include a name and address or telephone number placed under a heading, where the heading describes or encompasses any kind of work regulated under this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The criteria for issuance of a registration certificate by the Director shall be compliance by the applicant with all the applicable provisions of this article and submission to the Director of a completed application for registration and applicable fees. An incomplete application shall be considered to be abandoned if an applicant fails to complete his or her application within sixty days from the date that the application was filed with the Director. An application submitted subsequent to the abandonment of a former application shall be treated as a new application. Registration certificates may be issued by the Director subject to such conditions, limitations, and restrictions imposed by the Director as the Director deems necessary to protect customers and consumers, provided such conditions, limitations, and restrictions are consistent with the provisions of this article. Violation of such a condition, limitation, or restriction of a registration certificate shall be a violation of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Change of ownership.
<section prefix = "1">
In the event of a change of ownership of a moving business, a new registration and payment of new registration fees shall be required. The moving business may continue to operate provided that the moving business has filed a completed application for registration with the Director and paid all applicable fees. For purposes of this subsection, "change of ownership" shall mean a change in the ownership or operators of a moving business which is either a sole proprietorship or partnership.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Corporations or other legal entities, other than sole proprietorships or partnerships, owning or operating a moving business which have a change of ten (10) percent or more of the ownership shall notify the Director of the change no later than thirty (30) days after the date of change.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 94-136, § 1, 7-12-94; Ord. No. 01-108, § 1, 6-19-01; Ord. No. 05-52, § 1, 3-1-05)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-327.1. Decals; moving vehicle signage</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
No moving company shall engage in moving household goods without first obtaining a decal from the Director for each vehicle used by the mover for moving household goods. The Director is authorized to charge a non-refundable vehicle decal fee for each moving vehicle in an amount set forth by administrative order of the county manager. Such fees shall be effective upon approval by the Commission. All fees collected shall be deposited in a separate County fund to be utilized solely for the administration and enforcement of this section. Except for short term rental vehicles, such decal shall be affixed to the lower left corner of the front window in the vehicle at all times, upon issuance of a vehicle decal. The vehicle decal remains the property of Miami-Dade County and shall be used only under the authority of the Director. No vehicle decal may be sold, assigned or otherwise transferred. If a vehicle is destroyed or sold, the mover must remove the vehicle decal (if in existence) and surrender the remains to the Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Vehicle decals issued to moving companies who use short term rental vehicles must be visible in the lower left corner of the front window or affixed to a magnetic sign on the driver's side of the vehicle.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Each vehicle decal issued pursuant to this section shall be renewed annually in the same manner as original application is made, upon application to the Director evidencing continued compliance with the provisions of this section. The Director is authorized to charge a non-refundable renewal fee in an amount set forth by administrative order of the county manager. Such fees shall be effective upon approval by the Commission. All fees collected shall be deposited in a separate County fund to be utilized solely for the administration and enforcement of this section. Decals shall expire concurrent with the expiration of the moving registration certificate.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The decal for each moving vehicle shall at all times be displayed and available for inspection by any police officer or by personnel authorized by the Director to perform enforcement duties.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Each moving vehicle must clearly display signage, on the exterior of the driver and passenger sides, with letters at least three (3) inches high and in contrasting colors, the moving company's name, physical address, telephone number and moving registration certificate number. If the short term use of a rental vehicle by a moving company is necessary, at a minimum, the same information and requirements must be affixed to the vehicle through the use of magnetic signs.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 01-108, § 1, 6-19-01; Ord. No. 05-52, § 1, 3-1-05)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-328. Loss, destruction, or mutilation of registration certificate or decal; replacement</catch_line>
<text>
In the event of loss, destruction, or mutilation of a registration certificate or decal issued pursuant to the provisions of this article, the person to whom the registration certificate was issued may obtain a replacement thereof upon furnishing satisfactory proof of loss, destruction, or mutilation to the Director and payment of the applicable fee established by administrative order of the County Manager. Applications for a replacement certificate or decal shall include the following information:
<section prefix = "a">
Name and address of the applicant.

</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A verified explanation of the loss, destruction, or mutilation of the registration certificate or decal.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Such other items and information as may be required by the Director.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-329. Valid certificate of insurance for cargo legal liability valuation and insurance</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The registrant shall furnish the Director with a valid certificate of insurance for cargo legal liability valuation and insurance which shall be valid for the period of registration and shall include at a minimum the following:
<section prefix = "1">
Valuation of sixty cents ($0.60) per pound per article; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Insurance for loss or damage to household goods as a result of loss or damage to any commercial motor vehicle, with the exception of loss or damage as the result of acts of God, in the amount of no less than ten thousand dollars ($10,000.00) per shipment; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Motor vehicle combined bodily liability insurance and property damage liability insurance which shall be issued by an insurance carrier or company which is a participant in the Florida Insurance Guaranty Association and which shall be in accordance with the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Fifty thousand dollars ($50,000.00) per occurrence for a commercial motor vehicle with a gross vehicle weight of less than 35,000 pounds.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
One hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00) per occurrence for a commercial motor vehicle with a gross vehicle weight of 35,000 pounds or more, but less than 44,000 pounds.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Three hundred thousand dollars ($300,000.00) per occurrence for a commercial motor vehicle with a gross vehicle weight of 44,000 pounds or more.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The insurance carrier or company shall qualify as an insurance company authorized to transact insurance in the State of Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Said insurance shall be kept in full force and effect by the certificate holder at all times. Failure to file evidence of such insurance with the Director, or failure to maintain the same in full force and effect, may be cause for the suspension or revocation of the registration certificate of the mover. Said insurance shall provide that the certificate holder's insurance coverage may neither expire nor be canceled prior to thirty (30) days after the Director receives written notice of said expiration or cancellation from the carrier.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 94-136, § 1, 7-12-94)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-330. Contract for service and disclosure statement required</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
In any agreement for service, the mover shall prepare a written contract for service. The contract for service shall be provided by the mover to the shipper for the shipper's written authorization and signature before commencing the performance of any transportation or accessorial services.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A contract for service shall clearly and conspicuously disclose, at a minimum, the following:
<section prefix = "1">
The name and telephone number of the mover and the address of the mover at which employees of the mover are on duty during business hours.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The name of the shipper, the addresses at which the items are to be picked up and delivered, if available; and a telephone number where the shipper may be reached, if available.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The agreed pickup and delivery date, or the period of time within which pickup, delivery, or the entire move will be accomplished, if provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
A description of the transportation and accessorial services expected to be provided during a move.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
In the event that no estimate has been provided pursuant to this article, the total cost of the transportation and accessorial services to be provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
The method of payment, subject to the provisions of Section 8A-334 of this Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
In the event that an estimate has been provided pursuant to this article, the maximum amount required to be paid by the shipper to the mover at the time of delivery, subject to the provisions of Section 8A-332 of this Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
The name and telephone number of any other person who may authorize pickup or delivery of any items to be transported, if the shipper designates such a person in writing.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
A statement regarding the mover's limitation of liability, subject to the provisions of Section 8A-336 of this Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
A brief description of the procedures for shipper inquiry and complaint handling and a telephone number which the shipper may use to communicate with the mover, accompanied by a statement disclosing who shall pay for such calls if other than the mover.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
If the cost for services provided is based on weight, a statement that the shipper has a right to observe any weighing before and after loading.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The contract for service provided by a mover to a shipper shall include the following language in bold capitalized letters of at least 12-point type:
PLEASE READ CAREFULLY:
THIS CONTRACT FOR SERVICE IS REQUIRED BY COUNTY LAW AND MUST INCLUDE THE TERMS AND COSTS ASSOCIATED WITH YOUR MOVE. IN ORDER FOR THE CONTRACT FOR SERVICE TO BE ACCURATE, YOU MUST DISCLOSE ALL INFORMATION RELEVANT TO THE MOVE TO THE MOVER. COUNTY LAW REQUIRES THAT A MOVER RELINQUISH POSSESSION OF YOUR GOODS AND COMPLETE YOUR MOVE UPON PAYMENT OF NO MORE THAN THE SPECIFIED MAXIMUM AMOUNT DUE AT DELIVERY.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Prior to beginning the move, the mover shall present to the shipper a copy of the Moving Consumer Bill of Rights and Disclosure Statement (Disclosure Statement) on its letterhead in the form approved and as amended by the Director. The Disclosure Statement shall be signed by the mover and shipper and shall indicate the time of each signature.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The Disclosure Statement, once signed and dated by the mover and shipper, shall be incorporated in the mover's contract for services and shall bind all parties.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Failure to present the Disclosure Statement shall constitute a violation of this Section and shall be subject to civil penalties described in this Chapter.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 94-136, § 1, 7-12-94; Ord. No. 01-108, § 1, 6-19-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-331. Estimates of moving costs</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
A mover shall provide to the shipper a written estimate of the costs for moving the shipper's household goods, to include all transportation and accessorial services. No mover shall charge for preparing an estimate unless, prior to preparing the estimate, the mover:
<section prefix = "1">
Clearly and conspicuously discloses in writing to the customer the amount of the charge for preparing the estimate or, if the amount cannot be determined, the complete basis upon which the charge will be calculated, and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Obtains the customer's written authorization on the written estimate to prepare an estimate.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
It is unlawful for a mover to require a shipper to waive the shipper's right to a written estimate. A shipper cannot waive the shipper's right to a written estimate.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The written estimate provided to the shipper shall, at a minimum, include the following:
<section prefix = "1">
The total cost for transportation and accessorial services to be provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
A description of the transportation and accessorial services to be provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
A listing of the basis for which any charges may be assessed for the transportation and accessorial services to be provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The following language in bold capitalized letters of at least 12-point type:
UNDER COUNTY LAW YOU ARE ENTITLED TO A WRITTEN ESTIMATE OF THE TOTAL COST OF YOUR MOVE AND A COPY OF THE DISCLOSURE STATEMENT. PLEASE REVIEW THESE DOCUMENTS TO MAKE SURE THEY ARE COMPLETE.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
A copy of the estimate, signed by the mover, shall be delivered to the shipper prior to performing any transportation or accessorial service and a copy shall be maintained by the mover as part of the mover's records.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Nothing in this article shall be construed to require a customer to enter into a contract for service with a mover based upon the issuance of an estimate.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The estimate and disclosure may be provided on the same form as the contract for service.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
No mover shall provide an oral estimate to any customer.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Reserved.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Mover shall provide to the consumer, at the time of performing a moving estimate, a copy of Moving Consumer Bill of Rights and Disclosure Statement on its letterhead, in the form approved and as amended by the Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Failure to present the Disclosure Statement shall constitute a violation of this Section and shall be subject to civil penalties described in this Chapter.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 94-136, § 1, 7-12-94; Ord. No. 01-108, § 1, 6-19-01; Ord. No. 05-52, § 1, 3-1-05)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-332. Charges in excess of written estimate; unlawful charges; refusal to relinquish goods prohibited</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
A mover shall not charge more than the total amount of the written estimate unless there is a change in the requested services. If a change in the requested services results in additional cost, the mover shall prepare and execute a new contract for services consistent with such changes prior to the performance of any transportation or accessorial services.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
It is unlawful for a mover to fail to relinquish to a shipper any of the shipper's household goods or to fail to timely complete all transportation and accessorial services required to be performed pursuant to the contract for service because the shipper has refused to pay for charges in excess of the amount set forth in (a) above or in excess of the total amount set forth in the contract for service as required by Section 8A-330(b)(5).
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The mover shall relinquish possession of all of the shipper's household goods to the shipper and timely complete all transportation and accessorial services required to be performed pursuant to the contract for service upon payment of the total amount set forth in the contract for service as required by Section 8A-330(b)(5).
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
It is unlawful for a mover to charge a consumer for equipment. However, the shipper may purchase, lease or rent the equipment, if necessary, for storage purposes only at a location other than the mover's storage facility.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 94-136, § 1, 7-12-94; Ord. No. 01-108, § 1, 6-19-01; Ord. No. 05-52, § 1, 3-1-05)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-333. Inventory</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
A written inventory shall be prepared by the mover, unless the shipper waives, in writing, preparation of an inventory. The written inventory shall be prepared and signed by both the shipper and the mover prior to departure of the mover's motor vehicle from the shipper's pick-up point(s). No mover shall charge for preparing an inventory unless, prior to preparing the inventory, the mover:
<section prefix = "1">
Clearly and conspicuously discloses in writing to the customer the amount of the charge for preparation of the inventory or, if the amount cannot be determined, the complete basis upon which the charge will be calculated.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
It is unlawful for a mover to require a shipper to waive the preparation of an inventory.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 94-136, § 1, 7-12-94)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-334. Acceptable forms of payment</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
A mover shall accept a minimum of two (2) of the following methods of payment:
<section prefix = "1">
Cash, cashier's check, money order, or traveler's check; or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Valid personal check, showing on its face the name and address of the shipper or authorized representative; or
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Valid credit card, which shall include but not be limited to Visa or MasterCard.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A mover shall clearly and conspicuously disclose to the shipper in the contract for service and estimate which methods of payment the mover will accept pursuant to this section.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 94-136, § 1, 7-12-94)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-335. Reasonable dispatch</catch_line>
<text>
Except when delays are caused by actions of the shipper, or circumstances beyond the control of the mover, the following shall apply:
<section prefix = "1">
Each mover shall cause shipments to be transported on the dates or during the time period agreed upon by the mover and the shipper and specified in the contract for service.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
A shipper may seek recourse in a court of competent jurisdiction if a mover fails to perform either pickup or delivery or any accessorial services as agreed upon in the contract for service and the shipper incurs any reasonable expenses that would not otherwise have been incurred.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-336. Liability of movers</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
A mover shall not limit valuation on a shipment of household goods to an amount less than sixty cents ($0.60) per pound per article in the shipment. Except when the shipper chooses a declared valuation in excess of the minimum valuation, a mover shall offer the minimum coverage at no additional charge to a shipper.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A mover shall disclose to the consumer/shipper on its bill of lading and/or contract the applicable valuation for a shipper's household goods and the availability of additional valuation coverage or insurance up to the declared value of shipment, which may be purchased by the customer at an additional cost. The rejection or selection of additional valuation coverage shall be made in writing on a form prescribed by the Director. The form shall fully advise the shipper of the nature of the limitation of valuation and shall state that the minimum coverage is equal to the limit referred to in subsection (a) unless otherwise requested. The heading of the form shall be in 12-point bold type and shall state: "By signing this form, you are waiving certain valuable coverage which protects your possessions above the minimum amounts set by law. Please read carefully."
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 94-136, § 1, 7-12-94; Ord. No. 01-108, § 1, 6-19-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-337. Records; inquiry or complaint handling; inspection</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
A mover shall maintain moving records which shall include, but not be limited to, all estimates and contracts for services. All such records held by the mover shall be available for inspection and copying by the Director, for a period of at least five (5) years from the date of completion of performance of the contract for service.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A mover shall establish and maintain a procedure for responding to inquiries and complaints from shippers. The procedure shall include a means whereby the shipper may communicate with the principal office of the mover by telephone.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The mover shall retain and make part of the file relating to a shipment a written record of all complaints and inquiries received from a shipper.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
All complaints and inquiries on file with the Director pertaining to a contract for service or mover shall be a public record open to public inspection as required by state law.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The premises and all commercial motor vehicles of all movers shall be open to the Director for inspection, investigation or for such other purposes as are necessary for the enforcement and administration of this article during the business hours of the mover and in no event not less than between the hours of 9:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m., Monday through Friday, except legal holidays.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Each complaint filed with the Director against a moving company shall be provided to the moving company by the Director and the moving company shall promptly and thoroughly investigate said complaint. If the complaint cannot be satisfied within ten (10) days from receipt by the moving company, the moving company shall advise the Director of the status of the complaint and the reason for the delay. A moving company shall object to or satisfy the complaint filed by the consumer and provide the Director with a written response stating the disposition of the complaint, the specific reasons for the objection, if applicable, no later than ninety (90) days after receipt of the complaint by the moving company.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 94-136, § 1, 7-12-94; Ord. No. 01-108, § 1, 6-19-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-338. Collection of freight charges on shipments involving loss or destruction in transit</catch_line>
<text>
No mover shall collect, or shall require a shipper to pay, any charges when a shipper's household goods are totally lost or destroyed. The shipper shall, however, remain liable for any charges for valuation coverage, pursuant to Section 8A-336 of this Code, or any insurance premium related to the shipment for which the insurance was secured from a third party.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-339. Claims</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
No claim against a mover for damage under this article shall be denied solely because the damage was not noted at the time of delivery. If a customer files a claim for loss or damage not noted at the time of delivery, a mover remains obligated to investigate such claim.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Whenever a mover requires a signed statement acknowledging delivery or receipt of items, the statement shall include a clear and conspicuous notice that the shipper may make notations regarding the household goods as delivered, and that the shipper may file a claim with the mover for lost or damaged household goods.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
A shipper shall have a period of up to sixty (60) days after the completion of delivery of the household goods to notify a mover in writing of any claim for loss, damage, or delay resulting from the performance of its contract for service.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Each claim filed against a mover shall be promptly and thoroughly investigated by the mover. If the claim cannot be satisfied within thirty (30) days, the mover shall advise the claimant of the status of the claim and the reason for the delay. A mover shall object to or satisfy a claim filed by a shipper no later than ninety (90) days after receipt of the claim.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
When an asserted claim made to a mover for loss of an item or an entire shipment cannot be otherwise authenticated upon investigation, the mover may request from the shipper, and the shipper shall be required to sign, a sworn statement in writing that the household goods for which the claim is filed has not been received from any other source. If the shipper presents a false or fraudulent statement, the shipper shall be liable for damages to the mover.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 94-136, § 1, 7-12-94)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-340. Director's duties, functions and powers</catch_line>
<text>
The duties, functions, powers and responsibilities of the Director shall include the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Enforce all of the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Upon receipt of complaints or upon the Director's initiative, investigate, inspect, sample, and test any matters regulated hereunder.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Institute civil actions or proceedings to enforce all the provisions of this article and subpoenae issued by the Director, including seeking mandatory and prohibitory injunctions, the imposition and recovery of civil penalties and such other remedies and attorney's fees as set forth in Section 8A-348 of this Code. Such civil actions or proceedings may be instituted by the Director regardless of whether a cease and desist order or notice to correct the violation or other lawful order of the Director has been issued or other administrative proceeding is pending.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Prosecute through the State Attorney in the criminal courts for violations of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Deny, revoke, suspend and issue registration certificates and impose conditions, limitations, and restrictions upon same in accordance with Sections 8A-327 and 8A-343 of this Code. Notwithstanding the foregoing, no revocation or suspension of a registration certificate by the Director shall be effective until the rendition of the appeal, if any, of such revocation or suspension pursuant to Section 8A-349 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, or until the time period for filing such appeal has expired, whichever is later.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Issue subpoenae to compel the presence of any person or document or thing at any hearing, conference or proceeding authorized herein upon information or belief by the Director that a violation of any provision of this article has occurred or may occur.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Inquire into the practices, functions and policies of movers and make such recommendations to the Commission as the Director may deem necessary.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Administer oaths and certify official acts of the Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Investigate, upon the Director's initiative, the practices of any mover.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Apply to any judge of the circuit or county court, criminal or civil division, for the issuance of an administrative search warrant.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Conduct a program for monitoring consumer satisfaction levels in the field of moving and make such monitoring information available to the Commission and the public.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Render, in the Director's discretion, assistance and technical advice to movers.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
Institute informal conferences for discussing and resolving any matter covered by this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "n">
Publish and disseminate information to the public concerning movers.
</section>
<section prefix = "o">
Submit to the Commission proposed rules, regulations, and standards to effectuate the purposes of this article. No such proposed rules, regulations, and standards shall become effective until approved by the Commission by ordinance.
</section>
<section prefix = "p">
Provide movers with information concerning the rules, regulations, and standards enacted during the immediate past year.
</section>
<section prefix = "q">
Issue cease and desist orders, notices to correct violations, and any other lawful orders of the Director which shall briefly set forth the general nature of the violation of this article and specify the time within which the violation shall be rectified or stopped. If an order to cease and desist or notice to correct violations or any other lawful order of the Director is not obeyed, the Director shall have the power and authority to revoke or suspend the registration certificate, if any has been issued, or deny the issuance of a registration certificate and take such other action authorized by this article. Notwithstanding the foregoing, no revocation or suspension of a registration certificate by the Director shall be effective until the rendition of the appeal, if any, of such revocation or suspension pursuant to Section 8A-349 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, or until the time period for filing such appeal has expired, whichever is later. Orders to cease and desist, notices to correct violations, and any other lawful orders of the Director hereunder may be enforced by the institution by the Director of civil actions for mandatory and prohibitory injunctions, civil penalties and other remedies and attorney's fees as set forth in Section 8A-348 of the Code of Miami-Dade County in a court of competent jurisdiction.
</section>
<section prefix = "r">
Appoint and designate, in the Director's discretion, various technical advisory panels.
</section>
<section prefix = "s">
Enter into written assurances of compliance pursuant to Sections 8A-82.1 and 8A-342 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, with respect to the matters regulated under this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "t">
Enter into a cooperative agreement with the Florida Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, subject to approval by the Board of County Commissioners, for the referral, investigation and prosecution of consumer complaints related to the intrastate transportation of household goods pursuant to Section 507.13, Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "u">
The powers of the Director enumerated in this article shall be in addition to and not a limitation of any other powers of the Director pursuant to any other provisions of this article or any other provisions of law or ordinance.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-341. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 95-137, § 2, adopted July 25, 1995, repealed former § 8A-341, relative to the movers consumer services board, which derived from Ord. No. 94-136, § 1, adopted July 12, 1994.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-342. Assurances of compliance</catch_line>
<text>
Each violation of any of the terms and conditions of a verified, written assurance entered into pursuant to Section 8A-82.1 of the Code with respect to the matters regulated under this article shall constitute a separate offense under this article by the persons who executed the assurance, their respective officers, directors, agents, servants, and employees; and by those persons in active concert or participation with any of the foregoing persons and who receive actual notice of the assurance of compliance. Decisions, actions, and determinations of the Director, pursuant to Sections 8A-82.1 and 8A-340(s) or assurances of compliance executed thereunder, shall not be subject to review pursuant to Section 8A-349 of this Code.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-343. Denial, revocation and suspension of certificates</catch_line>
<text>
The Director may deny, revoke, or suspend a registration certificate issued pursuant to the provisions of this article if the Director determines that the applicant or registrant has:
<section prefix = "a">
Violated any provision of this article, or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Misrepresented or concealed a fact on the application, renewal application or replacement application for a registration certificate, or
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Aided or abetted a person who has not obtained a registration certificate to evade or avoid the provisions of this article, or
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Engaged in any conduct as part of the performance of a contract for service which constitutes fraud, or
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Violated any condition, limitation, or restriction of a registration certificate imposed by the Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Was enjoined by a court of competent jurisdiction from engaging in the trade or business of moving or was enjoined by a court of competent jurisdiction with respect to any of the requirements of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Failed to comply with the terms of a cease and desist order, notice to correct a violation, written assurance of compliance, or any other lawful order of the Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Was convicted of a violation of this article.

Notwithstanding the foregoing, no revocation or suspension of a registration certificate by the Director shall be effective until the rendition of the appeal, if any, of such revocation or suspension pursuant to Section 8A-349 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, or until the time period for filing such appeal has expired, whichever is later.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-344. Civil penalties</catch_line>
<text>
In addition to any other judicial or administrative remedies or penalties provided by law, rule, regulation or ordinance, any person who violates any of the provisions of this article or any cease and desist order of the Director or any notice to correct a violation or any assurance of compliance entered into pursuant to Section 8A-82.1 of the Code and this article with respect to matters regulated under this article or any other lawful order of the Director or any condition, limitation, or restriction of a registration certificate issued by the Director, shall be subject to the judicial imposition and recovery of a civil penalty in an amount of not more than ten thousand dollars ($10,000.00) per offense. Each day during any portion of which such violation occurs or continues to occur constitutes a separate offense. Such monies recovered by the Director shall be deposited in a separate county fund to be used exclusively for enforcement of this article.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-345. Criminal penalties</catch_line>
<text>
In addition to any other judicial or administrative remedies or penalties provided by law, rule, regulation or ordinance, if any person violates or fails or refuses to obey or comply with any of the provisions of this article or any lawful order of the Director or any cease and desist order of the Director or any notice to correct a violation of the Director or any assurance of compliance entered into pursuant to Section 8A-82.1 of the Code and this article, or any condition, limitation, or restriction of a registration certificate issued by the Director, such person, upon conviction of any such offense, shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00), or by imprisonment not to exceed sixty (60) days in the county jail, or both, in the discretion of the court. Each day or portion thereof of continuing violation shall be deemed a separate offense.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-346. Presumption of continuous operation</catch_line>
<text>
Except as expressly provided otherwise in this article, any person operating as a mover without first obtaining a registration certificate pursuant to this article shall be presumed to be operating as a mover on a continuous basis without a registration certificate from the date the registration certificate was first required by this article. Such presumption may be overcome by evidence presented by the mover. This section creates a rebuttable presumption of continuous operation.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-347. Private cause of action</catch_line>
<text>
Any person who suffers a loss as a result of a violation of any of the provisions of this article, any lawful order of the Director, any cease and desist order or notice to correct a violation issued by the Director or any assurance of compliance entered into pursuant to Section 8A-82.1 of the Code and this article, may recover compensatory damages, punitive damages, attorney's fees, and court costs from the person committing such violation. Nothing herein shall be construed to require the Director to bring any such action on behalf of a private person.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-348. Enforcement procedure; remedies; attorney's fees; costs</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It shall be unlawful for any person to violate any of the provisions of this article. In addition to any other judicial or administrative remedies provided by law, rule, regulation, ordinance, or this article, the Director shall have the following judicial remedies available to enforce the provisions of this article:
<section prefix = "1">
The Director may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to seek temporary or permanent, prohibitory or mandatory injunctive relief to enforce compliance with or prohibit the violation of any of the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Director may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to impose and recover a civil penalty in an amount of not more than ten thousand dollars ($10,000.00) for each violation of any of the provisions of this article. Each day during any portion of which such violation occurs or continues to occur constitutes a separate violation. The right of trial by jury shall be available in any court to determine both liability for and the amount of the civil penalties to be imposed and recovered hereunder.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Director may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to seek restitution and other equitable relief:
<section prefix = "i">
To recover any sums and costs expended by the Director for tracing, investigating, preventing, controlling, abating or remedying any violation of any of the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
To provide restitution to any customers or consumers injured by any violation of any of the provisions of this article.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Upon the rendition of a judgment or decree by any of the courts of this state against any person and in favor of the Director under any of the provisions of this article, the trial court, or, in the event of an appeal in which the Director prevails, the appellate court, shall adjudge or decree against said person and in favor of the Director a reasonable sum as fees or compensation for the Director's attorney prosecuting the suit in which the recovery is had. Where so awarded, compensation or fees of the attorney shall be included in the judgment or decree rendered in the case. This provision shall apply to all civil actions, legal or equitable, filed after the effective date of this article by the Director. Cessation of any violation of any of the provisions of this article whatsoever, prior to rendition of a judgment or entry of a temporary or final decree, or prior to execution of a negotiated settlement, but after an action is filed by the Director under any of the provisions of this article, shall be deemed the functional equivalent of a confession of judgment or verdict in favor of the Director, for which attorney's fees shall be awarded by the trial court as set forth hereinabove.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All the judicial and administrative remedies in this article are independent and cumulative.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 94-136, § 1, 7-12-94)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-349. Appeals from actions, decisions or determinations of the director; judicial review</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Any person regulated by this article who is aggrieved by any action, decision or determination of the Director pursuant to this article may request an administrative hearing before a hearing officer to appeal the action, decision or determination of the Director which resulted in the grievance. Appeal by administrative hearing of the action, decision or determination complained of shall be accomplished by filing a written request with the Director within fifteen (15) days after the date of the action, decision or determination complained of, a written notice of appeal which shall set forth the nature of the action, decision or determination to be reviewed and the basis for the administrative hearing. A timely request for administrative hearing shall be scheduled and heard by a Hearing Officer pursuant to Section 8CC of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. Customers shall not be deemed to be persons regulated by this article for the purposes of this section. The Hearing Officer shall set the matter for hearing on the earliest practicable regularly scheduled hearing date or as soon as possible, but no sooner than ten (10) days after the request has been filed and shall cause notice of the hearing to be served upon the aggrieved party by first class mail. The notice may include, but not be limited to, the applicable Sections of 8CC-6(b)(2) through (9) of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. The Hearing Officer shall hear and consider all relevant facts in accordance with the procedures set forth in Sections 8CC-6(e), (f), (g), (i), (j), (k), (l), (m)(2), and (n) of the Code of Miami-Dade county (any reference in these sections to Inspector shall mean "Director" and to violator shall mean "the person filing the appeal", and may affirm, modify or reverse the action, decision or determination appealed from. The decision of the Hearing Officer shall constitute final administrative review and no rehearing shall be permitted. Nothing herein shall be construed to prevent or prohibit the Director from instituting any civil or criminal action or proceeding authorized by this article at any time.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Director, the Miami-Dade County Consumer Advocate, or any person regulated by this article who is aggrieved by any decision of the Hearing Officer may appeal a final order of the Hearing Officer by filing a notice of appeal in the Circuit Court in and for Miami-Dade County, Florida, in accordance with procedures and within the time provided by the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure for review of administrative action. The words "action," "decision" and "determination" as used herein shall not include the filing or institution of any action, conference or proceeding by the Director in any court or otherwise. Customers shall not be deemed to be persons regulated by this article for the purposes of this section.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 94-136, § 1, 7-12-94; Ord. No. 97-69, § 3, 6-3-97)</history>
</law>
