<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 29 TAXATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_IV._UTILITY_TAX</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-36. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
For the purposes hereof, the following words and phrases shall have the meanings respectively ascribed to them by this section:
Bottled gas: All types and kinds of natural, liquefied petroleum and manufactured gas for lighting, heating, cooking, power or any other purpose delivered to any purchaser thereof within the unincorporated area of Miami-Dade County.
Coal: All coal for lighting, heating, cooking, power, energy or any other purpose competing with any other utility or energy source taxed under this chapter delivered to any purchaser thereof within the unincorporated area of Miami-Dade County.
Coin-Box Telephone service: Service relating to coin-box telephones installed within the unincorporated area of Miami-Dade County, insofar as such service requires the payment of a guaranteed amount, but such term shall not pertain to nor include the service rendered at the time of and in consideration of the deposit of money in the telephone coin-boxes.
Electricity: All electric current or energy for lighting, heating, cooking, power or any other purpose delivered to any purchaser thereof within the unincorporated area [of Miami-Dade County].
Fuel oil: All bunker C oil, number 1 and 2 fuel oil, and kerosene or any combination thereof capable of being used for lighting, heating, cooking, power or any other purpose and delivered to any purchaser thereof within the unincorporated area of Miami-Dade County.
Metered gas: All types and kinds of natural and manufactured gas for lighting, heating, cooking, power or any other purpose delivered to any purchaser thereof within the unincorporated area of Miami-Dade County.
Purchase: Every act or transaction whereby possession of, utilization of, control over or title to electricity, water, metered gas, bottled gas, coal, fuel oil, and the duty and obligation to pay therefor become vested in the purchaser within the unincorporated area of Miami-Dade County, but such term shall not pertain to nor include any such act or transaction when undertaken or performed by an agency or instrumentality of the United States Government, the State, the County or a municipality.
Purchaser: Every person legally liable for the payment of electricity, water, metered gas, bottled gas, coal or fuel oil delivery rendered to him, by a seller, unless such person is an agency or instrumentality of the United States Government, the State, the County, a municipality, or a house of public worship, which qualifies for exemption from the State sales tax under Section 212.08(7)(c)(1), Florida Statutes.
Seller: Every person delivering electricity, water, metered gas, bottled gas, coal or fuel oil to any purchaser thereof.
Telegraph service: All types and kinds of service as are rendered by telegraph companies to any purchaser of such service within the unincorporated area of Miami-Dade County.
Water service: The water supply furnished to all consumers in the unincorporated area of Miami-Dade County for retail use and not for resale, except water delivered to a purchaser in a bottle or other container.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-37. Rate and amount of excise tax on purchase of public utility services: Collection of tax</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby levied and imposed by the County upon every purchase in the unincorporated area of electricity, metered gas, bottled gas, coal, fuel oil, and water service, included in or reflected by any bill rendered by the seller to the purchaser an excise tax which shall be determined as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
When the seller, in accordance with his rules and regulations, renders a bill to the purchaser to cover purchases made during the period of time to which the bill is applicable, the amount of excise tax shall be ten (10) percent of the total amount shown on any such bill due and payable on account of such purchases (not exceeding four cents ($0.04) per gallon for purchases of fuel oil), exclusive of governmental charges, annual service fees collected pursuant to Section 32-54 of the Code, and adjustments caused by the increased cost of energy-producing fuels, provided such governmental charges, service fees, taxes and fuel adjustments are shown separately on any such bill.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
In the use and application set out in this section, purchases of electricity, metered gas, bottled gas, coal, fuel oil and water service, shall be considered and treated as constituting and being distinct and unrelated classes of purchases, and in the event that more than one (1) such class shall be shown upon the same bill, the amount of excise tax payable pursuant hereto shall be determined and computed for each such class separately.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The seller is required and it shall be his duty to render to each purchaser bills covering all such purchases made, and the amount of such excise tax shall be entered and shown by the seller as a separate item on each such bill and shall become due and payable to the County whenever such bill becomes due and payable under the rules and regulations of the seller. Each such bill shall include purchases applicable to but one (1) location, or to but one (1) family or business where more than one (1) family or business uses separate metered services at one (1) location in the unincorporated areas.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The purchaser is required and it shall be his duty to pay such excise tax to the seller, as agent for the County, at the time of the payment of each such bill, and in the event that the purchaser shall fail, neglect or refuse to pay such excise tax to the seller when such bill becomes due and payable, the seller is hereby empowered to discontinue forthwith to make any further sales or to render any further service to the purchaser until the total amount, including such excise tax, shown upon such bill has been paid in full. The seller is hereby authorized and required and it shall be his duty to collect such excise tax from such purchaser at the time of the payment of each such bill and to remit the same to the Finance Department in accordance with the provisions hereinafter stated, provided that the seller shall have the right and privilege of assuming and paying such excise tax himself in lieu of collecting the same from the purchaser; and that whenever the seller shall fail or neglect to collect such excise tax from the purchaser within one (1) year from the date of the bill on which such tax was or should have been imposed, the seller shall be deemed to have assumed such excise tax himself and shall thereupon become liable for the payment of the amount thereof to the County to the same extent as if such excise tax had been collected from the purchaser, with further recourse to the purchaser therefor.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
This section shall be applicable to all bills for electricity, metered gas, bottled gas, coal, fuel oil, taxable telecommunications service, and water service; except that any bills for the purchase of sixteen (16) ounces or less of bottled gas in a container or less than one (1) gallon of fuel oil shall be exempt from taxation, and further in reference to those purchases enumerated in Section 166.231, Florida Statutes, this article shall only apply to the extent permitted therein; the sale of fuel oil and coal to a public or private utility; either for resale or for use as fuel in the generation of electricity; or the sale of fuel used for the propulsion of land, water or air vehicles or as fuel for other engines, the use of which does not compete with those utilities or energy sources specified in Section 166.231, Florida Statutes. There is further exempted from the tax hereby imposed, fuel and electricity used to operate farm machinery, irrigation pumps and agricultural first-processing machinery.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Any provision of this section to the contrary notwithstanding, all taxes included in any bill which contains any charge for services rendered prior to October 1, 1970, are waived, whether such taxes have been paid or not, and all sellers shall refund collected taxes or give credit therefor at their option.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
There shall be a 50% exemption for any business which is new or substantially expanded from the tax levied by this section on the purchase of electricity, provided the business is located on or within an enterprise zone as established by Florida Statutes and is determined eligible for such exemption by the Department of Revenue of the State of Florida. The exemption shall be available for all businesses determined qualified as provided in Section 29-37(8) below for five (5) years from the date of such determination, provided that no business shall be deemed qualified for the exemption after December 31, 2015.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
A business shall apply for the exemption provided in Section 29-37(7) above by presenting evidence of qualification to the Office of Community and Economic Development (OCED) of Miami-Dade County in a form approved by the Director of OCED. Upon presentation of acceptable evidence of qualification, the Director shall forward such evidence to the Department of Revenue of the State of Florida for a determination as to whether the business is eligible for the exemption provided herein.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-38. Remittance of tax to County by seller</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Every seller is hereby required to execute and file not later than the twentieth day of each month at the office of the Finance Department a certified statement on a form prescribed by such Department, setting forth the amount of such excise tax to which the County became entitled under the provisions hereof on account of bills paid by purchasers during the preceding fiscal month, and contemporaneously with the filing of such statements, shall pay the amount of such excise tax to the Finance Department. All collected tax, interest and penalties shall be deposited to the credit of the general fund of the County to be expended for governmental purposes solely within the unincorporated area or for Countywide projects or purposes that will benefit the residents of the unincorporated area.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Interest is assessed at the rate of 1 percent per month of the delinquent tax from the date that the tax was originally due until paid. In the event of an administrative or judicial determination that additional taxes are due, interest shall run from the date that the taxes were originally due, not from the date of the administrative or judicial determination.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Penalties. Failure to file a return shall be subject to a penalty of no less than fifteen dollars ($15.00). Upon a finding that the failure [to remit] any tax or file a return was due to willful neglect or willful negligence a penalty of 5 percent per month of the delinquent tax, not to exceed a total penalty of 25 percent shall be imposed. Furthermore, in the event a finding is made that the taxpayer submitted a fraudulent return or willfully intended to evade payment of the tax, a specific penalty of 100 percent of the tax. Any penalty imposed shall be in addition to interest due pursuant to subsection (b).
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The Board of County Commissioners has the authority to settle or compromise a seller's liability for any such tax, interest, or penalty as provided in Section 166.234, Florida Statutes.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 70-72, § 3, 9-21-70; Ord. No. 71-36, § 1, 5-4-71; Ord. No. 83-86, § 1, 9-20-83; Ord. No. 84-26, § 1, 4-3-84; Ord. No. 11-48, § 2, 7-7-11)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-39. Records to be kept</catch_line>
<text>
Every seller is hereby required to establish and maintain appropriate accounts and records showing in such detail as the Finance Director may prescribe the amount of such excise tax payable to the County under the provisions hereof, and such accounts and records shall be open to inspection by the Finance Director or his duly authorized agent at all reasonable times. The Finance Director is hereby authorized and empowered to promulgate from time to time such rules and regulations with respect to the establishment and maintenance of such accounts and records as he may deem necessary to carry into effect the purpose and intent of the provisions hereof.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-40. Reports of deliveries for resale</catch_line>
<text>
Every manufacturer, distributor, wholesaler or seller who shall deliver electricity, metered gas, bottled gas, coal, fuel oil, telephone service, telegraph service or water service, to any seller or other person having a place of business in the unincorporated area of Miami-Dade County, or licensed to do business therein, to be sold or resold to ultimate purchasers, shall report to the Finance Department semi-annually, as of June 30th and December 31st, the names and addresses of such sellers or other persons, and the quantities received by each of them during the preceding six (6) months, such reports to be filed not later than one month after the close of each semi-annual period.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-41. Recognition of expense in regulation of rates</catch_line>
<text>
All reasonable expense incurred by a seller in making the collections and remittances and in fulfilling the duties prescribed herein is hereby declared to be and to constitute an operating expense and shall be accorded full recognition as such in the establishment of rates and charges for rendering electric, metered gas, bottled gas, coal, fuel oil, or water service in the County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-42. Violations</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful and a violation hereof for any purchaser to evade the payment of the excise tax provided for herein or any part thereof, or to fail or neglect to pay such excise tax within thirty (30) days after the same has become due and payable; or for any seller to fail or refuse to pay to the County all amounts of excise tax payable to the County by the seller, or to fail or refuse to file the monthly certified statement or to set forth any erroneous or false information therein with intent to defraud the County, or to refuse to permit the Finance Director or his duly authorized agent to examine the accounts and records to be kept as required hereby.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (4) ---
Editor's note— Article IV, §§ 29-36—29-42, is derived from Ord. No. 70-72, §§ 1—7, enacted Sept. 21, 1970, effective Oct. 1, 1970. Section 9 of said ordinance authorized inclusion of said ordinance as a part of this Code. (Back)
Charter reference— Authority to levy tax, § 1.01(D). (Back)
State Law reference— Utility tax, F.S. § 166.231 et seq. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
