<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_LI._MIAMI-DADE_COUNTY_HIV_HEALTH</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-551. Creation and purposes</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created and established the Miami-Dade County HIV Health Services Planning Council. The Council's purpose is to enable the County to apply for, receive and allocate financial assistance under the Ryan White Act and advise the Board of County Commissioners on HIV/AIDS related health services issues.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-552. Membership requirements; appointment of members; terms; removal</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The council shall be composed of thirty-one (31) members from the following categories of representatives:
<section prefix = "1">
Health care providers;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Community based and AIDS service organizations;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Social service providers;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Mental health providers;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Local public health agencies;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Hospital or health care planning agencies;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Affected socio-economic communities, including individuals with HIV disease;
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Non-elected community leaders who do not provide HIV related health care services subject to funding under the Ryan White Act;
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
State government;
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Agencies receiving grants under Title III of the Ryan White Act;
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
The lead agency for Health Resources and Services Administration adult and pediatric HIV-related care demonstration project.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Board of County Commissioners shall designate at the time of appointment which category listed in subsection (a) above each member shall represent. Appointments shall comply with the following requirements:
<section prefix = "1">
The Board shall appoint at least one member form each category listed in subsection (a) above, the President of the Primary Health Care Consortium of Miami-Dade County, at least one provider receiving a grant under the Special Projects of National Significance Program, and an individual designated by the grantee of Housing Opportunities for Persons with AIDS (HOPWA) Program for Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Board shall appoint at least six (6) individuals with HIV disease as members, and six (6) additional individuals with HIV disease as alternates. To the greatest extent possible, the gender, racial, ethnic and cultural make-up of the alternates should reflect that of the six (6) members. These alternates shall serve as non-voting members except when the chairperson certifies that a member with HIV disease is unable to serve due to the disease, in which case a designated alternate shall vote for such absent member.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Board shall appoint no more than ten (10) individuals who personally provide or who represent entities that provide HIV related health care services subject to funding under the Ryan White Act. Of these ten (10) appointments, no more than seven (7) shall be full or part-time employees of entities that provide such services. No provider shall have more than one representative or employee as a member, except the Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services, which may have two (2) members.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Members shall be appointed in accordance with Sections 2-11.38 and 2-11.38.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The term of office of members shall be in accordance with Section 2-11.38.2 of the Code of Miami-Dade County. Members shall be appointed to three (3) year terms, which shall end concurrent with the last day of the county's fiscal year, except that initially nine (9) members shall be appointed to a one-year term and ten (10) members to a two-year term.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Attendance requirements for members shall be in accordance with Section 2-11.39, except that absences from meetings by members with HIV disease due to the disease shall not be counted as an absence. If a member appointed to represent a category listed in subsection (a) above loses such representative status, fails to maintain the qualifications for membership set forth in Section 2-11.38, fails to maintain attendance requirements, voluntarily resigns, or for other good cause is removed, the member shall forfeit membership on the council and the County Manager shall recommend a replacement to fill the unexpired term of such member.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 92-100, § 2, 9-15-92; Ord. No. 94-206, § 1, 11-1-94)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-553. Organization</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The council shall elect a chairperson and vice-chairperson from among its members, who shall serve at the will of the council. The chairperson and vice-chairperson shall not personally provide or represent entities that provide HIV-related health care services subject to funding under the Ryan White Act. The chairperson shall preside at all meetings at which he or she is present. The vice-chairperson shall act as chairperson in the absence or inability of the chairperson.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The council shall have assistance from staff designated by the county manager and legal representation from the county attorney's office. The staff shall maintain and keep the records of the council; prepare, in cooperation with the chairperson, the agenda for each meeting; be responsible for the preparation of such reports, minutes, documents, resolutions or correspondence as the council may direct; and generally administer the business and affairs of the council, subject to budgetary limitations.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
In order to transact any business or to exercise any power vested in the council, a quorum consisting of no less than thirteen (13) members shall be present.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The council shall not transact business or exercise its powers unless a majority of the quorum in attendance agrees to the activity. The chairperson or five (5) council members upon written request to the chairperson may call for a special meeting.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The council may appoint committees to accomplish its tasks, and may appoint as committee members individuals who are not council members.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 92-100, § 3, 9-15-92; Ord. No. 94-206, § 1, 11-1-94)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-554. Powers and duties</catch_line>
<text>
The Council shall:
<section prefix = "a">
Have those powers and duties given HIV health services planning councils by the Ryan White Act as it presently exists or as it may be amended;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Advise the Board of County Commissioners on HIV/AIDS related health care services issues; and
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Seek to have, in cooperation with other state and local bodies with planning authority, a comprehensive plan for the organization and delivery of all HIV/AIDS related health services in Miami-Dade County.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-555. Conflict of interest waiver</catch_line>
<text>
Sections 2-11.1 (c) and (d) of the Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance of Miami-Dade County are waived for council members for transactions arising from the exercise of those powers given the council by the Ryan White Act.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-556. Reports</catch_line>
<text>
The chairperson or the chairperson's designee shall present to the Board of County Commissioners on an annual basis a written report describing the council's activities and shall appear as needed before the Board to present any matters pertinent to the council.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-557—2-580. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
</law>
