<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XVIIA._RU-4L_LIMITED_APARTMENT_H</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-207.2. Uses permitted</catch_line>
<text>
No land, body of water or structure shall be used, or permitted to be used and no structure shall be hereafter erected, constructed, moved or reconstructed, structurally altered or maintained for any purpose in a RU-4L District which is designed, arranged or intended to be used or occupied for any purpose, except for one (1) of the following uses:
<section prefix = "A">
Those uses permitted in the RU-1, RU-1M(a), RU-1M(b), RU-2, RU-3, RU-TH and RU-RH Districts subject only to the requirements, limitations, and restrictions applicable therefor in said districts; including, but not limited to, lot width, area, yard areas, height, and coverage.
(A.1)
Workforce housing units in compliance with the provisions of Article XIIA of this code.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Multiple family apartment house use with only one (1) principal building on a lot, parcel or tract, designed for more than four (4) family units subject to the following:
<section prefix = "1">
Minimum lot width and area. The minimum lot width shall be one hundred (100) feet and the minimum lot area shall be ten thousand (10,000) square feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Lot coverage. The maximum area covered by all buildings shall not exceed thirty (30) percent of the lot.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Setback requirements. The setbacks shall be as follows:
<section prefix = "a">
Minimum setback from front property line shall be twenty-five (25) feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Minimum setback from interior side property line shall be fifteen (15) feet for structures of not more than two (2) stories and twenty (20) feet for structures over two (2) stories.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Minimum setback from side street property line shall be twenty-five (25) feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Minimum setback from a rear property line shall be twenty-five (25) feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Where doors, windows or other openings in the building wall of a living unit face a wall of the same building and/or a wall of another building (accessory) on the same site, there shall be provided a minimum clear distance of not less than thirty (30) feet. Said distance to be measured on a line projected at right angles at the opening from the wall containing the opening to the opposite wall. Cantilevers and open porches may project from the building wall into the required open space (court only) not more than four (4) feet and that stairways may project from the building wall into the required open space (court only) not more than seven and one-half (7½) feet. Stairways when located in the required open space (court) shall be supported by the necessary columns only; support by a wall is strictly prohibited.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Height. No building or structure, or part thereof shall be erected or altered to a height exceeding six (6) stories, and shall not exceed seventy-five (75) feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Floor area ratio. The floor area ratio shall not exceed the following:
<section prefix="1" type="table">
<table class="thead1 table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">Height of<br />Building</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">Floor Area<br />Ratio</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1-story</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0.30</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2-story</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0.50</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3-story</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0.75</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">4-story</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0.80</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">5-story</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0.85</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6-story</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0.90</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Maximum number of units. The maximum number of dwelling units shall be determined on the basis of a total of twenty-three (23) dwelling units per net acre.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Open space. On each lot with structures not exceeding four (4) stories, there shall be provided an open space equal to at least twenty-five (25) percent of the total lot area. On lots with structures over four (4) stories, there shall be provided an open space equal to at least thirty-five (35) percent of the total lot area; and said space shall be unencumbered with any structure or off-street parking, and shall be landscaped and well maintained with grass, trees and shrubbery, excepting only areas used as pedestrian walks and ingress and egress drives; said ingress and egress drives shall not exceed a maximum width required to serve the parking area.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Trees. Landscaping and trees shall be provided in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Multiple-family housing developments [shall be] permitted only after staff review of the site plan to ensure compliance with all RU-4L District requirements and site plan review criteria. Said plan shall be in accordance with the requirements contained in subparagraphs (1) through (8) of paragraph (B) above, except that interior setbacks and spacing requirements may be disregarded in approving the plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
Housing projects, whether in single or multiple buildings, and as defined in Chapter 421, of the Florida Statutes, built for or by the Miami-Dade County Department of Housing and Urban Development.
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
A community residential facility as defined in Section 33-1(30.1) shall be permitted in a dwelling unit upon establishing the following:
<section prefix = "a">
That the total number of resident clients on the premises not exceed fourteen (14) in number. Facilities for more than fourteen (14) resident clients must be approved through public hearing pursuant to Section 33-13
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
That the operation of the community residential home be licensed by the State of Florida Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
That the community residential home not be located within a radius of one thousand two hundred (1,200) feet of another existing, unabandoned legally established community residential home in a multi-family zone. The one thousand two hundred-foot distance requirement shall be measured by following a straight line from the nearest portion of the structure of the proposed use to the nearest portion of the structure of the existing use;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
That the community residential home conform to existing zoning regulations applicable to other multiple family uses permitted by this section;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
That the sponsoring agency of the community residential home notify the Director in writing of its intention to establish said facility. Such notice shall contain the address and legal description of the site, the number of resident clients, as well as a statement from the State of Florida Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services indicating the need for and licensing status of the proposed facility. Absence of this notification and statements shall prohibit the use and occupancy of any structure for use as a community residential home; and
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Nothing in this section shall permit persons to occupy a community residential home who would constitute a direct threat to the health and safety of other persons or whose residency would result in substantial physical damage to the property of others.

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-207.2.1. Site plan review</catch_line>
<text>
The Department shall review plans for compliance with zoning regulations and for compliance with the site plan review criteria. The purpose of the site plan review is to encourage logic, imagination, innovation and variety in the design process and thereby ensure the congruity of the proposed development and its compatibility with the surrounding area. All plans submitted to the Department shall be reviewed and approved or denied within fifteen (15) days from the date of submission. The applicant shall have the right to extend the fifteen-day period by an additional fifteen (15) days upon timely request made in writing to the Department. The Department shall have the right to extend the fifteen-day period by written notice to the applicant that additional information is needed to process the site plan. Denials shall be in writing and shall specifically set forth the grounds for denial. If the plan is disapproved the applicant may appeal to the appropriate Community Zoning Appeals Board in accordance with procedure established for appeals of administrative decision.
Procedure. Exhibits prepared by design professionals such as architects and landscape architects shall be submitted to the Department and shall include, but not be limited to the following:
<section prefix = "1">
Site plan including the following information:
<section prefix = "a">
Lot lines and setbacks.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Location, shape, size and height of existing and proposed buildings, decorative walls and entrance features.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Landscaping in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Location of off-street parking and loading facilities and waste collection areas.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Indication of exterior graphics, as required.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Indication of any site design methods used to conserve energy.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Floor plans and elevations of all structures, including total gross square foot area of each floor.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Figures indicating the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Gross and net acreage.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Amount of landscaped open space in square feet required and provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Amount of building coverage at ground level in square feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Total trees required and provided in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Parking required and provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Total amount of paved area in square feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Such other design data as may be needed to evaluate the project.

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-207.2.2. Site plan review criteria</catch_line>
<text>
The following criteria shall be utilized in the plan review process:
<section prefix = "1">
Purpose and intent: The proposed development fulfills the objectives of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Planning studies: Design, planning studies or neighborhood area studies accepted or approved by the Board of County Commissioners that include development patterns or environmental design criteria which would apply to the development proposals under review shall be utilized in the plan review process.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Landscape: Landscape shall be preserved in its natural state insofar as is practicable by minimizing tree removal. Landscape shall be used to shade and cool, direct wind movements, enhance architectural features, relate structure design to site, visually screen noncompatible uses and block noise generated by the major roadways and intense use areas.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Buffers: Buffering elements in the form of architectural design and landscape design that provide a logical transition to adjoining existing or permitted uses shall be provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Scale: Scale of proposed structures shall be compatible with surrounding proposed or existing uses or shall be made compatible by the use of buffering elements.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Circulation: Pedestrian and auto circulation shall be separated insofar as is practicable, and all circulation systems shall adequately serve the needs of the development and be compatible and functional with circulation systems outside the development.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Energy considerations: Site design methods to reduce energy consumption shall be encouraged. Energy site conservation methods may include siting of structures in relation to prevailing breezes and sun angles and use of landscape materials for shade and transpiration.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Parking areas: Building wall extensions, planting, berms or other innovative methods shall be used as a means of minimizing the adverse effect of the visual impact of parking areas. This requirement is in addition to the requirements of the landscape regulations of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Open spaces: Open space shall relate to any natural characteristics in such a way as to preserve and enhance their scenic and functional qualities to the fullest extent possible.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Graphics: Graphics, as required, shall be designated as an integral part of the overall design of the project.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Art display: Permanent interior and exterior art displays and water features should be encouraged in the overall design of the project.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Visual screening for decorative walls: In an effort to prevent graffiti vandalism, the following options shall be utilized for walls abutting zoned or dedicated rights-of-way:
<section prefix = "a">
Wall with landscaping. The wall shall be setback two and one-half (2½) feet from the right-of-way line and the resulting setback area shall contain a continuous extensively landscaped buffer which must be maintained in a good healthy condition by the property owner, or where applicable, by the condominium, homeowners or similar association. The landscape buffer shall contain one (1) or more of the following planting materials:
<section prefix = "1">
Shrubs. Shrubs shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Hedges. Hedges shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Vines. Climbing vines shall be a minimum of thirty-six (36) inches in height immediately after planting.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Metal picket fence. Where a metal picket fence abutting a zoned or dedicated right-of-way is constructed in lieu of a decorative wall, landscaping shall not be required.

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-207.2.3. Convenience retail facilities</catch_line>
<text>
Not more than one (1) food and drug convenience retail service facility of the BU-1 type shall be permitted as an accessory use to an apartment use or apartment development, said facility not to exceed one thousand (1,000) square feet in a development having a minimum of three hundred (300) apartment units, provided that:
<section prefix = "1">
Such services relate to the needs of the inhabitants of the proposed complex;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Such services are not provided direct access from public roads;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Such services are not visible from public roads;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Detached signs and signs visible from public roads are not used;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Such services are designed as an integral part of the total design as determined by site plan review;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Such services are located in the principal structure or in a community service center structure.

An additional one (1) square foot of retail area shall be permitted for each apartment unit above three hundred (300) units; provided, however, that the maximum square footage for such facilities shall not exceed three thousand (3,000) square feet.
</section>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (21) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 64-4, § 2, enacted February 4, 1964, amended Ch. 33 to add the provisions above relating to the RU-4L Limited Apartment House District. These provisions have been designated as Article XVIIA by the editors in their discretion. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
