<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_III._CERTIFICATES_OF_PUBLIC_CONV</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-33. Required</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful for any public utility as herein defined to commence the construction of any water system or sewer system anywhere in Miami-Dade County, Florida, or to extend, enlarge, expand or change the service area of any existing system, without first filing an appropriate application and obtaining from the Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Water and Sewer Board a certificate of public convenience and necessity issued pursuant to the provisions of this chapter. Each public utility engaged in the construction or operation or extension of any water or sewer system on the effective date of this chapter shall file with the Board an appropriate application for a certificate within ninety (90) days after the entire membership of the Board has been appointed and duly qualified to act authorizing such public utility to commence or continue such construction, operation or extension.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-34. Public systems</catch_line>
<text>
Any municipality owning or operating a water or sewer system on the effective date of this chapter [3] shall be entitled to receive a certificate of public convenience for the service area actually being served by such municipally owned or operated system as a matter of right, without cost or expense to such municipality, upon the filing of an appropriate application for certificate within the period of time herein specified. Such certificate shall be issued without notice and without public hearing.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-35. Contents of certificates; expiration date; construction</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Each certificate of public convenience and necessity issued hereunder for new or existing systems shall contain the name of the public utility to which it is issued, its principal place of business, the nature of the service authorized, and the specific territory or service area in which the public utility is authorized to operate, construct, maintain, repair, remove, or extend lines, facilities or equipment for the supply or distribution of water and the collection and disposal of sewage under, on, over or across, and along any public roads, streets or highways, for the purpose of constructing or operating a water or sewer system. Each certificate shall contain adequate, uniform provisions:
<section prefix = "1">
To prevent the creation of any obstruction or conditions which are or may become dangerous to the traveling public.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To require the licensee under said certificate to repair any damage or injury to the road or highway or street by reason of the exercise of the privileges granted in said certificate and to repair said road or highway or street promptly, restoring the same to a condition at least equal to that which existed immediately prior to the infliction of such damage or injury.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Whereby the licensee under said certificate shall hold the Board and its members, and the County harmless from the payment of any compensation or damages resulting from the exercise of the privileges granted in said certificate.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
To require that, in the event of widening or repair or reconstruction of any such road or highway or street, the public utility under such certificate shall move or remove such water or sewerage lines at no cost to the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
To require such additional uniform undertakings as may be reasonably necessary for the protection of the County and the public.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Each certificate issued in accordance with the provisions of this chapter shall remain in force and effect until terminated, revoked, or cancelled, upon due notice and hearing, in accordance with the provisions herein contained.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Subject to the limitations contained in this chapter, the certificate shall be construed as vesting in the lawful holder thereof the exclusive right or privilege to operate and serve such certificate. However, no certificate shall be construed as a franchise or to confer any vested property right upon the holder thereof, nor to deny the right of the Board to cancel, terminate or revoke a certificate and grant another certificate to another public utility to render the same type or class of service within the same territory, if the public convenience and necessity and the public interest require it, after due notice and public hearing. The Board may adopt and prescribe rules and regulations governing maps or sketches and the legal descriptions delineating service areas which each holder of a certificate is authorized to serve, to the end that such maps, sketches and descriptions shall be uniform and standardized.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 60-20, § 9, 7-5-60)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-36. Certificates required for existing systems</catch_line>
<text>
Each and every public utility engaged in the construction, operation or extension of any water system or sewer system on the effective date of this chapter [4] shall be entitled to receive from the Board a certificate of public convenience and necessity authorizing such public utility to continue serving the specific territory it served on the effective date of this chapter, if within ninety (90) days after the date on which the entire membership of the Board has been appointed and duly qualified to act, a preliminary application for such certificate shall be made and filed with the Board in the form prescribed by the Board. Each such application, except those filed by municipalities, shall be accompanied by a filing fee of two hundred fifty dollars ($250.00).
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-37. Procedure for obtaining certificates for existing systems</catch_line>
<text>
If the Board shall determine that the territory professed to be served by any qualified applicant for a certificate under Section 32-36 hereof does not conflict with, overlap or infringe upon any portion of the territory professed to be served by any other applicant and that all requirements of this chapter have been complied with, the Board shall issue to the applicant a certificate of public convenience and necessity authorizing it to continue serving such territory.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-38. Determination of property conflicts in existing systems</catch_line>
<text>
If the territory professed to be served by any applicant for a certificate under Section 32-36 hereof conflicts with, overlaps, infringes upon or duplicates any portion of the territory professed to be served by any other applicant, the Board, after notice and public hearing, shall resolve such conflict, overlapping, infringement or duplication in professed service areas by a determination establishing and fixing such boundary line or lines between or among the professed territories as may be required by public convenience and necessity, taking into consideration such other matters as the Board may deem appropriate in the public interest, health and welfare, and the Board shall issue certificates accordingly. In making such determination the Board shall state its reasons therefor and make findings of the facts upon which the determination is predicated.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-39. Certificates required for new systems</catch_line>
<text>
From and after the effective date of this chapter, no public utility or other person shall commence the construction of a water system or sewer system, or any facilities incident thereto, without first obtaining from the Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Water and Sewer Board a certificate of public convenience and necessity issued pursuant to the provisions of this chapter. Notwithstanding any other provision of Chapter 32 of the Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, the Water and Sewer Board shall not issue any new or expanded certificate of public convenience and necessity unless and until the Water and Sewer Authority approves any change limitation or modification of its assigned service area where such certificate affects the Authority's assigned service area.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-40. Procedure for certificates for new systems</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
All applications for certificates required under Section 32-39 hereof shall be filed with the Board in compliance with rules and regulations promulgated by the Board and in such form as the Board may from time to time adopt or prescribe. Each such application shall be accompanied by a filing fee of two hundred fifty dollars ($250.00). Upon the filing of an application complying with the rules and regulations of the Board and payment of the filing fee, the Board shall cause the application to be set for public hearing. At least ten (10) days' written notice of such public hearing shall be given by mail to each of the public utilities that have registered with the Board in accordance with the provisions of Section 32-53 hereof, and notice shall be given by the Board to the Public Health Department, and notice of such public hearing shall be published once in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County at least ten (10) days prior to the date of such public hearing. Pursuant to such notice the Board shall conduct a public hearing to determine whether public convenience and necessity require or permit such construction or operation of said new water or sewer system; and the Board shall take into consideration whether or not in the issuance of the certificate applied for it would be in the public interest, health and welfare and whether the applicant can reasonably be expected to provide adequate service at reasonable rates. After such public hearing the Board shall make its determination of public convenience and necessity and shall state the reasons therefor and make findings of fact upon which the determination is predicated.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Board may prescribe in the certificate a reasonable time within which the applicant shall provide the services specified in the certificate within the service area described therein. If the services authorized by the certificate are not provided within the time so prescribed, the certificate shall be canceled and rendered null and void; provided, that prior to the expiration of the time prescribed in the certificate the Board shall have the power, for good cause shown, to extend such time and to impose such conditions as will assure the providing of adequate service at reasonable rates and any other reasonable conditions commensurate with the public interest, health and welfare.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Board shall not grant a certificate for the construction, operation, extension or expansion of a water or sewer system into any territory described in a prior certificate issued to another public utility except in accordance with rules approved by the Board of County Commissioners, or unless the Board shall first determine, after public notice and hearing, that the existing facilities are inadequate to meet the reasonable needs of the public involved, or that the standards of service are inadequate to provide for the reasonable needs of the consumers involved. In the event of any such determination, the Board may revoke, amend, limit or restrict any certificate previously issued. In making any such determination the Board shall be governed by consideration of the public interest, health and welfare, and shall endeavor to provide for the benefit of the consumers affected adequate standards of service at the lowest feasible rates. Any such determination shall embody a statement of the reasons therefor and findings of the facts upon which the determination is predicated.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 60-20, § 14, 7-5-60; Ord. No. 62-28, § 3, 7-3-62)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-41. Certificate required for extensions of systems; approval by Board for new water source</catch_line>
<text>
No public utility shall extend the facilities of its water and sewer systems without first obtaining for such extension a certificate of public convenience and necessity in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, unless such extension is made in accordance with rules approved by the Board of County Commissioners. Any such applications for extensions of water and/or sewer service areas into previously unassigned areas must be accompanied by a release by the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority issued pursuant to Section 32A-16(a) of the Code. Any action of the Board granting an extension of water and/or sewer systems issued under this section shall incorporate, as a minimum, the applicable conditions of release set out in Section 32A-16(a) of the Code. No public utility shall effectuate a change of more than ten (10) percent in the source of their water supply without the approval of the Board after a public hearing has been conducted. Utilities owned or operated by municipalities shall have the right to extend facilities within their municipal boundaries as a matter of right.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-42. Transfer of certificate</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Approval of Board required. No certificate issued pursuant to the provisions of this chapter shall be sold, in whole or in part, assigned, or transferred by the holder to another, until the same has been approved and authorized by the Board as herein provided. The provisions of this section shall be applicable to municipally owned or operated water and sewer systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Application for approval of transfer. When any such certificate is proposed to be sold, assigned, or transferred, all of the parties, nominal and actual, to such transaction shall jointly file an application with the Board, in such form as may be prescribed by said Board, and shall set forth, among other things, the details of the transaction, specifying the consideration and the method of payment, the date such transaction is desired to be consummated, a financial statement of the transferee, the certificate authority, if any, held by said transferee under this chapter, the franchise authority, if any, held by the transferee, and any other pertinent facts. Such application shall be accompanied by a fee of one hundred dollars ($100.00). In such application the proposed transferee shall agree to pay all taxes, assessments, and obligations which may be due or owing to the State, County, and any other political subdivision of the State or County, by the transferor to the date of the entry of the order by the Board approving the transfer, as a condition precedent to such approval.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Notice of filing applications. Upon the filing of an application for approval of the transfer of a certificate the Board shall issue and serve by mail, upon all parties entitled to notice of hearing on application for certificate to commence construction or operation of a new system, a written notice which shall contain the general pertinent facts of such application. Said notice shall require any objections or protests to such transfer to be filed in writing with the Board, by a date to be fixed in such notice. Any objection or protest filed shall state fully the basis therefor. In the event no such written protest is filed with the Board within the time fixed in such notice, then and in that event, the Board may consider said application and act upon the same as an ex parte matter without the necessity of public hearing, and for the purpose of such consideration, the Board may require either, or both, of the parties to such proposed transfer to appear before it for the purpose of giving testimony, or to produce any such records or information as the Board may direct and find necessary to consider in passing upon said application.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Public hearing on transfer. In the event one (1) or more written protests stating material and legal grounds therefor are filed with the Board objecting to the proposed transfer of any such certificate within the time allowed, then the Board shall cause a public hearing to be held, and shall issue and serve, by mail, upon the applicants and all parties who have filed such protests a written notice that a public hearing will be held by the Board at a stated time on the application for, and the protests objecting to, approval of the proposed transfer. At such hearing the applicants shall present testimony and evidence in support of the proposed transfer, and those who have filed written protests shall be entitled to present testimony and evidence in opposition thereto.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Disposition of application for transfer. Following a public hearing on an application for approval of transfer of a certificate under this chapter, and written protests thereto, if the Board finds and determines that the proposed transfer is not contrary to the public interest, health, and welfare, it shall enter an appropriate order in the premises. If the Board finds otherwise the application shall be denied. In making its determination of whether or not the transfer is in the public interest, health, and welfare, the Board shall consider, but shall not be limited to, the following factors: The effect of said proposed transfer upon the policy of Miami-Dade County as expressed and codified in Chapter 32A of the Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County; the effect of said transfer on the consumers of the area of the transferee as to rates, service, and the quality of water and sewer service; the effect of the proposed transfer on the transferor as to its ability to maintain quality of water and sewer service to its existing consumers and to the proposed consumers located within the service area of the transferee; the effect of the proposed transfer based upon the considerations expressed within the comprehensive development master plan, as amended, for Metropolitan Miami-Dade County. The consideration of such factors shall not exclude consideration of factors other than those specifically mentioned above.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Judicial assignee of permit. Notwithstanding any of the provisions herein, any executor, administrator, receiver, trustee in bankruptcy or in reorganization, or other court officer, shall be entitled, as judicial assignee, to operate the business of the certificate holder, without the approval of the Board, upon filing with the Board a certified copy of his order of appointment, but any sale, transfer, or assignment by any such judicial officer shall be subject to the terms and conditions hereof. Any sale or transfer accomplished by means of judicial decree or order shall not be subject to the provisions of this section. However, the purchaser at judicial sale or under judicial decree shall register and comply with all other provisions of this chapter.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 60-20, § 16, 7-5-60; Ord. No. 77-27, § 1, 5-3-77)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-43. Cancellation of permit for failure to serve</catch_line>
<text>
When any public utility fails or refuses, or is unable to provide any reasonable service, or make any reasonable extension of its existing facilities, within the territory authorized to be served by said public utility, as may be directed and required by the Board, the certificate held by said public utility under the provisions of this chapter may be revoked and canceled in whole or in part by the Board after notice and public hearings; and any public utility holding a certificate from the Board authorizing a similar service in contiguous territory may be authorized, after notice and public hearing, to make such reasonable extensions of its facilities into, and render such reasonable service in, the territory covered by any such canceled certificate or portion thereof, as may be justified by the public interest, health, and welfare, and as may be required by public convenience and necessity, provided, however, that no public utility shall be required to extend its facilities into such new territory, except in accordance with rules approved by the Board of County Commissioners. The power to cancel a certificate as provided herein for failure to render service shall be in addition to the power of the Board to cancel a certificate when the existing facilities are inadequate to provide for the reasonable needs of the consumers involved, and in addition to the power to levy and impose fines for violations of this chapter, provided, however, that all such public hearings relating to water quality required by this section shall be heard by the Environmental Quality Control Board as hearing examiner for the Water and Sewer Board. The Environmental Quality Control Board shall thereafter make findings of facts and recommendations to the Water and Sewer Board. The findings of fact relating to water quality shall be binding upon the Water and Sewer Board.
</text>
When any public utility fails or refuses, or is unable to provide any reasonable service, or make any reasonable extension of its existing facilities, within the territory authorized to be served by said public utility, as may be directed and required by the Board, the certificate held by said public utility under the provisions of this chapter may be revoked and canceled in whole or in part by the Board after notice and public hearings; and any public utility holding a certificate from the Board authorizing a similar service in contiguous territory may be authorized, after notice and public hearing, to make such reasonable extensions of its facilities into, and render such reasonable service in, the territory covered by any such canceled certificate or portion thereof, as may be justified by the public interest, health, and welfare, and as may be required by public convenience and necessity, provided, however, that no public utility shall be required to extend its facilities into such new territory, except in accordance with rules approved by the Board of County Commissioners. The power to cancel a certificate as provided herein for failure to render service shall be in addition to the power of the Board to cancel a certificate when the existing facilities are inadequate to provide for the reasonable needs of the consumers involved, and in addition to the power to levy and impose fines for violations of this chapter, provided, however, that all such public hearings relating to water quality required by this section shall be heard by the Environmental Quality Control Board as hearing examiner for the Water and Sewer Board. The Environmental Quality Control Board shall thereafter make findings of facts and recommendations to the Water and Sewer Board. The findings of fact relating to water quality shall be binding upon the Water and Sewer Board.
<catch_line>Sec. 32-44. Review and assessment of existing service area</catch_line>
<text>
Board review and assessment of existing service areas assigned pursuant to the terms of this chapter may be initiated at any time by the Board of County Commissioners; Director, Environmental Resources Management of Miami-Dade County; the Director of the Miami-Dade County Health Department; the Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning; the Consumer Advocate of Miami-Dade County; or the staff of the Water and Sewer Board, or any other department or agency or instrumentality of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County. The application for a service area review and assessment shall designate the area or areas sought to be reviewed and the reasons of the applicant therefor. Upon receipt of such an application, the Secretary of the Board shall notify the affected utility of its filing and all other utilities adjacent to the service area concerned. In addition, the Secretary shall notify all affected County agencies, instrumentalities or departments of the application. Said notices shall include a copy of the application and shall request information dealing with the quality and capacity of service now being provided or available within the area concerned by the utility, the extent of service that is actually available without water or sewer main extension by the utility; and, the extent to which further development in the area is in accordance with the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan. The Secretary to the Board shall thereupon schedule the matter for a public hearing in not less than forty-five (45) days from receipt of the application and shall notify all parties of the date thereof and shall publish notice of the time and place of said hearing in a newspaper of general circulation in the existing service area. In the event the Board determines, after due notice and public hearing, that it is required for the public convenience and necessity that a currently unserved portion of an assigned service area should be reassigned, either to another utility or should not be assigned to any utility, the Board shall enter its order accordingly and shall state its reasons therefor and make findings of fact upon which the determination is predicated.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-45. Acquisition of public utility by Miami-Dade County or Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority</catch_line>
<text>
Notwithstanding any other section of this chapter, upon acquisition by Metropolitan Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority of any public utility, as defined in this chapter, either through merger, transfer, negotiated sale, eminent domain, or otherwise:
<section prefix = "a">
Any and all certificates or temporary certificates of public convenience and necessity and designated service areas possessed by the acquired public utility shall be cancelled and terminated and of no further force and effect as to said public utility as of the date upon which Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority assumes the duties and responsibilities of providing water and sewer service to the consumers within the service areas formerly served by the public utility. On that date, Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority shall assume said duties and responsibilities of providing water and/or sewer service without any further action of the Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Any and all franchise agreements between the acquired public utility and any municipality shall terminate and cease to exist as of the date upon which change of title from that utility to Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water Sewer Authority occurs and any municipal charter, ordinance or resolution approving same are specifically repealed.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Any and all outstanding orders of the Board and/or provisions of Chapter 32 of the Code that affect the public utility to be acquired shall have no further effect, and shall not be enforced or enforceable against Miami-Dade County, the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority or the acquired public utility as of the date upon which change of title from the utility to Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority takes place. However, said public utility shall be responsible and liable for compliance with said orders and/or provisions of the Board, Director of Environmental Resources Management or Environmental Quality Control Board or other affected County regulatory agency, at all times up to the date upon which change of title occurs or thereafter for orders and/or provisions where compliance was required prior to the date of County or Authority ownership of the acquired public utility. This continuing responsibility and liability of the acquired utility is subject to qualification, however, by the other provisions of this section and said responsibility and liability shall be for specific acts that were required to be performed prior to the date of County or Authority ownership of the acquired utility where said orders or provisions had become or became final by virtue of the expiration of all times for rehearings and appeals, if any, in connection with said specific acts.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Any and all escrowed funds possessed by the acquired public utility or being held on its behalf, escrowed pursuant to Board order or the Code, shall be released to the use of Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority for the purpose of providing water and/or sewer service to consumers within the service area of the acquired public utility. If such funds have been escrowed by the acquired public utility for certain capital projects or other particular purposes, Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority shall assume the responsibility for fulfillment of those specific projects or purposes without the need for such escrow accounts and shall rebate to consumers of the acquired public utility or to those consumers directly responsible for establishing said fund or funds, any of such funds not so utilized for those specific projects or purposes.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Upon acquisition of a public utility, Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority shall be liable to make construction cost refunds to developers for which the acquired utility was liable, except to the extent that such liability is extinguished or assumed by the acquired utility by the terms of the agreement reflecting a sale, merger or transfer or by eminent domain proceedings.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Notwithstanding any provision hereof, as of the date upon which change of title from the acquired public utility to Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority occurs, any and all contracts, agreements, memoranda, understandings or other obligations, whether written or verbal, for service, construction, cost allocations, charges, costs, refunds, reimbursements or other payments, notwithstanding any terms or provisions thereof, shall be modified, amended, revised, construed and entered for all purposes, including, without limitation, the determination of all obligations of Miami-Dade County, the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority and the acquired public utility, as if the charges, rules, regulations, standards, specifications and practices of Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority are in effect on the date that any service, construction, cost allocations, charges, costs, refunds, reimbursements or other payments are to be performed or made had been incorporated originally in such contracts, agreements, memoranda, understandings or other obligations and any provisions of said contracts, agreements, memoranda, understandings or other obligations which are contrary to said charges, rules, regulations, standards, specifications and practices shall be deemed null, void, invalid and unenforceable. The Authority or County Commission shall waive or modify the provisions of this subsection for acquisitions prior to the date hereof in those exceptional circumstances where a developer has substantially altered its position and expended substantial sums of money in reliance on said differing standards and said alteration of position has been authorized or cause by action of the County or Authority.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
In the interim period between the date upon which Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority signs a letter of intent with said utility or such other date as may be agreed to between Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority and the acquired utility to purchase that utility, and the date upon which the change of title of that public utility to Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority occurs, the rates, charges, fees, construction standards and specifications imposed by the utility upon consumers within its franchised service area shall remain subject as before to control of the Board. However, any developer, as described in Section 32-55, who desires to enter into a service agreement with that utility during the interim period described above, shall be required to install improvements and to submit design data that meet the standards set forth in the rules and regulations of Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority. Said developer shall have the right to appear before the Board during the interim period to obtain a waiver or modification of said standards during the interim period where the developer can show mitigating circumstances, that preexisted the date upon which binding contract, agreement or settlement agreement was signed that justify such a waiver or modification.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Notwithstanding any other provision of the Code, personnel rules or any other rules, regulations or administrative orders, the Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority (when the system is acquired by the Authority) or the County Manager (when the system is acquired by the County) may determine that all or certain of the employees of the acquired utility (except for acquired utilities of municipalities) should be retained as employees in those or similar capacities, in the County's service, in order to maintain service continuity and prevent a detrimental interruption of these essential services. In so doing, the determination of the Director or the Manager shall result in the waiver of any requirements for competitive or promotional examinations and the Director or County Manager may place said employees in a job status or classification reasonably comparable to that held by the employee prior to the acquisition, if available. Any employee so hired shall be considered and treated as a new County employee and shall serve a probationary period as determined by the County Manager or Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
The terms of this section shall be applicable to all public utilities heretofore or hereafter acquired by either Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 32-46—32-49. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (3) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 60-20 from which this chapter is derived became effective "thirty (30) days after enactment" on July 5, 1960. (Back)

--- (4) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 60-20 from which this chapter is derived became effective "thirty (30) days after enactment" on July 5, 1960. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
