<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_II._LAW_DEPARTMENT</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-12. Created; full-time employment; unclassified service; office facilities; funds provided; County Attorney as head</catch_line>
<text>
The County Law Department is hereby created and established under and pursuant to the provisions of Section 4.06 of the Charter. All personnel of the Department shall devote full time to the service of the County, and shall be exempt from the classified service. Office facilities for the Department shall be provided and maintained in the County courthouse. Sufficient funds for the proper operation and maintenance of the Department shall be provided in the County budget. The department shall be operated under the direction and supervision of the County Attorney, who shall serve under the jurisdiction of the County Commission.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-13. County Attorney—Appointment; term; compensation; appointment and removal of assistants and employees; qualifications</catch_line>
<text>
There shall be a County Attorney appointed by the County Commission. He shall serve at the will and under the jurisdiction of the County Commission. The County Commission shall fix the compensation of the County Attorney. The County Attorney shall be the chief civil law officer of the County and shall be the Director or head of the Law Department. He shall select, appoint and employ all personnel of the Department, and shall be responsible for the performance of all duties and functions assigned to the Department. With approval of the County Commission as to salaries, he shall appoint such Assistant County Attorneys as may be necessary for the proper and efficient performance of his duties. Subject to budget provisions, he shall employ such legal secretaries and office personnel as needed for proper operation of the Department, and fix the compensation of such employees. The County Attorney shall have the right to discharge, remove and replace any assistants or other personnel of the Law Department at any time without cause. The County Attorney and all Assistant County Attorneys shall be members of The Florida Bar in good standing.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-14. Same—Duties and functions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The County Attorney shall be the attorney of record in all civil suits, actions and legal proceedings wherein the County, County Commission, Manager, departments, boards or County officials or employees are parties by virtue of their official positions or actions. He shall institute and prosecute all eminent domain proceedings and other civil suits, actions and legal proceedings authorized by the County Commission. He shall defend all civil suits, actions and legal proceedings brought against the County. The County Attorney shall not be required to represent any County official or employee in respect to their private or personal affairs or actions.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The County Attorney shall serve as legal adviser to the County Commission, Manager, department heads, County boards, and County officers. When requested, he shall render written legal opinions on matters relating to County government and the interpretation, construction and meaning of the constitutional amendment, charter, statutes, ordinances, resolutions and contracts affecting or pertaining to the County government, and such opinions shall be binding upon, and adhered to by all appointed County officials or employees, except in the performance of judicial or quasi-judicial powers of duties. Copies of all written opinions of law rendered by the County Attorney shall be furnished to the Chairman of the County Commission and the Manager.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The County Attorney shall prepare, or review and approve as to form and legal sufficiency, all County ordinances, resolutions, deeds, contract documents and other legal instruments affecting or pertaining to the County, or in which the County is a party.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The County Attorney, or an Assistant County Attorney, shall attend and be present during all regular and special meetings of the County Commission. When requested, he shall attend meetings of special committees of the County Commission, and meetings of County boards.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The County Attorney shall represent the County and department heads in hearings or trials before the Personnel Advisory Board in appeals taken by County employees under the provisions of the Larger Counties Civil Service Act, codified herein as Article IV of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The County Attorney shall perform all duties and functions imposed by general or special laws upon County Attorneys; and he shall perform such other legal duties as may be assigned by the County Commission.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 70-91, § 1, 12-1-70)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-15. Limitation on power to compromise, confess judgment, accept service of process</catch_line>
<text>
The County Attorney shall not compromise, settle or adjust any claims, debts, demands or causes of action in favor of or against the County, or offer to confess judgment against the County, without prior approval of the County Commission or, to the extent he possesses settlement authority, the County Manager or his designee; nor shall the County Attorney accept service of process in any suit or action brought against the County; provided, that this section shall not be construed to limit the discretion of the County Attorney in the proper conduct of the trial of any action, suit or proceeding, nor deprive him of the powers and privileges ordinarily exercised in judicial proceedings by attorneys acting for private clients.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-16. First Assistant County Attorney</catch_line>
<text>
The County Attorney shall designate a First Assistant County Attorney, and during the absence or disability of the County Attorney such First Assistant County Attorney shall be vested with all powers and shall perform all duties and functions of the County Attorney; and in event the Office of County Attorney becomes vacant by death, resignation or other cause the First Assistant County Attorney shall act and serve as County Attorney until such time as the County Commission shall appoint a successor. The First Assistant County Attorney shall perform such other duties as may be assigned to him by the County Attorney.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-17. Annual report</catch_line>
<text>
The County Attorney shall prepare and submit to the County Commission annually a written report concerning the work and activities of the Law Department.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-18. Records and files</catch_line>
<text>
The County Attorney, upon his resignation or removal, shall surrender forthwith to his successor in office all records and files in his possession belonging to the County or relating to the legal affairs of the County, together with a written consent of substitution of his successor in all suits, actions or legal proceedings then pending and undetermined in which the County is a party. All records of the Law Department, except the work products of the County Attorney or his assistants in pending litigation, shall be public records.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-19. Prosecution of violations of County ordinances</catch_line>
<text>
All prosecutions for violations of any County ordinance punishable by fine or imprisonment shall be conducted by the State Attorney, and the County Attorney shall not be responsible for the handling of any criminal prosecutions on behalf of the County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-19.1. Appropriation of funds for prosecution of violations of County ordinances</catch_line>
<text>
The Board hereby appropriates the funding to pay the salary of one (1) Assistant State Attorney whose sole function shall be to prosecute violations of special laws or ordinances of the County. The County Manager is hereby directed to make the funds hereby appropriated available to the State Attorney of the Eleventh Judicial Circuit on a continuing basis.
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 78-67, §§ 1, 2, adopted Oct. 17, 1978, did not expressly amend the Code; hence, inclusion herein as § 2-19.1 is at the discretion of the editor.

State law reference— Salaries and other related costs of State Attorneys' offices, authority of County to appropriate funds, F.S. § 27.34(1).
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-20. Special counsel</catch_line>
<text>
The County Commission may employ special counsel for specific needs of the County. The County Attorney shall not be responsible for the performance of any duties assigned to such special counsel. All special counsels shall serve under the direction and supervision of the County Commission. The compensation fixed and paid for services of special counsel shall not be included in the budget for the Law Department.

FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (6) ---
Annotations—AO's 2-2, 9-1 (Back)
Charter reference— Department of Law, § 4.06. (Back)

</text>
</law>
