<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXXI._IU-3_INDUSTRIAL_UNLIMITEDM</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-264. Uses permitted</catch_line>
<text>
No land, body of water or structure shall be used or permitted to be used, and no structure shall be hereafter erected, constructed, moved or reconstructed, structurally altered or maintained for any purpose in an IU-3 District which is designed, arranged or intended to be used or occupied for any purpose, except for any one (1) or more of the uses listed in this section.
<section prefix = "1">
Every use permitted in the IU-1 and IU-2 Districts, except adult entertainment uses as defined in Section 33-259.1, adult day care centers, and private schools and nonpublic educational facilities as defined in Section 33-151.11 are prohibited in the IU-3 District.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Residential uses as a watchman's or caretaker's quarters used in connection with an existing industrial use located on the premises concerned but for no other residential use.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Uses listed below, subject to the provisions of Section 33-265
Acetylene, generation and storage.
Acids and derivatives.
Alcohol, industrial.
Aluminum, powder and paint manufacture.
Ammonia.
Animal reduction plants.
Asphalt or asphalt products.
Atomic reactor.
Blast furnace.
Bleaching products.
Blooming mill.
Boiler manufacture (other than welded).
Brass and bronze foundries.
Calcium carbide.
Casein.
Caustic soda.
Celluloid.
Cellulose products.
Cement, lime, gypsum or plaster of Paris.
Charcoal, lampblack or fuel briquettes.
Charcoal pulverizing.
Chlorine.
Cider and vinegar.
Cleaning and polishing preparation: dressings and blackings.
Coal tar product.
Coke oven products (including fuel gas) and coke oven product storage.
Cotton wadding.
Cottonseed oil, refining.
Creosote.
Distillation, manufacture or refining of coal, tar, asphalt, wood, bones.
Distillery (alcoholic), breweries and alcoholic spirits.
Dyestuff.
Dynamite storage.
Excelsior.
Explosives.
Fat rendering.
Fertilizer, organic or inorganic, manufacture.
Film, photographic.
Fireworks.
Fish cannery or curing.
Fish oils, meal and by-products.
Flour, feed and grain milling.
Forge plant, pneumatic drop and forging hammering.
Foundries.
Gelatin products.
Glue, gelatin (animal) or glue and size (vegetable).
Graphite.
Guncotton (explosive).
Hair, felt or feathers, washing, curing and dyeing.
Hair, hides and raw fur, curing, tanning, dressing, dyeing and storage.
Hydrogen and oxygen manufacturing.
Insecticides, fungicides, disinfectants, or related industrial and household products (depending on materials and quantities used).
Ink manufacture from primary raw materials (including colors and pigments).
Jute, hemp and sisal products.
Lampblack, carbonblack and boneblack.
Lead oxide.
Linoleum and other similar hard surface floor coverings (other than wood).
Locomotive and railroad car building and repair.
Match manufacture and storage.
Metal and metal ores, reduction, refining, smelting and alloying.
Molasses.
Nitrate (manufactured and natural) of an explosive nature; and storage.
Nitroleng of cotton or other materials.
Nylon.
Oil cloth, oil treated products and artificial leather.
Oil refinery.
Oil wells.
Oils, shortening and fats (edible).
Ore pumps and elevators.
Paint manufacture, depending upon materials and quantities used.
Paper and paperboard (from paper machine only).
Paper and pulp mills.
Petroleum, gasoline and lubricating oil—refining and wholesale storage.
Phenol.
Pickles, vegetable relish and sauces, sauerkraut.
Plastic material and synthetic resins.
Potash.
Poultry slaughtering and packing (wholesale).
Pyroxylin.
Radioactive waste handling.
Rayon and rayon yarns.
Refractories (coal fired).
Refuse disposal.
Rendering and storage of dead animals, offal, garbage and waste products.
Rubber—natural or synthetic, including tires, tubes, or similar products, gutta percha, chickle and valata processing.
Sawmill.
Scrap metal reduction.
Shoddy.
Slaughterhouse.
Smelting.
Soaps (other than from vegetable by-products) or detergents, including fat rendering.
Solvent extraction.
Starch manufacture.
Steel works and rolling (ferrous).
Stockyards.
Storage batteries, wet cell.
Sugar refining.
Testing—jet engines and rockets.
Textiles bleaching.
Turpentine and resin.
Wallboard and plaster, building insulation.
Wire ropes and cable.
Wood preserving treatment.
Wool pulling or scouring.
Yeast.

</section>
</text>
No land, body of water or structure shall be used or permitted to be used, and no structure shall be hereafter erected, constructed, moved or reconstructed, structurally altered or maintained for any purpose in an IU-3 District which is designed, arranged or intended to be used or occupied for any purpose, except for any one (1) or more of the uses listed in this section.
<section prefix = "1">
Every use permitted in the IU-1 and IU-2 Districts, except adult entertainment uses as defined in Section 33-259.1, adult day care centers, and private schools and nonpublic educational facilities as defined in Section 33-151.11 are prohibited in the IU-3 District.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Residential uses as a watchman's or caretaker's quarters used in connection with an existing industrial use located on the premises concerned but for no other residential use.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Uses listed below, subject to the provisions of Section 33-265
Acetylene, generation and storage.
Acids and derivatives.
Alcohol, industrial.
Aluminum, powder and paint manufacture.
Ammonia.
Animal reduction plants.
Asphalt or asphalt products.
Atomic reactor.
Blast furnace.
Bleaching products.
Blooming mill.
Boiler manufacture (other than welded).
Brass and bronze foundries.
Calcium carbide.
Casein.
Caustic soda.
Celluloid.
Cellulose products.
Cement, lime, gypsum or plaster of Paris.
Charcoal, lampblack or fuel briquettes.
Charcoal pulverizing.
Chlorine.
Cider and vinegar.
Cleaning and polishing preparation: dressings and blackings.
Coal tar product.
Coke oven products (including fuel gas) and coke oven product storage.
Cotton wadding.
Cottonseed oil, refining.
Creosote.
Distillation, manufacture or refining of coal, tar, asphalt, wood, bones.
Distillery (alcoholic), breweries and alcoholic spirits.
Dyestuff.
Dynamite storage.
Excelsior.
Explosives.
Fat rendering.
Fertilizer, organic or inorganic, manufacture.
Film, photographic.
Fireworks.
Fish cannery or curing.
Fish oils, meal and by-products.
Flour, feed and grain milling.
Forge plant, pneumatic drop and forging hammering.
Foundries.
Gelatin products.
Glue, gelatin (animal) or glue and size (vegetable).
Graphite.
Guncotton (explosive).
Hair, felt or feathers, washing, curing and dyeing.
Hair, hides and raw fur, curing, tanning, dressing, dyeing and storage.
Hydrogen and oxygen manufacturing.
Insecticides, fungicides, disinfectants, or related industrial and household products (depending on materials and quantities used).
Ink manufacture from primary raw materials (including colors and pigments).
Jute, hemp and sisal products.
Lampblack, carbonblack and boneblack.
Lead oxide.
Linoleum and other similar hard surface floor coverings (other than wood).
Locomotive and railroad car building and repair.
Match manufacture and storage.
Metal and metal ores, reduction, refining, smelting and alloying.
Molasses.
Nitrate (manufactured and natural) of an explosive nature; and storage.
Nitroleng of cotton or other materials.
Nylon.
Oil cloth, oil treated products and artificial leather.
Oil refinery.
Oil wells.
Oils, shortening and fats (edible).
Ore pumps and elevators.
Paint manufacture, depending upon materials and quantities used.
Paper and paperboard (from paper machine only).
Paper and pulp mills.
Petroleum, gasoline and lubricating oil—refining and wholesale storage.
Phenol.
Pickles, vegetable relish and sauces, sauerkraut.
Plastic material and synthetic resins.
Potash.
Poultry slaughtering and packing (wholesale).
Pyroxylin.
Radioactive waste handling.
Rayon and rayon yarns.
Refractories (coal fired).
Refuse disposal.
Rendering and storage of dead animals, offal, garbage and waste products.
Rubber—natural or synthetic, including tires, tubes, or similar products, gutta percha, chickle and valata processing.
Sawmill.
Scrap metal reduction.
Shoddy.
Slaughterhouse.
Smelting.
Soaps (other than from vegetable by-products) or detergents, including fat rendering.
Solvent extraction.
Starch manufacture.
Steel works and rolling (ferrous).
Stockyards.
Storage batteries, wet cell.
Sugar refining.
Testing—jet engines and rockets.
Textiles bleaching.
Turpentine and resin.
Wallboard and plaster, building insulation.
Wire ropes and cable.
Wood preserving treatment.
Wool pulling or scouring.
Yeast.

</section>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-265. Control of uses</catch_line>
<text>
Any person, firm, corporation or other legal entity desiring to use any property or premises situated in an IU-3 District for the manufacture, assembly, processing or packaging of any article or matter enumerated in Section 33-264(3), or for the storage of relatively large quantities of such article or matter (not to include storage where storage is relatively small and incidental to the use of small quantities of such article or matter in connection with manufacture, processing or use permitted in more restrictive districts), or manufacture, assembly, processing, packaging or storage of similar articles or matter, or for any use or operation enumerated in said Section 33-264(3) or for similar use or operation, shall file with the Director a written application setting forth a full description of the proposed use or occupancy, and accurate legal description of the property or premises, a description of the structure or structures to be constructed or occupied, satisfactory proof that the proposed use will conform to the requirements of the Miami-Dade County Pollution Control Ordinance, and such other information as may be reasonably required by the Director, who shall determine from such information, whether or not the proposed use will, in fact, create objectionable influences ordinarily associated with the general type of such uses. If it is found that such use because of the method of operation, or type of materials used, the usual degree of hazardous conditions will not be created, the Director may assign the use to the IU-3 District or to a less restrictive zoning district. However, if it is determined that the high hazards usually anticipated in connection with the uses listed involving fire, explosions, noise, vibration, dust or emissions of smoke, odors, or toxic gases, or other hazards to public health, safety or welfare will be created, the Director shall require approval as result of a public hearing before such use is permitted. Upon filing of the application, the Director shall transmit such application, together with his recommendations, to the Community Zoning Appeals Board, who shall consider the application in accordance with the zoning procedure prescribed by article XXXVI of this chapter, and transmit its recommendations to the County Commission. Provided, however, no use specified in Section 33-264(3) shall be established within five hundred (500) feet of any RU or EU District except after approval after public hearing. Provided, that the spacing limitation shall be two hundred fifty (250) feet if the use is confined within a building and an exterior wall or walls of the building located on the establishment is not penetrated with any openings directly facing the RU or EU District. It is further provided that, except for exterior uses, such distances shall be measured from the closest point of the subject use in the building to the RU or EU District. In connection with exterior uses, the distance of five hundred (500) feet shall be measured from the closest point of the IU District to the RU or EU District. For purposes of establishing such distances, the applicant for such use shall furnish a certified survey from a registered surveyor, which shall indicate such distances. In case of dispute, the measurement scaled by the Director of the Department of Planning and Zoning shall govern.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-266. Wall or dike for storage of petroleum products</catch_line>
<text>
The premises used by gasoline, oil and petroleum storage tanks shall be surrounded by an unpierced fire wall or dike of such height and dimensions as to contain the maximum capacity required by current applicable Miami-Dade County codes. Where an abandoned rock pit is located in an IU-2 or IU-3 District, a permit may be issued to use such pits for oil storage tanks in which dikes may be omitted if the pit has the required capacity. All storage tanks and adjacent structures shall meet the requirements of the current applicable Miami-Dade County codes.
The foregoing paragraph requiring an unpierced fire wall or dike shall not apply to storage tanks containing liquefied petroleum, commonly known as bottled gas; such tanks may be erected without said wall or dike.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-266.1. Uses confined to buildings or within wall enclosures</catch_line>
<text>
At all manufacturing establishments or rebuildings, storage or repair places permitted in an IU-3 District, all materials and products shall be stored and all manufacturing, rebuilding, storing or renovating operations shall be carried on entirely within an enclosed building or confined and completely enclosed within masonry walls, at least six (6) feet in height but no higher than eight (8) feet, excepting only shipyards, dry docks, boat slips, and the like, where necessary frontage on the water may be open.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-266.2. Minimum landscaped open space, greenbelts, trees, maintenance</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Landscaped open space. A minimum of ten (10) percent of the net lot area of the site shall be developed as landscaped open space; provided, however, that an industrial-zoned site that abuts residentially zoned or developed property shall provide fifteen (15) percent of the net lot area as landscaped open space. It is further provided, however, that if the industrial-zoned site abuts property which is depicted as "Industrial and Office" on the Land Use Plan map of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan, is zoned GU and no building permit has been issued for a residence at the time of the approval of the building permit for the industrial use, the landscape open space requirement shall be ten (10) percent of the net lot area. Said landscaped open space may include entrance features, greenbelts, unpaved passive and active recreation areas, and other similar landscaped open space at ground level. Open space areas may also include tree preservation zones of "natural forest communities" as defined in Section 26B-1, Code of Miami-Dade County. Tree preservation zones shall be delineated on all plans submitted to Miami-Dade County for site plan review under Section 33-266.3 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, for the purpose of determining overall preservation area and percent of overall landscaped area. The requirements contained herein do not replace or substitute for any requirements contained within Chapter 18A, Code of Miami-Dade County.
Water bodies may be used as part of the required landscaped open space, but such water areas shall not be credited for more than twenty (20) percent of the required open space. The specific areas within enclosed or unenclosed malls which are landscaped with grass, trees and/or shrubbery, water areas therein and areas therein with permanent landscaped open space, but such areas shall not be credited for more than ten (10) percent of the required landscaped open space. For approved structures exceeding four (4) stories in height, additional landscaped open space shall be provided equivalent to twenty-five (25) percent of the gross floor area of each floor above four (4) stories.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Greenbelts. Continuous, extensively planted greenbelts, penetrated only at approved points for ingress or egress to the property, shall be provided along all property lines abutting public rights-of-way or properties zoned residential, in accordance with the following minimum standards:
<section prefix="1" type="table">
<table class="table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Size of Net</i> <br /> <i>Lot Area</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Width of</i> <br /><i>Greenbelts</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Up to 3 acres</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">8 feet</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than 3 acres</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10 feet</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 
It is provided, however, this greenbelt requirement shall not apply along property lines abutting property which is depicted as "Industrial and Office" on the Land Use Plan map of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan, is zoned GU and no building permit has been issued for a residence at the time of the approval of the building permit for the industrial use.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Trees. Landscaping and trees shall be provided in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Maintenance. All landscaped areas shall be continuously maintained in a good, healthy condition, and sprinkler systems of sufficient size and spacing shall be installed to serve all required landscaped areas except within tree preservation zones of "natural forest communities," as defined in Section 26B-1, Code of Miami-Dade County. Tree preservation zones shall also be maintained in a healthy natural condition free from trash, debris and disturbance of understory vegetation.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 79-99, § 1, 11-20-79; Ord. No. 85-87, § 6, 10-1-85; Ord. No. 95-223, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 03-76, § 3, 4-8-03)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-266.3. Site plan review</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
[Responsibility; purpose; procedures generally.] The Department shall review plans for compliance with zoning regulations and for compliance with the size plan review criteria. The purpose of the site plan review is to encourage logic, imagination, innovation and variety in the design process and encourage the congruity of the proposed development and its compatibility with the surrounding area. All plans submitted to the Department shall be reviewed and approved or denied within fifteen (15) days from the date of submission. The applicant shall have the right to extend the fifteen-day period by an additional fifteen (15) days upon request made in writing to the Department. Denials shall be in writing and shall specifically set forth the grounds for denial. Receipt of applicant's plans for fifteen (15) days without formal written denial shall constitute approval. If the plan is disapproved, the applicant may appeal to the appropriate Community Zoning Appeals Board. Appeals by the applicant shall be filed within thirty (30) days of the date the project was denied.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Required exhibits. The following exhibits shall be prepared by design professionals such as architects and landscape architects and submitted to the Department of Planning and Zoning:
<section prefix = "1">
Dimensioned site plan(s) indicating, as a minimum, the following information:
<section prefix = "a">
Existing zoning on the site and on adjacent properties.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The basic use, height, bulk and location of all buildings and other structures with setbacks.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Vehicular and pedestrian circulation systems including connection(s) to existing or proposed roadway and sidewalk system and the layout of parking, service and loading areas.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Graphics and/or notations indicating the site planning or structure design methods used to minimize the impact of those industrial activities that could have a negative impact on existing or proposed adjacent land uses.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Sketches of design elements to be used for buffering surrounding uses.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Elevation of the proposed buildings and other major design elements.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Landscape plans: Landscaping and trees shall be provided in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Figures indicating the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Proposed uses.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Gross floor area: .....square feet
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Gross floor area above four (4) floors: .....square feet
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Land area: Gross: ..... square feet .....acres Net: ..... square feet ..... acres
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Landscaped open space: Required: ..... square feet ..... % of net land area Provided: ..... square feet ..... % of net land area
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Trees: Required: ..... Provided: .....
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Off-street parking spaces: Required: ..... Provided: .....
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Criteria. The following shall be considered in the plan review process:
<section prefix = "1">
Planning studies: Planning studies approved by the Board of County Commissioners that include development patterns or environmental and other design criteria shall be considered in the plan review process.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Landscape: Landscape shall be preserved in its natural state insofar as is practicable by minimizing removal of existing vegetation. Landscape shall be used to shade and cool, enhance architectural features, relate structure design to the site, visually screen noncompatible uses, and ameliorate the impact of noise.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Compatibility: The architectural design and scale of the proposed structures shall be compatible with surrounding existing or proposed uses or shall be made compatible by the use of screening elements. Screening elements can include such devices as trees and shrubs, walls and fencing, berming or any combination of these elements. Visual buffering shall be provided between parking and service areas and adjacent nonindustrial uses.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Emergency access: Unobstructed on-site access for emergency equipment shall be considered.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Circulation: Internal vehicular and pedestrian circulation systems shall be designed to function with existing and/or approved systems outside the development. Vehicular traffic generated from the industrial activity should be routed in such a manner as to minimize impact on residential development.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Energy conservation: Applicants are advised to consider requirements of Chapter 52 of the South Florida Building Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Visual screening for decorative walls: In an effort to prevent graffiti vandalism, the following options shall be utilized for walls abutting zoned or dedicated rights-of-way:
<section prefix = "a">
Wall with landscaping. The wall shall be setback two and one-half (2½) feet from the right-of-way line and the resulting setback area shall contain a continuous extensively landscaped buffer which must be maintained in a good healthy condition by the property owner, or where applicable, by the condominium, homeowners or similar association. The landscape buffer shall contain one (1) or more of the following planting materials:
<section prefix = "1">
Shrubs. Shrubs shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Hedges. Hedges shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Vines. Climbing vines shall be a minimum of thirty-six (36) inches in height immediately after planting.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Metal picket fence. Where a metal picket fence abutting a zoned or dedicated right-of-way is constructed in lieu of a decorative wall, landscaping shall not be required.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 79-99, § 1, 11-20-79; Ord. No. 95-19, § 15, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 95-223, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-127, § 21, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 98-125, § 21, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 99-38, § 16, 4-27-99)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-266.4. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Section 33-266.4, pertaining to expansion of existing commercial structures, has been deleted as obsolete. The section was derived from Ord. No. 79-99, § 1, adopted Nov. 20, 1979.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-266.5. Validity of site plans</catch_line>
<text>
Where a site plan has been or is submitted to the Department for review and approval, and the same has been or is approved, and no construction has yet commenced, the site plan shall be valid for a period of twelve (12) months, within which time the applicant must file complete plans for building permit.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (42) ---
Editor's note— Barbed-wire fences in IU Districts, § 33-11(f); height of fences, walls and hedges in IU Districts, § 33-11(i); fence in lieu of wall in IU Districts, § 33-11(j); metal buildings in IU Districts, § 33-32 (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
