<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXXVI._ZONING_PROCEDURE</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-302. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
In construing the provisions hereof and each and every word, term, phrase or part thereof where the context will permit the definitions provided in Section 1.01, Florida Statutes, and Chapter 33 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and the following additional definitions, shall apply:
<section prefix = "a">
Comprehensive Development Master Plan. The words "Comprehensive Development Master Plan" shall mean and refer to the Comprehensive Development Master Plan for Miami-Dade County adopted by Ordinance No. 75-22 on March 31, 1975, or as amended.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Conforms to the Comprehensive Development Master Plan. The words "conforms to the Comprehensive Development Master Plan" shall mean and refer to zoning request or action which is consistent with the goals, objectives, standards and policies of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Development. The word "development" shall mean and refer to the carrying out of any use permitted on land by applicable zoning regulations (i.e., Chapter 33 of Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida) or making any material change in the use or character of the land, including, but not limited to, the placement of structure or structures on land. When appropriate to the context, development refers to the act of zoning or rezoning through district boundary changes, site or plot use approvals, or otherwise, which authorizes or permits development of the land.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Developments of County impact. The words "developments of County impact" shall mean and refer to any development which, because of its character, magnitude or location, would have a substantial effect upon the health, safety and welfare of the citizens of Miami-Dade County, Florida. Development activity meeting one (1) of the criteria specified in Section 33-304(d) is declared to be a development of County impact.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Developmental Impact Committee (Committee). The words "Developmental Impact Committee (Committee)" shall mean and refer to the Miami-Dade County Administrative Committee, created by Ord. No. 74-47, adopted on June 18, 1974.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Land. The word "land" shall mean and refer to earth, water and air above, below or on the surface.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Director. The word "Director" shall mean the Director Department of Planning and Zoning.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Department. The word "Department" shall mean the Department of Planning and Zoning.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
District. The word "District" shall mean and refer to the various zoning districts provided by Chapter 33 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
District boundary maps. The words "district boundary maps" shall mean those maps kept on file in the Department showing the boundaries of the various districts, and more particularly described in Section 33-3 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Record. The word "record" when pertaining to the record of any board shall mean and include any application, exhibits, appeal papers, written objections, waivers or consents, considered by such board, transcript or stenographic notes taken for the Department at a hearing held before such board, if any, the board's minutes and resolution showing its decision or action, and if the record of a lower board is transmitted to a higher board, the record of the higher board shall include that of the lower board. The word "record" shall also include any and all applicable portions of Chapter 33 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, the report and recommendations of the Director and the Developmental Impact Committee; the Comprehensive Development Master Plan for Miami-Dade County, Florida; and Ordinance No. 75-22, or as amended, or applicable neighborhood or area studies or plans approved by action of the Board of County Commissioners, as well as applicable district boundary maps, aerial photographs and final zoning resolutions. It shall also include the record made as a result of any previous zoning application on the same property. The Clerk of the County Commission shall identify all exhibits used or referred to at the zoning hearing. All exhibits so identified or introduced shall be a part of the record. The record shall not include documents prepared or relied upon by an expert not filed in accordance with the provisions of Section 33-f(D) of the Code, or any oral testimony or written reports or documents which were not filed in accordance with the provisions of Section 2-114.1 of the Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Regulations or zoning regulations. The word "regulations" or the words "zoning regulations" shall mean and refer to the contents of Chapter 33 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, as from time to time amended.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
Administrative official. The words "administrative official" shall mean the Director and any staff member of the Department authorized by the Director to enforce or interpret the regulations or various zoning resolutions.
</section>
<section prefix = "n">
Public benefit. The words "public benefit" shall mean and refer to a development which, after consideration of all of its aspects (including, but not limited to, environmental impact on facilities, economic and social) would be consistent with and not detrimental to the welfare of the community.
</section>
<section prefix = "o">
Unit. The word "unit" shall mean and refer to houses, apartments, group of rooms, or a single room occupied or intended for permanent or transient occupancy as separate living quarters.
</section>
<section prefix = "p">
Citizen participation. The words "citizen participation" shall refer to the suggestions and comments of responsible and recognized persons and groups to the Developmental Impact Committee during the deliberative processes and prior to final recommendations on appropriate developments. Citizen participation shall not refer to public hearings or adversary proceedings of any nature before the Developmental Impact Committee. The Developmental Impact Committee shall prepare appropriate guidelines involving citizen participation in the process.
</section>
<section prefix = "q">
Zoning actions. The words "zoning action" shall refer to any action pursuant to Chapter 33 of the Code of Miami-Dade County taken after a public hearing, including the acceptance of a declaration of restrictive covenants proffered at a public hearing.
</section>
<section prefix = "r">
Independent development parcel. The words "independent development parcel" shall refer to a development parcel which is buildable in one (1) or more phases, which parcel has parking, an independent circulation system, and sufficient identity to be developed independently of surrounding property. A development parcel may consist of one (1) or more platted tracts, developed as a single independent development parcel.
</section>
<section prefix = "s">
"Immediate vicinity" means an area in which a parcel of land proposed for alternative development is located that is physically, functionally or geographically identifiable as a distinct realm, place or neighborhood, or an area within a radius of not more than five hundred (500) feet from the parcel proposed for alternative development, whichever is smaller.
</section>
<section prefix = "t">
"Open space" means that portion of a parcel of land which is not covered with a building and is open to the sky and may include patios, limited roof overhangs, screened enclosures with screened roofs, open trellises, walkways, swimming pools, tennis courts, landscaped areas, decks, and non-covered parking areas.
</section>
<section prefix = "u">
"Parcel proposed for alternative development" means the site of the structure for which alternative site development option approval is sought.
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
"Proposed alternative development" means any building activity for which alternative site development approval is sought.
</section>
<section prefix = "w">
"Underlying district regulations" means the site development regulations of the particular zoning district in which proposed alternative development is located, such as setbacks, lot area, frontage, and depth, lot coverage, and structure height.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-303. Exclusive procedure</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The procedure provided herein shall be exclusive in the unincorporated area of the County; provided, however, that unless a governmental facility is authorized as a designated permitted use in a zoning district, Miami-Dade County and its agencies and authorities shall not be bound by the procedures herein contained in constructing, erecting or operating any governmental facility listed below in the unincorporated area of Miami-Dade County, and the Board of County Commissioners may establish any governmental facility listed as follows where the Board may direct without regard to the zoning or use classification of any particular site or location: public parks, playgrounds and buildings, and structures supplementary and incidental to such uses; domestic violence centers; fire stations; police stations; public auto inspection stations; public water and sewer treatment and distribution facilities; public libraries; public buildings and centers; public hospitals, nursing homes and health facilities; public auditoriums, arenas, museums, art galleries and convention halls; maximum and minimum detention facilities; solid-waste collection and disposal facilities; public maintenance and equipment yards; public bus stations and Rapid-Transit stations and facilities; and uses determined by the Board of County Commissioners to be similar to those listed above.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Board of County Commissioners may only authorize the erection, construction and operation of the governmental facilities enumerated in Subsection (a) above by resolution following public hearing. The said public hearing shall be held upon at least fifteen (15) days' notice of the time and place of such hearing published in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County, which publication shall include the time and place of hearing before the Board of County Commissioners. A courtesy notice containing general information as to the date, time, and place of the hearing, the property location and general nature of the application may be mailed to the property owners of record, within a radius of three hundred (300) feet of the property described in the application, or such greater distance as the Director may prescribe; provided, however, that failure to mail or receive such courtesy notice shall not affect any action or proceeding taken hereunder. To provide additional notice to the public, the property shall be posted by a sign or signs indicating the action desired and the time and place of the public hearing thereon. Failure to post such property shall not affect any action taken hereunder. At the public hearing the Board of County Commissioners shall consider, among other factors, the type of function involved, the public need therefor, the existing land use pattern in the area, alternative locations for the facility and the nature of the impact of the facility on the surrounding property. After considering these said factors, the Board of County Commissioners shall take such action as is necessary to provide for and protect the public health, safety and welfare of the citizens and residents of Miami-Dade County.
<section prefix = "1">
In the event the Board of County Commissioners authorizes the construction, erection, use or operation of a governmental facility in accordance with the procedures delineated above, or in the event the Board otherwise determines that County-owned property should be utilized by the County for a particular public purpose, the property shall be posted by a sign or signs conspicuously located thereon indicating the governmental facility or use authorized for the property. Such sign or signs may be removed upon the commencement of construction. The County Manager or designee shall periodically check the property to ensure that the signs provided for in this subsection remain in existence and accurately depict the proposed use of the subject property. This subsection shall be construed as directory only and failure to comply with the provisions hereof shall not affect the validity of the County Commission's action authorizing the use of the property for the designated purposes.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Any facility which is designated as or intended to be operated as a domestic violence center at the time of consideration, planning, erection, construction or acquisition, shall be exempt from the notice and public hearing provisions set forth in Subsection (b) above.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The procedure established by this chapter shall be the exclusive procedure when applicable to any airport zoning regulations in both the unincorporated and incorporated areas of the County, and no application for a district boundary change, change in zoning regulations, appeals of administrative decisions, special exceptions or unusual and new uses or variances shall be considered or granted by any County Board or Commission unless the same is provided for by this chapter and only by the procedure and method so provided; provided, however, the Board of County Commissioners may change the zoning regulations without following the procedure provided therefor in this article; provided, however, that no such change will be made unless the written recommendation of the Director and Zoning Official are first considered by the Board. No special permit shall be considered or granted by any County Board or Commission.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
A commissioner may request a deferral of consideration of any item relating to the construction, erection, use or operation of a governmental facility for up to thirty (30) days the first time the item appears on a commission agenda or the first time the item is raised at a commission meeting if the proposed construction, erection, use or operation of the governmental facility affects that commissioner's district exclusively or primarily. Upon the commissioner's invoking this right, discussion upon that item shall cease and the commission shall move to another item of business. The provisions of this Subsection (d) shall be deemed waived unless asserted by a commissioner before the board takes action on the resolution in question.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 60-14, 4-19-60; Ord. No. 61-30, § 1, 6-27-61; Ord. No. 66-66, § 1, 12-20-66; Ord. No. 74-68, § 1, 9-3-74; Ord. No. 75-94, § 1, 11-4-75; Ord. No. 79-30, § 1, 4-17-79; Ord. No. 81-113, § 1, 10-6-81; Ord. No. 87-29, § 1, 5-19-87; Ord. No. 93-11, § 1, 2-16-93; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 97-12, § 2, 2-25-97)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-303.1. Developmental Impact Committee</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
There is hereby established a Developmental Impact Committee composed of members representing the following County departments and agencies or their successor departments or agencies:
<section prefix = "1">
Department of Public Works and Waste Management; two (2) members consisting of one representative from the Traffic Division and one representative from the Solid Waste Division.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources; three (3) members consisting of one representative from the Division of Environmental Resource Management, one representative from the Division of Planning, and one representative from the Development Services Division.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Parks, Recreation and Open Spaces Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Miami-Dade Water and Sewer.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Miami-Dade Police Department, consisting of a representative with responsibility for budget and the District Commander of the district where the application is located, or his or her designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Fire Rescue Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Miami-Dade Transit Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Metropolitan Planning Organization.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
The County Mayor shall invite the School Board of Miami-Dade County, Florida and the South Florida Water Management District each to assign a permanent representative to the Developmental Impact Committee who shall remain permanent employees of the School Board and the district respectively.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Whenever the Developmental Impact Committee is to consider a development of County impact that is proposed in a municipality, representatives of the municipal government shall be invited to serve and participate as ex officio members of the Committee upon all matters relating to the said development.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
The Executive Council of the Developmental Impact Committee shall consist of representatives from the following Departments: Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources; Department of Public Works and Waste Management; Water and Sewer Department; Parks, Recreation and Open Spaces Department; Transit Department; the Secretariat of the Metropolitan Planning Organization (MPO); and the County Mayor or his or her designee. Each Department shall be represented by the Director or an Assistant Director, except that the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources shall be represented by two of the following: the Director, the Assistant Director for Development Services, or the Assistant Director for Environmental Resources Management. Each member may assign staff of the respective department to act on his/her behalf as needed. The Executive Council shall discharge such duties and functions as conferred by the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida and by the ordinances, rules and regulations approved by the Board of County Commissioners. The duties and functions of the Executive Council Chair shall be assumed by each of its members on a rotating basis as needed.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Each named department shall appoint a representative or representatives to the Committee who shall serve full-time in that capacity unless otherwise permitted by the Chairman. The Chairman and members of the Committee shall be furnished with such administrative and clerical assistance as the County Manager deems necessary. They shall sit en banc and shall hold such meetings as required by the Chairman or as prescribed by this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
Duties of the Developmental Impact Committee. The Developmental Impact Committee shall perform the following duties:
<section prefix = "1">
Review all developments of County impact and recommend, where applicable, whether, and the extent to which:
<section prefix = "a">
The development, as proposed, conforms to the Comprehensive Development Master Plan for Miami-Dade County, Florida, and is consistent with the recommendations of any applicable neighborhood or area studies or plans which have been approved by action of the Board of County Commissioners, or is otherwise compatible with the existing area or neighborhood development;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The development would serve a public benefit;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The development, as proposed, will have a favorable or unfavorable impact on the environment and natural resources of Miami-Dade County, including a consideration of the means and estimated cost necessary to minimize the adverse impacts, if any; the extent to which alternatives to alleviate adverse impacts may have a significant impact on the natural and human environment, and an identification of any irreversible or irretrievable commitment of natural resources which would be involved should the development be implemented;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The development, as proposed, will have a favorable or unfavorable impact on the economy of Miami-Dade County, Florida;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The development, as proposed, will efficiently use or unduly burden water, sewer, solid waste disposal, education, recreation or other necessary public facilities which have been constructed or planned and budgeted for construction in the area;
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The development, as proposed, will efficiently use or unduly burden or affect public transportation facilities, including mass transit, public streets, roads and highways, which have been planned and budgeted for construction in the area, and if the development is or will be accessible by private or public roads, streets, or highways.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Review and make recommendations concerning all applications for development approval of a development of regional impact and notices of change to a previously approved development if regional impact which would change in any respect the conditions existing in a current development order, resolution or declaration of restrictions governing land development; provided, however, applications to extend a commencement, build-out date, expiration date, phasing deadline, or applicable mitigation requirements for the maximum period of time declared by state law regardless of any previous extension not to constitute a substantial deviation from existing development orders for currently valid developments of regional impact development orders, and related applications for zoning actions to accomplish only the requested extension, shall not be subject to review by the Developmental Impact Committee; it is further provided, however, that, pursuant to F.S. § 380.06(19)(c)(2), the foregoing exception from DIC review shall not apply to development orders for which, before December 1, 2011, the County has notified a developer that has commenced any construction within the phase for which mitigation is required that the County has entered into a contract for construction of a facility with funds to be provided from the development's mitigation funds for that phase as specified in the development order or written agreement with the developer.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Upon application, determine whether a development of regional impact ("DRI") is essentially built out and issue an appropriate order.
<section prefix = "a">
As used in this subsection "essentially built out" shall mean:
<section prefix = "i">
The development is in compliance with all applicable terms and conditions of the development order except the build out date; and
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Either:
<section prefix = "A">
the amount of the development that remains to be built is less than the substantial deviation threshold specified in § 380.06(19)(b), Fla. Stat., as amended, for each individual land use category, or, for a multi-use development, the sum total of all unbuilt land used as a percentage of the applicable substantial deviation threshold is equal to or less than 100 percent; or
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
The Developmental Impact Committee has determined, after the state land planning agency has previously agreed in writing, that the amount of the development to be built does not create the likelihood of any additional regional impact not previously reviewed.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Hearings before the Executive Council of the DIC pursuant to this subsection shall be noticed in the same manner as applications filed before the Community Zoning Appeals Boards pursuant to Section 33-310 for modifications of DRIs.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The DIC determination that a DRI is essentially built out may be appealed, within fourteen (14) days to the Board of County Commissioners pursuant to the provisions of Section 33-314, Code of Miami-Dade County. The fourteen (14) day appeal period provided herein shall commence on the fourteenth day after transmittal of an order of the Executive Council to the Director. Where the fourteenth day falls on a weekend or legal holiday, the appeal period shall be deemed to extend to the next business day. If the DIC determination is not appealed, the determination shall become final.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Review and make recommendations upon, pursuant to the criteria stated in (D)(1), those applications for zoning action or "development" as defined in Section 33-302 which do not constitute developments of County impact but which, if granted, could result in developments having a significant impact on the natural and human environment of Miami-Dade County, Florida. Such developments shall include but not be limited to those listed in Section 33-303.1(D)(6)(a)1 through 8.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Identify and develop guidelines, and propose rules and regulations concerning the preparation of recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners required by (D)(1), (3) and (6)(c); provided, however, that, as a minimum standard, all recommendations shall fully specify the basis for the conclusions reached as to each item listed in Section 33-303.1(D)(1), (3) and (6)(c). Where a development would have only a neutral impact in terms of the aforesaid items, the recommendation shall so specify.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Upon request, assist the Director and the Zoning Official in the preparation of written recommendations and conditions to the Community Zoning Appeals Board and the Board of County Commissioners as required by Chapter 33 of the Code of Miami-Dade County. The nature and extent of such assistance shall be established by the Executive Council, after consultation with the Director and the Zoning Official, and shall be specified and adopted as part of the committee's rules and regulations, as herein prescribed.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Review and make recommendations concerning County zoning actions, with the exception of applications which seek only non-use variances and/or a modification of a condition(s) or covenant(s) and which do not approve a change of use or an increase in the floor area for any and all nonresidential use(s), which are:
<section prefix = "a">
Required by the regulations to be taken after public hearing, and which would allow individually, or cumulatively within an independent development parcel:
<section prefix = "1">
Residential developments involving in excess of two hundred fifty (250) dwelling units.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Business uses involving in excess of ten (10) acres or one hundred thousand (100,000) square feet of retail floor area, or one thousand (1,000) vehicle off-street parking space capacity.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Recreational, cultural, or entertainment facilities involving in excess of one thousand (1,000) vehicle off-street parking space capacity for single performance or twenty (20) acres.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Office buildings or office complexes involving in excess of one hundred twenty-five thousand (125,000) square feet of floor space, or one thousand (1,000) vehicle off-street parking space capacity.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Industrial, processing or manufacturing activity involving fifty (50) acres, or five hundred (500) vehicle off-street parking space capacity.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Hotel and/or motel developments involving in excess of two hundred fifty (250) units.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
All planned area developments.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Mixed-use developments with two (2) or more of the land use types specified in 1. through 6. above where none of the individual land uses in the development meet or exceed the thresholds listed in 1. through 6. above and where the sum of the percentages of the appropriate thresholds listed in 1. through 6. above for each applicable land use in the development is greater than one hundred thirty (130) percent. Where a development addresses more than one (1) threshold within a particular land use type listed in 1. through 6. above, then the threshold in that land use type which generates the highest percentage shall be utilized in the calculation of the total mixed-use percentage for the subject development.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Required by the regulations to be taken after public hearing, which zoning action would change in any respect an existing resolution pertaining to an application reviewed by the Developmental Impact Committee, and is presumed to constitute a substantial deviation. All such applications for change shall be presumed to request substantial deviation, unless the requested action neither equals, exceeds, or conflicts with either of the following limitations and standards:
<section prefix = "1">
An increase in the number of dwelling units of twenty (20) percent or one hundred (100) units, whichever is less.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
An increase in the floor area for nonresidential uses of twenty (20) percent or thirty thousand (30,000) square feet, whichever is less;
The foregoing presumption of substantial deviation shall not apply whenever the Executive Council determines that the requested modification would not constitute a potential negative impact under the guidelines of Section 33-301.1(D)(1). The determination by the Executive Council shall be final and not subject to administrative appeal. There shall be no right of judicial review until after final action on the application by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Committee shall recommend to the applicable Board whether, and to the extent to which, the development permitted by the approval of zoning action referred to in (6)(a) and (b) above will efficiently use or unduly burden water, sewer, solid waste disposal, education, recreation or other necessary public facilities or public transportation facilities, including roads, streets and highways, which have been constructed or planned and budgeted for construction in the area, and whether the proposed development will have a favorable or unfavorable impact on the economy of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
No public hearing shall be held by any board on any application for zoning action approval subject to review by the Developmental Impact Committee until the Committee has made its recommendations with regard thereto.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The Committee shall promulgate rules and regulations establishing guidelines, criteria and procedures for the expeditious review of all said zoning actions involving site or plot use plans. In establishing such criteria, the Committee is instructed to encourage originality, increase residential amenities, enhance the appearance of the neighborhood, and, where possible, to preserve the natural features and encourage the best utilization of the land for the benefit, use, and enjoyment of future residents and owners of the property consistent with the overall good of the community.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Issue letters of interpretation as to whether an application would permit a "development of County impact."
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Assist the Director in the preparation of a development manual prescribing uniform standards of, and procedures for, development in Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Establish, and from time to time amend, rules and regulations relating to the preparation of site plans, and other matters, which will assist the general public in complying with the provisions of this section, or such other ordinances relating hereto as may be enacted; provided, however, that such rules and regulations, and amendments thereto, shall only become effective when approved by the Board of County Commissioners following public hearing thereon and filed with the Clerk of the County Commission.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Serve, in their individual capacities as Committee members, as liaison to the respective County departments or agencies on all matters herein prescribed.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Render preliminary opinions, following preapplication conferences, if requested, on development impacts of zoning applications as established by rule and regulation.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Assist in the preparation and updating of a capital improvement program for Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
Encourage in any manner deemed appropriate by the Developmental Impact Committee responsible citizen contributions to its deliberative processes prior to making final recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
Perform such other functions as prescribed by the County Manager.
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
Recommend a reasonable review fee to be established by administrative order. No such administrative order shall be effective until approved at a public hearing before the Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
Serve as the Land Development Regulation Commission as provided for in Section 163.3164, Florida Statutes, and develop, recommend and review land development regulations, or amendments thereto, and make recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners as to the consistency of the proposal with the Comprehensive Development Master Plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
Review and make recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners concerning all development agreements as defined in Section 33G-8 as required by Section 33G-8((a) and (b)) of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
Review and make recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners on all applications for public charter school facilities and all applications for expansions or modifications to existing public charter school facilities.
</section>
<section prefix = "20">
Review and accept on behalf of Miami-Dade County declarations of restrictive covenants running in favor of Miami-Dade County and proffered by applicants for public charter school facilities that are exempt pursuant to Section 33-161 of this code from the zoning hearing process in this article, provided that said declarations provide for development restrictions or enhancements that will ensure development of proposed charter school facilities that are consistent with the Comprehensive Development Master Plan and with applicable zoning regulations.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 75-47, § 2, 6-18-75; Ord. No. 76-51, § 1, 6-1-76; Ord. No. 76-56, § 1, 6-15-76; Ord. No. 76-107, § 2, 12-7-76; Ord. No. 77-3, § 1, 1-4-77; Ord. No. 80-93, § 1, 9-16-80; Ord. No. 82-4, § 2, 2-2-82; Ord. No. 83-59, § 2, 7-19-83; Ord. No. 87-48, § 1, 7-7-87; Ord. No. 88-50, § 1, 6-7-88; Ord. No. 89-10, § 4, 2-21-89; Ord. No. 89-66, § 2, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 91-24, § 2, 2-19-91; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 21, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 98-176, § 1, 12-3-98; Ord. No. 99-123, § 3, 9-21-99; Ord. No. 00-31, § 2, 2-24-00; Ord. No. 01-87, § 1, 5-8-01; Ord. No. 03-133, § 1, 6-3-03; Ord. No. 04-108, § 3, 6-8-04; Ord. No. 09-76, § 1, 9-1-09; Ord. No. 11-86, § 1, 11-15-11; Ord. No. 13-16, § 3, 2-5-13</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-303.2. Airport Developmental Impact Committee</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby established an Airport Developmental Impact Committee Executive Council. When a zoning application under Article XXXVII of this code (Miami International Airport (Wilcox Field) Zoning) or under Article XXXVIII of this code (Opa Locka Airport Zoning) is for property located entirely in the unincorporated area of Miami-Dade County, the Airport Developmental Impact Committee Executive Council shall be composed of the County's Developmental Impact Committee Executive Council established by Section 33-303.1 of this code, and the Director of Miami-Dade County Aviation Department, or designee, as a non-voting member. When a zoning application under Article XXXVII or Article XXXVIII of the code is for property located in whole or in part in the incorporated area of any municipality, the Airport Developmental Impact Committee Executive Council shall be composed of the persons described above and the Mayor of the municipality, if not a voting member of the municipal governing body, or if the Mayor is a voting member, then the City Manager of said municipality serving as the representative from the municipality where the application property is located. The Airport Developmental Impact Committee Executive Council shall, in accordance with the procedures in Section 33-303.1 of this code, review and make recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners on all applications for exceptions, variances and appeals of decisions on applications for site plan approval under Article XXXVII and Article XXXVIII of this code.
Mailed notice of meetings of the Airport Developmental Impact Committee Executive Council shall be provided in the manner prescribed for notice of applications for special exceptions under Section 33-310(d)(2) of this code. Mailed notice of meetings shall also be provided simultaneously to any municipality in which an application site is located. Applications shall comply with the procedural requirements of Section 33-304 of this code.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-304. Applications</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
All requests for a district boundary change, changes in the zoning regulations, appeals of administrative decisions, special exceptions or unusual uses, new uses, variances, approvals of or modifications to developments of regional impact ("DRI"), including substantial deviation determinations, and determinations that a DRI is essentially built out, shall be made by filing an application therefor with the Director on application forms prescribed by the Director or by rule and regulation of the Developmental Impact Committee. Forms shall include, but not be limited to, disclosure forms for corporations, trusts, and partnerships, and disclosure of information regarding contract purchasers and their percentage(s) of interest. Disclosure shall not be required of: i) any entity, the equity interests in which are regularly traded on an established securities market in the United States or another country; or ii) pension funds or pension trusts of more than five thousand (5,000) ownership interests; or iii) any entity where ownership interests are held in a partnership, corporation or trust consisting of more than five thousand (5,000) separate interests, including all interests at every level of ownership, and where no one (1) person or entity holds more than a total of five (5) percent of the ownership interest in the partnership, corporation or trust. Entities whose ownership interests are held in a partnership, corporation, or trust consisting of more than five thousand (5,000) separate interests, including all interests at every level of ownership, shall only be required to disclose those ownership interest which exceed five (5) percent of the ownership interest in the partnership, corporation, or trust. Disclosure forms shall be established by administrative order to be approved by the Board of County Commissioners. Such disclosure forms shall be included in the agendas distributed in connection with the public hearing on the application. Where applicable, requests shall specify whether, and the extent to which, the requested change in land use or proposed development conforms to the Comprehensive Development Master Plan for Miami-Dade County, Florida.
All requests which authorizes or permits development filed pursuant to this section shall include a boundary survey of the property which is the subject of the application performed in accordance with Chapter 61G17-6.0031, Florida Administrative Code as may be amended from time to time in the event any portion of the property is contiguous to or across the street from a municipal boundary. It is further provided that such survey shall depict the location of any municipal boundary on or across the property being surveyed. The boundary survey submitted shall have been updated within one year proceeding the date of an application filed pursuant to this section.
Upon the approval of a zoning application in whole or in part, a period of six (6) months must run prior to the filing of any subsequent application on the same property; provided that the appropriate board upon approving the application may provide for a different waiting period upon a showing of good cause. Applications approved for withdrawal without prejudice must wait a period of six (6) months prior to the filing of any subsequent application on the same property; provided that the appropriate board upon approving the withdrawal without prejudice may provide for a different waiting period upon a showing of good cause. Upon the final denial of a zoning application without prejudice, a period of one (1) year must run prior to the filing of a subsequent application on the same property; provided that the appropriate board upon denying the application without prejudice may provide for a different waiting period upon a showing of good cause. Upon the withdrawal or final denial of a zoning application with prejudice in whole or in part, a period of eighteen (18) months must run prior to the filing of a subsequent application. In the event an application in whole or in part has been twice or more denied or withdrawn, a period of two (2) years must run prior to the filing of any subsequent application. Such periods of limitation shall not commence to run until the decision has been rendered by the last Board to consider the application. Further, such periods of limitation shall not apply to applications filed by the Director or the Zoning Official.
Notwithstanding the provisions in the foregoing paragraph, it is expressly provided that, except for applications that have been twice or more denied or withdrawn, there shall be no period of limitation for either (1) a subsequent application that proposes a lesser total density or a less intense use than the preceding application, as determined by the Director at the time of filing; (2) a subsequent application that proposes five (5) or fewer residential units; or (3) a subsequent application that proposes development in the "urban infill area," as that area is defined in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan.
An application may be withdrawn without prejudice by the applicant as a matter of right, provided the request for withdrawal is in writing and executed in the same manner as provided by Section 33-309 for the executing of application, and filed with the Department no later than forty (40) days prior to the public hearing; otherwise all such requests for withdrawal shall be with prejudice save and except that the Community Zoning Appeals Boards or the Board of County Commissioners may permit withdrawals without prejudice at the time the matter is considered by such Boards; provided, further, no application may be withdrawn after final action has been taken.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
All zoning hearing applications delineated in this chapter shall only be accepted during the established filing periods. which shall consist of three consecutive days beginning on the first and third Monday of each month. It is provided however that no zoning application will be accepted on a day set forth above which occurs on a legal holiday. Administrative variances may be filed at any time.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
At the end of each said time period set forth in subpart (b) the Director shall promptly identify and group those applications for district boundary changes, use special exceptions, unusual and new uses and use variances which relate to or affect any particular or immediate neighborhood or area as determined by the Director, and, to the extent possible, shall notice public hearings thereon, in accordance with Section 33-310 of the Code of Miami- Dade County, so as to allow the appropriate board to consider and determine the effect of the said applications on the said neighborhood or area as a whole and their relation to and conformity with the Comprehensive Development Master Plan. Upon receipt of an application, the Director shall forward the application to the appropriate Departments, as determined by the Director, for review. To allow for timely processing of applications. Department comments are to be provided to the Director within twenty-one (21) days following transmittal of the request for review, unless a greater review period is allowed by the Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
All applications for zoning action which would permit, if granted, development activity that meets one (1) of the following criteria are hereby declared "developments of county impact":
<section prefix = "1">
Residential apartment developments involving in excess of eight hundred (800) units;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
All planned developments (provided by article XXXIIIB) or cluster developments (provided by article XXXIIIA) involving in excess of eight hundred (800) units;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Business uses involving in excess of thirty (30) acres or one hundred fifty thousand (150,000) square feet of retail floor area, or one thousand five hundred (1,500) vehicle off-street parking space capacity;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Mobile home parks involving in excess of eight hundred (800) mobile home units;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Townhouse developments involving in excess of one hundred (100) acres or eight hundred (800) units;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Recreational, cultural, or entertainment facilities, exclusive of golf courses, involving in excess of one thousand five hundred (1,500) vehicle off-street parking space capacity for single performances of fifty (50) acres;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Office buildings or office complexes involving two hundred fifty thousand (250,000) square feet of floor space, or one thousand five hundred (1,500) vehicle off-street parking space capacity;
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Industrial, processing or manufacturing activity involving in excess of one hundred (100) acres, or one thousand (1,000) vehicle off-street parking space capacity;
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Hotel and/or motel developments involving in excess of five hundred (500) units;
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Detached single-family development involving in excess of eight hundred (800) units.
If any applicant is in doubt as to whether his proposed development would be a development of County impact, he may request a determination from the Developmental Impact Committee. Within thirty (30) days of the receipt of such request, the Chairman, on behalf of the Developmental Impact Committee, shall issue a letter of interpretation with respect to the proposed development. Where an application seeks only a special exception for site or plot use plan approval, the Developmental Impact Committee may require completion of a site plan application on a form prescribed by rule and regulation.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Amendments to an application shall be permitted; provided that, unless otherwise requested, suggested or concurred in by the Developmental Impact Committee, no substantial amendment shall be accepted by the Director within thirty (30) days prior to the first scheduled hearing on the application by the appropriate board or once the application has been heard and determined by the Community Zoning Appeals Board; provided further that an applicant may petition the appropriate board to permit such amendment at the time of hearing on the application and such amendment shall be accepted if approved by majority vote of those present upon good cause shown and provided it falls within the scope of the legal advertisement. In determining good cause, the appropriate board shall consider, among other factors, the timeliness of the amendment and the degree of inconvenience or surprise to objectors to the application. It is further provided that an amendment to correct a scrivener's error shall be permitted at any time up to and including the time of hearing.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
All planned area development applications shall adhere to the following procedures which shall be deemed exclusive notwithstanding any other section herein: The Department shall submit the required exhibits for the total development plan to the Developmental Impact Committee for review in accordance with standards and review procedures of the Developmental Impact Committee. At a public hearing held by the Community Zoning Appeals Board, the developer shall present the proposal. The Community Zoning Appeals Board shall have the recommendations of the Developmental Impact Committee. The Community Zoning Appeals Board shall consider the information presented by the applicant, the recommendations of the Developmental Impact Committee and viewpoints of the public expressed at the hearing. The Community Zoning Appeals Board shall take formal action either approving the plan as presented, approving it subject to certain specified modifications, or disapproving it. Upon approval, plans, documents and recordable development agreements shall be filed with the Department and recorded in the official records and shall thereby constitute the planned area development district. If the planned area development is approved with specific modifications, as incorporated in the Community Zoning Appeals Board resolution, those modifications shall be made by the applicant prior to filing documents and plans with the Department. Such filing shall be completed within sixty (60) working days from the date the action of the Community Zoning Appeals Board becomes final including all appeals. Failure to do so shall nullify the Community Zoning Appeals Board's action unless waived by the Community Zoning Appeals Board or if appealed, by the County Commission. The Director shall review all modifications in accordance with the Community Zoning Appeals Board's resolution. The approved planned area development shall be indicated on the zoning map as would any other district boundary change. Review at the development tract level may then be initiated pursuant to the provisions of the planned area development districts.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Extensions granted by the Florida Legislature for development orders or development permits shall be approved administratively upon application on a form prescribed by the Director and shall not be subject to the provisions of Sections 33-310 and 33-310.1 of this Chapter. It is provided, however, that an extension shall not be approved administratively where the Director determines: (i) that the permit holder is in significant noncompliance with the conditions of the permit or order, as established through the issuance of a warning letter or notice of violation, the initiation of formal enforcement, or other equivalent action; (ii) that extension of the permit or order would delay or prevent compliance with a court order; or (iii) that extension of the permit or order would create an immediate threat to public safety or health.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 60-14, 4-19-60; Ord. No. 61-30, § 1, 6-27-61; Ord. No. 62-48, § 1A, 12-4-62; Ord. No. 63-12, § 1, 4-16-63; Ord. No. 71-35, § 1, 4-22-71; Ord. No. 74-20, § 1, 4-3-74; Ord. No. 74-40, § 1, 6-4-74; Ord. No. 75-47, § 3, 6-18-75; Ord. No. 76-107, § 1, 12-7-76; Ord. No. 78-16, §§ 1, 2, 3-21-78; Ord. No. 78-52, § 2, 7-18-78; Ord. No. 79-20, § 1, 3-6-79; Ord. No. 83-59, § 3, 7-19-83; Ord. No. 88-82, § 1, 9-6-88; Ord. No. 89-24, § 1, 4-4-89; Ord. No. 89-96, § 1, 10-17-89; Ord. No. 91-31, § 1, 3-5-91; Ord. No. 92-67, § 2, 7-7-92; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 95-217, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-127, § 34, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 98-125, § 21, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 98-172, § 1, 12-1-98; Ord. No. 00-31, § 2, 2-24-00; Ord. No. 02-9, § 1, 1-29-02; Ord. No. 02-150, § 1, 9-12-02; Ord. No. 02-254, § 1, 12-3-02; Ord. No. 03-131, § 1, 6-3-03; Ord. No. 13-16, § 4, 2-5-13)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-304.1. Voluntary contribution or dedication of property to Miami-Dade County or Miami-Dade County School Board</catch_line>
<text>
No applicant for zoning action pursuant to Chapter 33 shall seek to induce favorable consideration of such application through contribution, dedication or conveyance of land for use of Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade County School Board unless the following requirements have been met:
<section prefix = "A">
Property proposed to be conveyed to Miami-Dade County.
<section prefix = "1">
The zoning applicant has submitted to the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management an environmental site assessment for the subject property which specifically complies with the requirements set forth in the American Society for Testing and Materials (ASTM) Standards on Environmental Site Assessments for Commercial Real Estate, Second Edition, E1527-94 Standard Practice for Environmental Site Assessments: Phase I Environmental Site Assessment Process and 1528-93 Standard Practice for Environmental Site Assessments Transaction Screen Process.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management has provided a recommendation after considering the environmental site assessment.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Property proposed to be conveyed to the Miami-Dade County School Board.
<section prefix = "1">
The zoning applicant has submitted to the Miami-Dade County School Board an environmental site assessment for the subject property which specifically complies with the requirements set forth in the American Society for Testing and Materials (ASTM) Standards on Environmental Site Assessments for Commercial Real Estate, Second Edition, E1527-94 Standard Practice for Environmental Site Assessments: Phase I Environmental Site Assessment Process and 1528-93 Standard Practice for Environmental Site Assessments Transaction Screen Process.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Miami-Dade County School Board has provided a recommendation regarding the School Board's acceptance of the proposed conveyance or dedication after considering the environmental site assessment.

This section shall not be the subject of any variance request.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-305. District boundary maps</catch_line>
<text>
The Board of County Commissioners shall by resolution adopt, approve and ratify the district boundary maps as originally adopted by Resolution No. 895 of August 2, 1938, and as modified, amended and changed by subsequent resolutions, and the Director shall continue to maintain and keep on file in the Department such maps showing thereon the boundaries of districts. The district boundary maps shall be amended, modified and changed by resolution of the County Commission or Community Zoning Appeals Board as hereinafter provided, and shall be prima facie evidence of the boundaries of districts.
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Section 33-3 refers to the zoning maps on file in the office of the Building and Zoning Department and provides that changes in the boundaries shall be made in accordance with appropriate law.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-306. Community Zoning Appeals Boards—Establishment</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
There are hereby established multiple Community Zoning Appeals Boards whose boundaries shall coincide with the boundaries of Community Councils established pursuant to the Code of Miami-Dade County. The Community Councils shall serve as Community Zoning Appeals Boards and shall have jurisdiction over zoning applications as provided in this chapter. Each member shall be a qualified elector of Miami-Dade County, with an outstanding reputation for civic interest, community welfare, integrity and responsibility; provided, no member shall be employed by Miami-Dade County, or be a member of the County Commission. The seven (7) members of each Community Zoning Appeals Board shall serve without compensation but shall be entitled to reimbursement for necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties, upon approval of the County Commission.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
These boards are created and established pursuant to Section 4.08 of the Home Rule Charter, and for the purpose of facilitating the zoning powers granted by the Home Rule Charter to the Board of County Commissioners, and to provide a board to hear, consider and review appeals from the zoning regulations or decisions of an administrative official, and to take appropriate action as in this article provided and limited.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 60-14, 4-19-60; Ord. No. 61-30, § 1, 6-27-61; Ord. No. 64-39, § 17, 9-1-64; Ord. No. 64-65, § 1, 12-15-64; Ord. No. 68-51, § 1, 9-19-68; Ord. No. 96-127, § 35, 9-4-96)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-307. Community Zoning Appeals Boards—Term of office</catch_line>
<text>
The term of office of the members of each of the Community Zoning Appeals Boards shall be the terms established as members of Community Councils. In the event a vacancy should occur on a Community Zoning Appeals Board the appropriate Community Zoning Appeals Board may fill the vacancy for the remaining board member's term by appointment pursuant to Section 20-43(A)(7) of the Code.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-307.1. Community Zoning Appeals Board; prohibition of members appearance</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
No member of a Community Zoning Appeals Board may appear on behalf of a third person before another Community Zoning Appeals Board or before the County Commission sitting in its capacity as the zoning authority pursuant to Chapter 33, Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
No member of a Community Zoning Appeals Board shall appear at any public hearings or meetings before the Board of County Commissioners or any other federal, state, or local board or tribunal, to advocate concerning any zoning application that was heard by, or that could reasonably be expected to be heard by, any Community Council.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Violation of this section shall constitute grounds for removal pursuant to § 20-43.2
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-64, § 1, 6-8-99; Ord. No. 05-139, § 1, 7-7-05)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-308. Community Zoning Appeals Board—Organization</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
The Director shall serve as secretary for the Community Zoning Appeals Boards, shall be in attendance at all meetings as an advisor and be permitted to propound questions and give evidence; provided, the Director shall have authority to designate a staff member of the Department to act in the Director's stead.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Meetings of the Community Zoning Appeals Boards shall be held, where practical, in the area of each Community Zoning Appeals Board's jurisdiction at a time and place determined by the Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Each Community Zoning Appeals Board shall elect a Chair and a Vice-Chair from its members, each of whom shall serve until a successor is elected.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
Rules and regulations for the Community Zoning Appeals Boards shall be adopted by the County Mayor or the Mayor's designee and approved by the County Commission.
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
The Chair, or Vice-Chair, or Acting Chair, may administer oaths and compel the attendance of witnesses in the same manner prescribed in the Circuit Court.
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
Voting Requirements. No action shall be taken on any matter before the Community Zoning Appeals Boards unless a quorum of four (4) members is present, and only upon not less than a majority vote of all members present and voting provided however that any approval or denial of any application or portion thereof pursuant to Chapter 33 shall require not less than three (3) votes. When there is an insufficient number of votes to either approve or deny an application, the result shall be deemed a tie vote. Whenever a tie vote occurs, and no other available motion on the application is made and approved before the next application is called for consideration or before a recess or adjournment is called, whichever occurs first, the matter shall be carried over to the next regularly scheduled meeting.
</section>
<section prefix = "G">
Minutes will be kept of all meetings and proceedings and shall include and state the vote of each member on each question, and the motion shall state the reason upon which it is made; such reason or reasons being based upon the prescribed guides and standards and good zoning and planning principles. If a member is absent from voting, the minutes shall so indicate. The Community Zoning Appeals Boards shall keep accurate records of their public hearings which shall be filed, together with their minutes and resolutions, with the Department, and the same shall be open for public inspection at reasonable times and hours.
</section>
<section prefix = "H">
The Director shall furnish from the Department such staff as may be necessary to assist and advise the Community Zoning Appeals Boards in the fulfillment of their duties, and is authorized to retain a qualified reporter to record and transcribe the public hearing proceedings of the Community Zoning Appeals Board, and shall provide County transportation for such Board for the purpose of making inspections of sites involved in zoning applications.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 60-14, 4-19-60; Ord. No. 61-30, § 1, 6-27-61; Ord. No. 62-18, § 1B, 12-4-62; Ord. No. 64-3, § 1, 2-4-64; Ord. No. 64-39, § 19, 9-1-64; Ord. No. 64-54, § 1, 10-23-64; Ord. No. 64-65, § 2, 12-15-64; Ord. No. 66-66, § 2, 12-20-66; Ord. No. 68-51, § 3, 9-19-68; Ord. No. 72-99, § 2, 12-19-72; Ord. No. 79-104, § 1, 12-4-79; Ord. No. 80-20, § 1, 3-4-80; Ord. No. 91-19, § 2, 2-19-91; Ord. No. 91-20, § 1, 2-19-91; Ord. No. 96-127, § 35, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 97-16, § 3, 2-25-97; Ord. No. 11-62, § 2, 8-2-11)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-309. Community Zoning Appeals Board/Board of County Commissioners Applications for public hearing</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
All hearings before the Community Zoning Appeals Board or the Board of County Commissioners shall be initiated by the filing with the Department an application on forms prescribed by the Director, executed and sworn to by the owner or owners of at least seventy-five (75) percent of the property described in the application, or by tenant or tenants, with owner's written sworn-to consent or by duly authorized agents, evidenced by a written power of attorney, if not a member of the Florida Bar, or by the Director, or by any person aggrieved by an order, requirement, decision or determination of an administrative official when appealing the same, or by anyone desiring an amendment or repeal to the zoning regulations. All properties described in one (1) application must be contiguous and immediately adjacent to one (1) another, and the Director may require more than one (1) application if the property concerned contains more than forty (40) acres, or the fee paid for one (1) application would not equal the cost of processing the same. Only applications which the Community Zoning Appeals Board or the Board of County Commissioners are authorized to consider and act upon shall be accepted for filing.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Applications which are to be considered by the Community Zoning Appeals Boards in accordance with this chapter shall be assigned by the Director to the Community Zoning Appeals Board which has jurisdiction based upon the location of the property which is encompassed by the application. In the event that the property which is encompassed by the application is located in more than one (1) Community Zoning Appeals Board's district the application shall be heard directly by the County Commission.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Whenever any hearing is initiated by the Director or the Zoning Official, pursuant to this section, the County Mayor may order that no building permits shall be issued for any construction work on the property involved in the hearing, until the hearing has been finally concluded in accordance with the provisions of this Code. Should the County Mayor issue such an order the administrative personnel shall schedule the application for the first public hearing date after appropriate legal notice.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 60-14, 4-19-60; Ord. No. 61-30, § 1, 6-27-61; Ord. No. 69-88, § 1, 12-3-69; Ord. No. 70-39, § 1, 5-13-70; Ord. No. 70-80, § 1, 10-27-70; Ord. No. 72-53, § 1, 9-19-72; Ord. No. 74-20, § 2, 4-3-74; Ord. No. 83-60, § 1, 7-19-83; Ord. No. 91-91, § 1, 9-16-91; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-127, § 35, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 97-16, § 3, 2-25-97; Ord. No. 97-106, § 1, 7-8-97; Ord. No. 09-76, § 4, 9-1-09; Ord. No. 11-86, § 2, 11-15-11; Ord. No. 13-16, § 5, 2-5-13)</history>
Note—According to Ordinance No. 97-66, § 1, adopted May 20, 1997, notwithstanding the provisions of Section 42 of Ordinance No. 97-127, all zoning applications that were filed prior to February 4, 1997, but have not been advertised for public hearing as of the effective date of this ordinance shall be heard by the appropriate Zoning Appeals Board if such hearing is otherwise within the jurisdiction of the Community Zoning Appeals Board. Further, all zoning applications pending before the Zoning Appeals Board and the Board of County Commissioners that have not been concluded prior to July 31, 1997, and that are otherwise within the jurisdiction of the Community Zoning Appeals Boards shall be heard by the appropriate Community Zoning Appeals Board, if necessary, readvertising shall be accomplished at the expense of the County. It is provided, however, that all appeals from the Zoning Appeals Board shall continue to be heard by the Board of County Commissioners.
<catch_line>Sec. 33-310. Notice and hearing prerequisite to action by the Community Zoning Appeals Boards or Board of County Commissioners</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
When an application as prescribed by Sections 33-304 and 33-309 has been filed hereunder the Director shall, no later than thirty (30) days after filing, at the cost of the applicant, provide mailed courtesy notice of such filing as provided in Section 33-310(d); provided, however, that the failure to mail or receive this courtesy notice shall not affect any action or proceeding taken hereunder. The courtesy notice shall include the applicant's name, the processing number, the property size, the location (and street address, if available) of the property, a general description of the action requested in the application, and a statement that the application was filed and is being reviewed by the Department and that a future notice will be provided prior to the public hearing thereon. The notice shall additionally state and make clear that any interested person is entitled to discuss the application with the County employees processing and reviewing the application to the same extent as the applicant is so entitled and that the application may change during the hearing process. The person or persons mailing the courtesy notice provided, herein shall attach an affidavit or affidavits thereof to the application's file setting forth the compliance with this subsection. The courtesy notice provided in this paragraph shall not be required for appeals filed in conjunction with Section 33-313 or 33-314 of the Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Applications filed hereunder shall be promptly transmitted to the appropriate board, together with the written recommendation of the Director. Where applicable the Developmental Impact Committee shall issue its recommendation, which shall include a statement of the Director as to the application's relationship to the Comprehensive Development Master Plan. All such recommendations shall state all facts relevant to the application, including an accurate depiction of known living, working, traffic and transportation conditions in the vicinity of the property that is the subject of the application, and also a description of all projected effects of the proposed zoning action on those conditions. Before reaching a conclusion, each recommendation shall list all known factors both in favor of and against each application. All such recommendations shall be signed and considered final no earlier than thirty (30) days prior to the public hearing to give the public an opportunity to provide information to the staff prior to the recommendations becoming final. This shall not preclude earlier, preliminary recommendations. All documents of the County departments evaluating the application, which documents pertain to the application, are open for public inspection to applicants or other interested persons.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
No action on any application shall be taken by the Community Zoning Appeals Boards or the Board of County Commissioners on any appeal, until a public hearing has been held upon notice of the time, place and purpose of such hearing, the cost of said notice to be borne by the applicant. Notice shall be provided as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
Said notice shall be published twice in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County, as follows: (A) a full legal notice, to be published no later than twenty (20) days and no earlier than thirty (30) days prior to the public hearing, to contain the date, time and place of the hearing, the property's location (and street address, if available), and nature of the application, including all specific variances and other requests; and (B) a layman's notice, to be published in the newspaper of largest circulation in Miami-Dade County, no later than twenty-five (25) days and no earlier than thirty-five (35) days prior to the public hearing, to contain the same information as the above described full legal notice except that the property's legal description may be omitted and the nature of the application and requests contained therein may be summarized in a more concise, abbreviated fashion. The layman's notice may be published in a section or a supplement of the newspaper distributed only in the locality where the property subject to the application lies. In the event that any time periods specified in this subsection shall conflict with any applicable provision of the Florida Statutes, the provision of the Florida Statutes shall govern.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Mailed notice containing general information, including, but not limited to, the date, time and place of the hearing, the property's location (and street address, if available), and nature of the application shall be sent as provided by Subsection 33-310(d) no sooner than thirty (30) days and no later than twenty (20) days prior to the hearing.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The property shall be posted no later than twenty (20) days prior to the hearing in a manner conspicuous to the public, by a sign or signs containing information including, but not limited to, the applied for zoning action, application number, and the time and place of the public hearing. The property owner shall be responsible for ensuring that the sign is maintained on the site until completion of the public hearing and for removal of the sign within two (2) weeks following completion of the public hearing.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Mailed notice shall be accomplished by placing in the United States mail a written notice to all property owners of record, as reflected on the Miami-Dade County Property Appraiser's tax roll as updated, within the following radius of the property described in the application, or such greater distance as the Director may prescribe:
<section prefix = "1">
Approvals of or modifications to Developments of Regional Impact ("DRI"), including substantial deviation determinations or modifications thereof, one (1) mile.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
For applications, other than for Developments of Regional Impact, required to be reviewed by the Development Impact Committee; for district boundary changes, use variances, special exceptions, or unusual uses unless the foregoing are specifically itemized in subsection (d)(3) or (d)(4); for any modification of a covenant accepted or condition imposed in connection with a prior district boundary change or use variance; but this subsection shall not apply to residential uses of less than five (5) units, one-half (½) mile.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
For modification or elimination of conditions or restrictive covenants, or parts thereof, after public hearing, mailed notice shall be accomplished by placing in the United States mail a written notice to all property owners of record, as reflected on the Miami-Dade County Property Appraiser's tax roll as updated, within the same radius of the property as required to be noticed for zoning action imposing or accepting the condition or restrictive covenant sought to be modified or eliminated, or such greater distance as the Director may prescribe.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
For district boundary change involving a change of prefix within BU (Business) or IU (Industrial) and use variance involving such a use prefix change; for unusual use for outdoor patio dining, outdoor display, adult congregate living facility, day nursery, convalescent home, day camp, home for the aged, institution for the handicapped, kindergarten, nursing home, retirement village, entrance feature, mobile home as watchman's quarters, bathing beach; for special exception for resubdividing/refacing of platted lots, servant's quarters in RU-1 district, convalescent home, eleemosynary and philanthropic institution in RU-4 districts, dude ranch in AU district, temporary farm labor housing in AU district; and for all other applications for zoning action not specified in Subsections (d)(1), (2), (3) and (4), five hundred (500) feet.
A courtesy notice shall also be mailed to the president of any homeowners' association having any member who resides within the area of mailed notice described above when such residency is shown upon a current updated notice filed with the Director; provided, however, that the failure to mail or receive this courtesy notice shall not affect any action or proceeding taken hereunder. The Director shall establish and maintain a process by which homeowners' associations may provide notice of the areas in which their members reside. Homeowners' associations shall keep these notices current by updating them in accordance with procedures to be prescribed by the Director.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The person or persons responsible for providing the notices provided in Subsection (c) above shall attach to the application file a sworn affidavit or affidavits setting forth that they have complied with said subsection. Failure to provide the newspaper notices as provided, or failure to mail the required written notices as provided, or failure to post the property as provided renders voidable any hearing held on the application. The failure to send out courtesy notices shall not render a hearing voidable.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The Director shall have the discretion to expand any of the notice provisions contained in this section to provide more information if deemed appropriate.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
If the notices described in Subsection (c)(1) above are published, and the affidavits required by Subsection (e) are of record, no judicial proceeding to void a hearing shall be commenced after the time for appeal from a resolution of an administrative or quasijudicial tribunal as provided in the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedures.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 60-14, 4-19-60; Ord. No. 61-30, § 1, 6-27-61; Ord. No. 64-30, § 1, 7-21-64; Ord. No. 64-65, § 3, 12-15-64; Ord. No. 74-20, § 3, 4-3-74; Ord. No. 74-40, § 2, 6-4-74; Ord. No. 75-47, § 4, 6-18-75; Ord. No. 87-29, § 1, 5-19-87; Ord. No. 89-129, § 1, 12-19-89; Ord. No. 94-200, § 1, 11-1-94: Ord. No. 95-26, § 1, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 95-180, § 1, 10-5-95; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-127, § 35, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 98-175, § 1, 12-3-98; Ord. No. 00-31, § 2, 2-24-00; Ord. No. 03-93, § 2, 4-22-03; Ord. No. 09-76, § 2, 9-1-09; Ord. No. 11-86, § 3, 11-15-11; Ord. No. 13-16, § 6, 2-5-13)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-310.1. Administrative modification or elimination of conditions and restrictive covenants</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Standards. The Director is authorized to consider and approve applications to modify or eliminate any condition or part thereof which has been imposed by any final decision adopted by resolution, and to modify or eliminate any restrictive covenant, or part thereof, accepted at public hearing, where the requirements of at least one of the following subsections have been demonstrated. Upon demonstration that such requirements have been met, an application may be approved as to a portion of the property encumbered by the condition or the restrictive covenant where the condition or restrictive covenant is capable of being applied separately and in full force as to the remaining portion of the property that is not a part of the application and both the application portion and the remaining portion of the property will be in compliance with all other applicable requirements of prior zoning actions and of this chapter.
<section prefix = "I">
Substantial Compliance With Previous Approval. The Director shall approve an application to modify or eliminate a condition or part thereof, or a restrictive covenant or part thereof, where it is demonstrated that the proposed modification or elimination will result in substantial compliance with the previous zoning action regarding a site plan, as demonstrated by all of the following:
<section prefix = "A">
Development density and intensity have not materially changed, in that:
<section prefix = "1">
the number of buildings is not increased by more than 10 percent;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
the number of stories is the same or fewer;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
the height of the building(s) is the same or less;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
the number of units is the same or fewer;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
the lot coverage and floor area ratio are the same or less;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
the number of bedrooms and corresponding parking spaces may be increased or decreased by as much as 10%, based on the entire plan, provided the plan complies with all other requirements of this subsection and of this chapter; and
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
density or intensity (floor area ratio) may be transferred from one building to another or from one stage of development to another, provided that the total floor area ratio is not changed.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Design has not materially changed, in that:
<section prefix = "1">
the roadway patterns, including ingress-egress points, are in the same general location as shown on the original plans, and are no closer to the rear or interior side property lines than shown on the original plans;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
the parking area is in the same general location and configuration;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
the building setbacks are the same or greater distance from perimeter property lines, except that the building setbacks for detached single-family development, zero lot line, rowhouse, townhouse and cluster development may also be decreased, provided that such decrease is limited such that the resulting setback distance will be the greater of either
<section prefix = "a">
the underlying zoning district regulations, or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
any condition or restrictive covenant regulating the setback for which a substantial compliance determination is sought;
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
the landscaped open space is in the same general location, is of the same or greater amount, and is configured in a manner that does not diminish a previously intended buffering effect;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
the proposed perimeter walls and/or fences are in the same general location and of a comparable type and design as previously approved;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
elevations and renderings of buildings have substantially similar architectural expressions as those shown on the approved plans;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
recreational facilities, if shown on plans approved by a prior zoning action, either remain the same or are converted from one recreational use to another;
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
if recreational facilities were not shown in the approved plans, they may be added, provided there is no increase in lot coverage or decrease in required open space and such facilities are located internally within the proposed development;
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
if a variance for signage has been granted, the proposed sign(s) are no greater in size and are placed in the same general location on the site as approved by zoning action. An entrance sign location may be moved the same proportional distance as a relocated entrance drive;
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
the proposed changes do not have the effect of creating any noncompliance or nonconformity with the strict application of the zoning code that were not previously approved at public hearing, or of expanding the scope of existing variances, alternative site development options, or other approvals pursuant to alternative development standards such that they would differ to a greater degree from the strict application of the zoning code;
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
additional outparcels may be added where:
<section prefix = "a">
there is no increase in the project's total floor area ratio or lot coverage;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
there is no reduction in the total amount of landscaped open space; and
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
addition of the outparcel does not result in noncompliance with any other provision of this subsection on any other portion of the subject property.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
reductions in the number of parking spaces on the site are permitted if sufficient parking spaces are provided to satisfy the requirements of this code.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
The slope of any lake for which a modification is requested complies with Section 33-16 and all other applicable provisions of this code.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "II">
Reformation of Resolutions and Declarations of Restrictive Covenants to Correct Clerical or Scrivener's Errors.
<section prefix = "A">
The Director shall approve an application to reform a clerical or scrivener's error, in a prior zoning action, including an error in an application, declaration of restrictive covenants accepted upon public hearing, or notice, which error causes the zoning action not to accurately reflect the board's intent, and where it is demonstrated that all of the following requirements are met:
<section prefix = "1">
the reformation shall not include a change of judgment, policy, or prior intent of the board;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
prior to the conclusion of the public hearing at which the zoning action for which reformation is sought was taken, the current applicant either did not know of the error, or knew of the error and made it known to the adopting board;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
the reformation of the previous resolution or declaration is essential to insure that the zoning action reflects the intent of the adopting board;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
the record, including, but not limited to, the staff recommendation, minutes, and motion, evidences the clear intent of the board;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
the substance of the decision of the board was evident at the time of the adoption of the zoning action, and there was no intent to deceive the public or the board on the part of the current applicant at any time;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
failure to approve the reformation would lead to an unjust result;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
the error in the prior zoning action did not mislead anyone in a way that would cause them to be prejudiced by the reformation; and
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
any errors related to public notice did not affect the legal sufficiency of the required notice.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions, the Director, within thirty (30) days of the transmittal of a resolution, may reform a clerical or scrivener's error in a zoning action including a declaration of restrictive covenants accepted upon public hearing, without public notice, if:
<section prefix = "1">
the error is not related to public notice, and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
the error causes the resolution or declaration as written to inaccurately reflect the clear decision of the board.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
A reformed zoning action shall relate back to the original zoning action and the effective date of the corrected language shall be deemed to be the same as the effective date of the previous resolution.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "III">
Modification or Elimination of Conditions and Restrictive Covenants Associated with Voluntarily Abandoned Zoning Actions. The Director shall approve an application to modify or eliminate a condition or part thereof, or a restrictive covenant or part thereof (except where the covenant requires a public hearing), where it is demonstrated by the following that the condition, restrictive covenant or part thereof was imposed to mitigate the adverse impacts of a zoning action which has been entirely and voluntarily abandoned, in that:
<section prefix = "A">
the applicant has provided a sworn affidavit stating that the applicant has sufficient title and authority to abandon the development rights under the zoning action for the property for which the modification or elimination is sought, that the applicant intends to abandon the zoning action and all rights thereunder, and that no material changes to the character or use of the land have ever been undertaken pursuant to the zoning action;
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
the development rights granted by the zoning action have been voluntarily abandoned in writing in a form approved by the Director;
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
the zoning action which imposed or accepted the condition or restrictive covenant was not a district boundary change; and
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
abandonment of the zoning action will not cause the subject property to fail to comply with any applicable provision of this code or the Comprehensive Development Master Plan.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "IV">
Modification or Elimination of Conditions and Restrictive Covenants That Are Satisfied or Moot. The Director shall approve an application to modify or eliminate a condition or part thereof, or a restrictive covenant or part thereof (except where the covenant requires a public hearing), where it is demonstrated by the following that the condition, restrictive covenant or part thereof either is satisfied or is moot:
<section prefix = "A">
Satisfied conditions, covenants, or restrictions. The requirements imposed by a condition, restrictive covenant or part thereof do not create a continuing obligation, and are fully completed or satisfied; and, in the case of a restrictive covenant, any procedural or approval requirement set forth in the covenant is satisfied. Applications under this paragraph must be accompanied by a sworn affidavit that the conditions of this subsection have been satisfied.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Moot conditions, covenants, or restrictions. The condition, restrictive covenant or part thereof is moot in that it can no longer serve the purpose for which it was imposed. A condition, restrictive covenant or part thereof in effect for a period of more than five (5) years shall be determined to be moot upon demonstration of any of the four (4) following:
<section prefix = "1">
The purpose of the condition, restrictive covenant or part thereof is apparent from the zoning record of the subject property, including record facts pertaining to the character of the subject property and its immediate vicinity, and the impacts that were projected to be generated by the zoning action at the time the condition or covenant was imposed; and either
<section prefix = "a">
the property subject to the condition or covenant has been developed in a manner or to an extent which does not, and under existing zoning approvals cannot, generate the adverse impacts intended to be prevented or mitigated by the condition or covenant; or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
since the imposition of the condition or covenant, all abutting parcels and the immediate vicinity have been zoned or developed in a manner or to an extent that the impacts previously anticipated or projected to be prevented or mitigated by the condition or restrictive covenant are not, and cannot be, adverse to the abutting parcels or the immediate vicinity.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The purpose of the condition, restrictive covenant or part thereof is not apparent from the zoning record of the subject property, including record facts pertaining to the character of the subject property and its immediate vicinity, and
<section prefix = "a">
the condition, restrictive covenant or part thereof if imposed under current circumstances, would not and could not mitigate or prevent any describable harm or create any describable benefit to the public or to owners or residents of property in the immediate vicinity to a degree that is greater than de minimus; and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
the condition or restrictive covenant does not include a date of expiration.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The condition or restrictive covenant for which modification or elimination is sought involves the timing or phasing of development, and
<section prefix = "a">
the development which is the subject of the condition or restrictive covenant is completed; and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
no enforcement action regarding the condition or restrictive covenant has been initiated.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The condition or restrictive covenant for which modification or elimination is sought involves only the timeliness of filing or recording of a document, and
<section prefix = "a">
the failure to file or record the document was due to circumstances beyond the control of the applicant, or to excusable neglect; and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
no one is prejudiced by the modification or elimination of the condition or restrictive covenant regarding the timing of the filing or recording; and
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
the document has been recorded or filed subsequent to the deadline set by the original approval, and accepted by the County.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "V">
Modification or Elimination of Conditions and Restrictive Covenants When No New Adverse Impacts Will Result. The Director shall approve an application to modify an approved site plan, or modify or eliminate a condition or part thereof, or a restrictive covenant or part thereof (except where the covenant requires a public hearing), where it is demonstrated by the following that the modification or elimination will not result in a material new adverse impact on the public health, safety, welfare, or aesthetic values:
<section prefix = "A">
The proposed modification or elimination does not contravene or eliminate an express prohibition or timing or phasing requirement contained in the prior zoning action;
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
The request does not include a modification or elimination of conditions or restrictive covenants imposed simultaneously with a district boundary change;
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
The modification or elimination of the condition, restrictive covenant, or part thereof will not create new adverse impacts. The application will be deemed not to create new adverse impacts upon demonstration of the following:
<section prefix = "1">
the modification or elimination will result in an increase of not more than 10% in trips generated above that generated by the approved development, except that trips generated in excess of 10% shall be permitted where completely mitigated by increased capacity constructed since the current development was approved. Trip generation shall be calculated based on the most current methodology applied by the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
the modification or elimination will result in an increase in projected demand for local parks of no more than 10% or 1/5 acre, whichever is greater, except that demand in excess of 10% or 1/5 acre shall be permitted if there is sufficient capacity of local parks to accommodate the increase in demand created by the modification;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
the modification or elimination will result in an increase in demand placed on public stormwater drainage systems of not more than 10%;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
the modification or elimination will result in a projected increase in the number of school-age children residing on the subject property of not more than ten percent (10%), or not more than three (3) school-age children, whichever is greater;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
the modification or elimination will not result in any increase in potable water, sanitary sewer, or solid waste disposal demand for which adequate capacity is not available, or any change in existing or planned facilities will not affect the level of service of potable water, sanitary sewer, or solid waste disposal;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
the modification or elimination will not result in any material increase in the risk of potential for discharge or spillage of pollutants, or generation of carbon monoxide at unsafe levels;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
the modification or elimination will not result in any material increase in the potential for damage to jurisdictional wetlands;
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
the modification or elimination will not result in a reduction in the area under tree canopy of greater than 10%;
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
the modification or elimination will not result in any material increase in the risk of smoke, fire, odors, gases, excessive noise or vibration;
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
the modification or elimination will result in an increase in building cubic content on the subject property of no more than 10%, or no more than 10% of the median building cubic content on similarly zoned parcels in the immediate vicinity, whichever is larger;
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
the modification or elimination will not result in a decrease in the features or landscaping that buffer the existing use from properties in the immediate vicinity;
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
the modification or elimination will not result in any material decrease in the privacy enjoyed by adjoining properties;
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
the modification or elimination will not result in any material diminution of an existing view or vista to any landmark, natural area, or waterbody from any window or door in any residential unit on an adjoining parcel of land;
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
the modification or elimination will not result in any material increase in the potential for vehicular-pedestrian conflicts;
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
the modification or elimination will not result in any material and obvious departure from the aesthetic character of the immediate vicinity, taking into account the architectural design, scale, height, mass and building materials of existing structures, pattern of development and open space;
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
the modification or elimination will not result in any material increase in the area of shadow, or of light from outdoor lighting, cast onto adjacent parcels;
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
the modification or elimination will not result in any material change in the manner or hours of operation on the subject property so differing from the similar existing or approved uses in the immediate vicinity that the convenient, safe, peaceful or intended uses of such uses is interrupted or materially diminished;
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
the modification or elimination will not result in any material change in the density or intensity of use of the subject property so differing from the density or intensity of other existing or approved uses in the immediate vicinity that the subject property would represent an obvious departure from the established development pattern of the immediate vicinity;
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
the modification or elimination will not result in any material change in the type of use of the subject property so differing from the existing or approved uses in the immediate vicinity that the subject property would represent an obvious departure from the established pattern of use in the immediate vicinity;
</section>
<section prefix = "20">
the modification or elimination will not result in a use of land that will have a significant adverse impact upon the value of properties in the immediate vicinity; and
</section>
<section prefix = "21">
the modification or elimination will not result in a material increase in height or volume of open lot uses or facilities, or a material increase in intensity of allowed open lot uses, including, but not limited to, outdoor storage of products, materials or equipment, fleamarkets, carnivals, telecommunications facilities, concrete and asphalt batching plants, landfills and private playgrounds and recreational facilities.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
The subject property complies with all other applicable requirements of prior zoning actions and this code.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "VI">
Modification of Conditions and Restrictive Covenants to Extend Timing or Phasing Deadlines. The Director shall approve an application to modify a condition or part thereof, or a restrictive covenant or part thereof (except where the covenant requires a public hearing) that is related solely to the timing or phasing of development, where the applicant demonstrates satisfaction of one of the following two requirements:
<section prefix = "A">
The applicant has been reasonably diligent in fulfilling the requirements of the condition or restrictive covenant, but is unable to perform within the time set forth in the condition or restrictive covenant, and
<section prefix = "1">
No enforcement actions are pending with regard to the timing or phasing condition or covenant; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The condition or restrictive covenant was not imposed to enforce compliance with an obligation that was imposed or accepted prior to the zoning action in which the condition or restrictive covenant sought to be modified was imposed or accepted; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The extension of time or modification of phasing is:
<section prefix = "a">
no greater than fifty (50%) of the time frame set forth in the condition or restrictive covenant or six (6) months, whichever is less; or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
no greater than ten percent (10%) of the number of residential units (if the time frame or phasing schedule is set forth in terms of completion of residential units) or twenty-five (25) residential units, whichever is less; or
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Development pursuant to the zoning action has not proceeded because of a pending appeal or pending litigation regarding the zoning action, and the application secks only an extension of time or modification of phasing for the length of time that development has not proceeded due to such appeal or litigation.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Procedures for Administrative Determinations.
<section prefix = "1">
Applications. An application for administrative determination of substantial compliance with a prior administrative approval or zoning action, for reformation to correct a clerical or scrivener's error, for modification or elimination of conditions and restrictive covenants associated with voluntarily abandoned zoning actions or administrative approvals, or for modification or elimination of conditions or restrictive covenants which are satisfied or moot, or for modification or elimination of conditions or restrictive covenants where no new adverse impacts will result, or for modifications of conditions or restrictive covenants to extend timing or phasing deadlines, or for parts of any of the foregoing, shall be submitted to the Department on a form required by the Director. If the application involves a restrictive covenant, the application shall demonstrate that any procedural or other consent or approval requirements to modify or eliminate the restrictive covenant have been satisfied.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Notice. Within fifteen (15) days after the determination, notice of the Director's decision shall be published in a newspaper of general circulation; except that substantial compliance determinations shall be published in the newspaper of largest circulation in Miami-Dade County or a section or supplement in the newspaper of largest circulation in Miami-Dade County distributed only in the locality where the property subject to the application lies. Additionally, for applications for administrative modification or elimination of conditions and restrictive covenants associated with voluntarily abandoned zoning actions or administrative approvals, or conditions or restrictive covenants which are satisfied or moot, or for modification or elimination of conditions or restrictive covenants where no new adverse impacts will result, or for modifications of conditions or restrictive covenants to extend timing or phasing deadlines, mailed written notice shall be provided to all property owners of record, as reflected on the Miami-Dade County Property Appraiser's tax roll as updated, within the same radius of the property as required to be noticed for the zoning action adopting or accepting the condition or restrictive covenant, or such greater distance as the Director may prescribe.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Appeals. Any aggrieved person may appeal the Director's decision pursuant to Section 33-314 within thirty (30) days after the date of newspaper publication. For purposes of this section, an applicant for a substantial compliance determination shall not be considered an aggrieved person. If no timely appeal is taken, the decision shall become final, and the necessary changes shall be made upon the zoning maps and records. Any modifications or releases of recorded restrictive covenants, or parts thereof, shall be promptly recorded in the public records of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 03-93, § 3, 4-22-03; Ord. No. 13-16, § 7, 2-5-13)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-310.2. Application for administrative approval on existing mobile home park site</catch_line>
<text>
Within thirty (30) days of the filing of an application for an administrative approval pursuant to Section 33-169.1 by the director for the full or partial redevelopment of an existing mobile home park, the Director shall, at the cost to applicant, provide notice in a newspaper of general circulation, and shall post notice in at least 4 locations on mobile home park property.
If the mobile home park is listed by the applicant as vacant, the applicant shall provide documentation demonstrating the expiration date of the last leasehold in the park and a copy of the closure notice to park residents. The department shall provide closure information to the appropriate state agency.
Notice of the Director's decision shall be published within fifteen (15) days after the determination, at the cost to applicant, in a newspaper of general circulation and posted in at least four locations on the park property. Any aggrieved person may appeal the Director's decision pursuant to Section 33-311 within thirty (30) days after the date of newspaper publication. If no timely appeal is taken, the decision shall become final, and the necessary changes shall be made upon the zoning maps and records.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-311. Community Zoning Appeals Board—Authority and duties</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Except as otherwise provided by this chapter, the Community Zoning Appeals Boards and Board of County Commissioners shall have the authority and duty to consider and act upon applications, as hereinafter set forth, after first considering the written recommendations thereon of the Director or Developmental Impact Committee. Provided, however, no such action shall be taken until notice of time and place of the hearing at which the Community Zoning Appeals Boards will consider the application has been first published as provided in Section 33-310.2. The Community Zoning Appeals Boards are advised that the purpose of zoning and regulations is to provide a comprehensive plan and design to lessen the congestion in the highways; to secure safety from fire, panic and other dangers, to promote health, safety, morals, convenience and the general welfare; to provide adequate light and air; to prevent the overcrowding of land and water; to avoid undue concentration of population; to facilitate the adequate provisions of transportation, water, sewerage, schools, parks and other public requirements, with the view of giving reasonable consideration among other things to the character of the district or area and its peculiar suitability for particular uses and with a view to conserving the value of buildings and property and encouraging the most appropriate use of land and water throughout the County. The Community Zoning Appeals Board and Board of County Commissioners or any of their members may inspect the premises and area under consideration. The Community Zoning Appeals Boards shall have authority over the following zoning applications except where the Board of County Commissioners has direct jurisdiction.
<section prefix = "1">
Minimum square footage requirements. Hear and grant or deny applications to increase or decrease the minimum square footage requirements for building in a particular area, provided, it finds that the increase or decrease would be comparable with that required for the area or surrounding area or that established by improvements in the area or surrounding area.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Appeal of administrative variances, administrative adjustments; and appeals of administrative determination regarding existing mobile home parks issued pursuant to Section 33-310.2, administrative site plan review substantial compliance determinations, and administrative correction of clerical or scrivener's errors.
<section prefix = "a">
Upon application for, hear and decide appeals where it is alleged there is an error in the granting or denial of an administrative variance, administrative adjustment, administrative determination regarding mobile home park property redevelopment action pursuant to Section 33-169.1, administrative site plan review, determination of substantial compliance, or administrative correction of a clerical or scrivener's error, pursuant to the provisions of this Code. Such administrative decisions shall not include appeals filed pursuant to Sections 2-114.1 through 2-114.4
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Pursuant to the provisions of Section 33-36.1 any aggrieved property owner in the area may appeal the decision of the Director to the appropriate Community Zoning Appeals Board within fifteen (15) days after the Director's decision is published in a newspaper of general circulation. An aggrieved applicant must file a new application with the appropriate Miami-Dade County Community Zoning Appeals Board pursuant to the provisions of this chapter and must comply fully with the requirements of Section 33-311 "Variances from Other Than Airport Regulations".
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Special exceptions (for all applications other than public charter schools), unusual and new uses. Hear application for and grant or deny special exceptions, except applications for public charter schools; that is, those exceptions permitted by the regulations only upon approval after public hearing, new uses and unusual uses which by the regulations are only permitted upon approval after public hearing; provided the applied for exception or use, including exception for site or plot plan approval, in the opinion of the Community Zoning Appeals Board, would not have an unfavorable effect on the economy of Miami-Dade County, Florida, would not generate or result in excessive noise or traffic, cause undue or excessive burden on public facilities, including water, sewer, solid waste disposal, recreation, transportation, streets, roads, highways or other such facilities which have been constructed or which are planned and budgeted for construction, are accessible by private or public roads, streets or highways, tend to create a fire or other equally or greater dangerous hazards, or provoke excessive overcrowding or concentration of people or population, when considering the necessity for and reasonableness of such applied for exception or use in relation to the present and future development of the area concerned and the compatibility of the applied for exception or use with such area and its development.
<section prefix = "a">
Hear application for and grant or deny unusual uses for Wireless Supported Service Facilities, which by the regulations are only permitted upon approval after public hearing; provided the applied for use, in the opinion of the Community Zoning Appeals Board, would not have an unfavorable effect on the economy of Miami-Dade County, Florida, would not generate or result in excessive noise or traffic, cause undue or excessive burden on public facilities, including water, sewer, solid waste disposal, recreation, transportation, streets, roads, highways or other such facilities which have been constructed or which are planned and budgeted for construction, are accessible by private or public roads, streets or highways, tend to create a fire or other equally or greater dangerous hazards, or provoke excessive overcrowding or concentration of people or population, when considering the necessity for and reasonableness of such applied for use in relation to the present and future development of the area concerned and the compatibility of the applied for use with such area and its development, provided that:
<section prefix = "i">
The applicant shall demonstrate that the proposed Wireless Supported Service Facility will cure:
<section prefix = "a">
signal interference problems; or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
the applicant's lack of wireless service coverage or capacity in the area intended to be served by the proposed Wireless Supported Service Facility
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
The applicant shall provide information to permit independent verification of factual data relied upon by the applicant to establish 3(a)(i) above, including, but not limited to the following:
<section prefix = "a">
the purpose for the proposed Wireless Supported Service Facility; and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
the following technical data for the proposed Wireless Supported Service Facility and for each existing, authorized, pending and proposed adjacent facility:
<section prefix = "i">
site name or other reference;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
facility latitude and longitude;
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
site elevation;
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
for each antenna at each of the included facilities:
<section prefix = "1">
height of antenna radiation center;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
antenna type and manufacturer;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
maximum effective radiated output power, including the maximum total power radiated from all channels;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
azimuth of main antenna lobe; and
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
beam tilt and null-fill of each antenna.
<section prefix = "c">
a complete up- and down-link power budget for the proposed Wireless Supported Service Facility, including any differences that may exist with the power budgets of the adjacent facilities, to ensure that all of the gain and loss factors used by the applicant are included in a verification analysis.
<section prefix = "d">
complete descriptions of methodology, formulas, data presented in appropriate parameter data units (e.g., Erlangs, Watts, dBm, ft.), existing traffic studies and trend analyses if the proposed facility is intended to cure a lack of capacity, and any other information necessary for an independent engineer to verify statements concerning signal interference or lack of capacity or coverage; and
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
identification of any equipment that differs from industry standards.
<section prefix = "iii">
that the applicant shall reimburse the department for fees charged to the department for independent verification of factual data relied upon by the applicant, as required pursuant to paragraph 3 a ii above.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
<section prefix = "a">
Use variances from other than airport regulations. Upon appeal or direct application in specific cases to hear and grant applications for use variances from the terms of the zoning regulations as will not be contrary to the public interest, where owing to special conditions, a literal enforcement of the provisions thereof will result in unnecessary hardship, and so the spirit of the regulations shall be observed and substantial justice done; provided, that the use variance will be in harmony with the general purpose and intent of the regulation, and that the same is the minimum use variance that will permit the reasonable use of the premises; and further provided, no variance from any airport zoning regulation shall be granted under this subsection; provided, however, no use variance shall be granted permitting a BU or IU use in any residential, AU or GU District, unless the premises immediately abuts a BU or IU District. A "use variance" is a variance which permits a use of land other than which is prescribed by the zoning regulations and shall include a change in permitted density.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Non-use variances from other than airport regulations. Upon appeal or direct application in specific cases to hear and grant applications for non-use variances from the terms of the zoning and subdivision regulations, the Board (following a public hearing) may grant a non-use variance upon a showing by the applicant that the non-use variance maintains the basic intent and purpose of the zoning, subdivision and other land use regulations, which is to protect the general welfare of the public, particularly as it affects the stability and appearance of the community and provided that the non-use variance will be otherwise compatible with the surrounding land uses and would not be detrimental to the community. No showing of unnecessary hardship to the land is required. For the purpose of this subsection, the term "non-use variances" involves matters such as setback lines, frontage requirements, subdivision regulations, height limitations, lot size restrictions, yard requirements and other variances which have no relation to change of use of the property in question.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Alternative non-use variance standard. Upon appeal or direct application in specific cases to hear and grant applications for non-use variances from the terms of the zoning and subdivision regulations, upon a showing by the applicant that the variance will not be contrary to the public interest, where owing to special conditions, a literal enforcement of the provisions thereof will result in unnecessary hardship, and so the spirit of the regulations shall be observed and substantial justice done; provided, that the non-use variance will be in harmony with the general purpose and intent of the regulation, and that the same is the minimum non-use variance that will permit the reasonable use of the premises; and further provided, no non-use variance from any airport zoning regulation shall be granted under this subsection.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Variances from airport zoning regulations. Hear applications for and grant or deny variances from any airport zoning regulations, but in considering, granting or denying any such variance the Community Zoning Appeals Boards shall be governed and shall abide by the guides and standards, general purpose and intent of the particular airport zoning regulation concerned. No such application shall be heard until the recommendation of the Director of the Aviation Department is first obtained, which recommendation shall be considered, together with that of the Director's. The granting of a variance under this subsection does not authorize or permit violation of other zoning regulations or the zoning regulations of any municipality concerned unless authorized by the appropriate County or municipal board, body or commission concerned, as the case may be.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Variances from subdivision regulations. Hear applications for and grant or deny variances from subdivision regulations (Chapter 28 of the Code of Miami-Dade County) in accordance with and pursuant to the authority and standards set forth in Section 28-19 of the code.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Hear applications to modify or eliminate any condition or part thereof which has been imposed by any final decision adopted by resolution, and to modify or eliminate any provisions of restrictive covenants, or parts thereof, accepted at public hearing, except as otherwise provided in Section 33-314(C)(3); provided, that the appropriate board finds after public hearing (a) that the modification or elimination, in the opinion of the Community Zoning Appeals Board, would not generate excessive noise or traffic, tend to create a fire or other equally or greater dangerous hazard, or provoke excessive overcrowding of people, or would not tend to provoke a nuisance, or would not be incompatible with the area concerned, when considering the necessity and reasonableness of the modification or elimination in relation to the present and future development of the area concerned, or (b) (i) that the resolution that contains the condition approved a school use that was permitted only as a special exception, (ii) that subsequent law permits that use as of right without the requirement of approval after public hearing, and (iii) that the requested modification or elimination would not result in development exceeding the standards provided for schools authorized as a matter of right without the requirement of approval after public hearing. It is further provided, however, that no zoning application to delete or modify, in a manner inconsistent with Section 33-310.1(A)(I)(B)(7), a common open space or common use amenity within a residential site plan that was previously approved upon public hearing shall be approved except upon a two-thirds vote of the members present at the hearing at which the application is decided; this provision shall not apply to an application to modify or delete a condition or restrictive covenant, or parts thereof, within an urban center district or urban area district.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Hear and grant or deny applications for district boundary changes on individual pieces of property or on a neighborhood or area-wide basis except where the Board of County Commissioners has direct jurisdiction.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Hear and make recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners on applications for developments of regional impact and related requests, including requests for modifications thereof and substantial deviation determinations pursuant to F.S. § 380.06(19), as amended, as provided by Section 33-314 except an application for modification or elimination of a condition or restrictive covenant that is not a substantial deviation, or an application to extend a commencement date, build-out date, expiration date, phasing deadline, or applicable mitigation requirements for the maximum period of time declared by state law regardless of any previous extension not to constitute a substantial deviation from development orders for currently valid developments of regional impact development orders, and related applications for zoning actions to accomplish only the requested extension, where such application does not contain a request for any other action under this chapter requiring a public hearing apart from modifying the DRI development order; it is provided, however, that, pursuant to F.S. § 380.06(19)(c)(2), the foregoing exception from CZAB review shall not apply to development orders for which, before December 1, 2011, the County has notified a developer that has commenced any construction within the phase for which mitigation is required that the County has entered into a contract for construction of a facility with funds to be provided from the development's mitigation funds for that phase as specified in the development order or written agreement with the developer.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
The Community Zoning Appeals Boards shall review those plans submitted as part of an application for a planned development. The Community Zoning Appeals Board shall decide if the proposed development is in accordance with the provisions for a planned development and shall diligently consider the recommendations of the Director and the Zoning Official or the Developmental Impact Committee prior to recommending approval, approval with modification, or denial. The Community Zoning Appeals Board shall approve an application for a planned development only when plans and other exhibits are in compliance with the criteria for a planned development and otherwise meet the criteria contained in this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Notwithstanding anything in Section 24-58.1 to the contrary, the Community Zoning Appeals Board shall hear, grant or deny applications for unusual uses or amendments or modifications thereto described in Section 33-13(e) when said unusual uses, amendments or modifications are in connection with a class I or class IV permit application, as defined in Section 24-58.1.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Hear and make recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners on applications for projects or modifications thereto within the Core Sub-District of the Downtown Kendall Urban Center District as provided by Section 33-314
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Hear applications to modify or eliminate any condition or part thereof which has been imposed by any final decision adopted by resolution regulating any parcel of land located within the Downtown Kendall Urban Center, the Naranja Community Urban Center, or any other Urban Center zoning districts, where and to the extent that modification or elimination of the condition or part thereof is necessary to allow development conforming in all respects with the Downtown Kendall Urban Center District, the Naranja Community Urban Center District, or any other applicable Urban Center zoning district regulations.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
Alternative Site Development Option for Single-family and Duplex Dwellings. This subsection provides for the establishment of an alternative site development option, after public hearing, for single-family and duplex dwellings, when such uses are permitted by the underlying district regulations, in the GU, RU-1, RU-1Z, RU-1M(a), RU-1M(b), RU-2, RU-TH, RU-3, RU-3M, RU-3B, RU-4L, RU-4M, RU-4, RU-4A, RU-5, EU-M, EU-S, EU-1, EU-1C, EU-2, and AU zoning districts, in accordance with the standards established herein. In considering any application for approval hereunder, the Community Zoning Appeals Board shall consider the same subject to approval of a site plan or such other plans as necessary to demonstrate compliance with the standards herein.
<section prefix = "a">
Purpose. The purpose of this subsection is to create objective standards to regulate the site-specific development of single-family and duplex uses in specified zoning districts. The standards provided in this subsection are alternatives to the generalized standards contained in regulations governing the specified zoning districts. The site development standards permit alternative patterns of site development in accordance with the Comprehensive Development Master Plan ("CDMP") where the public interest served by the underlying district regulations and CDMP will be served, and the objectives of the creative urban design, urban infill development and redevelopment, or the preservation and enhancement of property values will be promoted, as demonstrated by the proposed alternative development's compliance with the standards of this subsection. A zoning application for development in compliance with the alternative standards shall be approved upon demonstration at public hearing that the proposed development is in compliance with the applicable alternative standards and does not contravene the enumerated public interest standards established herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
For the purposes of this subsection, the following terms shall have the following meanings:
"Immediate vicinity" means an area in which a parcel of land proposed for alternative development is located that is physically, functionally or geographically identifiable as a distinct realm, place or neighborhood, or an area within a radius of not more than five hundred (500) feet from the parcel proposed for alternative development, whichever is smaller.
"Open space" means that portion of a parcel of land which is not covered with a building and is open to the sky and may include patios, limited roof overhangs, screened enclosures with screened roofs, open trellises, walkways, swimming pools, tennis courts, landscaped areas, decks, and non-covered parking areas.
"Parcel proposed for alternative development" means the site of the structure for which approval is sought under this subsection.
"Proposed alternative development" means any building activity for which approval is sought under this subsection.
"Underlying district regulations" means the site development regulations of the particular zoning district in which the proposed alternative development is located, such as setbacks, lot area, frontage, and depth, lot coverage, and structure height.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Setbacks for a single-family or duplex dwelling shall be approved after public hearing upon demonstration of the following:
<section prefix = "1">
the character and design of the proposed alternative development will not result in a material diminution of the privacy of adjoining residential property; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
the proposed alternative development will not result in an obvious departure from the aesthetic character of the immediate vicinity, taking into account existing structures and open space; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
the proposed alternative development will not reduce the amount of open space on the parcel proposed for alternative development to less than 40 percent of the total net lot area; and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
any area of shadow cast by the proposed alternative development upon an adjoining parcel of land during daylight hours will be no larger than would be cast by a structure constructed pursuant to the underlying district regulations, or will have no more than a de minimus impact on the use and enjoyment of the adjoining parcel of land; and
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
the proposed alternative development will not involve the installation or operation of any mechanical equipment closer to the adjoining parcel of land than any other portion of the proposed alternative development, unless such equipment is located within an enclosed, soundproofing structure; and
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
the proposed alternative development will not involve any outdoor lighting fixture that casts light on an adjoining parcel of land at an intensity greater than permitted by this code; and
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
the architectural design, scale, mass, and building materials of any proposed structure or addition are aesthetically harmonious with that of other existing or proposed structures or buildings on the parcel proposed for alternative development; and
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
the wall of any building within a setback area required by the underlying district regulations shall be improved with architectural details and treatments that avoid the appearance of a "blank wall"; and
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
the proposed alternative development will not result in the destruction or removal of mature trees within a setback required by the underlying district regulations, with a diameter at breast height of greater than ten (10) inches, unless the trees are among those listed in Section 24-60(4)(f) of this code, or the trees are relocated in a manner that preserves the aesthetic and shade qualities of the same side of the lot; and
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
any windows or doors in any building to be located within an interior side setback required by the underlying district regulations shall be designed and located so that they are not aligned directly across from facing windows or doors on buildings located on an adjoining parcel of land; and
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
total lot coverage shall not be increased by more than twenty (20) percent of the lot coverage permitted by the underlying district regulations; and
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
the area within an interior side setback required by the underlying district regulations located behind the front building line will not be used for off-street parking except:
<section prefix = "A">
in an enclosed garage where the garage door is located so that it is not aligned directly across from facing windows or doors on buildings located on an adjoining parcel of land; or
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
if the off-street parking is buffered from property that abuts the setback area by a solid wall at least six (6) feet in height along the area of pavement and parking, with either:
<section prefix = "i">
articulation to avoid the appearance of a "blank wall" when viewed from the adjoining property, or
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
landscaping that is at least three (3) feet in height at time of planting, located along the length of the wall between the wall and the adjoining property, accompanied by specific provision for the maintenance of the landscaping, such as but not limited to, an agreement regarding its maintenance in recordable form from the adjoining landowner; and
<section prefix = "13">
any structure within an interior side setback required by the underlying district regulations:
<section prefix = "A">
is screened from adjoining property by landscape material of sufficient size and composition to obscure at least sixty (60) percent of the proposed alternative development to a height of the lower fourteen (14) feet of such structure at time of planting; or
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
is screened from adjoining property by an opaque fence or wall at least six (6) feet in height that meets the standards set forth in paragraph (f) herein; and
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
any proposed alternative development not attached to a principal building, except canopy carports, is located behind the front building line; and
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
any structure not attached to a principal building and proposed to be located within a setback required by the underlying district regulations shall be separated from any other structure by at least three (3) feet; and
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
when a principal building is proposed to be located within a setback required by the underlying district regulations, any enclosed portion of the upper floor of such building shall not extend beyond the first floor of such building within the setback; and
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
the eighteen (18) inch distance between any swimming pool and any wall or enclosure required by this code is maintained; and
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
safe sight distance triangles shall be maintained as required by this code; and
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
the parcel proposed for alternative development will continue to provide on-site parking as required by this code; and
</section>
<section prefix = "20">
the parcel proposed for alternative development shall satisfy underlying district regulations or, if applicable, prior zoning actions or administrative decisions issued prior to the effective date of this ordinance (August 2, 2002), regulating lot area, frontage and depth; and
</section>
<section prefix = "21">
the proposed development will meet the following:
<section prefix = "A">
interior side setbacks will be at least three (3) feet or fifty (50) percent of the side setbacks required by the underlying district regulations, whichever is greater;
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
side street setbacks shall not be reduced by more than fifty (50) percent of the underlying district regulations;
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
interior side setbacks for active recreational uses shall be no less than seven (7) feet in an EU, AU or GU zoning district or three (3) feet in all other zoning districts to which this subsection applies;
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
front setbacks will be at least twelve and one-half (12½) feet or fifty (50) percent of the front setbacks required by the underlying district regulations, whichever is greater;
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
rear setbacks will be at least three (3) feet for detached accessory structures and ten (10) feet for principal structures.
<section prefix = "d">
The lot area, frontage, or depth for a single-family or duplex dwelling shall be approved upon demonstration of at least one of the following:
<section prefix = "1">
the proposed lot area, frontage or depth will permit the development or redevelopment of a single-family or duplex dwelling on a parcel of land where such dwelling would not otherwise be permitted by the underlying district regulations due to the size or configuration of the parcel proposed for alternative development, provided that:
<section prefix = "A">
the parcel is under lawful separate ownership from any contiguous property and is not otherwise grandfathered for single-family or duplex use; and
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
the proposed alternative development will not result in the further subdivision of land; and
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
the size and dimensions of the lot are sufficient to provide all setbacks required by the underlying district regulations; and
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
the lot area is not less than ninety (90) percent of the minimum lot area required by the underlying district regulations; and
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
the proposed alternative development will not result in an obvious departure from the aesthetic character of the immediate vicinity; and
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
the parcel proposed for alternative development is not zoned AU of GU, nor is it designated agricultural or open land under the Comprehensive Development Master Plan; and
</section>
<section prefix = "G">
Sufficient frontage shall be maintained to permit vehicular access to all resulting lots.
<section prefix = "2">
the proposed alternative development will result in open space, community design, amenities or preservation of natural resources that enhances the function or aesthetic character of the immediate vicinity in a manner not otherwise achievable through application of the underlying district regulations, provided that:
<section prefix = "A">
the density of the proposed alternative development does not exceed that permitted by the underlying district regulations; and
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
the size and dimensions of each lot in the proposed alternative development are sufficient to provide all setbacks required by the underlying district regulations, or, if applicable, any prior zoning actions or administrative decisions issued prior to the effective date of this ordinance (August 2, 2002); and
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
each lot's area is not less than eighty (80) percent of the lot area required by the underlying district regulations; and
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
the proposed alternative development will not result in an obvious departure from the aesthetic character of the immediate vicinity; and
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
the parcel proposed for alternative development is not zoned AU of GU, nor is it designated agricultural or open land under the Comprehensive Development Master Plan; and
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
sufficient frontage shall be maintained to permit vehicular access to all resulting lots.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
the proposed lot area, frontage or depth is such that:
<section prefix = "A">
the proposed alternative development will not result in the creation of more than three (3) lots; and
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
the size and dimensions of each lot are sufficient to provide all setbacks required by the underlying district regulations; and
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
no lot area shall be less than the smaller of:
<section prefix = "i">
Ninety (90) percent of the lot area required by the underlying district regulations; or
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
The average area of the developed lots in the immediate vicinity within the same zoning district;
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
the proposed alternative development will not result in an obvious departure from the aesthetic character of the immediate vicinity; and
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
the parcel proposed for alternative development is not zoned AU or GU, nor is it designated agricultural or open land under the Comprehensive Development Master Plan; and
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
sufficient frontage shall be maintained to permit vehicular access to all resulting lots.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
if the proposed alternative development involves the creation of new parcels of smaller than five (5) gross acres in an area designated agricultural in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan:
<section prefix = "A">
the abutting parcels are predominately parcelized in a manner similar to the proposed alternative development on three (3) or more sides of the parcel proposed for alternative development; and
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
the division of the parcel proposed for alternative development will not precipitate additional land division in the area; and
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
the size and dimensions of each lot in the proposed alternative development are sufficient to provide all setbacks required by the underlying district regulations; and
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
the proposed alternative development will not result in an obvious departure from the aesthetic character of the surrounding area defined by the closest natural and man-made boundaries lying with the agricultural designation; and
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
Sufficient frontage shall be maintained to permit vehicular access to all resulting lots.
<section prefix = "e">
A lot coverage ratio for a single-family or duplex dwelling shall be approved upon demonstration of the following:
<section prefix = "1">
total lot coverage shall not be increased by more than twenty (20) percent of the lot coverage permitted by the underlying district regulations provided, however, that the proposed alternative development shall not result in total lot coverage exceeding 50% of the net lot area; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
the proposed alternative development will not result in the destruction or removal of mature trees on the lot with a diameter at breast height of greater than ten (10) inches, unless the trees are among those listed in Section 24-60(4)(f) of this code, or the trees are relocated in a manner that preserves the aesthetic and shade qualities of the lot; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
the increase in lot coverage will not result in a principal building with an architectural design, scale, mass or building materials that are not aesthetically harmonious with that of other existing or proposed structures in the immediate vicinity; and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
the proposed alternative development will not result in an obvious departure from the aesthetic character of in the immediate vicinity.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
An alternative maximum height of walls, hedges or fences for a single-family or duplex dwelling shall be approved upon demonstration of the following:
<section prefix = "1">
no wall, hedge or fence shall exceed eight (8) feet in height; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
no wall, hedge or fence located in a front setback required by the underlying district regulations shall exceed six (6) feet in height; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
the additional height of a proposed wall, hedge or fence will not obscure in whole or in part an existing view or vista to any landmark, natural area, or waterbody from any window or door in a residential unit on an adjoining parcel of land; and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
proposed walls or fences shall be:
<section prefix = "A">
articulated to avoid the appearance of a "blank wall" when viewed from adjoining property; or
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
landscaped with landscaping that is at least three (3) feet in height at time of planting, located along the length of the wall between the wall and the adjoining property, accompanied by specific provision for the maintenance of the landscaping, such as but not limited to, an agreement from the landowner regarding its maintenance in recordable form from the adjoining property owner; or
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
where facing a public right-of-way, set back at least two and one-half (2½) feet from the right-of-way line and extensively landscaped with shrubs of a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting, which will form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting; hedges of a minimum of three (3) feet in height immediately after planting, which will form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting; and/or climbing vines of a minimum of thirty-six (36) inches in height immediately after planting; and
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
proposed fences shall be constructed or installed so that the "unfinished" side is directed inward toward the center of the parcel proposed for alternative development; and
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
proposed fences are constructed of durable materials and are decorative; and
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
safe sight distance triangles are maintained pursuant to this code.
<section prefix = "g">
Notwithstanding the foregoing, no proposed alternative development shall be approved upon demonstration that the proposed alternative development:
<section prefix = "1">
will result in a significant diminution of the value of property in the immediate vicinity; or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
will have substantial negative impact on public safety due to unsafe automobile movements, heightened vehicular-pedestrian conflicts, or heightened risk of fire; or
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
will result in a materially greater adverse impact on public services and facilities than the impact that would result from development of the same parcel pursuant to the underlying district regulations; or
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
will combine severable use rights obtained pursuant to Chapter 33B of this code in conjunction with the approval sought hereunder so as to exceed the limitations imposed by Section 33B-45 of this code.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Proposed alternative development under this subsection shall provide additional amenities or buffering to mitigate the impacts of the development as approved, where the amenities or buffering expressly required by this subsection are insufficient to mitigate the impacts of the development. The purpose of the amenities or buffering elements shall be to preserve and protect the quality of life of the residents of the approved development and the immediate vicinity in a manner comparable to that ensured by the underlying district regulations. Examples of such amenities include but are not limited to: active or passive recreational facilities, common open space, additional trees or landscaping, convenient covered bus stops or pick-up areas for transportation services, sidewalks (including improvements, linkages, or additional width), bicycle paths, buffer areas or berms, street furniture, undergrounding of utility lines, and decorative street lighting. In determining which amenities or buffering elements are appropriate for a proposed development, the following shall be considered:
<section prefix = "A">
the types of needs of the residents of the parcel proposed for development and the immediate vicinity that would likely be occasioned by the development, including, but not limited to, recreational, open space, transportation, aesthetic amenities, and buffering from adverse impacts; and
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
the proportionality between the impacts on residents of the proposed alternative development and the immediate vicinity and the amenities or buffering required. For example, a reduction in lot area for numerous lots may warrant the provision of additional common open space. A reduction in a particular lot's interior side setback may warrant the provision of additional landscaping.
<section prefix = "15">
Alternative Site Development Option for Single-family Zero Lot line Dwellings. This subsection provides for the establishment of an alternative site development option, after public hearing, for zero lot line dwellings, when such uses are permitted by the underlying district regulations, or when such uses were approved for development by a prior public hearing action, in accordance with the standards established herein. In considering any application for approval hereunder, the Community Zoning Appeals Board shall consider the same subject to approval of a site plan or such other plans as necessary to demonstrate compliance with the standards herein.
<section prefix = "a">
Purpose. The purpose of this subsection is to create objective standards to regulate site specific development of zero lot line dwellings. The standards provided in this subsection are alternatives to the generalized standards contained in regulations governing this specified type of residence. A zoning application for development in compliance with the alternative standards shall be approved upon demonstration at public hearing that the proposed development is in compliance with the applicable alternative standards and does not contravene the enumerated public interest standards established herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Alternative setbacks for a zero lot line dwelling shall be approved after public hearing upon demonstration of the following:
<section prefix = "1">
the character and design of the proposed alternative development will not result in a material diminution of the privacy of adjoining residential property; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
the proposed alternative development will not result in an obvious departure from the aesthetic character of the immediate vicinity, taking into account existing structures and open space; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
the proposed alternative development will not reduce the amount of open space on the lot proposed for alternative development to less than 40% of the total net lot area; and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
any area of shadow cast by the proposed alternative development upon an adjoining parcel of land during daylight hours will be no larger than would be cast by a structure constructed pursuant to the applicable underlying district regulations, or will have no more than a de minimus impact on the use and enjoyment of the adjoining parcel of land; and
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
the proposed alternative development will not involve the installation or operation of any mechanical equipment closer to the adjoining parcel of land than any other portion of the proposed alternative development, unless such equipment is located within an enclosed, soundproofing structure; and
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
the proposed alternative development will not involve any outdoor lighting fixture that casts light on an adjoining parcel of land at an intensity greater than permitted by this code; and
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
the architectural design, scale, mass, and building materials of any proposed structure or addition are aesthetically harmonious with that of other existing or proposed structures or buildings on the parcel proposed for alternative development; and
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
the wall of any building within a setback area required by the underlying district regulations or the regulations in effect at the time of development, shall be improved with architectural details and treatments that avoid the appearance of a "blank wall"; and
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
the proposed alternative development will not result in the destruction or removal of mature trees within a setback required by the underlying district regulations or the regulations in effect at the time of development, with a diameter at breast height of greater than ten (10) inches, unless the trees are among those listed in Section 24-60(4)(f) of this code, or the trees are relocated in a manner that preserves the aesthetic and shade qualities of the same side of the lot; and
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
any windows or doors in any building to be located within an interior side setback required by the underlying district regulations or the regulations in effect at the time of development shall be designed and located so that they are not aligned directly across from facing windows or doors on buildings located on an adjoining parcel of land; and
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
total lot coverage shall not be increased by more than ten (10%) percent of the lot coverage permitted by the underlying district regulations or the regulations in effect at the time of development; and
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
the area within an interior side setback required by the underlying district regulations or the regulations in effect at the time of development, located behind the front building line will not be used for off-street parking except
<section prefix = "A">
in an enclosed garage where the garage door is located so that it is not aligned directly across from facing windows or doors on buildings located on an adjoining parcel of land; or
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
if the off-street parking is buffered from property that abuts the setback area by a solid wall at least six (6) feet in height along the area of pavement and parking, with either:
<section prefix = "i">
articulation to avoid the appearance of a "blank wall" when viewed from the adjoining property, or
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
landscaping that is at least three (3) feet in height at time of planting, located along the length of the wall between the wall and the adjoining property, accompanied by specific provision for the maintenance of the landscaping, such as but not limited to, an agreement regarding its maintenance in recordable form from the adjoining landowner; and
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
any structure within an interior side setback required by the underlying district regulations or the regulations in effect at the time of development:
<section prefix = "A">
is screened from adjoining property by landscape material of sufficient size and composition to obscure at least sixty percent (60%) of the proposed alternative development to a height of the lower fourteen (14) feet of such structure at time of planting; or
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
is screened from adjoining property by an opaque fence or wall at least six (6) feet in height that meets the standards set forth in paragraph (f) herein; and
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
any proposed alternative development not attached to a principal building, except canopy carports, is located behind the front building line; and
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
any structure not attached to a principal building and proposed to be located within a setback required by the underlying district regulations or the regulations in effect at the time of development shall be separated from any other structure by at least three (3) feet; and
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
when a principal building is proposed to be located within a setback required by the underlying district regulations or the regulations in effect at the time of development, any enclosed portion of the upper floor of such building shall not extend beyond the first floor of such building within the setback; and
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
the eighteen (18) inch distance between any swimming pool and any wall or enclosure required by this code is maintained; and
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
safe sight distance triangles shall be maintained as required by this code; and
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
the parcel proposed for alternative development will continue to provide on-site parking as required by this code; and
</section>
<section prefix = "20">
the parcel proposed for alternative development shall satisfy underlying district regulations or the regulations in effect at the time of development or, if applicable, prior zoning actions or administrative decisions issued prior to the effective date of this ordinance (May 2, 2003) regulating lot area, frontage and depth; and
</section>
<section prefix = "21">
the proposed alternative development of the lot will meet the following:
<section prefix = "A">
the interior side setbacks will be at least four (4) feet or the minimum distance necessary to comply with Fire safety requirements, whichever is greater;
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
the side street setback shall not be reduced by more than fifty percent (50%) of the underlying district regulations or the regulations in effect at the time of development;
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
the interior side setbacks for active recreational uses shall be no less than seven (7) feet or the minimum distance necessary to comply with Fire safety requirements, whichever is greater;
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
the front setback of the dwelling or accessory use shall not be reduced;
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
the rear setback will be at least three (3) feet for detached accessory structures and ten (10) feet for principal structures;
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
the proposed alternative development shall not encroach into the maintenance easement as required by this chapter and shown on the approved plat; and
</section>
<section prefix = "G">
the proposed alternative development shall not contain openings on the zero lot line side of the structure, other than permitted by the underlying district regulations.
<section prefix = "c">
An alternative lot coverage ratio for a zero lot line dwelling shall be approved upon demonstration of the following:
<section prefix = "1">
total lot coverage shall not be increased by more than ten percent (10%) of the lot coverage permitted by the underlying district regulations or the regulations in effect at the time of development; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
the proposed alternative development will not result in the destruction or removal of mature trees on the lot with a diameter at breast height of greater than ten (10) inches, unless the trees are among those listed in Section 24-60(4)(f) of this code, or the trees are relocated in a manner that preserves the aesthetic and shade qualities of the lot; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
the increase in lot coverage will not result in a principal building with an architectural design, scale, mass or building materials that are not aesthetically harmonious with that of other existing or proposed structures in the immediate vicinity; and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
the proposed alternative development will not result in an obvious departure from the aesthetic character of in the immediate vicinity.
<section prefix = "d">
An alternative maximum height of walls, hedges or fences for a zero lot line dwelling shall be approved upon demonstration of the following:
<section prefix = "1">
no wall, hedge or fence shall exceed eight (8) feet in height; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
no wall, hedge or fence located in a front setback required by the underlying district regulations or the regulations in effect at the time of development shall exceed six (6) feet in height; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
the additional height of a proposed wall, hedge or fence will not obscure in whole or in part an existing view or vista to any landmark, natural area, or waterbody from any window or door in a residential unit on an adjoining parcel of land; and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
proposed walls or fences shall be:
<section prefix = "A">
articulated to avoid the appearance of a "blank wall" when viewed from adjoining property, or
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
landscaped with landscaping that is at least three (3) feet in height at time of planting, located along the length of the wall between the wall and the adjoining property, accompanied by specific provision for the maintenance of the landscaping, such as but not limited to, an agreement from the landowner regarding its maintenance in recordable form from the adjoining property owner, or
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
where facing a public right-of-way, set back at least two and one-half (2-½) feet from the right-of-way line and extensively landscaped with shrubs of a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting, which will form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting; hedges of a minimum of three (3) feet in height immediately after planting, which will form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting; and/or climbing vines of a minimum of thirty-six (36) inches in height immediately after planting; and
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
proposed fences shall be constructed or installed so that the "unfinished" side is directed inward toward the center of the parcel proposed for alternative development; and
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
proposed fences are constructed of durable materials and are decorative; and
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
safe sight distance triangles are maintained pursuant to this code.
<section prefix = "e">
Notwithstanding the foregoing, no proposed alternative development shall be approved upon demonstration that the proposed alternative development:
<section prefix = "1">
will result in a significant diminution of the value of property in the immediate vicinity; or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
will have substantial negative impact on public safety due to unsafe automobile movements, heightened vehicular-pedestrian conflicts, or heightened risk of fire; or
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
will result in a materially greater adverse impact on public services and facilities than the impact that would result from development of the same parcel pursuant to the underlying district regulations.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Proposed alternative development under this subsection shall provide additional amenities or buffering to mitigate the impacts of the development as approved, where the amenities or buffering expressly required by this subsection are insufficient to mitigate the impacts of the development. The purpose of the amenities or buffering elements shall be to preserve and protect the quality of life of the residents of the approved development and the immediate vicinity in a manner comparable to that ensured by the underlying district regulations. Examples of such amenities include but are not limited to: active or passive recreational facilities, common open space, additional trees or landscaping, convenient covered bus stops or pick-up areas for transportation services, sidewalks (including improvements, linkages, or additional width), bicycle paths, buffer areas or berms, street furniture, undergrounding of utility lines, and decorative street lighting. In determining which amenities or buffering elements are appropriate for a proposed development, the following shall be considered:
<section prefix = "A">
the types of needs of the residents of the parcel proposed for development and the immediate vicinity that would likely be occasioned by the development, including, but not limited to, recreational, open space, transportation, aesthetic amenities, and buffering from adverse impacts; and
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
the proportionality between the impacts on residents of the proposed alternative development and the immediate vicinity and the amenities or buffering required. For example, an increase in the lot area coverage for numerous lots may warrant the provision of additional common open space. A reduction in a particular lot's interior side setback may warrant the provision of additional landscaping.
(15.1)
Alternative Site Development Option for Three-unit or Four-unit Apartment House, Multiple-Family Apartment House Use and Multiple-Family Housing Developments. This subsection provides for the establishment of an alternative site development option, after public hearing, for three-unit or four-unit apartment house use, multiple-family apartment house use and multiple-family housing developments, when such uses are permitted by the applicable district regulations, in the RU-3, RU-3M, RU-4L, RU-4M, RU-4, RU-4A, and RU-5 zoning districts, in accordance with the standards established herein. In considering any application for approval hereunder, the Community Zoning Appeals Board shall consider the same subject to approval of a site plan or such other plans as necessary to demonstrate compliance with the standards herein.
<section prefix = "a">
Purpose. The purpose of this subsection is to create objective standards to regulate the site-specific development of three-unit or four-unit apartment house use, multiple-family apartment house use and multiple-family housing development uses in specified zoning districts. The standards provided in this subsection are alternatives to the generalized standards contained in regulations governing the specified zoning districts. The site development standards permit alternative patterns of site development in accordance with the Comprehensive Development Master Plan ("CDMP") where the public interest served by the underlying district regulations and CDMP will be served, and the objectives of the creative urban design, urban infill development and redevelopment, or the preservation and enhancement of property values will be promoted, as demonstrated by the proposed alternative development's compliance with the standards of this subsection. A zoning application for development in compliance with the alternative standards shall be approved upon demonstration at public hearing that the proposed development is in compliance with the applicable alternative standards and does not contravene the enumerated public interest standards established herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
For the purposes of this subsection, the following terms shall have the following meanings:
"Common open space" means that portion of a parcel of land which is not covered with a building and is open to the sky and may include, except as otherwise restricted by the regulations governing the specified zoning district, patios, limited roof overhangs, screened enclosures with screened roofs, open trellises, pedestrian walkways and sitting areas, shuffle board recreational areas, swimming pools, tennis courts, landscaped areas, decks, lakes, entrance features, accessory buildings related to active or passive recreational uses, golf courses, similar open space amenities on roof decks and other above-grade surfaces, and ingress and egress drives not exceeding the maximum width required to serve the parking area.
"Applicable district regulations" means the site development regulations of the particular zoning district in which the proposed alternative development is located or the requirements, limitations and restrictions applicable to the particular type of proposed alternative development such as setbacks, lot area and frontage, lot coverage, floor area ratio, common open space, private open space, structure height and densities.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Setbacks for a three-unit or four-unit apartment house use, multiple-family apartment house use or multiple-family housing development shall be approved after public hearing upon demonstration of the following:
<section prefix = "1">
the character and design of the proposed alternative development will not result in a material diminution of the privacy of adjoining property; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
the proposed alternative development will not result in an obvious departure from the aesthetic character of the immediate vicinity, taking into account existing structures and open space; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
the proposed alternative development will not reduce the amount of common open space on the parcel proposed for alternative development by less than 20% of the open space percentage required by the applicable district regulations; and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
any area of shadow cast by the proposed alternative development upon an adjoining parcel of land during daylight hours will be no larger than would be cast by a structure(s) constructed, pursuant to the underlying district regulations, or will have no more than a de minimus impact on the use and enjoyment of the adjoining parcel of land; and
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
the proposed alternative development will not involve the installation or operation of any mechanical equipment closer to the adjoining parcel of land than any other portion of the proposed alternative development, unless such equipment is located within an enclosed, soundproofing structure and if located on the roof of such an alternative development shall screened from ground view and from view at the level in which the installations are located, and shall be designed as an integral part of and harmonious with the building design; and
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
the proposed alternative development will not involve any outdoor lighting fixture that casts light on an adjoining parcel of land at an intensity greater than permitted by this code; and
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
the architectural design, scale, mass, and building materials of any proposed structure(s) or addition(s) are aesthetically harmonious with that of other existing or proposed structure(s) or building(s) on the parcel proposed for alternative development; and
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
the wall(s) of any building within a setback area required by the applicable district regulations shall be improved with architectural details and treatments that avoid the appearance of a "blank wall"; and
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
the proposed alternative development will not result in the destruction or removal of mature trees within a setback required by the underlying district regulations, with a diameter at breast height of greater than ten (10) inches, unless the trees are among those listed in Section 24-60(4)(f) of this code, or the trees are relocated in a manner that preserves the aesthetic and shade qualities of the same side of the lot, parcel or tract; and
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
any windows or doors in any building(s) to be located within an interior side setback required by the applicable district regulations shall be designed and located so that they are not aligned directly across from facing windows or doors on buildings located on an adjoining parcel of land; and
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
total lot coverage shall not be increased by more than twenty percent (20%) of the lot coverage permitted by the applicable district regulations; and
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
the area within an interior side setback required by the applicable district regulations located behind the front building line will not be used for off-street parking except:
<section prefix = "A">
in any parking garage where the garage door or entrance(s) or exit(s) is located so that it is not aligned directly across from facing windows or doors on buildings located on an adjoining parcel of land; or
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
if the off-street parking is buffered from property that abuts the setback area by a solid wall at least six (6) feet in height along the area of pavement and parking, with either:
<section prefix = "i">
articulation to avoid the appearance of a "blank wall" when viewed from the adjoining property, or
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
landscaping that is at least three (3) feet in height at time of planting, located along the length of the wall between the wall and the adjoining property, accompanied by specific provision for the maintenance of the landscaping, such as but not limited to, an agreement regarding its maintenance in recordable form from the adjoining landowner; and
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
any structure(s) within an interior side setback required by the applicable district regulations:
<section prefix = "A">
is screened from adjoining property by landscape material of sufficient size and composition to obscure at least sixty percent (60%) of the proposed alternative development to a height of the lower fourteen (14) feet of such structure(s) at time of planting; or
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
is screened from adjoining property by an opaque fence or wall at least six (6) feet in height that meets the standards set forth in paragraph (f) herein; and
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
any proposed alternative development not attached to a principal building(s), except canopy carports, is located behind the front building line; and
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
any structure(s) not attached to a principal building(s) and proposed to be located within a setback required by the applicable district regulations shall be separated from any other structure(s) by at least five (5) feet; and
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
when a principal building(s) is proposed to be located within a setback required by the applicable district regulations, any enclosed portion of the upper floor of such building shall not extend beyond the first floor of such building within the setback; and
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
the eighteen (18) inch distance between any swimming pool and any wall or enclosure required by this code is maintained; and
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
safe sight distance triangles shall be maintained as required by this code; and
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
the parcel proposed for alternative development will continue to provide on-site parking as required by this code; and
</section>
<section prefix = "20">
the parcel proposed for alternative development shall satisfy applicable district regulations or, if applicable, prior zoning actions for similar uses issued prior to the effective date of this ordinance (May 16, 2003), regulating setbacks, lot area and frontage, lot coverage, floor area ratio, common open space, private open space, structure height and densities; and
</section>
<section prefix = "21">
the proposed development will meet the following:
<section prefix = "A">
interior side setbacks shall not be reduced by more than twenty-five percent (25%) of the setbacks required by the applicable district regulations, except that no such alternative interior side setback shall be permitted from an interior side property line adjoining lands approved or developed for single-family or duplex residential use or designated for Low Density, Agriculture or Open Land on the Land Use Plan map of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan;
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
side street setbacks shall not be reduced by more than twenty-five percent (25%) of the setbacks required by the applicable district regulations;
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
interior side setbacks for active recreational uses shall not be reduced by more than 25% of the setbacks required by the applicable district regulations, except that no such alternative interior side setback shall be permitted from any interior side property line adjoining lands approved or developed for single-family or duplex residential use or designated for Low Density, Agriculture or Open Land on the Land Use Plan map of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan;
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
front setbacks shall not be reduced by more than twenty-five percent (25%) of the setbacks required by the applicable district regulations;
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
rear setbacks shall not be reduced by more than twenty-five percent (25%) required by the applicable district regulations, except that no such alternative rear setback shall be permitted from a rear property line adjoining lands developed for single-family or duplex residential use or designated for Low Density, Agriculture or Open Land on the Land Use Plan map of the CDMP; and
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
setbacks between principal building(s) shall not be reduced by more than twenty-five percent (25%) of the setback required by the applicable district regulations.
<section prefix = "d">
A lot coverage or floor area ratio for a three-unit or four-unit apartment house use, multiple-family apartment house use or multiple-family housing development shall be approved upon demonstration of the following:
<section prefix = "1">
total lot coverage or floor area ratio shall not be increased by more than twenty percent (20%) of the lot coverage and floor area ratio permitted by the applicable district regulations; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
the proposed alternative development will not result in the destruction or removal of mature trees on the lot with a diameter at breast height of greater than ten (10) inches, unless the trees are among those listed in Section 24-60(4)(f) of this code, or the trees are relocated in a manner that preserves the aesthetic and shade qualities of the lot; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
the increase in lot coverage or floor area ratio will not result in principal building(s) with an architectural design, scale, mass or building materials that are not aesthetically harmonious with that of other existing or proposed structures in the immediate vicinity; and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
the proposed alternative development will not result in an obvious departure from the aesthetic character of the immediate vicinity.
<section prefix = "e">
Common open space for a multiple-family apartment house use or multiple-family housing development shall be approved upon demonstration of the following:
<section prefix = "1">
common open space shall not be decreased by more than twenty percent (10%) of the common open space required by the applicable district regulations; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
the proposed alternative development will not result in the destruction or removal of mature trees on the lot with a diameter at breast height of greater than ten (10) inches, unless the trees are among those listed in Section 24-60(4)(f) of this code, or the trees are relocated in a manner that preserves the aesthetic and shade qualities of the lot; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
the common open space provided shall be used to shade and cool, direct wind movements, enhance architectural features, relate structure design to site, visually screen non-compatible uses and block noise generated by major roadways and intense use areas; and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
the common open space provided shall relate to any natural characteristics in such a way as to preserve and enhance their scenic and functional qualities to the fullest extent possible; and
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
the proposed alternative development will not result in an obvious departure from the aesthetic character of the immediate vicinity.
<section prefix = "f">
The lot area and frontage for a three-unit or four-unit apartment house use, multiple-family apartment house use or multiple-family housing development shall be approved upon demonstration of at least one of the following:
<section prefix = "1">
the proposed lot area and lot frontage will permit the development or redevelopment of a lot, parcel or tract of land where such development would not otherwise be permitted by the applicable district regulations due to the size or configuration of the parcel proposed for alternative development, provided that:
<section prefix = "A">
the lot, parcel or tract is under lawful separate ownership from any contiguous property; and
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
the proposed alternative development will not result in the further subdivision of land; and
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
the size and dimensions of the lot, parcel or tract are sufficient to provide all setbacks required by the underlying district regulations; and
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
the lot area is not less than ninety percent (90%) of the minimum lot area required by the applicable district regulations; and
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
the proposed alternative development will not result in an obvious departure from the aesthetic character of the immediate vicinity; and
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
the parcel proposed for alternative development does not adjoin or lie adjacent to AU or GU zoned lands, nor lands designated for Low Density, Agricultural or Open Land under the Land Use Plan map of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan; and
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "G">
the lot frontage dimension is not less than ninety percent (90%) of the minimum lot frontage required by the applicable district regulations, except that the frontage dimension of a flag-lot, parcel or tract shall be permitted to be reduced to the minimum width necessary to allow vehicular access as determined by the County; and
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "H">
the resultant lot frontage provides vehicular ingress and egress to all resulting lots, parcels or tracts, including on-site access to emergency equipment.
<section prefix = "2">
the proposed alternative development will result in open space, community design, amenities or preservation of natural resources that enhances the function or aesthetic character of the immediate vicinity in a manner not otherwise achievable through application of the applicable district regulations, provided that:
<section prefix = "A">
the density of the proposed alternative development does not exceed that permitted by the applicable district regulations; and
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
the size and dimensions of each lot, parcel or tract in the proposed alternative development are sufficient to provide all setbacks required by the applicable district regulations, or, if applicable, any prior zoning actions for similar uses issued prior to the effective date of this ordinance (May 16, 2003); and
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
the area of each lot, parcel or tract is not less than eighty percent (80%) of the area required by the applicable district regulations; and
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
the proposed alternative development will not result in an obvious departure from the aesthetic character of the immediate vicinity; and
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
the parcel proposed for alternative development does not adjoin or lie adjacent to AU or GU zoned lands, nor lands designated for Low Density, Agricultural or Open Land under the Land Use Plan map of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan; and
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
the resultant lot frontage provides vehicular ingress and egress to all resulting lots, parcels or tracts, including on-site access to emergency equipment.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
the proposed lot area and frontage is such that:
<section prefix = "A">
the proposed alternative development will not result in the creation of more than two (2) lots, parcels or tracts; and
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
the size and dimensions of each lot, parcel or tract are sufficient to provide all setbacks required by the applicable district regulations; and
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
no lot area shall be less than the smaller of:
<section prefix = "i">
ninety percent (90%) of the lot area required by the applicable district regulations; or
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
the average area of the developed lots, parcels or tracts in the immediate vicinity within the same zoning district; and
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
the proposed alternative development will not result in an obvious departure from the aesthetic character of the immediate vicinity; and
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
the parcel proposed for alternative development does not adjoin or lie adjacent to AU or GU zoned lands, nor lands designated for Low Density, Agricultural or Open Land under the Land Use Plan map of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan; and
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
the resultant lot frontage provides vehicular ingress and egress to all resulting lots, parcels or tracts, including on-site access to emergency equipment.
<section prefix = "g">
A lot coverage or floor area ratio for a three-unit or four-unit apartment house use, multiple-family apartment house use or multiple-family housing development shall be approved upon demonstration of the following:
<section prefix = "1">
total lot coverage or floor area ratio shall not be increased by more than twenty percent (20%) of the lot coverage and floor area ratio permitted by the applicable district regulations; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
the proposed alternative development will not result in the destruction or removal of mature trees on the lot with a diameter at breast height of greater than ten (10) inches, unless the trees are among those listed in Section 24-60(4)(f) of this code, or the trees are relocated in a manner that preserves the aesthetic and shade qualities of the lot; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
the increase in lot coverage or floor area ratio will not result in principal building(s) with an architectural design, scale, mass or building materials that are not aesthetically harmonious with that of other existing or proposed structures in the immediate vicinity; and
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
the proposed alternative development will not result in an obvious departure from the aesthetic character of the immediate vicinity.
<section prefix = "h">
An alternative maximum height of walls, hedges or fences for a three-unit or four-unit apartment house use, multiple-family apartment house use or multiple-family housing development shall be approved upon demonstration of the following:
<section prefix = "1">
no wall, hedge or fence shall exceed eight (8) feet in height; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
no wall, hedge or fence located in a front or side street setback required by the applicable district regulations shall exceed six (6) feet in height; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
the additional height of a proposed wall, hedge or fence will not obscure in whole or in part an existing view or vista to any landmark, natural area, natural feature of the site such as a lake or golf course, or waterbody from any window or door in a residential dwelling unit on an adjoining parcel of land; and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
proposed walls or fences shall be:
<section prefix = "A">
articulated to avoid the appearance of a "blank wall" when viewed from adjoining property, or
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
landscaped with landscaping that is at least three (3) feet in height at time of planting, located along the length of the wall between the wall and the adjoining property, accompanied by specific provision for the maintenance of the landscaping, such as but not limited to, an agreement from the landowner regarding its maintenance in recordable form from the adjoining property owner, or
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
where facing a public right-of-way, set back at least two and one-half (2-½) feet from the right-of-way line and extensively landscaped with shrubs of a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting, which will form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting; hedges of a minimum of three (3) feet in height immediately after planting, which will form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting; and/or climbing vines of a minimum of thirty-six (36) inches in height immediately after planting; and
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
proposed fences shall be constructed or installed so that the sides are "finished" in accordance with the applicable regulations; and
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
proposed fences are constructed of durable materials and are decorative; and
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
safe sight distance triangles are maintained pursuant to this code.
<section prefix = "i">
