<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_X._PARK_AND_RECREATION_DEPARTMEN</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-85. Established; Director as head; appointment; term; employees</catch_line>
<text>
A Department of Parks and Recreation is established. The head of this Department shall be the Director of Parks and Recreation, who shall be appointed by and serve at the will of the Manager. The organization and operating procedures of the Department shall be prescribed in administrative orders and regulations of the Manager. The Manager shall appoint such employees and other personnel as may be necessary to operate the Department. The salaries and compensation of all personnel, except employees within the classified service, shall be fixed by the County Commission upon recommendation of the Manager.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-86. Functions, powers and duties</catch_line>
<text>
The Department of Parks and Recreation shall administer, manage, operate and care for all real and personal property held or acquired by the County for park, parkway, recreational, sports or cultural purposes, and it shall plan, provide, develop, maintain and operate all parks, recreational, sports and cultural facilities and programs of the park system in a manner so as to provide maximum use and benefit consistent with public safety and welfare in accordance with and consistent to the policy adopted by the County Commission. It shall perform such administrative functions as are directed by the Manager. The Director shall be responsible for the collection, accounting and transfer to the Finance Department of all revenues received through the operation of facilities within the parks in accordance with administrative procedures prescribed by the Manager; supervise and inspect the operations and services of all revenue producing facilities or businesses operated on properties under the care or control of the Department, and enforce the terms of leases and licenses, and with the Manager's approval, make rules and regulations for the use and occupancy and operation of the properties and facilities under the care or control of the Department, and such rules and regulations, when approved by the County Commission, shall have the force and effect of law in the County. The Director, with the approval of the Manager, shall make a uniform schedule of fees for the use of the properties and facilities under the care or control of the Department.
</text>
The Department of Parks and Recreation shall administer, manage, operate and care for all real and personal property held or acquired by the County for park, parkway, recreational, sports or cultural purposes, and it shall plan, provide, develop, maintain and operate all parks, recreational, sports and cultural facilities and programs of the park system in a manner so as to provide maximum use and benefit consistent with public safety and welfare in accordance with and consistent to the policy adopted by the County Commission. It shall perform such administrative functions as are directed by the Manager. The Director shall be responsible for the collection, accounting and transfer to the Finance Department of all revenues received through the operation of facilities within the parks in accordance with administrative procedures prescribed by the Manager; supervise and inspect the operations and services of all revenue producing facilities or businesses operated on properties under the care or control of the Department, and enforce the terms of leases and licenses, and with the Manager's approval, make rules and regulations for the use and occupancy and operation of the properties and facilities under the care or control of the Department, and such rules and regulations, when approved by the County Commission, shall have the force and effect of law in the County. The Director, with the approval of the Manager, shall make a uniform schedule of fees for the use of the properties and facilities under the care or control of the Department.
Annotations—AO's 4-1, 4-2, 4-3, 4-7, 4-28.

Charter reference— Authority of Manager to issue and place into effect administrative orders, rules and regulations and to prescribe the organization and operating procedure of departments of the County, § 4.02.
<catch_line>Sec. 2-86.1. Appointment of litter enforcement officers; qualifications</catch_line>
<text>
The County Director of Parks and Recreation is hereby authorized to designate and appoint such employees of the Department of Parks and Recreation as he deems advisable as litter enforcement officers of the County, solely for the purposes of Section 403.413, Florida Statutes, also known as the Florida Litter Law.
The directors of any municipal park and recreation departments in the County are similarly authorized to designate and appoint such of their employees as they in their discretion deem advisable as litter enforcement officers of the county, solely for the purposes of Section 403.413, Florida Statutes, also known as the Florida Litter Law.
Such employees as are designated and appointed as litter enforcement officers by their respective directors of parks and recreation shall have the following qualifications:
<section prefix = "a">
They shall have attended a course of at least five (5) days' duration on the duties of litter enforcement officers jointly given or approved by the directors of the departments of public safety and parks and recreation.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
They shall be personally approved and certified by the director of the Miami-Dade Police Department as persons of good moral character and standing in the community, and suited by temperament and learning to be litter enforcement officers of the County.

</section>
</text>
The County Director of Parks and Recreation is hereby authorized to designate and appoint such employees of the Department of Parks and Recreation as he deems advisable as litter enforcement officers of the County, solely for the purposes of Section 403.413, Florida Statutes, also known as the Florida Litter Law.
The directors of any municipal park and recreation departments in the County are similarly authorized to designate and appoint such of their employees as they in their discretion deem advisable as litter enforcement officers of the county, solely for the purposes of Section 403.413, Florida Statutes, also known as the Florida Litter Law.
Such employees as are designated and appointed as litter enforcement officers by their respective directors of parks and recreation shall have the following qualifications:
<section prefix = "a">
They shall have attended a course of at least five (5) days' duration on the duties of litter enforcement officers jointly given or approved by the directors of the departments of public safety and parks and recreation.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
They shall be personally approved and certified by the director of the Miami-Dade Police Department as persons of good moral character and standing in the community, and suited by temperament and learning to be litter enforcement officers of the County.

</section>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-86.2. Appointment of Park Security Officers; qualifications, powers and duties</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The County Director of the Park and Recreation Department is hereby authorized to designate and appoint certain employees of the Park and Recreation Department as Park Security Officers, for the sole purpose of enforcing the Miami-Dade County ordinances, rules and regulations pertaining to the conduct of members of the public in, on and at facilities operated or managed by the Park and Recreation Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Park Security Officers shall have the following qualifications:
<section prefix = "1">
Satisfactory completion of a course of at least forty (40) hours' duration pertaining to the duties of enforcement officers, which course shall be jointly given by the Directors of the Departments of Public Safety, and Park and Recreation.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Approval and certification by the Director of the Miami-Dade Police Department as persons of good moral character and standing in the community, suited by temperament and learning to be enforcement officers of the County.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Park Security Officers shall while on duty:
<section prefix = "1">
Issue citations for violations of County ordinances, rules and regulations pertaining to the conduct of members of the public in, on and at facilities operated or managed by the Park and Recreation Department. Citations shall be on a form approved by the Board of County Commissioners. Fines shall be in amounts approved by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Notify the Miami-Dade Police Department immediately when, in their judgment, an arrest or forcible restraint becomes the appropriate response to a situation.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Perform such additional duties as may be prescribed by ordinance or by administrative orders and regulations of the County Manager.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Park Security Officers shall be identified either by special uniform or badge or both. Park Security Officers shall not carry firearms.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 81-5, § 1, 1-20-81; Ord. No. 97-23, § 1, 3-18-97)</history>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (20) ---
Annotation—AO 9-1 (Back)
Cross reference— Parks and recreation generally, Ch. 25B; Park and Recreation Department rules and regulations, Ch. 26. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
