<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XIIA._WORKFORCE_HOUSING_DEVELOPM</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-193.3. Short title</catch_line>
<text>
This article shall be known as the "Workforce Housing Development Program of Miami-Dade County, Florida."
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-193.4. Legislative intent, findings, and purpose</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Need for workforce housing in Miami-Dade County. The health, safety, and welfare of the present and future residents of Miami-Dade County depend on the availability of a range of housing choices affordable to persons and families of all income levels in all areas of Miami-Dade County. Current patterns of development have resulted in a persistent shortage of housing for certain sectors of the community. Studies of market demand show that for the foreseeable future more than 50% of the new labor force in Miami-Dade County will require moderately priced housing units. Currently, there exists in Miami-Dade County a shortage of housing affordable to individuals and families of moderate incomes, particularly those whose earnings range from 65% to 140% of the County's median income, the "workforce target income group." The workforce target income group includes many public employees and others employed in key occupations that support the local community. Increasingly, the high cost and short supply of housing affordable to persons and families of moderate income mean that many employees in the workforce target income group cannot afford to live in Miami-Dade County, while others can only afford to live in areas concentrated according to price and income level.
The uneven distribution of moderately-priced housing results in additional stratification of housing according to price and income level. It is in the best interests of the public health, safety, and welfare of the present and future residents of Miami-Dade County to reduce or eliminate such economic stratification by adopting land use regulations that encourage development of land available for residential use in Miami-Dade County in a manner that emphasizes integration of new housing for individuals and families in the workforce target income group into new, expanding, or redeveloping neighborhoods.
The uneven geographic distribution of housing affordable to the workforce target income group, as well as the distance between jobs and available housing, also increase traffic congestion and decrease economic productivity. Traffic and roadway congestion in turn adversely affect the environment and diminish air quality, increasing the burden on the public health care system and resulting in rising health care costs. The public health, safety, and welfare of the present and future residents of Miami-Dade County can best be protected by adopting land use policies to ensure that housing affordable to the workforce target income group is distributed throughout the county near workplaces, rather than being concentrated in enclaves separate from jobs and higher-priced housing.
The Florida Growth Management Act requires Miami-Dade County to adopt a comprehensive plan to guide future development and growth, including a housing element consisting of standards, plans, and principles to be followed in the provision of housing for all current and anticipated future residents. Exercising the authority conferred by the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, and in furtherance of the Growth Management Act, the Board of County Commissioners has adopted the Comprehensive Development Master Plan ("CDMP"), including a housing element which establishes goals, objectives, and policies to ensure the provision of all variations of affordable housing products to meet the spatial and economic necessities of all current and future residents regardless of household type or income.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Causes and consequences of lack of sufficient workforce housing supply. In order to assess the extent of the housing shortage, identify the most severely affected sectors of the community, and ascertain the need for a workforce housing development program, the Board of County Commissioners established a task force consisting of county housing, zoning, and planning professionals, and representatives of the private, for-profit, development community. The mission of the task force was to analyze the current and anticipated future make-up of Miami-Dade County's workforce and population, the geographic distribution of moderately-priced housing, historical and current patterns of development applications and approvals, the distance between jobs and housing for the workforce target income group, the overall impact of the housing shortage on the economy of Miami-Dade County, and the adverse consequences failure to act would have on the health, safety, welfare, comfort, and convenience of the present and future residents of Miami-Dade County. The need for the workforce housing development program as identified by the task force is the result of a variety of factors, including, but not limited to, those noted below.
<section prefix = "1">
Increasing population pressure. Miami-Dade County, in both the incorporated and unincorporated areas, is experiencing a rapid increase in the numbers of residents in the workforce target income group, including persons with fixed or reduced incomes, young adults forming new households, minority households, single adults, and many public employees and others in key occupations serving the entire community including teachers, police and public safety personnel, health care workers and mid-level management workers. Studies show that, as a result of this population increase, for the foreseeable future more than one-half of the new labor force in Miami-Dade County will require workforce housing.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Cost burdens. Households in Miami-Dade County suffer from a high and increasing housing cost burden. Households have traditionally been regarded as "cost burdened" if they spend more than 30% of their gross income on housing costs. In Miami-Dade County, nearly 51% of all renter households pay more than 30% of their income in gross rent. In owner-occupied units, more than 36% of all households pay more than 30% of their income on housing.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Inadequate housing supply for the workforce target income group. Current patterns of development, the costs of acquiring land suitable for residential development, and the disposition of remaining developable land have resulted in an abundance of higher-priced housing and a shortage of housing economically attainable by the workforce target income group. With the exception of housing developed with government subsidies, privately developed new residential housing being built in Miami-Dade County generally is not affordable to the workforce target income group. Experience indicates that state and federal funds for the construction of affordable housing will not address the housing needs of the workforce target income group.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Overcrowding. Overcrowding is a major problem in Miami-Dade County. The problem is acute in low to moderate income households and households in the workforce target income group. Analyses indicate nearly 20% of all housing units in Miami-Dade County are overcrowded.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Concentration of housing based on economic status. Demographic analyses indicate that development applications and approvals that reduce the supply of land developable for residential use, and which result in a disproportionate amount of higher-priced housing, result in a reduced supply of housing for individuals and families in the workforce target income group, including young families, retired and elderly persons, single adults, female heads of houses, and minority households. Such development activity produces the undesirable and unacceptable effect of concentrating housing according to price, thus frustrating the policies and goals of the housing element of the CDMP, and increasing the threat to the public health, safety, welfare, comfort, and convenience of the present and future residents of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Need for involvement of private development community. Existing efforts to encourage private, for-profit, developers to construct housing within the economic reach of the workforce target income group have met with very limited success. It is apparent that the need for housing for the workforce target income group can only be addressed if the responsibility for ensuring a diverse and adequate supply of housing is shared by Miami-Dade County, and the private, for-profit, development community.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Authority to establish and administer a workforce housing development program. The Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter specifically authorizes the Board of County Commissioners to prepare and enforce comprehensive plans for the development of Miami-Dade County in the incorporated and unincorporated areas, to establish, coordinate, and enforce such zoning regulations as are necessary for the protection of the public, to exercise all powers and privileges granted to municipalities, counties and county officers by the Constitution and laws of the State, to exercise all powers not prohibited by the Constitution or by the Charter, and to perform any other acts consistent with law which are required by the Charter or which are in the common interest of the people of the County. The workforce housing development program of Miami-Dade County is declared to be a proper and necessary exercise of the powers conferred upon the Board of County Commissioners for the protection of the health, safety, welfare, comfort, and convenience of the present and future residents of Miami-Dade County.
Consistent with the goals, objectives, and policies of the land use and housing elements of the CDMP, the objective of the workforce housing development program is to increase the supply of housing affordable to the workforce target income group, and to address many of the problems associated with the short supply of housing affordable to the workforce target income group and with the uneven, poor geographic distribution of such housing throughout Miami-Dade County. Through utilization of a combination of density bonuses, relaxation of intensity standards, flexible design criteria, and other incentives, the workforce housing program established herein will help alleviate the existing housing shortage by making it more feasible for the private, for-profit, development community to create and deliver a greater number of housing units affordable to the workforce target income group. Dispersal of workforce housing units throughout this community will avoid overconcentration of such housing.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
Joint effort of private development community, public sector, and not-for-profit sector. It is the further intent of the Board of County Commissioners that the workforce housing development program established herein will foster and encourage the private, for-profit, development community to join with the public sector and the nonprofit sector to further the goal of meeting the housing needs of the workforce target income group.
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
Adoption of legislative intent, findings and purpose. The foregoing statements are declared to be the legislative intent, findings and purpose of the Board of County Commissioners and are hereby adopted and made a part hereof.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 07-05, § 1, 1-25-07; Ord. No. 08-51, § 1, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-193.5. Adoption of land use regulations and procedures for operation of Miami-Dade County's Workforce Housing Development Program</catch_line>
<text>
The Board of County Commissioners hereby adopts land use regulations and procedures for the operation of the Miami-Dade County workforce housing development program. The workforce housing development program, including all land use regulations and operating procedures, is deemed to be essential to assure the protection of the public health, safety, welfare, comfort, and convenience of the present and future residents of Miami-Dade County. All land use regulations adopted in connection with the workforce housing development program shall be supplemental to existing zoning on affected properties and shall be construed to be consistent therewith.
The Board of County Commissioners shall adopt by resolution such administrative procedures as may be necessary or proper to further the purposes of this article and thereby protect the public health, safety, welfare, comfort, and convenience of the present and future residents of Miami-Dade County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-193.6. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
The following words and phrases, as used in this article, have the following meanings:
<section prefix = "1">
Application means any request for zoning action, building permit, administrative site plan review, or administrative modification under Chapter 33, or any request for approval or extension of approval of any type of application for subdivision of land pursuant to Chapter 28, where such request seeks approval to develop residential or mixed uses subject to the requirements of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
At one location means all land owned by the applicant, including:
<section prefix = "a">
All adjacent parcels, the property lines of which are contiguous at any point; or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
All adjacent parcels, the property lines of which are separated only by a public or private street, road, highway or utility right-of-way, or other public or private right-of-way at any point; or
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All adjacent parcels, under common ownership or control of the applicant, including land owned or controlled by any business entities in which the applicant or immediate family members of the applicant possesses any form of management control.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Transit corridor area is the area which lies within a one-half mile radius of the Metrorail stations.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Urban Infill Area (UIA) is the area as defined in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan (CDMP).
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Work-force housing unit or WHU shall mean a dwelling unit, the sale, rental or pricing of which in accordance with this article is restricted to households whose income is within the workforce housing target income range.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Workforce housing target income range means households whose income range is established at 65% up to 140% of the most recent median family income for the County reported by the U.S. HUD as maintained by the Department of Planning and Zoning.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-193.7. Applicability</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
An application seeking to utilize the density bonus and intensity standards available under this article (a "WHU application") shall:
<section prefix = "A">
<section prefix = "1">
For WHU applications seeking approval of 20 or more dwelling units provide workforce housing units or a monetary contribution as provided in Section 33-193.9; and
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
For WHU applications seeking approval of fewer than 20 dwelling units, provide a monetary contribution as provided in Section 33-193.9.1
<section prefix = "B">
A WHU application seeking to develop property improved with one or more existing dwelling units priced to sell or rent to persons in the workforce housing target income range (Existing WHUs) shall provide for a total number of WHUs equal to the greater of the (1) Existing WHUs or (2) the number of WHUs that would have been required had there been no Existing WHUs on the property;
Each WHU application to develop improved property shall provide evidence satisfactory to the Director as to whether Existing WHUs are on the property.
<section prefix = "2">
The provisions of this article shall not apply to property located outside the Urban Development Boundary as designated in the Land Use Plan (LUP) map of the CDMP, as amended from time to time.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 07-05, § 1, 1-25-07; Ord. No. 08-51, § 1, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-193.8. Alternatives to on-site construction of WHUs; variances</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Alternatives. An applicant for a WHU application ("WHU applicant") may satisfy the requirement of on-site construction of all of the required WHUs or of a portion of required WHUs by one of the means described below upon demonstrating, after public hearing, that where, owing to special conditions, allowing the alternative will observe the spirit of this article, and that approving the alternative requested will further the development of housing for the workforce target income group in the unincorporated area of Miami-Dade County to an equal or greater extent than construction of the required WHUs on-site.
<section prefix = "1">
Off-site construction of WHUs. If an approval is obtained after public hearing in accordance with the standards in this section, a WHU applicant may comply with the requirements of this article by construction of 110% of the number of WHUs required by this article at one or more alternative sites within a 2 mile radius of the proposed location of the market rate units being proposed (the "Off-site WHUs"). The alternative site must contain both its market rate and workforce housing units and the Off-site WHUs. The alternative site shall be within the same Community Council jurisdiction as the market rate units being proposed and the construction of the Off-site WHUs on the alternative site shall occur concurrently with the market rate units on the primary site.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Monetary contribution in lieu of construction of WHUs. If an approval is obtained after public hearing in accordance with the standards in this section, or if permitted as of right pursuant to section 33-193.9, a WHU applicant may satisfy the requirements of this article by providing a monetary contribution to the affordable housing trust fund established in Chapter 17, Article VIII of this code, in lieu of construction of the required on-site workforce housing units. Any monetary contributions received by the County shall not be commingled with any other funds deposited into the affordable housing trust fund that are not associated with the WHU program, but shall be deposited into a separate account. The amount of such required monetary contribution shall be as established in section 33-193.9.1. All monetary contributions shall be made prior to the issuance of the first building permit on the market rate units.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Combination of off-site construction of WHUs and monetary contributions. If an approval is obtained after public hearing in accordance with the standards in this section, a WHU applicant may comply with the requirements of this article employing a combination of the alternatives (1) and (2) above in accordance with the standards of this section.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Variances. The following provisions of this article may be varied after public hearing, only upon demonstration that a literal enforcement of the provision of this article will result in an unnecessary hardship, that allowing the variance will observe the spirit of this article, that the degree to which the variance is granted is the minimum needed to avoid the hardship, and that the objectives of this article to increase the supply of housing for the workforce housing target group within the Community Council area will continue to be met if the requested variance is granted:
<section prefix = "1">
The applicable density bonus provisions or intensity standards;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The number of WHUs required for a WHU application;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The amount of the monetary contribution in lieu pursuant to Section 33-193.9.1
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
If zoning approval is required, the application for such approval shall be filed together with the application for approval of any off site WHUs and shall be considered and approved or denied at the same public hearing.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 07-05, § 1, 1-25-07; Ord. No. 08-51, § 1, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-193.9. Required Workforce Housing Units</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
All applications seeking to utilize the density or intensity bonus available pursuant to this article for developments shall include a minimum percentage of workforce housing units based on the following:
<section prefix="1" type="table">
<table class="table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">CDMP Land Use Category</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Proposed Gross Density of Development</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Percentage of All Residential Units Required To Be Work-Force Units</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Estate</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Up to and Including 2.5 Units Per Gross Acre.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">5 Percent<sup>1</sup> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">From 2.5 up to and Including 3.125 Units Per Gross Acre</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">12.5 Percent<sup>2</sup> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Low-Density Residential</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">From 3 up to and Including 6 Units Per Gross Acre.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">5 Percent<sup>1</sup> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">From 6 to 7.5 Units Per Gross Acre.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">12.5 Percent<sup>2</sup> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Low-Medium Density Residential</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">From 6 up to and Including 13 Units Per Gross Acre.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">5 Percent<sup>1</sup> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">From 13 up to and Including 16.25 Units Per Gross Acre.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">12.5 Percent<sup>2</sup> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Medium Density Residential</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">From 13 up to and Including 20 Units Per Gross Acre.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">5 Percent<sup>1</sup> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">From 20 up to and Including 31.25 Units Per Gross Acre.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">No Required Work-Force Units. Contribution in lieu of workforce housing units required pursuant to<a href="../level3/PTIIICOOR_CH33ZO_ARTXIIAWOHODEPR.html#PTIIICOOR_CH33ZO_ARTXIIAWOHODEPR_S33-193.9.1MOCOLICOWH"> Section 33-193.9.1</a> equal to 5% of the market rate units. </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Medium-High Density Residential</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">From 25 up to and including 75 Units Per Gross Acre</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">No Required Work-Force Units. Contribution in lieu of workforce housing units required pursuant to<a href="../level3/PTIIICOOR_CH33ZO_ARTXIIAWOHODEPR.html#PTIIICOOR_CH33ZO_ARTXIIAWOHODEPR_S33-193.9.1MOCOLICOWH"> Section 33-193.9.1</a> equal to 5% of the market rate units. </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">High Density Residential</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">From 50 up to and including 156 Units Per Gross Acre</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">No Required Work-Force Units. Contribution in lieu of workforce housing units required pursuant to<a href="../level3/PTIIICOOR_CH33ZO_ARTXIIAWOHODEPR.html#PTIIICOOR_CH33ZO_ARTXIIAWOHODEPR_S33-193.9.1MOCOLICOWH"> Section 33-193.9.1</a> equal to 5% of the market rate units. </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Office/Residential</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">In accordance with applicable CDMP provisions<sup>3</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Refer to applicable residential category above</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Business and Office</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">In accordance with applicable CDMP provisions<sup>4</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Refer to applicable residential category above</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Industrial</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">In accordance with applicable CDMP provisions</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">20 Percent<sup>1</sup> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Urban Center</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Those urban centers not rezoned as of February 4, 2007 (the effective date of this ordinance) </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">12.5 Percent<sup>2</sup> </td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 
1The number of WHUs to be provided shall be 5% of the total number of market rate units.
2The percentage of WHUs to be provided shall be a percentage of the total number of units.
3Office/Residential - One density category higher than that allowed in the adjoining or adjacent residentially designated area on the same side of the abutting principal roadway, or up to the density of existing adjoining or adjacent residential development, or zoning if the adjacent or adjoining land is undeveloped whichever is higher. If there is no adjacent or adjoining residential development existing, zoned or designated on the same side of the abutting principal roadway, then the allowable maximum residential density shall be based on that which exists or which the plan allows across the roadway. Where there is no residential use, zoning or designation on either side of the roadway, the intensity of residential development, including height, bulk and floor area ratio shall be no greater than that which would be permitted for an exclusively office use of the site.
4Business and Office - One density category higher than the LUP - designated density of the adjacent or adjoining residentially designated area on the same side of the abutting principal roadway, or up to the density of any such existing residential development, or zoning if the adjacent or adjoining land is undeveloped, whichever is higher. If there is no adjacent or adjoining residential use existing, zoned or designated on the same side of the roadway, the maximum allowable residential density will be that which exists or which this plan allows across the roadway. Where there is no residential use, zoning or designation on either side of the roadway, the intensity of residential development, including height, bulk and floor area ratio shall be no greater than that which would be permitted for an exclusively commercial use of the site.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
All applications for residential developments within Urban Centers depicted on the Land Use Plan (LUP) map of the CDMP that are zoned as an urban center as of the effective date of this article shall not be required to provide workforce housing units.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Applicants seeking to utilize the 12.5% density bonus shall not seek approval of any application or proffer any declaration of restrictive covenants providing for a density below 95% of the total maximum density permitted by the underlying zoning district regulations, all zoning actions approved on the property and the maximum allowable density bonuses.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 07-05, § 1, 1-25-07; Ord. No. 08-51, § 1, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-193.9.1. Monetary contribution in lieu of construction of WHUs</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
WHU developments of fewer than 20 residential units seeking to utilize the density or intensity bonus available pursuant to this article shall pay an amount as follows:
Number of market rate units to be developed × $110,000 20 = Total Contribution.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Developments for which a monetary contribution has been approved in accordance with section 33-193.8(A) or 33-193.8(D) and developments required to contribute pursuant to section 33-193.9(A) shall pay an amount as follows:
Number of WHUs required to be developed (fractions rounded down) × $110,000 = Total contribution.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 07-05, § 1, 1-25-07; Ord. No. 08-51, § 1, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-193.10. Density bonuses</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Any application providing a minimum of 12.5 percent WHUs on-site, or otherwise complying with Section 33-193.8 of this article, shall be entitled to a residential density bonus of 25 percent above the applicable CDMP Land Use map maximum density (provided the application satisfies all of the requirements of this article) as well as the benefit of the intensity standards provided in section 33-193.11
The density bonus for the primary site shall not be transferable to the off-site property, where an alternative site is approved after public hearing for the development of off-site WHUs.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
WHU applicants providing 5% workforce housing units or an approved contribution in lieu thereof shall be entitled to a density bonus above the CDMP maximum density to such increased density as is required to provide the 5% WHUs, as well as the benefit of the intensity standards provided in section 33-193.11
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
The total number of dwelling units permitted, including bonus units, market rate units, and WHUs may exceed the permitted maximum density allowed in the zoning district in accordance with the foregoing provisions, provided that in no event shall the density exceed the maximum densities, including applicable bonuses, set forth in the CDMP, as amended.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
Severable use rights, as provided in Chapter 33B of this code, shall not be utilized in conjunction with the density bonuses contained in this article.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 07-05, § 1, 1-25-07; Ord. No. 08-51, § 1, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-193.11. Intensity standards</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Notwithstanding zoning district regulations to the contrary, the following maximum intensity standards shall apply to applications seeking approval of a WHU application that provides either the WHUs required to obtain a density bonus or a monetary contribution in lieu thereof, under the provision of this Article:
<section prefix = "1">
In the EU-2 District:
<section prefix = "a">
Minimum lot size—Four (4) acres;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Minimum lot frontage—One hundred sixty-five (165) feet;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Maximum lot coverage—Twenty (20) percent.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
In the EU-1C District:
<section prefix = "a">
Minimum lot size—Two (2) acres;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Minimum lot frontage—One hundred twenty-five (125) feet.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
In the EU-1 District:
<section prefix = "a">
Minimum lot size—Thirty-two thousand five hundred (32,500) square feet;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Minimum lot frontage—One hundred ten (110) feet.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
In the EU-S District:
<section prefix = "a">
Minimum lot size—Twenty thousand (20,000) square feet;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Minimum lot frontage—One hundred ten (110) feet.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
In the EU-M District:
<section prefix = "a">
Minimum lot size—Twelve thousand five hundred (12,500) square feet;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Minimum lot frontage—One hundred (100) feet.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
In the RU-1 and RU-2 Districts:
<section prefix = "a">
Minimum net lot area of residential lots shall be 5,000 square feet and the minimum lot frontage shall be 50 feet, except that a maximum of 10 percent of the residential lots may be reduced to a minimum of 4,000 square feet and a minimum lot frontage of 40 feet; and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Maximum lot coverage shall not exceed the lot coverage permitted by the underlying district regulations by more than 20%.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
In the RU-1M(a), and RU-1M(b) Districts:
<section prefix = "a">
The minimum net lot area of residential lots shall be 4,000 square feet; and the minimum lot frontage shall be 40 feet; and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Maximum lot coverage shall not exceed the lot coverage permitted by the underlying district regulations by more than 20%.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
In the RU-TH district:
<section prefix = "a">
Minimum lot size shall be 1,250 square feet of net lot area; and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Minimum open space shall be 20 percent of the net lot area.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
In the RU-RH district:
<section prefix = "a">
Minimum lot size shall be 1,000 square feet of net lot area; and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Density shall not exceed 15 dwelling units per net acre; and
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
No private open space shall be required; and
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
A minimum of 10 percent common open space shall be provided in the way of greens.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
In the RU-3M district:
<section prefix = "a">
Maximum floor area ratio shall be 0.60; and'
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Maximum height shall be 3 stories not to exceed 40 feet in overall height; and
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Maximum lot coverage shall be 35% of net lot area; and
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Minimum open space shall be 20 percent of the net land area.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
In the RU-4L district:
<section prefix = "a">
Maximum floor area ratio shall be 0.9;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Maximum height shall be 6 stories;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Maximum lot coverage shall be 35% of net lot area.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
In the RU-4M district:
<section prefix = "a">
Maximum floor area ratio shall be 1.0;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Maximum height shall be 9 stories;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Maximum lot coverage shall be 35% of net lot area.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
In the RU-4 and RU-4A districts:
<section prefix = "a">
Maximum height shall be one additional story;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Maximum floor area ratio shall be 2.2 for a development over 9 stories.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
In the BU-1 and BU-1A districts if approved after public hearing:
<section prefix = "a">
Maximum floor area ratio — Add .015 per acre above that permitted by the district regulations;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Maximum lot coverage shall be 45% of net lot area;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Landscaped open space shall be the open space percentage required by the underlying district regulations for a one story building.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
In the BU-2 district if approved after public hearing:
<section prefix = "a">
Maximum floor area ratio — Add .015 per acre above that permitted by the district regulations
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Maximum lot coverage shall be 50% of net lot area;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Landscaped open space shall be the open space percentage required by the underlying district regulations for a one story building.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
In all transit corridor areas, parking shall be provided as required by section 33-124 of this code, except as follows:
<section prefix = "a">
the minimum parking required shall be:
<section prefix = "i">
Residential—One (1) parking space per dwelling unit.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Office—One (1) parking space per four-hundred (400) square feet of gross floor area.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Hotel—One (1) parking space for every two (2) guest rooms.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Severable use rights, as provided in Chapter 33B of this code, shall not be utilized in conjunction with the intensity standards contained in this article.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 07-05, § 1, 1-25-07; Ord. No. 08-51, § 1, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-193.12. Design and unit placement</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Workforce housing units shall be comparable in design and materials to market-rate units within the development in terms of exterior appearance. Workforce housing units may be grouped or dispersed throughout the development.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Notwithstanding underlying zoning regulations that limit the number of residential units that may be constructed on a single platted lot, residential developments incorporating workforce housing units may utilize the following flexible design provisions, provided that the total development density shall not exceed that allowed by this article. Units to be developed in accordance with this section shall be approved only upon demonstration that a declaration of condominium has been filed in accordance with state law (if any unit is to be sold).
<section prefix = "1">
No more than 3 total residential units may be placed on a single platted lot, of which no more than one unit may be, but shall not be required to be, a market rate unit; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The entrance to each of the units on a single platted lot shall be:
<section prefix = "a">
Through a common hall/foyer area in the front of the building, which shall be concealed by a building wall with 1 entrance door, giving the appearance of a single-family residential unit; or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The entrance to the workforce housing unit(s) shall be clearly designed to be subordinate to the principal entrance of the building for the market rate unit. When the entrance is configured in this manner, the design shall incorporate architectural features and elements that clearly distinguish and develop the market rate unit entrance as the predominant entrance from the other entrances.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Buildings designed under these parameters shall not be located on the periphery of a development, adjacent to or across the street from previously established single-family residential neighborhoods.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The locations of the parking spaces for the units within the building shall be dispersed around the building so as not to create a parking field for all of the spaces in the front of the building.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 07-05, § 1, 1-25-07; Ord. No. 08-51, § 1, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-193.13. Required declaration of restrictive covenant</catch_line>
<text>
Prior to final approval of any application seeking to utilize the density or intensity bonus available pursuant to this article, the applicant shall submit a separate declaration of restrictive covenants, encumbering the entire project, approved in form by the Director and sufficient for recording in the public records of Miami-Dade County, Florida, including provisions requiring development of a specified number, type, and location of all dwelling units, a general plan for staging construction of all units, and such other provisions as the Department may require to demonstrate the applicant's compliance with this article. The development and the WHU staging plan must be consistent with the CDMP and any applicable land use, subdivision regulations, zoning and site plan approval for the property. The declaration of restrictive covenants shall require the property to be developed in accordance with the following specifications:
<section prefix = "A">
A general description of the covered development, including whether the covered development will contain rental dwelling units or owner-occupied dwelling units, or both;
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
The total number of market rate dwelling units and WHUs in the development and the timetable for construction; and
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
The location of the WHUs in the development and phasing, if any, and construction schedule for the development sequence demonstrating that:
<section prefix = "1">
WHUs will be built and made available for occupancy simultaneously with or before market-rate dwelling units, except that building permits for the last 10% of the market-rate units shall be withheld until building permits have been issued for all of the WHUs; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The last building shall not contain only WHUs.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
If the requirements of this article are to be satisfied through the use of an alternative to on-site construction as provided in section 33-193.8, of this code, the declaration of restrictive covenants shall identify and commit to the development of WHUs on an approved alternative site. A separate declaration of restrictive covenants encumbering the alternative site shall identify and commit to the development of the approved off-site WHUs, and shall further provide appropriate assurances that the WHUs that will be required for the alternative site itself will be provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
The declaration of restrictive covenants may be modified by mutual consent of the applicant and the Department of Planning and Zoning and the Miami-Dade Housing Agency, as long as the modified agreement remains in conformity with this article and substantially conforms to the recorded declaration's provisions relating to number, location, distribution and timing or construction of WHUs.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-193.14. Workforce housing agreement</catch_line>
<text>
Prior to the earlier of final plat approval or application for building permit for the first residential unit on the property subject to the requirements of this article applicant shall submit a declaration of restrictive covenants, approved in form by the Director and sufficient for recording in the public records of Miami-Dade County, Florida, encumbering the individual WHUs in the entire development, specifying the restrictions of the WHU and such further arrangements, restrictive covenants, and resale restrictions as are necessary to carry out the purposes of Chapter 17, Article IX of the code, sections 17-142 through 17-144 inclusive, and shall include the following:
<section prefix = "a">
A binding commitment that the restrictions of this article shall run with the land for the entire control period, and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A binding commitment that the covenants will bind the applicant, any assignee, mortgagee, or buyer, and all other parties that receive title to or an interest in the property, and
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
These covenants shall be senior to all other liens or encumbrances on the property including all instruments securing permanent financing, except that tax and assessment liens shall be superior to these covenants, and
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
A binding commitment that incorporates all terms and conditions regarding WHUs, including without limitation, the required shared equity agreement, eligibility standards, appropriate sale and rental price standards and affordability controls required of purchasers of WHUs pursuant to Chapter 17, Article VIII of this code.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-193.15. Penalties and enforcement</catch_line>
<text>
This article shall be enforceable in accordance with the provisions of Chapter 8CC of this code. Violations of this article shall also be punishable by a fine not to exceed one thousand dollars ($1,000.00) or by imprisonment in the county jail for a period not to exceed sixty (60) days, or by both such fine and imprisonment, in the discretion of the county court. Any continuing violations of the provisions of this article may be enjoined and restrained by injunctive order of the circuit court in appropriate proceedings instituted for such purpose.
</text>
</law>
