<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXIA._HOUSING_AND_URBAN_DEVELOPM</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-186. Declaration of legislative intent</catch_line>
<text>
The Board of County Commissioners finds that in order to carry on a central metropolitan government and to administer effectively coordinated public housing, slum clearance, urban renewal and relocation programs within Miami-Dade County, it is necessary that such programs be administered under policy determinations of the Board and the supervision of the Manager through a Director of Housing and Urban Development with the powers, duties and functions previously exercised by the Miami-Dade County Urban Renewal Agency with the advice and assistance of a Housing and Urban Development Advisory Board (hereafter referred to as HUD Board).
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-187. Department created; Director; organization; employees</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
A Department of Housing and Urban Development is hereby established.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The head of this department is the Director of Housing and Urban Development. The Director shall be appointed by the Manager subject to the approval of the Board of County Commissioners and shall serve at the will of the Manager.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The organization and operating procedures of the department shall be prescribed by administrative orders and regulations of the Manager.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The Manager shall appoint such employees as may be necessary to operate the department. The compensation of all personnel shall be fixed by the Commission upon recommendation of the Manager.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 67-32, § 2(a), 4-25-67; Ord. No. 88-123, § 1, 12-20-88; Ord. No. 90-66, § 1, 7-10-90)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-188. Powers of Director</catch_line>
<text>
Subject to the policy determination of the Board of County Commissioners and the administrative supervision of the Manager, the Director of Housing and Urban Development shall exercise the following powers:
<section prefix = "a">
All administrative powers, duties and functions heretofore vested in the Urban Renewal Agency, as defined in Chapter 30A, Metropolitan Code, except the power to enter into contractual commitments, which power may only be exercised with the approval of the County Commission.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
On behalf of the Manager, to initiate conferences with representatives of any departments of the County government and with representatives of any other local, State or federal agencies concerned with the programs of the department, in order to achieve maximum coordination in the development and execution of their programs.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Perform such other functions as may be delegated from time to time by the Manager with the approval of the Board of County Commissioners, including but not limited to the functions of any housing authority which may be transferred to Miami-Dade County under the provisions of Section 1.01(a)17 or 18(b) of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-189. Housing and Urban Development Advisory Board</catch_line>
<text>
A Housing and Urban Development Advisory Board is created (hereinafter referred to as "the HUD Board"). The Director of Housing and Urban Development shall serve as Secretary to the Board.
<section prefix = "a">
Membership. The HUD Board shall consist of twenty-two (22) members, to be designated as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
The Board of County Commissioners will make thirteen (13) appointments to the HUD Board. Ten (10) of these appointees are to represent the following disciplines: Construction, property management, banking, legal and other appropriate disciplines. Three (3) additional appointees shall be residents of low income public housing projects, owned, leased or operated by Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Overall Tenant Advisory Council (OTAC) will make nine (9) appointments. Four (4) appointees shall be residents of low income public housing projects, owned, leased or operated by Miami-Dade County, Florida, and shall include at least one (1) elderly/handicapped public housing resident, one (1) Section-8 resident, and two (2) at-large residents of public housing. Five (5) additional appointees are to represent professionals or community leaders from the following disciplines: Education, social service, community based organizations, employment/training, government, legal, civic and religious organizations. One (1) of these five (5) appointees shall represent an organization or agency involved with the elderly.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Terms. Members of the HUD Board shall serve staggered terms of four (4) years each. Of the initial members, six (6) members shall serve an initial term of four (4) years, six (6) members shall serve an initial term of three (3) years, five (5) members shall serve an initial term of two (2) years and five (5) members shall serve an initial term of one (1) year as determined by the Director of the Department of Housing and Urban Development. Vacancies shall be filled by appointment to fill the unexpired terms and shall be designated by the Board responsible for making the initial appointment where the vacancy has occurred. Terms of office of members of the HUD Board, appointed by the Board of County Commissioners or OTAC, which would normally expire on or between the dates of January 1 through June 30, or July 1 through December 31 of the termination year, shall be deemed ended and expired as of March 31 or September 30 thereof respectively; and the position thereon vacated may be refilled by the County Commission or by OTAC.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Removal. Members may be removed by a majority of the HUD Board members for one (1) or more of the following reasons: (1) Three (3) consecutive unexcused absences from (a) Advisory Board (b) general and/or (c) committee meetings; (2) potential business conflict of interest; (3) consistent demonstration of incompetent or disruptive activities when carrying out Board duties.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Function. The HUD Board shall review and evaluate all major plans, programs and projects prepared by the Director of Housing and Urban Development and make recommendations for approval, disapproval or modification to the Board of County Commissioners and the Manager. The HUD Board shall advise the Director of Housing and Urban Development and make recommendations to the Manager and the Board of County Commissioners in matters relating to the management of property and materials, tenant services, budget and finance, formulation and enforcement of policies and procedures and their consistency with existing federal mandates and County administrative practices. The HUD Board shall promote public interest in and understanding of matters relating to urban renewal, housing and other urban development and redevelopment plans and consult with citizens to ascertain their duties and need for public housing, slum clearance, urban renewal and other programs designed to improve living conditions in Miami-Dade County. The HUD Board may initiate studies designed to improve the functioning of the Department of Housing and Urban Development.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-190, 2-191. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (37) ---
Editor's note— Article XXIA, §§ 2-186—2-189, is derived from §§ 1—3 of Ord. No. 67-32, adopted April 25, 1967, effective ten days after enactment. Section 9 of said ordinance authorized its inclusion in this Code, in the discretion of the editors. Section 6 of the ordinance provided that in construing the foregoing sections, the definitions provided in Section 1.01, Florida Statutes, shall apply. (Back)
Subsequently, an administrative order of Feb. 16, 1988, separated a new department from the Housing and Urban Development Department. Said administrative order provided as follows: "This administrative order creates the new Department of Special Housing Programs and supersedes all previous administrative orders concerning the functions included in this Department. The Department of Special Housing Programs shall be responsible for the administration of such Federal, State and local housing programs as: Residential and Multifamily Rehabilitation Assistance, Urban Homesteading, and Rental Rehabilitation; the Section 8 programs (Existing, Moderate Rehabilitation, Substantial and New Construction); the Housing Development Grant Program (HODAG); and the Documentary Stamp Surtax Loan programs (Lottery, Community Development Corporation, Rental Housing, and the Developer Loan Program, involving first and second mortgages)." (Back)
Subsequently, Ord. No. 88-123, § 1, adopted Dec. 20, 1988, amended Art. XXIA, §§ 2-186—2-189, relative to expanding the role and membership of the HUD Advisory Board, and Ord. No. 90-66, § 1, adopted July 10, 1990, provided that the effective date for said Ord. No. 88-123, as set out in § 5 of said ordinance, be amended to indicate that Ord. No. 88-123 shall be effective June 1, 1992. (Back)
Annotation—AO 9-1 (Back)
Cross reference— Housing, Ch. 17; urban renewal, Ch. 30A. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
