<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXI._COUNTY_FIRE_DEPARTMENT</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-181. Established; fire chief; appointment, term, compensation; organization; employees</catch_line>
<text>
A Miami-Dade County Fire and Rescue Department is hereby established. The head of this Department shall be the Fire Chief, who shall be known by the title of Miami-Dade County Fire Chief. The organization and operating procedures of the Department shall be described in administrative orders and regulations of the Manager. The Manager shall in accordance with the Code and Personnel Rules appoint such employees and other personnel as may be necessary to operate the Department. The salaries, compensation and benefits of all employees shall be fixed by the County Commission upon recommendation of the Manager.
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 96-28, § 1, adopted Feb. 6, 1996, amended § 2-181 and § 3 of said ordinance provided sunset provisions which provided that the ordinance shall stand repealed five years from its effective date. Said ordinance became effective ten days after the date of enactment.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-182. Powers and duties; authority to enter into mutual fire protection agreements</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Miami-Dade County Fire Department shall:
<section prefix = "1">
Provide fire and rescue protection in the unincorporated area of the County and other areas of the County as directed by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Maintain County fire stations and firefighting equipment.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Provide central records, investigations and communications of fire protection and require each municipality to furnish the Department with all fire records prescribed by the Miami-Dade County Fire Chief.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Perform such additional duties as may be prescribed by ordinance of the County, resolution of the Board, administrative orders and regulations of the Fire Chief, or as to non-District functions, administrative orders and regulations of the Manager.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The County Manager shall have the power to enter into agreements with one (1) or more municipalities in Miami-Dade County to provide fire protection within such municipalities by the Miami-Dade County Fire Department, such agreement to have the prior approval of the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 66-37, § 2, 9-7-66; Ord. No. 96-28, § 1, 2-6-96; Ord. No. 98-115, § 1, 7-21-98; Ord. No. 03-069, § 1, 4-8-03)</history>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 96-28, § 1, adopted Feb. 6, 1996, amended § 2-182 and § 3 of said ordinance provided sunset provisions which provided that the ordinance shall stand repealed five years from its effective date. Said ordinance became effective ten days after the date of enactment.


Annotations—AO's 4-45, 4-54.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-183—2-185. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (36) ---
Editor's note— Art. XXI, §§ 2-181—2-191, entitled "County Fire Department," is derived from Ord. No. 66-37, §§ 1, 2, enacted September 7, 1966 and effective October 1, 1966. (Back)
Annotations—AO's 7-9, 9-1 (Back)
Cross reference— Fire prevention, Ch. 14; fire and rescue services district, § 18-24 et seq.; firefighter's pension fund, § 23-30 et seq. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
