<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_V._USED_MOTOR_VEHICLE_PARTS_DEAL</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-51. License to engage in business—Required; definition</catch_line>
<text>
No person shall, except as an incident to the sale or servicing of motor vehicles or unless licensed to do so by the Miami-Dade Police Director (hereinafter called the "Director") under the article, carry on or conduct within Miami-Dade County the business of:
<section prefix = "a">
Selling used parts of or used accessories for motor vehicles;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Wrecking or dismantling motor vehicles for resale of the parts thereof; or
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Rebuilding wrecked or dismantled motor vehicles; or
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Destroying motor vehicles by any means (including, but not limited to, such operations as crushing, shredding, flattening, bailing, compacting or melting).

The words used in this article shall be deemed and construed to include, embrace and apply to secondhand or used motor vehicles, parts, etc.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-52. Same—Application; fee</catch_line>
<text>
Application for the license shall be made on a form prescribed by the Director and shall contain the name of the applicant, the address where business is to be conducted, the kind or kinds of business, enumerated in Section 21-51 to be conducted, the residence address of the applicant if an individual, the names and residence addresses of the partners of the applicant if a partnership, the names and residence addresses of the principal officers of the applicant and the state of its incorporation as a corporation, the fingerprints and photographs of all persons whose names appear in the application, satisfactory evidence that an appropriate use and occupancy permit has been obtained from the Department of Planning and Zoning, and any other information required by the Director. The application shall be verified by the applicant and shall be accompanied by a fee established by the Manager by administrative order and approved by the Board of County Commissioners. The Director shall pay over for deposit in the general funds of the County all fees received under this article.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-53. Same—Prerequisite for issuance</catch_line>
<text>
The Director shall file each application received and, when satisfied that the applicant, if an individual, or each of the partners or principal officers of the applicant, if a partnership or corporation, is of good moral character and that the applicant, so far as can be ascertained, has complied and will comply with the provisions of this article, the zoning laws, and the laws of the State relating to registration of and certificates of title to motor vehicles, shall issue to the applicant a license to conduct the kind or kinds of business specified in the application at the address herein specified until October 1st next following the date on which the license is issued. In determining good moral character, for the purposes of this section, the Director's determinations shall be subject to the following provisions:
<section prefix = "a">
Prior arrests of the applicant may not be considered unless they resulted in conviction; provided, however, allegations which are the basis for any pending criminal charges may be considered if the charges are pending when the application is considered.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
If the applicant has had his or her civil rights restored, the Director shall only consider acts or omissions on the part of the applicant subsequent to the restoration of civil rights.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
In the case of subsequent applications of the same applicant, the Director shall only consider acts or omissions on the part of the applicant which have occurred subsequent to the date of the issuance of prior permits to the applicant.

This license shall be considered by the Tax Collector to be a prerequisite to the issuance of any occupational license to conduct the business.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-54. Same—Suspension and revocation</catch_line>
<text>
The Director may suspend or revoke a license, upon notice and reasonable opportunity to be heard, if it is found that:
<section prefix = "a">
The license was fraudulently procured or erroneously issued;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The licensee, or any partner or principal officer of the licensee, if a partnership or a corporation, has failed to comply with the provisions of this article or the laws of the State relating to registration of and certificates of title to motor vehicles; or
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The licensee, or any partner or principal officer of the licensee, if a partnership or a corporation, has been convicted of a felony or misdemeanor, involving any transaction in connection with a motor vehicle or any part or parts thereof.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-55. Same—Appeals from denied, suspended or revoked license</catch_line>
<text>
Any person who is denied a license or whose license is suspended or revoked by the Director may appeal to the County Commission by filing a written petition for review setting forth the reasons why the license should have been granted or should not have been suspended or revoked, as the case may be, but the Commission shall have no jurisdiction to entertain any such appeal unless the petition for review is filed with the Clerk of the Commission within thirty (30) days after the date of the Director's action. If the Commission hears testimony regarding the denial, suspension, or revocation of the license, all witnesses shall be sworn and the laws of evidence applicable to quasi-judicial proceedings shall govern.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-56. Records to be maintained</catch_line>
<text>
Every licensee shall maintain in its possession for the period of three (3) years, in such form as shall be prescribed by the Director, an accurate and complete record of:
<section prefix = "a">
Each motor vehicle, and every part, accessory, body, chassis or engine purchased or acquired unattached from a motor vehicle which can be identified by serial number, including, but not limited to, such accessories as radios, heaters, air conditioners, wheels, mirrors and hubcaps. Such record shall set forth the description, identifying or serial number, date of acquisition, name and address of person from whom acquired.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Every motor vehicle dismantled, wrecked or destroyed by the licensee, and the description, date of its dismantling, wrecking or destruction and the documentation required by Section 21-57 of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Every licensee, upon purchase or acquisition of any motor vehicle or part(s) thereof, shall require the seller to produce written identification, such as his driver's license, and shall make and maintain a record of the identification of the seller and the particular items acquired. All such records shall be open and available to inspection during reasonable business hours by any representative of the Director or any peace officer of the State, any County or municipality.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-57. Title certificate or documentation required prior to dismantling, wrecking, or destroying motor vehicles</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful for any person, firm, corporation or other legal entity to dismantle, wreck or destroy any motor vehicle without having in its possession a valid, properly endorsed and notarized title certificate to such motor vehicle. Any person undertaking to dismantle, wreck or destroy any motor vehicle shall, upon demand of any peace officer or law enforcement officer, produce for inspection an appropriate lawful title certificate, or other documentation to such motor vehicle required by this section. The foregoing notwithstanding:
<section prefix = "a">
It shall not be unlawful for any person, firm, corporation or other legal entity to dismantle, wreck, or destroy any motor vehicle five (5) model years old or less for which an insurance company, prior to January 1, 1990, has paid money as compensation for a total loss provided that such person has in its possession prior to such dismantling, wrecking or destruction a copy of the notarized bill of sale for such motor vehicle from the registered owner to the insurance company together with a copy of the completed report of total loss settlement therefor filed by the insurance company with the Florida Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles that has been certified by such Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
It shall not be unlawful for any person, firm, corporation or other legal entity to dismantle, wreck or destroy any motor vehicle which, on or after January 1, 1990, becomes salvage provided such person has in its possession prior to such dismantling, wrecking or destruction a valid, properly endorsed salvage certificate of title issued by the Florida Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles for such vehicle.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
It shall not be unlawful for any person, firm, corporation or other legal entity to dismantle, wreck or destroy any motor vehicle for which an insurance company, on or after January 1, 1990, has paid money as compensation for a total loss provided that such person has in its possession prior to such dismantling, wrecking, or destruction a valid, properly endorsed salvage certificate of title issued by the Florida Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles for such vehicle.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
It shall not be unlawful for any person, firm, corporation or other legal entity to dismantle, wreck or destroy any motor vehicle which a governmental body had determined to be abandoned property, as that term is defined in Chapter 705, Florida Statutes, or in Section 33-15.1 of the County Code, as these may be amended from time to time, without having therefor a valid, properly endorsed and notarized title certificate. The person, firm, corporation or other entity which dismantles, wrecks or destroys a motor vehicle pursuant to instructions from the government body which previously exercised control over the vehicle as abandoned property, shall have in its possession official documentation from the governmental body ordering the dismantling; wrecking or destruction. The official documentation from the governmental body under this subsection shall contain, at a minimum, the location where the motor vehicle was seized, a description of the motor vehicle by make, model, and year, the VIN number, where available, the name of the government enforcement officer who directed removal of the vehicle, and identification of the contract between the government and the legal entity charged with either the removal or the dismantling, wreckage or destruction of the motor vehicle. The person, firm, corporation or other legal entity who dismantles, wrecks or destroys a motor vehicle pursuant to governmental authority over abandoned property, shall after such dismantling, wreckage or destruction, return to the appropriate governmental body a copy of the documentation described herein, with the date and location that such dismantling, wreckage or destruction took place.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
It shall be unlawful for any person licensed to do business pursuant to this article to possess any vehicle or vehicle part or accessory owned by Miami-Dade County or any municipality within Miami-Dade County without proper documentation therefor as required by this article. Any person convicted of a violation of this provision shall be subject to a fine not to exceed one thousand dollars ($1,000.00) or imprisonment in the county jail for a term not to exceed one (1) year, or by both fine and imprisonment.

For purposes of subsections (a), (b) and (c) of this section the terms "salvage" and "total loss" shall be defined as provided in Section 319.30 Florida Statutes (1988), as the same may be amended from time to time.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-58. Failure to submit reports or permit inspection</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful for any licensee to fail, refuse or neglect to submit any report in the form and manner required by this article or to fail, refuse or neglect to keep records in the form and manner required by this article, or to fail, refuse or neglect to permit inspection of records required hereunder, or of the vehicle or parts to which the records pertain, by any officer or other duly authorized person.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-59. Penalty</catch_line>
<text>
Any person convicted of a violation of any of the provisions of this article shall be punished as provided in Section 1-5 of this Code.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 21-60—21-63. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (3) ---
Editor's note— This article is derived from Ord. No. 59-37, §§ 1—10, adopted September 15, 1959. Ord. No. 60-1 adopted January 5, 1960, declared Ord. No. 59-37 to be amendatory to this Code. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
