<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_V._STORMWATER_UTILITY*</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-51. Short title</catch_line>
<text>
This article shall be known as the Miami-Dade County Stormwater Utility Ordinance.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-51.1. Legislative intent; construction</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
The purpose of this article is to implement the provisions of Section 403.0893(1), Florida Statutes, by creating a Countywide stormwater utility and adopting stormwater utility fees sufficient to plan, construct, operate and maintain stormwater management systems set forth in the local program required pursuant to Section 403.0891(3), Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
This article shall be liberally construed to protect the public health, safety, and welfare and to effectuate the purposes set forth herein.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-51.2. Applicability</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
The provisions of this article shall be effective in both the unincorporated and incorporated areas of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Notwithstanding the provisions of Section 24-51.2(1) above, the provisions of this article shall not apply within any municipality which files with both the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners and the Director certified copies of a resolution of the governing body of such municipality which notifies the Board of County Commissioners and the Director that the municipality exercises thereby its option to exempt that the municipality exercises thereby its option to exempt the municipality from the provisions of this article, provided, however, (1) such certified copies are filed as set forth above no later than ninety (90) days from the date of enactment of this article and (2) the municipality commits in said resolution to implement within said municipality the provisions of Section 403.0893(1), (2), or (3), Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time, no later than two (2) years from the effective date of this article. Failure to file such certified copies or to implement Section 403.0893(1), (2) or (3), Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time, within the aforesaid respective time periods shall render the municipality's exemption from the provisions of this article null and void. Notwithstanding the foregoing, any municipality, at any time after the effective date of this article, may request, by resolution, that the Board of County Commissioners render the municipality's exemption from the provisions of this article null and void or grant the municipality an exemption from the provisions of this article subject to conditions determined by the Board of County Commissioners. Upon receipt of such a resolution of a municipality the Board of County Commissioners may, by resolution, render the municipality's exemption from the provisions of this article null and void or grant the municipality an exemption from the provisions of this article subject to conditions determined by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-51.3. Creation of Miami-Dade County Stormwater Utility; governing body; organization</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
There is hereby created and established by the authority of Section 403.0893(1), Florida Statutes, and the Home Rule Charter of Miami-Dade County, Florida, a Countywide stormwater utility implementing the provisions of Section 403.0893(1), Florida Statutes, which shall be named and known as the "Miami-Dade County Stormwater Utility" (hereinafter also referred to as the "Utility"). The Utility shall be a public body corporate and politic which, through its governing body, the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida, may exercise all those powers specifically granted herein, those powers granted by law and those powers necessary in the exercise of those powers herein enumerated.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The governing body of the Utility shall be the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Utility, acting through its governing body, shall be responsible for the operation, maintenance, and governance of a Countywide stormwater utility to plan, construct, operate and maintain stormwater management systems set forth in the local program required pursuant to Section 403.0891(3), Florida Statutes. The governing body may create by ordinance one (1) or more districts and subdistricts within the service area of the Utility.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The County Manager shall be the Director of the Utility.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The organization and operating procedures of the Utility shall be prescribed by administrative orders and regulations of the County Manager. The County Manager shall appoint such employees as may be necessary to operate the Utility. The salaries and compensation of all personnel of the Utility shall be determined by the Board of County Commissioners upon the recommendation of the County Manager.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-51.4. Fees</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
The Miami-Dade County Stormwater Utility is hereby authorized and directed to establish, assess, and collect stormwater utility fees upon all residential developed property and all nonresidential developed property in Miami-Dade County, Florida, sufficient to plan, construct, operate, and maintain stormwater management systems set forth in the local program required pursuant to Section 403.0891(3), Florida Statutes. Such fees shall be in an amount set forth in administrative orders of the County Manager after approval by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Each residential developed property shall be assessed a stormwater utility fee calculated by multiplying the rate for one (1) ERU by the number of the dwelling units on the parcel.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Each nonresidential developed property shall be assessed a stormwater utility fee calculated by multiplying the rate for one (1) ERU by a factor derived by dividing the actual impervious area of the particular nonresidential developed property by the statistically estimated average horizontal impervious area of residential developed property per dwelling unit, to wit, the square footage base equivalent established for one (1) ERU. Notwithstanding the foregoing, each nonresidential developed property classified by the Miami-Dade County Property Appraiser as land use type 71 shall be assessed a stormwater utility fee which is fifty (50) percent of the fee for nonresidential developed property calculated as described in the preceding sentence.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The fees payable hereunder shall be deposited in a separate County fund and shall be used exclusively by the Miami-Dade County Stormwater Utility to pay for the costs of planning, constructing, operating and maintaining stormwater management systems set forth in the local program required pursuant to Section 403.0891(3), Florida Statutes. No part of said fund shall be used for purposes other than the aforesaid.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-51.5. Billing; liens</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Fees shall be billed to the owner, tenant, or occupant of each developed property in accordance with the administrative orders of the County Manager. If the fees are not fully paid by said owner, tenant or occupant on or before the past due date set forth on the bill, a ten (10) percent late charge may be added to the bill and imposed by the Utility in accordance with regulations prescribed by the County Manager. Any unpaid balance for such fees and late charges shall be subject to an interest charge at the rate of eight (8) percent per annum. Imposition of said interest charge shall commence sixty (60) days after the past due date of the fees set forth on the bill.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Fees and late charges, together with any interest charges, shall be debts due and owing the Utility and all of same shall be recoverable by the County or its assignee, on behalf of the Utility, in any court of competent jurisdiction.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Utility shall establish procedures to notify owners, tenants, occupants, and managers of developed property of delinquent fee accounts. Subscribers to this service shall pay in advance a fee in an amount set forth in the administrative orders of the County Manager.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
All fees, late charges, and interest accruing thereupon, due and owning to the Utility which remain unpaid sixty (60) days after the past due date of the fees shall become a lien against and upon the developed property for which the fees are due and owing to the same extent and character as a lien for a special assessment. Until fully paid and discharged, said fees, late charges, and interest accrued thereupon shall be, remain, and constitute a special assessment lien equal in rank and dignity with the liens of County ad valorem taxes and superior in rank and dignity to all other liens, encumbrances, titles, and claims in, to or against the developed property involved for the period of five (5) years from the date said fees, late charges, and interest accrued thereupon, become a lien as set forth in this article. Said lien may be enforced and satisfied by the County, on behalf of the Utility, pursuant to Chapter 173, Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time, or by any other method permitted by law. The lien provided for herein shall not be deemed to be in lieu of any other legal remedies for recovery of said fee, late charges, and accrued interest available in the County and to the Utility.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
For fees which become more than sixty (60) days past due and unpaid, the County or the Utility shall cause to be filed in the Office of the Clerk of the Circuit Court of Miami-Dade County, Florida, a notice of lien or statement showing a legal description of the property against which the lien is claimed, its location by street and number, the name of the owner, and an accurate statement of the fees and late charges then unpaid. A copy of such notice of lien shall be mailed within a reasonable time to the owner of the property involved as shown by the records of the Tax Collector of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Liens may be discharged and satisfied by payment to the County, on behalf of the Utility, of the aggregate amounts specified in the notice of lien, together with interest accrued thereon, and all filing and recording fees. When any such lien has been fully paid or discharged, the County shall cause evidence of the satisfaction and discharge of such lien to be filed with the Office of the Clerk of the Circuit Court of Miami-Dade County, Florida. Any person, firm, corporation, or other legal entity, other than the present owner of the property involved, who fully pays any such lien shall be entitled to receive an assignment of lien and shall be subrogated to the rights of the County and the Utility with respect to the enforcement of such lien.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Notwithstanding other provisions to the contrary herein, the County, on behalf of the Utility, shall have the discretion not to file notices of lien for fees, late charges, and interest accrued thereupon in an amount less than fifty dollars ($50.00). If the County or the Utility elects not to file a notice of lien, said fees, late charges, and accrued interest shall remain as debts due and owing in accordance with (2) above.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
The Utility is authorized and directed to execute and deliver upon request written certificates certifying the amount of fees, late charges and interest accrued thereupon, which are due and owing to the Utility and the County, for any developed property which is subject to payment of said fees, or the Utility may certify that no fees, late charges or accrued interest are due and owing. Said certificates shall be binding upon the County and the Utility.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history>
</law>
