<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">Chapter 29 TAXATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="2">ARTICLE_XV._DISCRETIONARY_SALES_SURTAX_A</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 29.115. Sales surtax levied</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby levied and imposed a one (1) percent discretionary sales surtax authorized by Section 212.055(1), Florida Statutes (1999) on all transactions occurring in Miami-Dade County which transactions are subject to the state tax imposed on sales, use, rentals, admissions and other transactions by Chapter 212, Florida Statutes (1999)
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29.116. Surtax rate, limitations</catch_line>
<text>
The surtax rate shall be one (1) percent on the amount of taxable sales and taxable purchases representing such transactions. The limitations, conditions and provisions contained in Section 212.054, Florida Statutes (1999) as the same may be amended and supplemented from time to time are hereby incorporated herein.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-117. Exemption from Sales Surtax</catch_line>
<text>
All exemptions applicable to the discretionary sales surtax contained in Chapter 212, Florida Statutes are hereby incorporated herein as the same may be amended and supplemented from time to time including, but not limited to, the following:
<section prefix = "1">
The tax on any sales amount above five thousand dollars ($5,000.00) on any item of tangible personal property and on long-distance telephone service shall not be subject to the sales surtax. For purposes of administering the five thousand dollar ($5,000.00) limitation of an item of tangible personal property, if two (2) or more taxable items of tangible personal property are sold to the same purchaser at the same time and, under generally accepted business practice or industry standards or usage, are normally sold in bulk or are items that, when assembled, comprise a working unit or part of a working unit, such items must be considered a single item for purposes of the five thousand dollar ($5,000.00) limitation when supported by a charge ticket, sale slip, invoice, or other tangible evidence of a single sale or rental. The limitation provided in this subsection does not apply to the sale of any other service.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The sale at retail, the rental, the use, the consumption; the distribution, and the storage to be used or consumed in this state of the following are hereby specifically exempt from the sales surtax imposed by this article.
<section prefix = "1">
Exemptions; General groceries.
<section prefix = "a">
There are exempt from the sales surtax imposed by this article food and drinks for human consumption except candy. Unless the exemption provided by Chapter 212, Florida Statutes, for school lunches, for meals to certain patients or inmates, for meals provided by certain nonprofit organizations, or for food or drinks sold through vending machines pertains, none of such items of food or drinks means:
<section prefix = "1">
Food or drinks services, prepared, or sold in or by restaurants; drugstores; lunch counters; cafeterias; hotels; amusement parks; racetracks; taverns; concession stands at arenas, auditoriums, carnivals, fairs, stadiums, theaters, or other like places of business; or by any business or place required by law to be licensed by the Division of Hotels and Restaurants of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation, except bakery products sold in or by pastry shops, doughnut shops, or like establishments for consumption off the premises;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Foods and drinks sold ready for immediate consumption from vending machines, pushcarts, motor vehicles, or any other form of vehicle;
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Soft drinks, which include, but are not limited to, any nonalcoholic beverage, any preparation or beverage commonly referred to as a "soft drink," or any noncarbonated drink made from milk derivatives or tea, when sold in cans or similar containers. The term "soft drink" does not include: natural fruit or vegetable juices or their concentrates or reconstituted natural concentrated fruit or vegetable juices, whether frozen or unfrozen, dehydrated, powdered, granulated, sweetened or unsweetened, seasoned with salt or spice, or unseasoned; coffee or coffee substitutes; tea except when sold in containers as provided herein; cocoa; products intended to be mixed with milk; or natural fluid milk;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Foods or drinks cooked or prepared on the seller's premises and sold ready for immediate consumption either on or off the premises, excluding bakery products for off-premises consumption unless such foods are taxed under Subsection 1 or Subsection 2; or
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Sandwiches sold ready for immediate consumption.
For the purposes of this section, "Seller's premises" shall be construed broadly, and means, but is not limited to, the lobby, aisle, or auditorium of a theater, the seating, aisle, or parking area of an arena, rink, or stadium; or the parking area of a drive-in or outdoor theater. The premises of a caterer with respect to catered meals or beverages shall be the place where such meals or beverages are served.
<section prefix = "b">
<section prefix = "1">
Food or drinks not exempt under Section (a) shall be exempt, notwithstanding that Section, when purchased with food coupons or Special Supplemental Food Program for Women, Infants, and Children vouchers issued under authority of federal law.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
This section is effective only while federal law prohibits a state's participation in the federal food coupon program of Special Supplemental Food Program for Women, Infants, and Children if there is an official determination that state or local sales taxes are collected within that state on purchases of food or drinks with such coupons.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
This section shall not apply to any food or drinks on which federal law shall permit sales taxes without penalty, such as termination of the state's participation.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Department of Revenue shall make refunds or allow credits to a distributor equal to the fee imposed and paid under Section 403.7197 on containers purchased by consumers with food coupons or Special Supplemental Food Program for Women, Infants, and Children vouchers issued under authority of federal law.
<section prefix = "2">
Exemptions; Medical.
<section prefix = "a">
There shall be exempt from the sales surtax imposed by this article any product, supply, or medicine dispensed in a retail establishment by a pharmacist licensed by the state, according to an individual prescription or prescriptions written by a prescriber authorized by law to prescribe medicinal drugs; hypodermic needles; hypodermic syringes; chemical compounds and test kits used for the diagnosis or treatment of human disease, illness, or injury; and common household remedies recommended and generally sold for internal and external use in the cure, mitigation, treatment, or prevention of illness or disease in human beings, but not including cosmetics or toilet articles, notwithstanding the presence of medicinal ingredients therein, according to a list prescribed and approved by the Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services, which list shall be certified to the Department of Revenue from time to time and included in the rules promulgated by the Department of Revenue. There shall also be exempt from the sales surtax imposed by this article artificial eyes and limbs; orthopedic shoes; prescription eyeglasses and items incidental thereto or which become a part thereof; dentures; hearing aids; crutches; prosthetic and orthopedic appliances; and funerals. In addition, any items intended for one-time use which transfer essential optical characteristics to contact lenses shall be exempt from the sales surtax imposed by this article, however, this exemption shall apply only after one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000) of the sales surtax imposed by this article on such items has been paid in any calendar year by a taxpayer who claims the exemption in such year. Funeral directors shall pay tax on all tangible personal property used by them in their business.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
For the purposes of this subsection:
<section prefix = "1">
Prosthetic and orthopedic appliances means any apparatus, instrument, device, or equipment used to replace or substitute for any missing part of the body, to alleviate the malfunction of any part of the body, or to assist any disabled person in leading a normal life by facilitating such person's mobility. Such apparatus, instrument, device, or equipment shall be exempted according to an individual prescription or prescriptions written by a physician licensed under chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 460, chapter 461, or chapter 466, Florida Statutes, or according to a list prescribed and approved by the Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services, which list shall be certified to the Department of Revenue from time to time and included in the rules promulgated by the Department of Revenue.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Cosmetics means articles intended to be rubbed, poured, sprinkled, or sprayed on, introduced into, or otherwise applied to the human body for cleaning, beautifying, promoting attractiveness, or altering the appearance and also means articles intended for use as a compound of any such articles, including, but not limited to, cold creams, suntan lotions, makeup, and body lotions.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Toilet articles means any article advertised or held out for sale for grooming purposes and those articles that are customarily used for grooming purposes, regardless of the name by which they may be known, including, but not limited to, soap, toothpaste, hair spray, shaving products, colognes, perfumes, shampoo, deodorant, and mouthwash.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Chlorine shall not be exempt from the tax imposed by this article when used for the treatment of water in swimming pools.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
This subsection shall be strictly construed and enforced.

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-118. Trust fund created; uses of surtax proceeds and other moneys</catch_line>
<text>
Miami-Dade County shall be the depository of the surtax proceeds collected by the State and distributed to Miami-Dade County hereunder. The Board of County Commissioners shall deposit the proceeds from the surtax, the proceeds from MDTA revenues and the proceeds from the three (3) cents capital improvements local option gas tax dedicated to transit purposes in a special trust fund ("Fund A") set aside from other County funds in the custody of the Finance Director of the County. The Board of County Commissioners shall deposit the proceeds from the annual budgeted amount from the general fund for MDTA referred to in Section 5 of the ordinance from which this section derives in a special trust fund ("Fund B") set aside from other County funds in the custody of the Finance Director. Interest earnings on the investment of the moneys on deposit in Fund A and Fund B shall be credited thereto as the Finance Director shall deem appropriate. Exhibit 1 attached to the ordinance from which this section derives sets forth the Revenues consisting of Sales Tax, General Fund Subsidy/LOGT and MDTA Revenues and a component of Interest attributable to the investment of such Revenues and forecasts the breakdown of the sources of revenues which make up Revenues. Moneys in Fund A shall be expended solely for transportation purposes as provided in Subsections (a), (c) and (d) of this Section 29-118. Moneys in Fund B shall be expended solely for the purposes set forth in Subsections (b), (c) and (e) of this Section 29-118; provided, however, that if at any time during a fiscal year the Board of County Commissioners determines that the moneys on deposit in Fund A is not or will not be sufficient to meet the expenditure requirements of Fund A for such fiscal year, the Board may direct the Finance Director to transfer all or any portion of the moneys on deposit in Fund B to the credit of Fund A to make up such insufficiency. At the end of each County fiscal year commencing with the fiscal year ending September 30, 2000 all or any portion of the unencumbered balance in Fund B remaining after meeting the expenditure requirements for such fiscal year on account of Subsections (b), (c) and (e) of this Section 29-118 either shall remain in Fund B or shall be transferred by the Finance Director to the credit of Fund A or to the credit of the general fund at the direction of the Board of County Commissioners. The Finance Director for the purposes of this article shall establish five special accounts designated, respectively, the "MDX Account," the "Stakeholders Account," the "Municipalities Account," the "County Transportation Account," and the "County "Non-Transportation Account."
<section prefix = "a">
The Finance Director shall transfer from Fund A to the MDX Account moneys on deposit in Fund A at such times and in such amounts as shall be established by a cooperation agreement for transportation (the "Agreement") to be entered into between Miami-Dade County and the Miami-Dade County Expressway Authority ("MDX"). For the purpose of enabling the Finance Director to quantify the amounts to be deposited to the MDX Account the County and MDX shall furnish to the Finance Director on or before January 1 in the fiscal year ending September 30, 2000 and on or before October 1 in each fiscal year thereafter a written schedule of required deposits applicable to such year and the times when amounts on deposit in the MDX Account shall be transferred to or upon the direction of MDX and shall furnish written amendments during the course of any year as required.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Finance Director shall transfer from Fund B to the Stakeholders Account from moneys on deposit in Fund B in each year the respective amounts for the respective purposes set forth in Exhibit 2 to the ordinance from which this section derives under the headings "County-Wide Cultural Improvements" to the account of the Miami-Dade Department of Cultural Affairs or its successor and "A More Competitive Tourism Message" to the account of the Greater Miami Convention and Visitors Bureau or its successor and under the subheading "Scholarships to Local Colleges/Universities" under the heading "Champion Our Children Fund" to the account or accounts of the respective entities which will confer such scholarships and under the subheading "Arts in Education" under the heading "Champion Our Children Fund" to the account of the Miami-Dade Department of Cultural Affairs or its successor.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Finance Director shall transfer from Fund B to the Municipalities Account the aggregate of the sums listed in the column entitled "3-YR SUM" in Exhibit 2 attached to the ordinance from which this section derives under the heading "Municipal Revenue Enhancements" which sums will be disbursed as soon as practicable to the municipalities listed in such heading. The municipalities may use the 3-YR SUM for any municipal purpose. The Finance Director further shall transfer from Fund A to the Municipalities Account annually the aggregate of the sums listed in the column entitled "YEARLY" in Exhibit 2 attached to the ordinance from which this section derives which sums will be disbursed at such times as the Finance Director shall determine. The aggregate of the YEARLY sums shall be adjusted annually by the percentage change in collection of the County local option fuel tax imposed pursuant to Section 336.025, Florida Statutes (1997) for the most recent 12-month period ending September 30. The municipalities shall use such YEARLY moneys only for transportation expenditures needed to meet the requirements of the capital improvement element of an adopted comprehensive plan as provided in Section 336.025(1)(b)3, Florida Statutes (1997).
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The Finance Director shall transfer from Fund A to the County Transportation Account in each year the respective annual amounts (where noted) for the respective purposes set forth in the annual MDTA budget for maintenance and operation and in Exhibit 2 to the ordinance from which this section derives under the headings "Transit Fare Reductions," "Bus Service," "Rail Transit Expansion," "2020 Transportation Plan Restoration," "Transit System Improvements" and "County Roadway, Traffic and Pedestrian Mobility Enhancements," except the purposes listed therein under the subheading "Community Enhancements" shall be funded from moneys in the County Non-Transportation Account. The Finance Director shall disburse the amounts on deposit in the County Transportation Account at such times as the Finance Director shall determine or as required to meet acquisition, construction or payment schedules or as required to meet funding requirements established in documents securing indebtedness payable in whole or in part from moneys in Fund A. The moneys in the County Transportation Account shall be used for the purposes described under the foregoing headings subject to any amendments made in accordance with the MPO process.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The Finance Director shall transfer from Fund B to the County Non-Transportation Account in each year the respective annual amounts (where noted) for the respective purposes set forth in Exhibit 2 to the ordinance from which this section derives under the headings "Champion Our Children Trust Fund," (excluding the subheadings "Scholarships to Local Colleges/Universities" and "Arts in Education" which are provided for under Subsection (b) of this Section 29-118) "Economic Development and Job Creation," "Major Capital Infrastructure Improvements," "Property Tax and Budget Relief" and "Beach Renourishment and Maintenance" and under the subheading "Community Enhancements" under the heading "County Roadway, Traffic and Pedestrian Mobility Enhancements." The Finance Director shall disburse the amounts on deposit in the County Non-Transportation Account at such times as the Finance Director shall determine or as required to meet acquisition, construction or payment schedules or as required to meet funding requirements established in documents securing indebtedness payable in whole or in part from moneys in Fund B. In determining the annual amounts payable under the heading "Property Tax and Budget Relief" pursuant to the Save Our Seniors Program, the Finance Director may rely on a schedule prepared annually by the County Tax Collector of the rebates owed to the respective local governments and to the County for lost revenues resulting from the Save Our Seniors Program.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
In the event that moneys in Fund B are pledged to secure indebtedness incurred by the County to finance capital improvements contemplated by Subsection (e) of this Section 29-118 the documents authorizing and securing such indebtedness shall limit the pledge of moneys in Fund B to those portions of such moneys derived from non ad valorem tax revenues.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
In the event that moneys on deposit in Fund A are insufficient in any year to meet the deposit requirements of the MDX Account or the YEARLY component of the Municipalities Account, the Finance Director is hereby authorized and directed to transfer available and unencumbered moneys on deposit in the County Transportation Account, as required to make up such deficiency.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
In the event that the Finance Director shall receive an opinion of the County Attorney that all or any part of the proceeds from the annual MDTA general fund subsidy or the proceeds from MDTA revenues are legally dedicated solely to transit system purposes, the Finance Director shall restrict said subsidy and revenues to transit system purposes to the extent required by such opinion of the County Attorney.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Exhibit 3 attached to the ordinance from which this section derives is included to indicate the capital improvements and the service, economic, cultural and revenue enhancements described in Exhibit 2 thereto which will benefit the respective Commission Districts and Municipalities.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-119. Abolition of tolls on existing County expressway system</catch_line>
<text>
As authorized by Section 348.0004, Florida Statutes (1999) the existing tolls and currently approved increases to such existing tolls on the existing County expressway system transferred to the Miami-Dade County Expressway Authority by the State of Florida in 1996 are hereby abolished and a portion of the surtax proceeds shall be the local source of funding to the County expressway system to replace toll revenues necessary to meet bond obligations of the Miami-Dade County Expressway Authority secured by such tolls and increases, all pursuant to Section 348.0004, Florida Statutes (1999) and as provided in the Agreement to be entered into as aforesaid.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-120. Value analysis</catch_line>
<text>
Value analysis, as provided in items (a) through (g) of Subsection (11) of Section 2-10.4 of the Code, shall be incorporated into the establishment of proposed transit routes, their feasibility, and all capital improvements made pursuant to this article.
</text>
</law>
