<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_CXL._MILITARY_AFFAIRS_BOARD</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2101. Creation of Military Affairs Board</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created and established pursuant to the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, as amended, the Miami-Dade County Military Affairs Board (hereinafter the "Board").
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2102. Powers and Duties of Board</catch_line>
<text>
The Board shall have the following powers and duties:
<section prefix = "a">
Provide the Board of County Commissioners with recommendations regarding military affairs in Miami-Dade County involving the Marine Corps, Army, Navy, Air Force, National Guard and Coast Guard (collectively "Armed Forces") and active, reserve, retired, disabled and deceased military personnel in Miami-Dade County (collectively "military personnel"); and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Promote measures to enhance the quality of life for active, reserve, retired and disabled military personnel and their families, and families of deceased military personnel in Miami-Dade County; and
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Advocate on behalf of military personnel in Miami-Dade County regarding, among other matters: health care; housing; housing and business loans; pension benefits; education; employment; incarceration; reintegration; unemployment benefits; disability claims; vocational training; and insurance; and
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Administer the medal of valor program created by Ordinance No. 10-29; and
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Take steps to increase awareness and support for our military personnel from Miami-Dade County who are serving in the Armed Forces around the world; and
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Interface with local Reserve Officer Training Corps ("ROTC") programs at both the high school and collegiate levels; and
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Solicit input from and maintain a strong relationship with the United States Department of Defense, Department of Homeland Security, Department of Veterans Affairs, the Red Cross and any other entity which interacts with the Armed Forces regarding military affairs or military personnel regarding, among other things, military affairs impacting Miami-Dade County, military personnel in Miami-Dade County and ROTC; and
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Coordinate Miami-Dade County's activities regarding Veteran's Day, Memorial Day and the 4th of July; and
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Promote, attract and solicit military activities in Miami-Dade County from throughout the United States and within Miami-Dade County to the greatest extent feasible and strive to generate and further community support for the United States Armed Forces in the United States and abroad; and
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Adopt an official seal; and
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
To submit annually to the Board of County Commissioners a report summarizing and evaluating all programs and activities undertaken by the Board during the previous fiscal year; and
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, accept and solicit gifts of money or services for the public purposes provided for in this article; and
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
Cooperate with any federal, state, county, or municipal government, agency or instrumentality; and
</section>
<section prefix = "n">
Create a standing committee relating to the Base Realignment and Closure process ("BRAC") charged with the following responsibilities and duties:
<section prefix = "1">
Working with other entities, such as federal and state agencies, to represent Miami-Dade County's interests by ensuring that local military bases remain open as part of the next BRAC round potentially scheduled for 2015; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Maximizing any opportunities for Miami-Dade County that may be realized from any potential realignment; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Minimizing any negative impacts to local communities; and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Developing a comprehensive plan, approved by the Military Affairs Board, to be recommended to the Board of County Commissioners after evaluating infrastructure needs, land use needs, 21st century mission of the armed forces, and community support; and
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Working with military bases in South Florida in order to put together a vision for the future and a relevance plan; and
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Providing advice and recommendations, approved by the Military Affairs Board, to the Board of County Commissioners regarding any actions it may take to further Miami-Dade County's interests with relation to any future BRAC round.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "o">
Expend funds for the purposes provided in this article. The Military Affairs Board shall only be authorized to expend funds deposited in the Military Affairs Trust Fund. The Mayor or his or her designee shall, on a monthly basis, provide the Military Affairs Board with an accounting of available funds. All expenditures of the Military Affairs Board shall be subject to a county audit.
</section>
<section prefix = "p">
To solicit and approve grant agreements for the public purposes provided for in this article. All funds received pursuant to a grant agreement shall be deposited in the Military Affairs Trust Fund. The Military Affairs Board shall only approve a grant agreement distributing funds to a third-party to the extent that funds are currently available in the Military Affairs Trust Fund.
</section>
<section prefix = "q">
To solicit and approve contracts for the public purposes provided for in this article, and only to the extent that funds are currently available in the Military Affairs Trust Fund. It is the intent of the County Commission that the Military Affairs Board be given the authority to enter into county contracts with the assistance of county staff subject to the limitations of this article. The contracting policies and procedures to be followed by the Military Affairs Board to give effect to this intent shall be set forth in an implementing order approved by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2103. Governing Board</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Composition and appointment. The Military Affairs Board shall consist of twenty-four (24) voting members appointed as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
Each member of the Board of County Commissioners shall designate one (1) member who shall be approved by the County Commission; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Chairperson of the County Commission shall appoint one (1) member of the County Commission who shall be the Military Liaison of the County Commission; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Mayor of Miami-Dade County shall appoint one (1) member of the Board; and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The command staff of Southern Command shall appoint one (1) member; and
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The command staff at the United States Air Force Base in Homestead shall appoint one (1) member; and
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
The command staff at the United States Coast Guard District 7 shall appoint one (1) member; and
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
The command staff at the United States Army National Guard Reserve Station located in Miami shall appoint one (1) member; and
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
The command staff of the United States Navy and Marine Corps Reserves located in Hialeah shall appoint two (2) members: one (1) member representing the United States Navy; and one (1) member representing the United States Marine Corps; and
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
The Miami-Dade Defense Alliance shall appoint one (1) member; and
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
The Greater Miami Chamber of Commerce shall appoint one (1) member; and
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
The Red Cross shall appoint one (1) member.
The Military Affairs Board shall also consist of the following non-voting members:
<section prefix = "1">
The Director of the Miami Veteran's Administration Healthcare System shall appoint one (1) member; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Each Congressperson whose district includes a portion of Miami-Dade County shall appoint one (1) member; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Each United States Senator representing the State of Florida shall appoint one (1) member; and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The United States Attorney from the Southern District of Florida shall appoint one (1) member; and
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The State Attorney for Miami-Dade County shall appoint one (1) member.

When making a selection, each person or entity shall consider that the voting members should reflect the gender, racial ethnic or cultural make-up of the community.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Qualifications. Each member of the Commission shall (i) be a United States citizen, a duly qualified elector of Miami-Dade County and (ii) shall comply with the requirements of Section 2-11.38 of the Code of Miami-Dade County. Additionally, each member shall be a person who has previously served or is currently serving in the Armed Forces, or has an interest in military affairs. Before taking any official action, each voting member shall take the prescribed oath of office.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Term. Members of the Board shall serve terms of three (3) years each.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Vacancies. Each person or entity shall appoint a new representative within one month when its appointee resigns or is removed.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Applicability of Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance. The Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance (the "Conflict of Interest Ordinance"), Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall be applicable to the members of the Board. It is declared to be the intent of the Commission, as expressed in this subsection, to provide that the Conflict of Interest Ordinance shall not operate to preclude individuals from serving as Board members on the basis of interests relating to Miami-Dade County when such interests do not conflict with the Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Organization and Procedure. The Chairperson of the Board shall be the Military Liaison of the County Commission selected by the Chairperson of the County Commission. The Board shall elect one (1) of its members as vice-chairperson and such other officers as the Board may determine to be necessary. The Board shall create by-laws and shall hold regular meetings in accordance with those by-laws. The Board may hold such other meetings as it deems necessary. A majority of the members of the Board shall constitute a quorum. All meetings of the Board shall be public and the Board shall maintain written minutes of all proceedings that shall be promptly prepared and recorded. Copies of all minutes and resolutions of the Board shall be forwarded to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners no later than thirty (30) days subsequent to any meeting of the Board.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 12-37, ยง 1, 5-15-12; Ord. No. 13-10, ยง 1, 2-5-13)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2104. Financial Support for the Board</catch_line>
<text>
Subject to Miami-Dade County's budgetary process and the availability of funds, the Mayor shall include in die County's annual budget, administrative costs and additional funds for the implementation of the Board's powers and duties. There is hereby created the Military Affairs Trust Fund for the public purposes provided for in this Ordinance. The Finance Director is hereby authorized and directed to establish the Military Affairs Trust Fund and disburse monies in accordance with the provisions of this Ordinance.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2105. Staff Support and Counsel</catch_line>
<text>
The Mayor shall provide the Board with adequate staff to perform its powers and duties. The Board shall utilize the County Attorney's Office for legal services. The Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners shall take and keep the minutes of the Military Affairs Board.
</text>
</law>
