<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXXVI._CHARTER_REVIEW_COMMISSION</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-331. Created</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created a Miami-Dade County Charter Review Commission which shall consist of nine (9) members, one (1) appointed by each member of the Board of County Commissioners.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-332. Purpose</catch_line>
<text>
The Charter Review Commission shall study the Charter of Miami-Dade County in its entirety and provide this Board with a written report setting forth its recommendations as to any proposed amendments or revisions to the Charter.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-333. Conducting of proceedings; status of "agency.</catch_line>
<text>
All proceedings of the Charter Review Commission shall be conducted in accordance with the Government-in-the Sunshine Law, Section 286.011, Florida Statutes, and the Citizens' Bill of Rights of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter. The Panel shall be deemed an "agency" for the purpose of compliance with the Public Records Law, Chapter 119, Florida Statutes.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-334. Delivery of report</catch_line>
<text>
The Charter Review Commission shall deliver its written report to this Board by January 1, 1982. Thereupon, this Board shall review and debate the report in time to enable it to present to the electorate at the Countywide elections to be held in the fall of 1982 any amendments to the Home Rule Charter which this Board approves.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-335. Clerical, etc., assistance</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager is hereby authorized to expend a sum not exceeding twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000.00) for the purpose of providing clerical and secretarial assistance to the Charter Review Commission.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (60) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 81-55, adopted May 19, 1981, did not specify manner of disposition; hence, designation of §§ 1—5 as Art. XXXVI, §§ 2-331—2-335 has been at the editor's discretion. (Back)
Charter reference— Review of Charter, § 8.08. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
