<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_X._TRUTH_IN_LIVE_ENTERTAINMENT</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-121. "Live entertainment per- formance" defined</catch_line>
<text>
The following definition shall apply to the provisions of this article: "Live entertainment performance" as used herein shall mean any mercantile, on stage entertainment performance by living persons indoors or outdoors, including but not limited to, rock music festivals, concerts, night club shows, plays, dramatic presentations, recitals, dinner club shows, and musical entertainment of any type, but shall not include any athletic event.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-122. False or deceptive advertising or promotion prohibited; information required in advertisement or promotion; responsibility of producer to advise public when tickets unavailable</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It shall be unlawful for any person to falsely or deceptively advertise or to promote to the public, in any manner with the intent to mislead or misrepresent, the sale of admission to live entertainment performances to be conducted within Miami-Dade County, Florida, unless such advertisement or promotion discloses the following information:
<section prefix = "1">
The name(s), title(s), description of the performance or act to be presented to the public;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Where a lead artist, musician or performer is advertised, the minimum length of time that said lead artist, musician or performer will actually be on stage and performing or, in a dramatic performance, the role to be played by said lead performer, artist or musician.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
It shall be the responsibility of the producer of a live entertainment performance who has publicly advertised the sale of tickets for admission to such a performance to advise the public at the earliest possible time when such tickets are no longer available for purchase.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 74-93, § 2, 11-5-74)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-123. Certain information to be made available to public upon request</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful for any person to advertise or to promote in any manner the sale of admission to live entertainment performances to be conducted within Miami-Dade County, Florida, unless such person makes available to the public by telephone or other method reasonably calculated to inform upon request the following information:
<section prefix = "a">
The name(s) of the person(s), agency, partnership or corporation responsible for producing the performance;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The total cost of admission to the performance and the place where tickets may be purchased;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The date(s) on which the performance will be held;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The time the performance will begin and end;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The time that seating will be open and available to the public prior to the time that the performance will begin;
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The number of intermissions during the performance and the length of each such intermission.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-124. Right to full refund of admission price when lead performer does not appear or perform as advertised; exemption</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful for any person, agency, partnership or corporation to refuse to refund to any member of the public who purchased an admission to any live entertainment performance the full admission price in the event that the person(s) who are advertised and promoted as the lead or main performer(s) fail to appear or to perform as advertised pursuant to the requirements of Section 21-122 of this article. Patrons shall be permitted to elect either to accept the offered refund or to decline the refund and remain if the live entertainment performance is to continue in the absence of the lead or main performer(s). This section shall not pertain to operatic, theatrical, musical or symphonic performances by companies consisting of seven (7) or more performers when it has been advertised in advance that the producing company reserves the right to make changes or substitutions in the cast of performers.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-125. Penalty for article violation</catch_line>
<text>
Any person, agency, partnership or corporation who violates, fails to comply with, or refuses to obey any of the provisions of this article shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment not to exceed sixty (60) days in the County Jail, or both, in the discretion of the court. Each violation of the specific requirements of this article shall be considered as a separate offense.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 21-126—21-130. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
</law>
