<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXXIIA._BIRD_ROAD_DESIGN_AND_IND</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-278.5. Applicability</catch_line>
<text>
The Bird Road Design and Industrial District (BRDI) District shall be applied only to those lands, in the area bounded on the north by S.W. 40th Street (Bird Road), on the south by S.W. 48th Street, on the east by S.W. 70th Avenue, and on the west by S.W. 74th Avenue, that appropriately may be used and utilized to provide for uncommon commercial uses and other commercial uses with unusual siting requirements in areas designated as "Industrial and Office" on the Comprehensive Development Master Plan Land Use Plan map that are of the nature, type and character commensurate with the public health, safety, comfort, convenience, and the general welfare of the County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-278.6. Uses permitted</catch_line>
<text>
No land, body of water, or structure shall be used or permitted to be used, and no structure shall be hereafter erected, constructed, reconstructed, moved, structurally altered, or maintained for any purpose in the Bird Road Design and Industrial (BRDI) District, except as provided in this article. The uses delineated herein shall be permitted only in compliance with the general requirements provided in this article.
<section prefix = "1">
Antique and secondhand goods shops.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Apparel stores.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Art galleries.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Artisanal use.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Artists' studios.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Bakeries.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Banquet halls.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Bars and lounges.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Brewery.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Cabinet shops.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Card and stationery shops.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Confectionery, ice cream stores.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Custom woodworking.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
Dance studios.
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
Decorative home items.
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
Designing, making and assembling of art and craft products including sale of finished products, art and craft type products and curios designed, made and assembled in the district.
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
Florist shops.
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
Furniture stores less than ten thousand (10,000) square feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
Gift stores.
</section>
<section prefix = "20">
Interior design shops.
</section>
<section prefix = "21">
Ironworks.
</section>
<section prefix = "22">
Jewelry stores.
</section>
<section prefix = "23">
Lamps and lighting fixtures.
</section>
<section prefix = "24">
Leather goods and luggage shops.
</section>
<section prefix = "25">
Live-work units defined as follows: Single-family unit containing a maximum of two bedrooms in connection with one of the uses delineated in this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "26">
Office uses.
</section>
<section prefix = "27">
Paint and wallpaper stores less than ten thousand (10,000) square feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "28">
Photograph studio and photo supply.
</section>
<section prefix = "29">
Plant sales (no nurseries or fertilizer).
</section>
<section prefix = "30">
Pottery shops.
</section>
<section prefix = "31">
Religious facilities.
</section>
<section prefix = "32">
Self-service mini-warehouse storage facility.
</section>
<section prefix = "33">
Shoe stores and shoe repair shops.
</section>
<section prefix = "34">
Stained glass art and windows.
</section>
<section prefix = "35">
Tobacco shops for hand rolling cigars and sale of tobacco products.
</section>
<section prefix = "36">
Training schools for arts and crafts work.
</section>
<section prefix = "37">
Restaurants and coffeehouses.
</section>
<section prefix = "38">
Uses determined by the Director to be similar to those enumerated above. In determining similarity between a proposed use and the uses enumerated above the Director shall be guided by the intent of this section and shall consider common characteristics including the nature of products offered for sale, the generation of pedestrian and vehicular traffic, and incompatibility with the primary uses permitted in this district.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-278.7. General requirements</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Building Placement and Design Parameters. Each use shall comply with the building content, setback, area, height, and landscape requirements for the IU-1 zoning district set forth in Section 33-49 (Table of minimum widths, area of lots; maximum lot coverage, and minimum building sizes), Section 33-51 (Setbacks in business and industrial districts), Section 33-58 (Height of building limited to width of street in certain districts), and Section 33-261 (Minimum landscaped open space, greenbelts, trees, and maintenance).
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Outdoor Display Areas. Products sold on the premises may be displayed against the front facade of the bay or building.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Parking.
<section prefix = "1">
For all uses except for banquet halls, bars, lounges, breweries, restaurants, and coffeehouses, parking shall be provided at a minimum of 1.25 parking spaces for each 1,600 square feet of gross floor area in the building, or fractional part thereof. Live-work units shall provide an additional 1.75 parking spaces per unit.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Parking for banquet halls, bars, lounges, breweries, restaurants, and coffeehouses shall be provided in accordance with Section 33-124 of this chapter. Notwithstanding the foregoing, if the required amount of parking is not available on the same lot, parcel, or premises as the banquet hall, bar, lounge, brewery, restaurant, or coffeehouse to be served, then parking may be provided on a lot or parcel of land that is in a BRDI, IU, or BU District and is within 300 feet from the site of the use to be served by submitting a covenant in accordance with Section 33-128(a) of this chapter. It is further provided that, if the availability of parking on the other lot or parcel is dependent on the hours of operation of the uses, then parking may be provided through such a covenant where the covenant specifies that the uses on the lot or parcel providing the parking are not in operation at the same time that the use to be served is in operation.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 09-71, ยง 1, 9-1-09)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-278.8. Conflicts with other chapters and regulations</catch_line>
<text>
This article shall govern in the event of conflicts with other zoning, subdivision, or landscape regulations of this code, or with the Miami-Dade Department of Public Works Manual of Public Works.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-278.9. Nonconforming structures, uses and occupancies</catch_line>
<text>
Nothing contained in this article shall be deemed or construed to prohibit a continuation of a legal nonconforming structure, use, or occupancy in the Bird Road Design and Industrial (BRDI) District that either (1) was existing as of the date of the district boundary change on the property to BRDI District, or (2) on or before said date, had received final site plan approval through a public hearing pursuant to this chapter or through administrative site plan review or had a valid building permit. However, any structure, use, or occupancy in the BRDI District that is discontinued for a period of at least six months, or is superseded by a lawful structure, use or occupancy permitted under this chapter, or that incurs damage to the roof or structure to an extent of 50 percent or more of its market value, shall be subject to Section 33-35(c) of this Code.
</text>
</law>
