<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_CXXX._AIRCRAFT_NOISE_ABATEMENT_A</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2031. Creation</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created an Aircraft Noise Abatement Advisory Board for Miami International Airport (the "NAAB").
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2032. Purpose</catch_line>
<text>
The purpose of the NAAB is to discuss, evaluate and recommend to the Board of County Commissioners measures to reduce or mitigate aircraft noise impacts to the areas surrounding Miami International Airport ("MIA").
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2033. Membership</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
NAAB Members. The NAAB shall consist of twenty (20) members. Each member may designate a single alternate to participate and vote on his or her behalf. The members of the NAAB shall comply with the requirements of Section 2-11.38 of the Code of Miami-Dade County and shall serve without compensation. Appointments to the NAAB shall be made as provided herein:
Notwithstanding and prevailing over anything in the Code of Miami-Dade County to the contrary, eight (8) members shall be residents of County Commission Districts 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 10 and 12, and shall be nominated by the County Commissioner representing each of those Districts;
One (1) member shall be a resident of the City of Miami, and shall be nominated by the Mayor of the City of Miami.
One (1) member shall be a resident of the City of Miami Springs, and shall be nominated by the Mayor of the City of Miami Springs.
One (1) member shall be a resident of the Village of Virginia Gardens, and shall be nominated by the Mayor of the Village of Virginia Gardens.
One (1) member shall be a resident of the City of Doral, and shall be nominated by the Mayor of the City of Doral.
One (1) member shall be a resident of the City of Miami Beach, and shall be nominated by the Mayor of the City of Miami Beach.
One (1) member shall be a resident of the City of West Miami, and shall be nominated by the Mayor of the City of West Miami.
One (1) member shall be a resident of the City of North Miami, and shall be nominated by the Mayor of the City of North Miami.
One (1) member shall be a resident of the City of North Bay Village, and shall be nominated by the Mayor of the City of North Bay Village.
One (1) member shall be a resident of the City of Sweetwater, and shall be nominated by Mayor of the City of Sweetwater;
One (1) member shall be a resident of the Village of Key Biscayne, and shall be nominated by the Mayor of the Village of Key Biscayne;
One (1) member shall be a resident of the Village of Miami Shores, and shall be nominated by the Mayor of the Village of Miami Shores;
One (1) member shall be a resident of the Village of El Portal, and shall be nominated by the Mayor of the Village of El Portal;
Any member who ceases to meet the membership requirements set forth above, shall immediately forfeit his or her office.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Term. The members of the NAAB shall serve staggered terms of three (3) years each. Notwithstanding any other provision of the Code, no member shall be permitted to serve more than eight (8) consecutive years. Members nominated by the Commissioner of County Commission Districts 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 10 and 12, shall serve an initial term of three (3) years. Members nominated by the Mayor of the City of Miami, the Mayor of the City of Miami Springs, the Mayor of the Village of Virginia Gardens, the Mayor of the City of Doral, the Mayor of the City of Miami Beach, the Mayor of the City of South Miami, the Mayor of the City of North Miami, the Mayor of the City of North Bay Village, the Mayor of the City of Sweetwater, the Mayor of the Village of Key Biscayne, the Mayor of the Village of Miami Shores and the Mayor of the Village of El Portal shall serve an initial term of two (2) years. Thereafter, all members will serve terms of three (3) years.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Vacancies. Vacancies in the membership of the NAAB shall be filled in the same manner by which the original NAAB members were appointed and shall be filled within 45 days.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Removal from Office. Notwithstanding any other provision of the Code, if any NAAB member is absent from two (2) consecutive NAAB meetings annually without an acceptable excuse, or from four (4) NAAB meetings annually without an acceptable excuse, the NAAB shall certify the same to the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 08-116, ยง 3, 10-7-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2034. Procedures</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Chair. A member of the NAAB, chosen by a majority of the members, shall serve as Chair of the NAAB.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Vice Chair. A member of the NAAB, chosen by a majority of the members, shall serve as Vice Chair of the NAAB.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Meetings. A majority of the members, then in office, constitutes a quorum for the purpose of conducting business and exercising the powers of the NAAB and for all other purposes. Meetings of the NAAB shall be held a minimum of four (4) times annually, shall be public and written minutes of the proceedings thereof shall be maintained. No vacancy in the membership of the NAAB shall impair the right of a quorum to exercise the right to perform all the duties of the NAAB.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 08-116, ยง 4, 10-7-08; Ord. No. 12-82, ยง 1, 10-2-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2035. Powers and duties</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Functions. The NAAB shall consider present and future aircraft noise impacts arising from operations at MIA. With the assistance of staff, the NAAB shall explore, consider and recommend programs and practices that may be helpful in reducing or mitigating aircraft noise impacts.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Report. The NAAB shall submit an annual written report to the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 08-116, ยง 5, 10-7-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2036. Staff</catch_line>
<text>
Miami Dade Aviation Department shall provide to the NAAB adequate staff and support services to enable the NAAB to carry out its purposes.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2036.1. Sunset</catch_line>
<text>
The provisions of this article shall sunset on October 7, 2018, unless extended by amendment of the Board of County Commissioners prior to such date.
</text>
</law>
