<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 29 TAXATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_VII._LOCAL_OPTION_GAS_TAX</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-63.1. Short title</catch_line>
<text>
This article shall be known as the "Dade County Local Option Gas Tax Ordinance."
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-63.2. Tax levied; effective period</catch_line>
<text>
Pursuant to Section 336.025, Florida Statutes, the Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners hereby levies and imposes a tax of four cents ($0.04) on every gallon of motor and special fuels purchased in Miami-Dade County, Florida. This tax shall be known as the "Local Option Gas Tax" and shall be imposed as of September 1, 1983, for a period of five (5) years.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-63.3. Interlocal agreement</catch_line>
<text>
The Commission hereby ratifies and confirms an interlocal agreement entered into by the County and eligible Miami-Dade County municipalities pursuant to Section 336.025, Florida Statutes; a true and correct copy of said agreement is attached hereto. The County Manager is authorized and directed to execute said agreement on behalf of the County in substantially the form as is attached hereto. As set forth in said interlocal agreement, the County agrees to distribute the net proceeds of the local option gas tax, seventy-four (74) percent to the County and twenty-six (26) percent to be distributed by formula among the eligible incorporated municipalities in Miami-Dade County.
</text>
<EditorsNote>
The text of the interlocal agreement is not reproduced in the Code; it may be found on file in the office of the Clerk.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-64. Relationship to State law</catch_line>
<text>
This article is adopted and shall be subject to the provisions of Section 55 of Chapter 83-3, Laws of Florida.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-65. Contingency of agreement becoming void</catch_line>
<text>
If for any reason, the interlocal agreement herein referred to shall be terminated or deemed of no force and effect, the local option gas tax shall continue to be imposed and, upon notification by the County, the Florida Department of Revenue shall distribute the proceeds of said tax to the County and eligible municipalities within the County in accordance with the method set forth in Section 336.025(4), Florida Statutes.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 29-66—29-70. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (7) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 83-52, adopted July 5, 1983, expressed an intent to amend the Code but did not specify disposition; therefore, codification of §§ 1—5 as Art. VII, §§ 29-63.1—29-65, has been at the discretion of the editor. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
