<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_II._PARKING_SPACES_FOR_DISABLED_</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-442. Parking spaces provided by governmental agencies for certain disabled persons</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Miami-Dade County and each municipality within Miami-Dade County, and each agency, instrumentality and authority thereof, having jurisdiction over street parking or publicly owned and operated parking facilities shall provide a minimum number of specially designated and marked motor vehicle parking spaces for the exclusive use of those severely physically disabled individuals who have permanent mobility problems that substantially impair their ability to ambulate and who have been issued an exemption entitlement parking permit pursuant to Section 316.1958, Florida Statutes, or Section 320.0848, Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The following minimum number of such parking spaces shall be provided:
<section prefix = "1">
One (1) space in the immediate vicinity of a building which houses a governmental entity or a political subdivision, including, but not limited to, State office buildings and courthouses, if no parking for the public is provided on the premises of such building;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
One (1) space for each one hundred fifty (150) metered on-street parking spaces; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
For publicly maintained and operated parking facilities intended for public use and not subject to paragraph (1), the number of parking spaces for disabled persons as set forth in the following table:
<section prefix="1" type="table">
<table class="table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="66.66666666666667%" /> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Total Parking in Lot</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Required<br />Number of<br />Accessible<br /><i>Spaces</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Up to 25</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 1</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH26PAREDERURE.html#PTIIICOOR_CH26PAREDERURE"> 26</a> to   50 </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 2</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 51 to   75</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 3</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 76 to  100</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 4</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">101 to  150</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 5</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">151 to  200</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 6</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">201 to  300</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 7</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">301 to  400</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 8</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">401 to  500</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 9</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">501 to 1000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2% of total</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Over 1000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">20</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">plus 1 for each 100 over 1000</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 
However, when parking spaces are leased at such publicly maintained and operated parking facilities, the number of parking spaces for disabled persons shall be increased or decreased on demonstrated and documented need. A minimum of four (4) parking spaces for disabled persons shall be provided at a physical restoration rehabilitation center or a hospital.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Such parking spaces shall be designed and located as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
All spaces shall have accessible thereto a curb-ramp or curb-cut, when necessary to allow access to the building served, and shall be located so that users will not be compelled to wheel behind parked vehicles.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Diagonal or perpendicular parking spaces shall be a minimum of twelve (12) feet wide.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Parallel parking spaces shall be located either at the beginning or end of a block or adjacent to alley entrances. Curbs adjacent to such spaces shall be of a height which will not interfere with the opening and closing of motor vehicle doors.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Each such parking space shall be prominently outlined with paint and posted with a permanent above-grade sign of a color and design approved by the Department of Transportation, bearing the international symbol of accessibility and the caption "PARKING BY DISABLED PERMIT ONLY." In addition, each such parking space shall be provided with a sign stating "TOW-AWAY ZONE AND FINE UP TO $250.00."
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 87-39, § 1, 6-16-87)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-443. Parking spaces provided by nongovernmental entities for certain disabled persons</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Any business, firm, or other person licensed to do business with the public may provide specially designed and marked motor vehicle parking spaces for the exclusive use of physically disabled persons who have been issued parking permits pursuant to Section 316.1958, Florida Statutes or Section 320.0848, Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Each such parking space shall conform to the requirements of Section 30-442(c) and (d) of this Code.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 87-39, § 1, 6-16-87)</history>
<catch_line>Secs. 30-444—30-446. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-447. Penalty for misuse of specially marked parking spaces</catch_line>
<text>
It is unlawful for any person to stop, stand, or park a vehicle within any parking space designated with an above-grade sign bearing the international symbol of accessibility or the caption "PARKING BY DISABLED PERMIT ONLY," or with both such symbol and caption, unless such vehicle displays a parking permit issued pursuant to Section 316.1958, Florida Statutes, or Section 320.0848, Florida Statutes, and such vehicle is transporting a person eligible for the parking permit. However, any person who is chauffeuring a person eligible for a disabled parking permit shall be allowed, without need for an identification parking permit, momentary parking in any such parking space for the purpose of loading or unloading a disabled person. No penalty shall be imposed upon the driver for such momentary parking. Whenever a law enforcement officer or a parking enforcement specialist finds a vehicle in violation of this section, that officer shall:
<section prefix = "1">
Have the vehicle in violation removed to any lawful parking space or facility or require the operator or other person in charge of the vehicle immediately to remove the unauthorized vehicle from the parking space. Whenever any vehicle is removed by a law enforcement officer, parking enforcement specialist, or agency to a storage lot, garage, or other safe parking space, the cost of such removal and parking shall be a lien against the vehicle.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Charge the motor vehicle owner in violation with a noncriminal traffic infraction.
<section prefix = "a">
Whenever evidence shall be presented in any court of the fact that any automobile, truck, or other vehicle was found to be parked in a properly designated handicapped parking space in violation of this section, it shall be prima facie evidence that the vehicle was parked and left in the space by the person, firm, or corporation in whose name the vehicle is registered and licensed according to the records of the Division of Motor Vehicles.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Violators of this article shall be punished by a mandatory fine of one hundred fifty dollars ($150.00). A motor vehicle owner who is guilty of repeat violations of this article may be punished by a fine not to exceed two hundred fifty dollars ($250.00).
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All fines collected in excess of twenty-five dollars ($25.00) for each violation shall be deposited in a separate account to be used in the following manner:
<section prefix = "i">
One-third to be used to defray expenses for the administration of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Two-thirds to be used to provide funds to improve accessibility and equal opportunity to qualified physically disabled persons and to provide funds to conduct public awareness programs concerning physically disabled persons.
The two-thirds shall be distributed in the following manner:
Thirty (30) percent to be retained by the County for county-wide purposes in accordance with state law, and seventy (70) percent to be allocated to the governmental entity having jurisdiction over the violation.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
To be eligible to receive funds each participating city would be required to submit an affidavit sworn by the chief administrative official which would assure that these funds would be used in accordance with state law. Monies not distributed to a city because of the failure of such city to submit an affidavit shall be placed in a fund for disbursement to other cities which have submitted affidavits in proportion to the percentage of citations issued by the complying city.

All fines collected in excess of twenty-five dollars ($25.00) for each violation of Section 30-292(1)(a)12., shall be eligible for inclusion in the fund described in Section 30-447(2)(c).
</section>
</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-448. Out-of-state vehicles bearing handicapped identification</catch_line>
<text>
Motor vehicles displaying a special license plate or parking permit issued to a physically disabled person by any other state or district subject to the laws of the United States shall be recognized as a valid license plate or permit, allowing such vehicle the special parking privileges allowed pursuant to the provisions of this article.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (2) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 87-39, § 1, adopted June 16, 1987, repealed former Art. II, §§ 30-441—30-447, relative to parking spaces for disabled persons and enacted in lieu thereof a new Art. II to read as herein set out. The provisions of former Art. II derived from Ord. No. 74-102, §§ 1—7, adopted Dec. 17, 1974; Ord. No. 83-22, § 1, enacted May 3, 1983; and Ord. No. 87-7, § 1, adopted March 3, 1987. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
