<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XCII._COMMUNITY_IMAGE_ADVISORY_B</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1334. Purpose</catch_line>
<text>
The Advisory Board shall be responsible for establishing the yearly Community Image plans, including budget and initiative priorities, based on the following Community Image 2000 Goals:
<section prefix = "1">
The proper maintenance of grass in and around our main roadways and transportation gateways;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The continued enhancement of our main roadways and transportation gateways through the replacement of unhealthy or damaged landscaping;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The enhancement of areas under overpasses and bridges;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The establishment of a standard color-scheme for bridge overpasses;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The proper maintenance around the Metrorail and Metromover system and the creation of exciting designs through lighting, painting, and cosmetic changes to the Metrorail and Metromover trains;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
The elimination of litter and trash on our main roadways and transportation gateways;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
The clearance of roadway intersections and emergency lanes of debris;
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
The enhancement of all roadways serving major tourist transportation terminals, such as the airport, seaport, and train station;
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
The enhancement of water retention areas near major roadways through the use of lighting and fountains.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
The education of the community regarding the goals of the Advisory Board, especially roadway and transportation gateway beautification.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1335. Organization of the board</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Membership. The Advisory Board shall be made up of the following members:
<section prefix = "a">
A representative from Florida Department of Transportation;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A representative from the Miami-Dade County Solid Waste Department;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
A representative member from Team Metro;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
A representative from each municipality located within Miami-Dade County;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
A representative from West Kendall;
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
A representative from the Miami-Dade County Public Works Department;
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
A representative from the Miami-Dade Transit Agency;
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
A representative from the Miami-Dade County Park and Recreation Department;
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
A representative from the County Manager's Office;
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
A Miami-Dade County Commissioner from each Commission District or his or her designee;
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
A representative from the Expressway Authority;
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
A representative from the Miami-Dade County Aviation Department;
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
A representative from the Miami-Dade County Seaport;
</section>
<section prefix = "n">
A representative from the Miami-Dade Planning and Zoning Department;
</section>
<section prefix = "o">
A representative from the Metropolitan Planning Organization ("MPO");
</section>
<section prefix = "p">
A representative from Miami-Dade County Public Schools;
</section>
<section prefix = "q">
A representative from Transportation Aesthetics Review Committee ("TARC");
</section>
<section prefix = "r">
A representative from the Citizen's Transportation Advisory Committee ("CTAC");
</section>
<section prefix = "s">
A representative from the Homestead/Florida City Chamber of Commerce;
</section>
<section prefix = "t">
A representative from the Greater Miami Chamber of Commerce;
</section>
<section prefix = "u">
A representative from the Greater Miami Convention and Visitors Bureau;
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
A representative from the Downtown Development Authority;
</section>
<section prefix = "w">
A representative from the Miami-Dade League of Cities;
</section>
<section prefix = "x">
A representative from Amtrak;
</section>
<section prefix = "y">
A representative from Tri-Rail.
</section>
<section prefix = "z">
A representative on behalf of the media sector.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Appointment of members. The County Manager shall contact each of the organizations, companies, and municipalities referenced in Section (1) above, and shall request that each of these organizations, companies, and municipalities submit the names of at least one (1) interested and eligible nominee. The nominee from West Kendall shall be selected by the Commissioner from District 11. These nominees shall be submitted to the Board of County Commissioners in the form of a report for approval and appointment to the Advisory Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Meetings. The Advisory Board shall hold regular meetings, no less than six times per year, and such other meetings as it deems necessary. Ten (10) of the duly appointed and sitting members of the Advisory Board shall constitute a quorum. Minutes shall be kept of all meetings of the Advisory Board and all meetings shall be duly noticed to the public.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Applicability of County Rules and Procedures. The Advisory Board shall at all times operate under the Florida Open Government laws, including the "Sunshine Law," public meeting laws and public records laws and shall be governed by all State and County conflict of interest laws, as applicable, including the Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance, Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Attendance requirement. Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code, any Advisory Board member shall be automatically removed if, in a given fiscal year he or she is absent from more than 50% of the year's meetings. A member shall be deemed absent from a meeting when he or she is not present at the meeting at least seventy-five percent of the time. By a one-third (1/3) vote of the members present, the provisions of this section may be waived.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Compensation. Members of the Advisory Board shall serve without compensation, but shall be entitled to reimbursement for necessary expenses incurred in the discharge of their duties.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Staff and Facility Support. The County Manager and the County Attorney shall provide such staff support to the Advisory Board as may be necessary to accomplish its purpose. The County Manager will provide such facilities as the Advisory Board may deem necessary to accomplish its purposes.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 01-164, § 2, 10-23-01; Ord. No. 02-31, § 1, 2-26-02; Ord. No. 03-215, § 1, 10-7-03)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1336. Function</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Submittal of Semi-annual Reports. The Advisory Board shall be responsible for providing two (2) reports per year for the duration of its existence, the first of which shall be submitted to the Board within three (3) months following the passage of this article or the first meeting of the Advisory Board, whichever is later. Each subsequent semi-annual report will be submitted within six (6) months following the submittal of the prior report, but provided that no more than two (2) reports need be presented to the Board of County Commissioners in one (1) year. For purposes of this article, a year shall be the 365 contiguous days following the submittal of the first Semi-annual report, regardless of whether those 365 days fall in a single calendar year.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Contents of the Semi-annual Reports. The first semi-annual report in a given year shall contain the Advisory Board's prioritization of the Community Image Goals, as set forth in Section 2 (A), above, with the highest priority given to the Community Image Goal most necessary for the enhancement of tourism. This report will include an analysis detailing which County departments, if any, have an existing responsibility and budget allotment to undertake the Community Image Goal. The second semi-annual report will provide an action plan for each of the Goals, including which County departments should be responsible to undertake the proposed action(s). The second semi-annual report will detail the approximate budget required for each of the proposed actions, shall constitute the final Community Image plan to be submitted to the Board for consideration, and will contain the Advisory Committee's final action plan based on the priorities and budgets contained therein.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Advisory Board may promulgate rules consistent with this article for the conduct of its meetings and the discharge of its responsibilities under this article. Any rules promulgated by the Advisory Board under this section shall be submitted to the Board of County Commissioners for ratification.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Implementation of the Community Image Plan. It shall be the responsibility of the County Manager to implement the elements of the plans that she or he, in her or his discretion, determines are in the best interest of the County.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 01-164, § 2, 10-23-01; Ord. No. 02-31, § 1, 2-26-02; Ord. No. 03-215, § 2, 10-7-03)</history>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-1337—2-1340. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (101) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 01-164, § 2, adopted Oct. 23, 2001, did not specifically amend the Code. Hence, its inclusion herein as article XCII, §§ 2-1334—2-1336, was at the discretion of the editor. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
