<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XII._PUBLIC_AND_BUS_PASSENGER_BE</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-151. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Director means the Director of Miami-Dade Transit Agency.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Department means the Miami-Dade Transit Agency.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
MDTA means Miami-Dade Transit Agency.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Permittee means an individual, firm, partnership, or corporation, or combination thereof who has entered into a contract with the County to provide bus benches at authorized MDTA bus stops.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Bus stop means a location designated by MDTA for buses to stop for the purpose of loading and unloading passengers.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Right-of-way means any right, title or interest in or to real property, or the use thereof acquired by the County or the State of Florida or the public and utilized for passage or travel including MDTA authorized bus stops.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 85-32, § 1(1), 5-7-85)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-152. Miami-Dade Transit Agency duties</catch_line>
<text>
MDTA shall be charged with the following duties and responsibilities:
<section prefix = "a">
Provide permittee with a complete and accurate list of all MDTA authorized bus stops.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Advise permittee of any changes in the list of MDTA authorized bus stops.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Enforce the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Forward requests, complaints, etc. to permittee and attempt to resolve same.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Assign an exclusive identification number to be displayed on each bench.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Issue permits for bus passenger benches pursuant to the provisions of this article and maintain appropriate files regarding same.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Investigate and prepare reports on alleged violations of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Perform any other duties assigned by the County Manager.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-153. Location on public property</catch_line>
<text>
No benches for use of the public shall be located in any public right-of-way in the unincorporated area of the County except in compliance with the provisions of this article.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-154. Permits—Bid procedure</catch_line>
<text>
Permits for bus passenger benches shall be issued pursuant to contract based upon the following procedure:
<section prefix = "a">
Unincorporated Miami-Dade County shall be divided into two (2) territories, hereinafter referred to as the "South Territory" and the "North Territory". Each territory shall be subdivided into three (3) geographic districts. The South Territory shall be comprised of Districts 1, 2, 3, and the North Territory shall be comprised of Districts 4, 5, and 6.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The territories shall be bounded as follows:
"South Territory" (Districts 1, 2, and 3)
District 1: North boundary, between U.S. 1 and Biscayne Bay, the boundary is Coral Reef Drive which is not included in District 1. Between U.S. 1 and the County line to the west, the boundary is North Kendall Drive which is not included in District 1; south boundary, County line; east boundary, between Kendall Drive and Coral Reef Drive, the boundary is U.S. 1 which is included in District 1. Between Coral Reef Drive and the County line to the south, the boundary is Biscayne Bay; west boundary, County line.
District 2: North boundary, Tamiami Trail which is not included in District 2; south boundary, North Kendall Drive which is included in District 2; east boundary, S.W. 87 Avenue which is not included in district 2; west boundary, County line.
District 3: North boundary, Flagler Street which is included in District 3; south boundary, between U.S. 1 and Biscayne Bay, the boundary is Coral Reef Drive [sic] loway Road, the boundary is North Kendall Drive which is included in District 3; east boundary, Biscayne Bay. Key Biscayne, Virginia Key and the Rickenbacker Causeway are included in District 3; west boundary, between Kendall Drive and Coral Reef Drive, the boundary is U.S. 1 which is not included in District 3. Between Flagler Street and Kendall Drive, the boundary is S.W. 87 Avenue which is included in District 3.

"North Territory" (Districts 4, 5, and 6)
District 4: North boundary, between Biscayne Bay and the County line to the west, the boundary is N.W./N.E. 103 Street which is included in District 4. Between Biscayne Bay and the Atlantic Ocean, the boundary is 87 Street which is included in the district; south boundary, between S.W. 87 Avenue and the County line to the west, the boundary is the Tamiami Trail which is included in District 4. Between S.W. 87 Avenue and Biscayne Bay, the boundary is Flagler Street which is not included in the District; east boundary, between Tamiami Trail and Flagler Street, the boundary is S.W. 87 Avenue which is not included in the District. Between N.W./N.E. 103 Street and Flagler Street, the boundary is the Atlantic Ocean; west boundary, County line.
District 5: North boundary, between the intercoastal waterway and the Atlantic Ocean, the boundary is the County line. Between the intercoastal waterway and the County line to the west, the boundary is N.W./N.E. 167 Street, N.E. 163 Street, and Sunny Isles Boulevard which are included in District 5; south boundary, between Biscayne Bay and the County line to the west, the boundary is N.W./N.E. 103 Street which is not included in the district. Between Biscayne Bay and the Atlantic Ocean, the boundary is 87 Street which is not included in District 5; east boundary, between N.E. 103 Street and 163 Street, the boundary is Biscayne Bay or the intracoastal waterway. Between N.E. 163 Street and the County line to the north, the boundary is the Atlantic Ocean; west boundary, County line.
District 6: North boundary, County line; south boundary, between the intercoastal waterway and the County line, the boundary is N.W./N.E. 167 Street, N.E. 163 Street, and Sunny Isles Boulevard which are not included in the district; east boundary, intercoastal waterway; west boundary, County line.

</section>
<section prefix = "c">
A contract(s) for placement of bus passenger benches in the public right-of-way in unincorporated Miami-Dade County shall be awarded by territory based upon competitive bids or request for proposals. The bid specifications or requests for proposals shall contain a complete listing of all official bus stops of the Metro Miami-Dade Transportation Administration within the applicable territory. Such contracts may be extended beyond their term without the need for further competitive process upon compliance with the requirements for bid waivers contained in Section 4.03D of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter and Section 2-8.1(b) of this Code.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-155. Same—Award of contract; term of contract; exclusivity and restriction on transfer</catch_line>
<text>
No permit for a bus passenger bench shall be issued by MDTA in a geographic territory (as defined in Section 21-154) except to a permittee. The permittee shall have the exclusive right to place bus passenger benches in the geographical territory specified in the contract subject to compliance with other provisions of this article. The permittee may not transfer any permit or contractual rights to any individual, partnership, corporation or other legal entity without the express written consent of the Director. No transfer of more than fifty (50) percent financial interest in the partnership, corporation or legal entity shall be permitted without the express written consent of the Director.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-156. Sale—Compliance with State and federal regulations</catch_line>
<text>
The permittee shall be responsible for compliance with applicable State and federal regulations.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-157. Same—Application and fee</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Each bus passenger bench shall require an application, permit, and fee and shall be issued a separate and distinct identification number by MDTA. The permits shall be renewable each year that the contract is in force and fees shall be paid annually.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
No bench shall be installed at a bus stop prior to obtaining a permit.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
When a bench is installed at a bus stop prior to obtaining a permit, the permittee shall be required by MDTA to pay a double permit fee.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 85-32, § 1(7), 5-7-85)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-158. Location of bus passenger benches</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Bus stops. No bus passenger bench shall be permitted at any location except an established transit stop authorized by MDTA where regularly scheduled, periodic stops are made. The Department shall have the right and duty to refuse approval of any location, or to require the removal of a bus bench from any location, when it appears that a traffic hazard may be created or that the public safety may be endangered, or when MDTA determines that the bus bench is improperly placed or is not compatible with the surrounding community. The decision of the Department in respect to the installation or maintenance of bus benches at any location in the unincorporated areas shall be final. If the permittee fails to remove a bus passenger bench after being ordered to do so by MDTA, the Department may have the bench removed in accordance with the provisions of Section 21-15 of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Distance requirements. No bus passenger bench shall be placed or maintained within five (5) feet of the outer edge of the pavement of any road, except at approved locations where sidewalks and curbs exist. Where no sidewalks and curbs exist, MDTA shall require bus benches to be located such distance in excess of five (5) feet as may be deemed necessary or desirable for the public safety and welfare. At approved locations where curbs and sidewalks exist, bus passenger benches may be placed and maintained at such locations as the Department shall designate, in order to ensure the safety and convenience of the public. The location of each bus passenger bench shall be approved by the Department prior to the issuance of a permit. Benches placed on State-maintained rights-of-way shall conform to applicable regulations of the State of Florida, Department of Transportation.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
At passenger shelter sites. Provided that bus benches comply with applicable setback requirements, they may be located at a bus stop where a bus passenger shelter has been installed, unless MDTA determines that the placement of said benches would interfere with the free flow of vehicular or pedestrian traffic or would impede handicapped persons. Unless MDTA, in its sole discretion, determines that there exists a need for additional bus benches, bus benches will be permitted at up to fifty (50) percent of the bus stops where a bus passenger shelter is located.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Advertising panel. Each bench shall be placed with the advertising panel at an angle of no greater than twenty (20) degrees to the adjacent roadway.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 85-32, § 1(8), 5-7-85)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-159. Construction and maintenance</catch_line>
<text>
Benches shall conform to the approved standards and specifications on file with the Product Control Branch of the Code Compliance Department. A permittee shall maintain each bus passenger bench in a good state of repair and appearance, and shall keep the area surrounding each bench free of debris, high grass, weeds, and other rubbish for a radius of seven (7) feet from the center of the bench. Failure to properly maintain the bench or the surrounding area shall constitute cause for cancellation of the permit and removal of the bench as provided in Section 21-165.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-160. Number of bus benches</catch_line>
<text>
Only one (1) bench shall be permitted at each approved designated bus stop except as otherwise designated by MDTA. The Director is authorized to revoke at any time the right of the permittee to place more than one (1) bus bench at a bus stop if the Director deems that it is in the best interest of MDTA.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-161. Identification</catch_line>
<text>
Each bus passenger bench shall display the name and business telephone number of the permittee.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-162. Benches without advertising</catch_line>
<text>
Each permittee shall agree to locate and maintain one (1) bench containing no advertising for every ten (10) approved benches that are placed that carry advertising. Such benches carrying no advertising shall be placed at locations designated by MDTA. No fee shall be charged for such benches, but permits will be required and an identification number shall be issued.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-163. Insurance</catch_line>
<text>
All permittees, before placing any benches on public rights-of-way in the unincorporated area of the County subject to this article, shall carry such insurance and submit evidence of such insurance to MDTA as may be required by the County. No permits shall be issued until the permittee has complied with this requirement. A permittee shall not cancel the required insurance coverage at any time without the express written consent of the MDTA Executive Director.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-164. Change of authorized bus stops</catch_line>
<text>
Whenever an authorized bus stop is changed or created by MDTA, the permittee shall be so notified. In the case of a deletion of an authorized bus stop, the permittee shall have fourteen (14) days to remove the public bench or benches. The permittee may request permission to move said bench or benches to other authorized bus stops within its designated area.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-165. Compliance with article required; removal of benches</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Failure to comply with any of the terms, conditions or requirements of this article shall constitute cause for cancellation of the permit for, and/or removal of the bench to which the violation pertains.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
All benches in the public right-of-way in the unincorporated area of the County shall be subject to this article and shall comply with all provisions hereof. Any bench found in violation may be removed without prior notice by MDTA immediately.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
In addition to the provisions of subsection (b) of this section, the Department may, at its discretion, require a permittee to remove a bus bench and deliver such bench to a County-owned or leased facility for storage and disposal if MDTA or the permittee finds a bench that:
<section prefix = "1">
Displays a bus passenger bench company name different than the company name of the existing bus bench permittee.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Lacks a bus passenger bench company name, or any of the identification required by Section 21-161 of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Is not located at an MDTA authorized bus stop.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Is in violation of any of the terms, conditions and requirements of this article.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Permittee shall be responsible for removal of all its bus passenger benches from the public right-of-way upon termination of its right to operate in Miami-Dade County for any reason including, but not limited to, expiration of the contract, default, or voluntary termination on the part of the permittee. Nothing contained in this subsection or in any other section of this article shall relieve the permittee of this obligation.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 85-32, § 1(15), 5-7-85)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-166. Bus shelter location and extension onto private property</catch_line>
<text>
Bus shelters shall be placed only at MDTA authorized bus stops. The shelter structure shall be permitted to extend onto private property, subject to private consent, provided all of the following prohibitions and requirements are met and only to the extent necessary to conform with setback requirements specified in subsection (c) of this section:
<section prefix = "a">
Bus shelters shall be prohibited on private property in the RU-1, RU-2, EU-1, EU-1C, EU-2, EU-S, EU-M and AU zoning districts.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Bus shelters shall not exceed one hundred fifty-two (152) square feet in size.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Bus shelters placed on Miami-Dade County or State of Florida maintained rights-of-way shall conform to Miami-Dade County Public Works Department's bus shelter setback requirements or State of Florida, Department of Transportation regulations, whichever is applicable.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-167. Bus passenger bench location and extension onto private property</catch_line>
<text>
Bus passenger benches for the use of the public shall only be permitted to extend onto private property, subject to private consent, provided all the following requirements are met:
<section prefix = "a">
Location. Bus passenger benches shall be permitted to be placed only at MDTA authorized bus stops, and to extend onto private property only to the extent necessary to conform with the setback requirements specified in subsection (b) of this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Setbacks. Bus passenger benches placed partially on a Miami-Dade County or State of Florida maintained right-of-way shall conform with Section 21-158 of this article.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-168. Enforcement</catch_line>
<text>
The enforcement of the provisions in this article and other chapters of the Code pertaining to the placement of bus passenger benches and bus shelters for use of the public whether on private property or public right-of-way shall be the responsibility of the Director of the Miami-Dade Transportation Administration or successor departments.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-169. Exemption of signs from zoning requirements</catch_line>
<text>
Signs affixed to bus shelters and bus passenger benches placed at MDTA authorized bus stops and extending onto private property are exempt from the provisions of Chapter 33 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 21-170—21-200. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (8) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 85-32, § 1, adopted May 7, 1985, amended the Code but did not specify section numbers to be assigned; therefore, codification of § 1(1)—(19) as Art. XII of Ch. 21, §§ 21-151—21-169, has been at the editor's discretion. (Back)
Cross reference— Miami-Dade Transit Agency, § 2-145 et seq.; Citizens' Transportation Advisory Committee, § 2-336 et seq.; vehicles for hire, Ch. 31. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
