<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 11 COURTS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_II._BAILIFFS</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 11-21. Appointment; term; duties</catch_line>
<text>
Each Judge of the Circuit Court and County Court in Miami-Dade County, Florida, and each Judge hereafter appointed or elected to either of such Courts, is hereby authorized to appoint and employ at County expense a Bailiff who shall serve at the pleasure of the appointing Judge and perform such duties and functions as shall be imposed by law and as may be prescribed by the presiding Judge. Each such Bailiff shall be subject to the order and direction of the Judge appointing him.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 11-22. Chief Bailiff for Circuit Court</catch_line>
<text>
In addition to the Bailiffs hereinabove provided the presiding Judge may appoint and employ a Chief Bailiff of the Circuit Court who shall serve at the pleasure of the presiding Judge and who shall be charged with the duty and responsibility of supervising and coordinating the activities of all other Circuit Court Bailiffs under the order, direction and supervision of the presiding Judge and who shall perform such other duties and functions prescribed by the presiding Judge.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 11-23. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Section 11-23, relating to the Chief Bailiff of the Civil Court of Record, has been deleted as obsolete. See Fla. Const. Art. V. The section was derived from Ord. No. 58-23, § 4, adopted June 24, 1958, and Ord. No. 59-13, § 4, adopted June 16, 1959.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 11-23.1. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Section 11-23.1, relating to the Chief Bailiff of the Criminal Court of Record, has been deleted as obsolete. See Fla. Const. Art. V. The section was derived from Ord. No. 59-13, § 5, adopted June 16, 1959.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 11-23.2. Bailiff for Grand Jury</catch_line>
<text>
The Grand Jury of Miami-Dade County, Florida, may employ a Bailiff who shall serve at the pleasure of the Grand Jury and who shall be appointed pursuant to the provisions of Section 1 of Chapter 30165, Acts of 1955, Laws of Florida, and shall perform the duties and functions imposed by law and as may be prescribed by the Grand Jury. Such Bailiff shall serve under the order and direction of the Grand Jury.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 11-24. Compensation</catch_line>
<text>
Each Bailiff appointed and employed under and pursuant to the provisions of this article shall be entitled to receive compensation as set forth in the County pay plan approved and adopted annually by the County Commission. All persons appointed or employed under and pursuant to the provisions of this article shall be excepted and excluded from the classified service of the County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 11-24.1. Expenses while guarding jury; reimbursement; expense report</catch_line>
<text>
Any Bailiff for the Circuit Court and County Court shall be entitled to reimbursement for his actual expenditures for meals and lodging incurred while guarding a petit jury during the trial of a criminal or civil action. The Finance Director shall make such reimbursement from County funds upon receipt of an expense report signed by the Bailiff and the trial Judge, subject to any maximum allowances for meals and lodging which may be established by appropriate administrative order of the County Manager.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 11-25. Seniority status preserved</catch_line>
<text>
Each person serving as a Bailiff for either the Circuit Court, the County Court or the Grand Jury upon the effective date [4] of this article, who shall be appointed or employed as Bailiff or Chief Bailiff under and pursuant to the provisions of this article, shall receive full credit for all time he served as Bailiff, and his compensation paid hereunder shall be computed upon the basis of seniority commencing from the date of his initial employment as Bailiff; provided, however, that in order for any Bailiff to become entitled to receive the increase in compensation provided for herein, he shall first deliver to the Finance Director of the County written evidence of his appointment or employment under the provisions of this article showing his full name and address, number of dependents, date of original employment as Bailiff, and his classification (Bailiff or Chief Bailiff) signed by the authorized appointing Judge, or by the Foreman of the Grand Jury.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 11-26. Temporary Bailiffs</catch_line>
<text>
In the event that any Judge of either the Circuit Court or the County Court shall find and determine that an additional Bailiff or Bailiffs are required in order for the court promptly and efficiently to dispose of its trial work, or that an emergency exists because of the illness, disability or absence of regular Bailiffs, then and in such event any such Judge may appoint and employ such temporary Bailiffs as he deems necessary. The appointing Judge shall determine the period of time for which any such temporary Bailiff is needed and shall prescribe the duties and functions of such employee. Each temporary Bailiff appointed hereunder shall receive the same compensation provided for other Bailiffs.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 11-27. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Section 11-27, relating to female Bailiffs, has been deleted as obsolete. The section was derived from Ord. No. 58-23, § 8, adopted June 24, 1958, and Ord. No. 59-13, § 10, adopted June 16, 1959.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 11-28. Funds provided</catch_line>
<text>
The compensation and salaries for Bailiffs appointed or employed in accordance with the provisions of this article shall be paid from County funds upon appropriate County attendance and payroll records certified by the appointing authority. The expenditure of County funds to provide Bailiffs for the Judges of the Circuit Court, the County Court and the Grand Jury in Miami-Dade County is declared to be a County purpose relating solely to the affairs, property and government of the County.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 11-29, 11-30. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (3) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 59-13, adopted June 16, 1959, amended Ord. No. 58-23, §§ 2, 3, 6—9, codified herein as §§ 11-21, 11-22, 11-25—11-28, and reenacted §§ 4 and 5 codified herein as §§ 11-23, 11-24. Prior to Ord. No. 59-13 there was no reference to the Criminal Court of Record or the Grand Jury. Ord. No. 58-23 was further amended by Ord. No. 59-13, which added §§ 5, 6 codified herein as §§ 11-23.1 and 11-23.2. Ord. No. 60-1, § 1, adopted Jan. 5, 1960, declared Ord. No. 59-13 to be amendatory to this Code. Sec. 12 of Ord. No. 59-13 repealed Ch. 30279, Acts 1955, Laws of Florida; § 2, Ch. 30165, Acts 1955, Laws of Florida; Ch. 57-879, Laws of Florida; and County Resolution No. 2848. (Back)
Cross reference— Bailiffs excepted from classified service, § 2-41. (Back)

--- (4) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 59-13, which amended Ord. No. 58-23, was enacted on June 16, 1959, effective ten (10) days thereafter. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
