<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XII._FAIR_CREDIT_DISCLOSURE_AND_</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-271. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
As used herein:
<section prefix = "a">
Consumer reporting agency means any individual, partnership, corporation, trust, estate, cooperative, association, or other entity which is defined as a consumer reporting agency by the Federal Fair Credit Reporting Act, including amendments thereto, and which does business in Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Consumer means an individual.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Investigative consumer report means a report which is subject to the provisions of the Federal Fair Credit Reporting Act, including amendments thereto, as they relate to investigative consumer reports.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Field representative means any person who collects information in Miami-Dade County on a consumer's character, general reputation, personal characteristics or mode of living through personal interviews with neighbors, friends, associates or acquaintances of the consumer reported for the purpose of preparing investigative consumer reports. The term includes agents and employees of consumer reporting agencies.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Medical information means information or records obtained, with the consent of the individual to whom it relates, from licensed physicians or medical practitioners, hospitals, clinics, or other medical or medically related facilities.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-272. Disclosures to consumers</catch_line>
<text>
Every consumer reporting agency shall, upon request and proper identification of any consumer, provide said consumer with a copy of its investigative consumer report (except such portions of reports containing medical information) pertaining to said consumer at the time of the request. The sources of information acquired solely for use in preparing an investigative consumer report and actually used for no other purpose need not be disclosed. It shall be sufficient for the purposes of this section if a carbon or photostatic copy of the report is provided to the consumer.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-273. Charge for disclosures</catch_line>
<text>
The consumer reporting agency may impose a reasonable charge on the consumer for furnishing a copy of its investigative consumer report to such consumer pursuant to Section 8A-272 of this article, the charge for which shall be indicated to the consumer prior to furnishing the copy and shall not exceed the cost of copying the report.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-274. Provisions as to liability</catch_line>
<text>
No consumer may bring any action or proceeding in the nature of defamation, invasion of privacy, or negligence with respect to the reporting of information against any consumer reporting agency, any user of information, or any person who furnishes information to a consumer reporting agency based on information disclosed pursuant to ordinance Section 8A-272 except as to false information furnished with malice or willful intent to injure such consumer, and then only to the same extent and under the same circumstances as provided for by Title 15, U.S.C., Section 1681n and Section 1681o, which are incorporated herein by reference, to wit:
"Civil liability for willful noncompliance.
Any consumer reporting agency or user of information which willfully fails to comply with any requirement imposed under this subchapter with respect to any consumer is liable to that consumer in an amount equal to the sum of—
<section prefix = "1">
any actual damages sustained by the consumer as a result of the failure;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
such amount of punitive damages as the court may allow; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
in the case of any successful action to enforce any liability under this section, the costs of the action together with reasonable attorney's fees as determined by the court.

"Civil liability for negligent noncompliance.
Any consumer reporting agency or user of information which is negligent in failing to comply with any requirement imposed under this subchapter with respect to any consumer is liable to that consumer in an amount equal to the sum of—
<section prefix = "1">
any actual damages sustained by the consumer as a result of the failure;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
in the case of any successful action to enforce any liability under this section, the costs of the action together with reasonable attorney's fees as determined by the court."


</section>
</section>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 75-51, § 4, repealed former § 8A-274, relative to restrictions on field representatives, and enacted in lieu thereof a new § 8A-274 as herein set out. Former § 8A-274 was derived from Ord. No. 74-55, § 4, adopted July 2, 1974, and Ord. No. 74-87, § 4, adopted Oct. 15, 1974.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-274.1. Notification of deleted or disputed information</catch_line>
<text>
Following any deletion from an investigative consumer report of information which is found to be inaccurate or whose accuracy can no longer be verified or any notation as to disputed information, the consumer reporting agency shall, at the request of the consumer, furnish notification that the item has been deleted or the statement, codification or summary pursuant to the Federal Fair Credit Reporting Act, including amendments thereto, to any person specifically designated by the consumer who has within two (2) years prior thereto received an investigative consumer report which contained the deleted or disputed information. The consumer reporting agency shall clearly and conspicuously disclose to the consumer his rights to make such a request. Such disclosure shall be made at or prior to the time the information is deleted or the consumer's statement regarding the disputed information is received. The charge, if any, for such notification shall be as provided in the Federal Fair Credit Reporting Act, including amendments thereto.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-274.2. Supervision of field representatives</catch_line>
<text>
The consumer reporting agency shall maintain reasonable procedures to insure maximum possible accuracy of investigative consumer reports. Such procedures insofar as all investigative consumer reports completed by field representatives with less than one (1) year experience shall include supervision of such field representatives by the person in charge of the consumer reporting agency or his delegate.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-274.3. Qualifications of field representatives</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
All field representatives shall be of good moral character and reputation. The consumer reporting agency shall conduct a background investigation on all prospective field representatives to include information about the person's moral character and reputation.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The consumer reporting agency shall require each field representative to submit to a written examination approved by the Miami-Dade County Consumer Protection Division concerning the Federal Fair Credit Reporting Act and the Miami-Dade County Fair Investigative Consumer Reporting and Disclosure Ordinance to affirmatively show that such field representative is familiar with the provisions of said statute and ordinance. Such examination shall be administered by the consumer reporting agency. The consumer reporting agency shall maintain evidence in its personnel files showing that each field representative has satisfactorily completed the examination.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
A consumer reporting agency shall furnish to each field representative an identification card which shall contain the field representative's name, physical description, and the name and business address of the consumer reporting agency. The identification card shall at all times be kept in the possession of the field representative and upon request the same shall be produced for inspection.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Each consumer reporting agency shall notify the Director, Consumer Protection Division, Miami-Dade County, Florida, within five (5) working days of a field representative's employment and termination of employment.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 74-87, § 5(3), 10-15-74; Ord. No. 75-51, § 7, 7-2-75)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-275. Penalty for violation</catch_line>
<text>
Any person including any consumer reporting agency, field representative, or any agent or employee thereof, who fails to comply with the provisions of this article shall be guilty of a violation of this article and upon conviction thereof shall be punished by a fine of not less than one thousand dollars ($1,000.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for not more than one (1) year, or by both such fine and imprisonment in the discretion of the County court.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (13) ---
Editor's note— Article XII, §§ 8A-271—8A-275, as derived from Ord. No. 74-55, §§ 1—5, adopted July 2, 1974, as amended. Ord. No. 74-57, § 1, adopted July 9, 1974, amended Ord. No. 74-55 to provide that the effective date of the ordinance would be Aug. 30, 1974. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
