<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_LXXI._PROTECTION_OF_PERSONS_DISC</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-967.1. Legislative findings and purpose</catch_line>
<text>
The Board of County Commissioners finds that it is in the best interest of the County to ensure that persons who have knowledge of unlawful activity, misfeasance or malfeasance by the County or independent contractors report such knowledge to the appropriate authorities for investigation and corrective action In order to encourage persons to report such information without fear of reprisal, it shall be the policy of the County to prohibit adverse action against a person for disclosing such information to an appropriate official or agency and, if appropriate, to reward such person when the information disclosed leads to the County's recovery of public funds.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-967.2. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
As used in this Article:
<section prefix = "1">
County shall include all Miami-Dade County departments, and all political subdivisions and special districts under the County Commission's legislative authority.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Employee shall mean a person who performs services for, and under the control and direction of, the County for wages or other remuneration.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Independent contractor shall mean a person, other than a federal, state or local government entity, engaged in any business and who enters into a contract with the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Person shall mean any natural person, corporation, firm, joint venture or entity other than a federal, state or local government entity or any employee thereof.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-967.3. Actions prohibited</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
No County employee shall take any adverse action that affects the rights or interests of any person in retaliation for the person's disclosure of information under this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The provisions of this article shall not be applicable when a person discloses information known by the person to be false.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 96-41, ยง 1, 3-5-96)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-967.4. Nature of information disclosed</catch_line>
<text>
The information disclosed under this article must include:
<section prefix = "1">
Any violation or suspected violation of any federal, state or local law, rule or regulation committed by an employee or agent of the County or independent contractor which creates and presents a substantial and specific danger to the public's health, safety or welfare; or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Any act or suspected act of gross mismanagement, malfeasance, misfeasance, gross waste of public funds, or gross neglect of duty committed by an employee or agent of the County or an independent contractor.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-967.5. To whom information disclosed</catch_line>
<text>
The information disclosed under this article must be disclosed to the County Manager or such official or officials as he may designate to receive such information on his behalf or any other appropriate public authority.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-967.6. Persons protected</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
This article protects persons who disclose information on their own initiative in a written and signed complaint; who are requested to participate in an investigation, hearing, or other inquiry conducted by the County, any state agency or federal government entity having the authority to investigate, police, manage, or otherwise remedy the violation or act; who refuse to participate in any adverse action prohibited by this article, or who are otherwise protected by the State Whistle-blower's Act. The provisions of this article may not be used by persons while they are under the care, custody, or control of the state or county correctional system, or after their release from the care, custody or control of the state or county correctional system, with respect to circumstances that occurred during any period of incarceration.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
No remedy or other protection under this article applies to any person who has committed or intentionally participated in committing a violation or suspected violation for which protection under this article is being sought.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
lt shall be an affirmative defense to any complaint brought pursuant to this article that the adverse action was predicated upon grounds other than, and would have been taken absent, the person's exercise of rights protected by this article.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 96-41, ยง 1, 3-5-96)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-967.7. Procedure where complaint of retaliation</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Any person protected by this article may file a written complaint within sixty (60) days after the action prohibited by this Article with the County Manager. The County Manager shall refer the complaint to the Independent Review Panel. The Independent Review Panel shall conduct a hearing after notice to the complainant, the respondent and the County department, political subdivision, special district or independent contractor involved. Any interested party may procure the attendance of witnesses and the production of records at such hearings in the manner provided by Section 2-50. All hearings requested pursuant to this paragraph shall be commenced insofar as is practicable within sixty (60) days of the County Manager's receipt of the complaint, except that the County Manager shall have the authority to extend such time for reasonable cause.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Independent Review Panel shall transmit its findings of fact, conclusions of law and any recommendation(s) together with the transcript of all evidence taken and all exhibits received by the Independent Review Panel to the County Manager for a final decision. The Manager may sustain, reverse or modify any action recommended by the Independent Review Panel. In any case in which the Independent Review Panel finds that the person filed a frivolous complaint in bad faith, the Independent Review Panel may direct the person to pay the costs of the hearing, including attorney's fees.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 96-41, ยง 1, 3-5-96)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-967.8. Relief</catch_line>
<text>
In any case brought under this article in which the County Manager or any other appropriate public authority finds that the person has been subjected to an adverse action in violation of this article, the Manager may:
<section prefix = "a">
Refer the matter to the appropriate department head for appropriate disciplinary action, if any;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Compensate the person, if appropriate, for the lost income, benefits or other lost remuneration caused by the adverse action.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-967.9. Reporting person's award program</catch_line>
<text>
Persons who report information pursuant to this article which results in the County's recovery of public funds shall be eligible to apply for an award of up to ten (10) percent of the net amount recovered or fifty thousand dollars ($50,000.00), whichever is less. The precise amount of any such award shall be set by the County Manager in accordance with the following procedure: The Manager shall select for each application a panel of three (3) County administrators who shall conduct an informal hearing for the purpose of recommending to the County Manager whether an award should be granted and the amount of any such award. The panel's recommendation shall include consideration of:
<section prefix = "1">
The significance of the information revealed to improving the efficiency of the County;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The likelihood that the County would have learned of the information if the person had not reported it; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
If the information was reported by more than one person, whether and how it should be apportioned.

The panel's written recommendation shall be submitted to the Manager whose decision as to whether an award should be granted and the amount thereof shall be final.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-967.10. Existing rights</catch_line>
<text>
This article shall not be construed to diminish the rights, privileges or remedies of any person under any other law or rule.
</text>
</law>
