<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_VI._OFFICE_OF_FAIR_EMPLOYMENT_PR</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 11A-34. Declaration of policy</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
It has been and is the policy of Miami-Dade County to provide equal employment opportunity for all without regard to race, sex, color, national origin, religion, age, disability, ancestry, marital status, pregnancy, sexual orientation or veteran's status and to prohibit unlawful discrimination on such basis.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
It is further the policy of Miami-Dade County to ensure equal opportunity within the County employment system by engaging in voluntary affirmative action to promote diversity within the County work force and employ a representative work force. However, nothing in this section shall be interpreted to require the County to grant preferential treatment to any individual because of sexual orientation.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 97-17, ยง 1, 2-25-97; Ord. No. 98-170, ยง 1, 12-1-98)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 11A-35. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 11A-37. Duties and powers</catch_line>
<text>
When used herein:
<section prefix = "a">
Affirmative action shall mean a program to ensure equal employment opportunity and treatment for all qualified individuals without regard to race, color, religion, national origin, age, disability, sex, marital status, pregnancy, veteran's status or sexual orientation, and to every extent possible, eliminate areas of underutilization in employment of minorities, women and persons with disabilities. However, nothing in this section shall be interpreted to require the County to grant preferential treatment to any individual because of sexual orientation.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Office shall mean the Miami-Dade County Office of Fair Employment Practices, a division of the Office of the County Manager.

</section>
</text>
When used herein:
<section prefix = "a">
Affirmative action shall mean a program to ensure equal employment opportunity and treatment for all qualified individuals without regard to race, color, religion, national origin, age, disability, sex, marital status, pregnancy, veteran's status or sexual orientation, and to every extent possible, eliminate areas of underutilization in employment of minorities, women and persons with disabilities. However, nothing in this section shall be interpreted to require the County to grant preferential treatment to any individual because of sexual orientation.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Office shall mean the Miami-Dade County Office of Fair Employment Practices, a division of the Office of the County Manager.

Sec 11A-36. Miami-Dade County Office of Fair Employment Practices recognized; office of Director established.
<section prefix = "a">
The position of Director of the Office of Fair Employment Practices is hereby created and established. The Director shall be appointed by and will serve at the will of the County Mayor. The position shall be exempt from the classified service of the County. The County Mayor shall appoint such assistants to the Director as may be necessary, subject to budgetary limitations.
</section>
</section>
When used herein:
<section prefix = "a">
Affirmative action shall mean a program to ensure equal employment opportunity and treatment for all qualified individuals without regard to race, color, religion, national origin, age, disability, sex, marital status, pregnancy, veteran's status or sexual orientation, and to every extent possible, eliminate areas of underutilization in employment of minorities, women and persons with disabilities. However, nothing in this section shall be interpreted to require the County to grant preferential treatment to any individual because of sexual orientation.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Office shall mean the Miami-Dade County Office of Fair Employment Practices, a division of the Office of the County Manager.

Sec 11A-36. Miami-Dade County Office of Fair Employment Practices recognized; office of Director established.
<section prefix = "a">
The position of Director of the Office of Fair Employment Practices is hereby created and established. The Director shall be appointed by and will serve at the will of the County Mayor. The position shall be exempt from the classified service of the County. The County Mayor shall appoint such assistants to the Director as may be necessary, subject to budgetary limitations.
Sec. 11A-37. Duties and powers.
The duties, functions, powers and responsibilities of the Office and its Director shall include the following:
<section prefix = "1">
Pursuant to Section 11A-28, jurisdiction over complaints of employment discrimination by county employees and applicants arising under Article IV of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Enforcement of the provisions of this article and rules and regulations promulgated hereunder.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Overall jurisdiction in the development implementation and monitoring of fair employment guidelines as they relate internally to Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Subject to the approval of the County Mayor or County Mayor's designee and the County Attorney, review and approve department affirmative action plans which address underutilization of minorities, women and the disabled.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Monitor County hiring and employment practices to ensure compliance with federal and state employment discrimination legislation. Reports of noncompliance shall be forwarded to the County Mayor or County Mayor's designee and the County Commission for review and determination.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Establish rules and procedures for processing and resolving complaints of employment discrimination by County employees.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Promulgation of rules and regulations to ensure fair employment practices within the County's employment system.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Assure that information and technical assistance is provided to all County administrators, County employees, and applicants for employment, concerning fair employment practices.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Publish and disseminate public information and materials relating to equal employment opportunities and fair employment practices, including serving as a fair employment resource to the community at large.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Make annual reports to the County Mayor or County Mayor's designee and the County Commission concerning the status of Miami-Dade County employment system as it relates to fair employment practices, the enforcement of the provisions of this article and recommendations concerning methods by which to improve the County's fair employment practices.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Perform such other administrative duties as may be assigned by the County Mayor.

</section>
</section>
</section>
<catch_line>Sec. 11A-37.1. Appeals process</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Any County employee or applicant protected by Section 11A-27 may file an appeal of an adverse determination of the Director within fifteen (15) days of receipt of the determination, unless the complaint involves the discipline of an employee with a right to appeal under Section 2-47 of the Code. If the complaint involves the discipline of an employee with the right to appeal, any issue of discrimination or retaliation shall be resolved through the process established under Section 2-47 of the Code of Miami-Dade County or, to the extent available under any applicable collective bargaining agreement, through grievance and arbitration. County employees and applicants with the right to appeal the Director's determination shall have the right to have a hearing examiner appointed under this article, subject to budgetary appropriations by the Board of County Commissioners, to review the determination of the Director. The hearing examiner shall conduct an evidentiary hearing and make findings of fact and a recommendation as to whether there has been a violation of Section 11A-28 and if so shall recommend an appropriate remedy.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Any hearing examiner appointed pursuant to this article shall be sufficiently independent to assure that no external interference or influence adversely affects the independence and objectivity of the hearing officer. Accordingly, there will be no external influence on the hearing examiner in the performance of his or her duties from any persons, including the Mayor or any member of the administrative staff, and that no Commissioner or employee of a Commissioner shall take part in the appointment or removal of officers and employees in the administrative services of the County, as such external influence would adversely affect the independence and objectivity of the hearing examiner.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Upon receipt of a request for an appeal, the Director shall refer the appeal request to a hearing examiner available to serve as such under Section 2-47. Subject to budgetary appropriations by the Board of County Commissioners, such hearing examiners may be paid a fee for their services, but shall not be deemed County officials or employees within the purview of Sections 2-10.2, 2-11.1 or otherwise. The hearing examiner shall conduct a hearing after notice to the County employee or applicant and the County department involved. The hearing shall be conducted in accordance with the procedures applicable to hearings under Section 2-47, except as may be provided herein. Any interested party may procure the attendance of witnesses and the production of records at such hearing in the manner provided by Section 2-50. All hearings requested pursuant to this paragraph shall be commenced insofar as is practicable within one hundred twenty (120) days of the Director's determination, except that the Director shall have the authority to extend such time for reasonable cause.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The hearing examiner shall transmit his or her findings of facts, and any recommendations, including any proposed remedies as set forth in subsection (5) of this section, together with a transcript of all evidence taken before him or her and all exhibits received by him or her to the Mayor or Mayor's designee for a final decision. The Mayor or Mayor's designee may sustain, reverse or modify the Director's decision. In any case in which the hearing examiner finds that the employee filed a frivolous complaint in bad faith, the hearing examiner may recommend and the Mayor or Mayor's designee may direct the employee to pay the costs of the hearing, including the County's attorney's fees.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Remedies. In the event the hearing examiner finds that there has been a violation of Section 11A-28, he or she may recommend the following remedies, and no others:
<section prefix = "a">
Hiring of the applicant or promotion of the employee with accrued seniority, with accrued benefits and with back pay;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Reinstatement of the employee to the same position held before the adverse action was commenced or to an equivalent position, or award reasonable front pay as alternative relief;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Reinstatement of the employee's fringe benefits and seniority rights, as appropriate;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Compensation of the employee, if appropriate, for lost wages, benefits or other lost remuneration caused by the adverse action; and/or
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Requiring reasonable accommodation.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
The Mayor or the Mayor's designee's final order shall be subject to review in accordance with the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure. For purposes of such review, any original jurisdictional notices required to be filed under the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure shall be filed with the Director. The Director shall provide the index and record on appeal when required by, and in accordance with, the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure. A fee may be charged by the Director for the preparation and transmission of the record on appeal to the court of competent jurisdiction. Such fee may be waived by the Director if the party requesting the record is indigent.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Any County employee found to have discriminated or retaliated against another County employee or applicant in violation of this section shall be considered to have committed a violation of the section and shall be subject to disciplinary action up to and including dismissal from County employment.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
A career service employee, except in the case of disciplinary action, shall have the option of utilizing an unfair labor practice procedure, or a grievance procedure established under Section 447.101 of the Florida Statutes or the procedures set forth in this Article VI, but such employee is precluded from availing himself or herself to more than one of these procedures. Applicants shall have the option of utilizing an unfair labor practice procedure or the procedures set forth in this Article VI, but such applicant is precluded from availing himself or herself to more than one of these procedures. Once an employee or applicant has selected a forum for his or her appeal to be heard, he/she is bound by that decision and cannot seek to be reheard in another forum.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
The Mayor or the Mayor's designee shall provide an annual report to the Board of County Commissioners with regard to the number of cases filed under this Article VI and the disposition of said cases.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 13-39, ยง 4, 5-7-13)</history>
</law>
