<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_CXXXII._COMMUNITY_ACTION_AGENCY_</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2043. Creation and purpose</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created the advisory board called the "Community Action Agency Board." The purpose of the Community Action Agency Board is to advise the County on the development, planning, implementation and evaluation of its Community Services Block Grant programs and other programs administered by the Community Action Agency; to advise the County on efforts or mechanisms to facilitate the reduction in poverty, the revitalization of low income communities and the empowerment of low income families and individuals to become self-sufficient; to provide for the oversight of quality services for the children and families served by the County's Head Start/Early Head Start program; and to make decisions related to the design and implementation of the County's Head Start/Early Head Start program on behalf of the Board of County Commissioners.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2044. The board composition; petition process; interim board composition</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Community Action Agency Board shall consist of forty-five (45) members as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
Elected officials.
<section prefix = "a">
Fifteen (15) members shall be the following elected officials:
<section prefix = "1">
The Mayor of Miami-Dade County;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The thirteen (13) Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The City of Miami Mayor;
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
These elected officials may appoint a designee to serve on their behalf.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
If an elected official selects a designee to serve on the Community Action Agency Board, the elected official shall submit a letter on an annual basis advising the Community Action Agency Board of such designation.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
If the elected official leaves office or his/her term of office expires and such elected official had selected a designee to serve, such designee may continue to serve until the newly elected official takes his/her seat with the Community Action Agency Board or appoints his/her own designee.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Citizen participants. Sixteen (16) members shall be individuals who reside within sixteen (16) defined different target areas served by the Community Action Agency, are sufficiently representative of the individuals/families that reside within that specific target area and are selected through a democratic process developed by Miami-Dade County and delineated in the Community Action Agency's Board bylaws. No two (2) members shall reside in the same target area. However, in the event that the number of citizen participants exceeds the number of target areas, more than one citizen participant may reside in the same target area, provided that each target area has at least one representative. A target area shall mean a neighborhood of low income individuals and families served by the Community Action Agency.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Community interests and organizations.
<section prefix = "a">
The remaining fourteen (14) members shall be representatives from the following: business; industry; labor; religious; law enforcement; social welfare; and education. Of the fourteen (14) members one shall be the Chair or his/her designee of the County's Head Start/Early Head Start Policy Council and one shall be the Chair or his/her designee of the County's Elderly Programs Committee of the Department of Human Services.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
There shall be a Nominating Committee, which will be convened by the County Manager, to select the initial twelve (12) members and fill any future vacancies. Such Nominating Committee shall consist of the Mayor of Miami-Dade County or his/her designee, the Chair of the Community Action Agency Board and the Chair of the Commission Committee of jurisdiction over the Community Action Agency or his/her designee. The Nominating Committee shall convene at least three (3) months prior to the scheduled vacancy of any position. The Chair of the Community Action Agency Board shall serve as the Chair of the Nominating Committee. The Nominating Committee shall solicit recommendations from the public to fill vacancies on the Community Action Agency Board by providing the public with notice of the availability of such position(s). The Nominating Committee shall review all recommendations and then submit a name for each vacancy plus an additional two (2) names to the Board of County Commissioners. The Board of County Commissioners shall make the appointments to the Community Action Agency Board from the candidates recommended by the Nominating Committee or request a new list of candidates for any of the vacant positions. In the event that the Board of County Commissioners requests additional candidates, the Nominating Committee will devise the process for developing said list.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Ex-officio members. The Board of County Commissioners may appoint ex-officio non-voting members, as recommended by the Community Action Agency Board. Such ex-officio members shall not count toward a quorum.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Petition process. The Community Action Agency Board, in order to comply with Community Services Block Grant funding requirements, shall establish a procedure in its bylaws to allow any individual living in a target area served by the Community Action Agency, a representative of individuals who reside in a target area served by the Community Action Agency or any community or religious organization, to petition for adequate representation on the Community Action Agency Board if they believe they are underrepresented.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Interim board composition. The Community Action Agency Board that exists at the time of the passage of this ordinance shall serve as the interim board for no more than ninety (90) days after the effective date of this ordinance, while the new Community Action Agency Board is convened.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 09-31, § 2, 5-5-09)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2045. Terms, reappointment, vacancies and attendance</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Elected officials or designees are not subject to length of terms or limits on consecutive terms and shall serve as long as s/he is in office.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
All other members shall serve two-year terms, except that the length of the terms of the initial appointees shall be adjusted to stagger the terms.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
A member may be reappointed; however, a member may not serve more than four (4) consecutive terms. A member who has served four (4) consecutive terms is eligible to be appointed again after a two-year hiatus from the Community Action Agency Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Vacancies shall be filled in the same manner that initial appointments are filled.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
A member may be removed for failure to comply with the attendance requirements set out in Section 2-11.39 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida as amended, or for any other reason as established in the Community Action Agency Board Bylaws.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 09-31, § 3, 5-5-09)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2046. Reimbursement</catch_line>
<text>
Members of the Community Action Agency Board shall serve without compensation, but may be entitled to receive reimbursement for out of town travel expenses consistent with the provisions of § 112.061, Florida Statutes.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2047. Organization, procedure and orientation</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Bylaws. The Community Action Agency Board shall make and adopt bylaws for its guidance, operation, governance and maintenance, provided such bylaws, and any amendments thereto, are consistent with federal and state laws and county ordinances, rules, regulations, policies and procedures and have been approved for form and legal sufficiency by the County Attorney's Office.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Officers. Immediately after the members are appointed, including the fourteen (14) Community Interests members appointed by the Board of County Commissioners, the members of the Community Action Agency Board shall elect a chair, a vice-chair and other officers as designated in the bylaws. An interim chair, vice-chair and other officers may be elected to serve until such time as the fourteen (14) members appointed by the Board of County Commissioners have been selected. Officers shall be elected for a two-year term.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Committees. The Community Action Agency Board shall have an executive committee and a finance committee. Other committee(s) considered necessary to address the core mission of the Community Action Agency shall be designated in the bylaws. The bylaws shall also allow for the creation of ad hoc committees as necessary.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Meetings.
<section prefix = "1">
Meetings shall be conducted upon the call of the chairperson; however, the Community Action Agency Board shall meet on a regular basis as determined in the bylaws during the County's fiscal year.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
All Community Action Agency Board meetings must be timely noticed at least seven (7) but not more than thirty (30) days prior to the meeting. Such notice shall be provided to the media and a copy shall be maintained at the Community Action Agency. However, if immediate action is necessary to address a matter of imminent harm to public health, safety and welfare, the Community Action Agency Board may schedule a meeting with no less than twenty-four (24) hours' notice.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Minutes shall be kept of all meetings of the Community Action Agency Board and such minutes shall be available for inspection by any interested person.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
All meetings shall be open to the public.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Quorum. A quorum of the Community Action Agency Board shall be one-half (½) of the total number of members seated on the Community Action Agency Board plus one (1).
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Inquiries and communications. All inquiries or communications from the Community Action Agency Board or any of its members to the Community Action Agency or to the County shall be made through the Chair of the Community Action Agency Board. Informal communications may be made freely from the Community Action Agency to the Community Action Agency Board members, pursuant to the Sunshine Laws.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Orientation. All new members of the Community Action Agency Board shall receive sufficient training and orientation to enable them to perform their duties.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 09-31, § 5, 5-5-09)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2048. Powers and duties</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Community Action Agency Board shall have the following powers and duties with regard to the Community Services Block Grant funding and programs:
<section prefix = "1">
To advise the Board of County Commissioners regarding: the development, planning, implementation and evaluation of Community Service Block Grant programs and other programs administered by the Community Action Agency; issues and causes of poverty in Miami-Dade County; the reduction of such poverty; the revitalization of low income communities; and the empowerment of low income families and individuals to become self-sufficient;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To provide guidance and support to the Board of County Commissioners, the Mayor and the County Manager in identifying and helping to reduce the causes of poverty in Miami-Dade County;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
To assist in the identification of public and private resources at the local, state, and federal levels to promote self-sufficiency, family stability and community revitalization for economically disadvantaged persons;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
To involve economically disadvantaged persons in developing and carrying out anti-poverty programs and encouraging their regular participation in the implementation of these programs;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
To ensure the Community Action Agency is in compliance with all governing federal, state, county laws, regulations, policies and procedures, grant and contractual requirements;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
To encourage and support coordination with other agencies dedicated to the eradication of poverty and the empowerment of the economically disadvantaged so as to avoid whenever possible overlap and duplication of services;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
To approve and provide a Community Action Plan every two years, which shall serve as a written or oral report, to the Board of County Commissioners and the written report to the State of Florida. The Community Action Plan shall contain, but not be limited to, the following information:
<section prefix = "a">
A community needs assessment update (including food needs);
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A description of the service delivery system targeted to low income individuals and families in the regions;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
A description of how linkages will be developed to fill identified gaps in services through information, referral, case management, and follow-up consultation;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
A description of how Community Service Block Grant funding will be coordinated with other public and private resources;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
A description of outcome measures to be used to monitor success in promoting self-sufficiency, family stability, and community revitalization and a description of the Community Action Agency's success in promoting these activities.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
A description of how the Community Action Plan interfaces with and is coordinated with Miami-Dade County's Strategic Plan;
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Any other information that the Community Action Agency is required to gather as a condition of receiving Community Service Block Grant funds from the State of Florida or the federal government; and
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
To perform any other duties or responsibilities that may from time to time be required as a condition of receiving Community Service Block Grant funds from the State of Florida or the federal government.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Community Action Agency Board shall have the following powers and duties with regard to Head Start/Early Head Start funding and programs:
<section prefix = "1">
To adopt practices that are consistent with federal regulations and that assure active, independent and informed governance of the County's Head Start/Early Head Start program. Adoption of any such practices shall be documented as a report and presented to the Board of County Commissioners;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To fully participate in the development, planning and evaluation of the County's Head Start/Early Head Start program as may be delineated more specifically in the CAA Board's bylaws;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
To ensure compliance with all applicable Federal, State and County laws and regulations;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
To recommend to the Board of County Commissioners for final approval the selection of service areas and delegate agencies, once any necessary Policy Council approval is attained and is consistent with County procurement policies and procedures;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
To review, consistent with County procurement policies and procedures, contracts and agreements under one million dollars, which are necessary for the day-to-day operation of the County's Head Start/Early Head Start program, including but not limited to, contracts with delegate agencies and ancillary service providers. The Community Action Agency Board shall review said contracts and agreements and send their recommendations to the Mayor or Mayor's designee for final review and approval. All other contracts and agreements shall be forwarded, with a recommendation from the Community Action Agency Board, to the Board of County Commissioners for final approval;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
To establish procedures and criteria for recruitment, selection and enrollment of children;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
To review and make recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners regarding all Head Start/Early Head Start program funding applications and amendments;
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
To establish procedures and guidelines for accessing and collecting information for review by the Board of County Commissioners as the governing body and the Policy Council regarding program planning, policies and Head Start/Early Head Start program operations. The CAA Board shall provide a quarterly report to the Board of County Commissioners ensuring that all planning, policies and Head Start/Early Head Start program operations are proceeding efficiently and according to the requirements of the Head Start Act. Additional reports outside of this quarterly reporting period shall be required to inform the Board of County Commissioners of issues and instances of exceptional importance that require immediate attention;
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Consistent with the County's financial management structure, to: approve all major Head Start/Early Head Start financial expenditures; approve the Head Start/Early Head Start operating budget, prior to final approval by the Board of County Commissioners; oversee audit findings and other actions necessary to comply with applicable laws and regulations governing financial statements and accounting practices; review and approve the annual self-assessment and financial audit; review and approve the County's progress in carrying out the programmatic and fiscal provisions in the County's grant application, including implementation of corrective actions; and review results from federal monitoring, including appropriate follow-up activities;
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
To establish advisory committees to oversee key responsibilities related to program governance and improvement of the County's Head Start/Early Head Start program if so approved by the Board of County Commissioners. If said advisory committee is approved by the Board of County Commissioners, the CAA Board shall contact the Office of Head Start and present information regarding the formation and purpose of the advisory committee;
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
To provide the following information to the Board of County Commissioners in an annual report:
<section prefix = "a">
A list of approved delegate agencies and service areas;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Procedures and criteria for recruiting, selecting and enrolling children in the County's Head Start/Early Head Start program;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All approved contracts and agreements pursuant to subsection (b)(5);
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
A copy of the annual report required by the Head Start Act.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
All other powers and duties not specifically delegated hereunder shall remain with the Board of County Commissioners as the federally-recognized governing body of the County's Head Start/Early Head Start program with the legal and fiscal responsibility for administering and overseeing programs under the Head Start Act, including the safeguarding of federal funds.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
To perform any other duties that may from time to time be designated by the Board of County Commissioners through a resolution.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 09-31, § 6, 5-5-09)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2049. Applicability of Federal, State and County Laws</catch_line>
<text>
The Community Action Agency Board shall be regulated by: the Community Service Block Grant statutes, regulations, resolutions, policies and contracts, including the conflicting interest prohibitions; the Head Start Act and regulations, as may be amended from time to time; Chapter 286 of Florida Statutes, ("Sunshine Law"); Chapter 119 of Florida Statutes ("Public Records Act"); Chapter 112, Part III of Florida Statutes ("Code of Ethics for Public Officers and Employees"); Section 2-11.1 of Miami-Dade County Code ("Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance"); and Article IB of Miami-Dade County Code ("Standards for Creation and Review of Boards Generally") to the extent that these County requirements do not conflict with federal and state Community Service Block Grant funding requirements.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2050. Staff support</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager's Office shall designate appropriate staff to support the Community Action Agency Board.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2051. Legal counsel</catch_line>
<text>
The County Attorney's Office shall provide legal counsel, as needed, to the Community Action Agency Board.
</text>
</law>
