<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 26 PARK AND RECREATION DEPARTMENT RULES AND REGULATIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_III._THE_SHANNON_MELENDI_ACT</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 26-37. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
As used in this article the following terms shall have the following meanings:
<section prefix = "A">
Community-based Organization (CBO) shall refer to any not-for-profit agency, group, organization, society, association, partnership, or individual whose primary purpose is to provide a community service to improve or enhance the well-being of the community of Miami-Dade County at large or to improve or enhance the well-being of certain individuals within this community who have special needs.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Child Event Worker shall refer to any full-time or part-time employee, agent, volunteer, independent contractor, or employee or volunteer of an independent contractor of a carnival or fair that hosts amusement rides in a park owned or operated by Miami-Dade County. The following persons shall be exempted from this definition:
<section prefix = "1">
Law enforcement personnel;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Emergency or fire rescue personnel;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Persons conducting deliveries; and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Military recruitment personnel.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Conviction shall refer to a determination of guilt of a criminal charge which is the result of a trial or the entry of a plea of guilty or nolo contendere, regardless of whether adjudication is withheld.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
Park vendor shall refer to any full-time or part-time employee, agent, volunteer, independent contractor, or employee or volunteer of an independent contractor that has a contract with, or permit from, Miami-Dade County to rent or sell food, beverages, sporting equipment, or any other goods or services in a park owned or operated by Miami-Dade County. The following persons and events shall be exempted from this definition:
<section prefix = "1">
Law enforcement personnel;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Emergency or fire rescue personnel;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Persons conducting deliveries;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
International or national sporting events;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
One-day events; and
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Carnivals, festivals, trade shows, and fairs that do not host amusement rides.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
Professional Background Screener shall refer to any person, company, organization or agency which, for monetary fees, dues, or on a not-for-profit basis, regularly engages in whole or in part in the practice of researching and assembling criminal history information on specific persons for the purpose of furnishing criminal history reports to third parties.
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
Programming Partner shall refer to any Not-For-Profit Program Service Provider that is selected by the Department under Article II of this chapter and the accompanying Administrative Order to provide programs in County Park and Recreation Facilities.
</section>
<section prefix = "G">
Sexual Offender shall include any individual who meets the criteria of a "sexual predator" as defined in Section 775.21(4) of the Florida Statutes, or a "sexual offender" as defined in Section 943.0435 of the Florida Statutes, or who is listed on the National Sex Offender Public Website owned or operated by the United States Department of Justice.
</section>
<section prefix = "H">
Violent felony shall refer to the following felonies: arson; sexual battery; robbery; kidnapping; aggravated child abuse; aggravated abuse of an elderly person or disabled adult; aggravated assault with a deadly weapon; murder; manslaughter; aggravated manslaughter of an elderly person or disabled adult; aggravated manslaughter of a child; unlawful throwing, placing, or discharging of a destructive device or bomb; armed burglary; aggravated battery; or aggravated stalking.
</section>
<section prefix = "I">
Volunteer shall refer to any individual performing volunteer duties for a CBO, for a Programming Partner, for the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department as a child event worker, or as a park vendor for more than three (3) days in any six (6) month period. Students volunteering in order to fulfill high school graduation requirements shall be exempted from this definition.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 26-38. Background checks required for child event workers, park vendors, and programming partner or community-based organization (CBO) employees and volunteers</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Upon adoption of this ordinance [Ord. No. 08-07], employers of child event workers, employers of park vendors, and Programming Partners and CBOs shall secure a nationwide criminal background check of all existing child event workers, park vendors, employees, and volunteers whose duties require physical presence on park property owned or operated by Miami-Dade County. In addition, prior to employing or allowing to volunteer a person whose duties would require physical presence on park property owned or operated by Miami-Dade County, employers of child event workers, employers of park vendors, and Programming Partners and CBOs shall secure a nationwide criminal background check of all such prospective child event workers, park vendors, employees or volunteers.
The nationwide criminal background checks shall be conducted by a Professional Background Screener and shall include a report as to whether each child event worker, park vendor, staff member or volunteer is listed on the National Sex Offender Public Registry, and a comprehensive report and analysis, obtained from no less than two independent databases/sources, on the nationwide criminal history of such child event worker, park vendor, staff member or volunteer.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Every three (3) years thereafter, employers of park vendors, and Programming Partners and CBOs shall secure nationwide criminal background checks for existing park vendors, staff members, and volunteers whose duties require physical presence on park property owned or operated by Miami-Dade County. However, employers of child event workers shall secure nationwide criminal background checks for existing child event workers whose duties require physical presence on park property owned or operated by Miami-Dade County every year thereafter.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Any child event worker, park vendor, or staff member or volunteer of a Programming Partner or CBO who:
<section prefix = "1">
Has been convicted of a violent felony or conspiracy to commit a violent felony within the past five (5) years; or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Has been convicted of a felony involving the trafficking of a controlled substance within the past (5) years; or
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Has two (2) or more convictions for a violent felony, for conspiracy to commit a violent felony, or involving the trafficking of a controlled substance; or
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Is a sexual offender or a sexual predator; or
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Has failed to provide the employer, Programming Partner or CBO with proof of United States citizenship or legal immigration status in the United States,
shall be prohibited from working or volunteering on park property owned or operated by Miami-Dade County. All child event workers, park vendors, and staff members and volunteers of a Programming Partner or CBO shall submit to their employer, to the Programming Partner, or to the CBO an affidavit affirming that no work or volunteer duties will be performed on park property owned or operated by Miami-Dade County in violation of this subsection and that any arrest will be reported to his/her employer within forty-eight (48) hours of such arrest.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
Employers of child event workers shall maintain copies of the results of the criminal background checks required by this section for a period of two (2) years from the date they were secured, and employers of park vendors, Programming Partners, and CBOs shall maintain such copies for a period of three (3) years from the date they were secured. Employers of child event workers, employers of park vendors, and Programming Partners and CBOs shall maintain the affidavits required by Section 26-38.C. and the copies of the proof of United States citizenship or legal immigration status until the person is no longer a child event worker, park vendor, staff member, or volunteer.
Employers of child event workers, employers of park vendors, and Programming Partners and CBOs shall, upon request, provide copies of these documents to Miami-Dade County or to any law enforcement personnel with jurisdiction.
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
Every child event worker, park vendor, and staff member and volunteer of a Programming Partner or CBO shall wear, in a conspicuous and visible manner, an identification badge that contains his/her photograph and full name while working or volunteering on park property owned or operated by Miami-Dade County, except when in costume and during a performance. The identification badge shall be of a size, design, and format approved by the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
Penalties and Enforcement.
<section prefix = "1">
It shall be unlawful for an employer of child event workers, an employer of park vendors, or a Programming Partner or CBO to knowingly permit or allow any child event worker, park vendor, staff member, or volunteer to work or volunteer on park property owned or operated by Miami-Dade County in violation of Section 26-38
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
It shall be unlawful for any child event worker, park vendor, or staff member or volunteer of a Programming Partner or CBO to work or volunteer on park property owned or operated by Miami-Dade County in violation of Section 26-38
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Any person who shall violate a provision of Section 26-38, or who shall knowingly or willingly provide false or erroneous information to his/her employer, or fail to comply therewith, or with any of the requirements thereof, shall upon conviction thereof in the County Court, be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for not more than sixty (60) days, or by both such fine and imprisonment.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Any person who violates or fails to comply with Section 26-38 may be subject to civil penalties in accordance with Chapter 8CC of this Code. Each day of violation or noncompliance shall constitute a separate offense.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 08-07, ยง 2, 1-10-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 26-39. Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department employees and volunteers</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Upon adoption of this ordinance [Ord. No. 08-07], the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department shall secure a nationwide criminal background check of all existing employees and volunteers whose primary duties require physical presence on park property owned or operated by Miami-Dade County. In addition, the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department shall secure a nationwide criminal background fingerprint check prior to employing, or allowing to volunteer, a person whose primary duties would require physical presence on park property owned or operated by Miami-Dade County. This nationwide criminal background fingerprint check shall be conducted through the Florida Department of Law Enforcement.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Every three (3) years thereafter, the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department shall secure nationwide criminal background checks for existing employees and volunteers whose primary duties require physical presence on park property owned or operated by Miami-Dade County. These nationwide criminal background checks shall be conducted by a Professional Background Screener and shall include a report as to whether each employee or volunteer is located on the National Sex Offender Public Registry, and a comprehensive report and analysis, obtained from two independent databases/sources, on the nationwide criminal history of such employee or volunteer.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Any employee or volunteer of the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department who:
<section prefix = "1">
Has been convicted of a violent felony or conspiracy to commit a violent felony within the past five (5) years; or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Has been convicted of a felony involving the trafficking of a controlled substance within the past (5) years; or
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Has two (2) or more convictions for a violent felony, for conspiracy to commit a violent felony, or involving the trafficking of a controlled substance; or
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Is a sexual offender or a sexual predator; or
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Has failed to provide the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department with proof of United States citizenship or legal immigration status in the United States,
shall be prohibited from working or volunteering on park property owned or operated by Miami-Dade County. All employees and volunteers of the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department shall submit to the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department an affidavit affirming that no work or volunteer duties will be performed on park property owned or operated by Miami-Dade County in violation of this subsection and that any arrest will be reported to his/her employer within forty-eight (48) hours of such arrest.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
The Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department shall maintain copies of the results of the criminal background checks required by this section for a period of three (3) years from the date they were secured. The Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department shall maintain the affidavits required by Section 26-39.C. and shall maintain copies of the proof of United States citizenship or legal immigration status until the person is no longer an employee or volunteer.
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
Every employee and volunteer of the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department shall wear, in a conspicuous and visible manner, an identification badge that contains his/her photograph and full name while working or volunteering on park property owned or operated by Miami-Dade County, except when in costume and during a performance. The identification badge shall be of a size, design, and format approved by the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
Penalties and Enforcement.
<section prefix = "1">
It shall be unlawful for any volunteer of the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department to volunteer on park property owned or operated by Miami-Dade County in violation of Section 26-39
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Any volunteer who shall violate a provision of Section 26-39, or who shall knowingly or willingly provide false or erroneous information to the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department, or fail to comply therewith, or with any of the requirements thereof, shall upon conviction thereof in the County Court, be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for not more than sixty (60) days, or by both such fine and imprisonment.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Any volunteer who violates or fails to comply with Section 26-39 may be subject to civil penalties in accordance with Chapter 8CC of this Code. Each day of violation or noncompliance shall constitute a separate offense.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 08-07, ยง 2, 1-10-08)</history>
</law>
