<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_III._TOWING_OF_MOTOR_VEHICLES</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-461. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
For the purposes of this article, the following definitions shall apply:
<section prefix = "1">
Commission shall mean the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
(1.5)
Consent Tower shall mean a person who tows a motor vehicle with the consent of the vehicle owner.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
County Manager shall mean the chief executive officer and head of the administrative branch of County government as provided in Article 3 of the Home Rule Charter of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
CSD shall mean the Miami-Dade County Consumer Services Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Decal shall mean an identifying sticker issued by the Director and appropriate for display in the lower left corner of the front window of a towing vehicle or equipment or car carrier used by a person licensed under this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Director shall mean the CSD Director or the Director's designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Express instruction shall mean a clear, definite and explicit request:
<section prefix = "a">
Made in writing by a police officer to immobilize, recover, tow, remove or store a specific and individual vehicle which is disabled or abandoned or parked without authorization, or whose operator is unable or unwilling to remove the vehicle;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Made in writing by a property owner or duly authorized agent of the property owner to immobilize, recover, tow, remove or store a specific and individual vehicle parked without permission of the property owner; however, such property owner or agent shall not be the person requested to immobilize, recover, tow, remove or store the vehicle or an employee or agent thereof; or
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Made by telephone, in person or in writing by a vehicle owner or the authorized driver to recover, tow, remove or store a specific and individual vehicle which is in the lawful control of the vehicle owner or authorized driver requesting the towing service. The foregoing notwithstanding, where the property owner is a government entity, the property owner or an employee or agent thereof, may be the same person requested to recover, tow, remove or store the vehicle.
Every request made in writing or in person must indicate the date and time of the instruction and must be signed by the police officer, the property owner or agent, or the vehicle owner or authorized driver in the presence of the person providing the requested service. Every request made by telephone must also be documented with the date and time of the call.
(6.5)
Immobilization, immobilize or immobilizing, also known as boot or booting, shall mean the act of placing, on a parked vehicle, a mechanical device that is designed to be attached to the wheel or tire so as to prohibit its usual manner of movement.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Industry shall mean the business of recovering, towing or removing vehicles and providing such vehicle storage services as may be associated therewith.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
License shall mean the certificate or document which allows a person to engage in Miami-Dade County in the activity of recovering, towing, removing and storing of vehicles for compensation. As used in this article, "license" shall not mean a municipal occupational license or a County occupational license.
(8.5)
Nonconsent Tower shall mean persons who perform "Police Directed Tows" or "Private Property Impounds" as defined herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Operate shall mean to provide for compensation the services of recovering, towing or removing vehicles and any vehicle storage services associated therewith.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Operator shall mean any person who provides for compensation the services of recovering, towing, or removing vehicles and any vehicle storage services associated therewith.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Person shall mean any natural person, firm, partnership, association, corporation or other entity of any kind whatsoever.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Personnel authorized by the CSD shall mean enforcement personnel authorized by the Director and presenting valid identification.
(12.5)
Police Directed Tow shall mean the removal and storage of wrecked or disabled vehicles at the direction of police/law enforcement from an accident scene or the removal and storage of vehicles in the event the owner or operator is incapacitated, unavailable, or otherwise does not consent to the removal of the vehicle, excepting, however, all incidents of Private Property Impounds as herein defined.
(12.6)
Private Property Impound shall mean towing or removal of a vehicle, without the consent of the vehicle's owner or operator, as such is authorized by Section 715.07, Florida Statutes, as may be amended, when that vehicle is parked on private real property.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Property owner shall mean that person who exercises dominion and control over real property, including but not limited to the legal titleholder, lessee, designated representative of a condominium association or any person authorized to exercise a share dominion and control over real property; however, "property owner" shall not mean or include a person providing towing services within the purview of this article. The foregoing notwithstanding, all government entities providing their own towing services may be property owners for purposes of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
Recover shall mean to take possession of a vehicle and its contents and to exercise control, supervision and responsibility over it.
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
Regulation shall mean a rule set forth in this article, the violation of which is sufficient grounds for fines; suspension or revocation of a towing license; civil damages, court costs and attorneys fees; and specified criminal penalties.
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
Remove shall mean to change the location of a vehicle by towing it.
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
Revoke shall mean to annul and make void the license of a person engaged in the business of providing towing services.
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
Store shall mean to place and leave a towed vehicle at a location where the person providing the towing service exercises control, supervision and responsibility over the vehicle. The storage facility must be securely fenced or locked for the protection of vehicles and property.
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
Tow shall mean to haul, draw or pull along a vehicle by means of another vehicle equipped with booms, car carriers, winches or similar equipment.
</section>
<section prefix = "20">
Trade name shall mean any name under which a person, corporation, partnership, association, firm or any other entity operates its business.
</section>
<section prefix = "21">
Vehicle shall mean an automobile, truck, bus, trailer, semitrailer, truck tractor semitrailer combination, recreational unit primarily designed as temporary living quarters which either has its own motive power or is mounted on or drawn by another vehicle, or any other mobile item using wheels and being operated on the roads of Miami-Dade County, which is used to transport persons or property and is propelled by power other than muscular power; provided, however, that the term does not include bicycles, mopeds, traction engines, road rollers or vehicles which run only upon a track.
</section>
<section prefix = "22">
Wrecker class shall mean the type of towing vehicle, equipment or apparatus used to recover, tow or remove vehicles. The wrecker classes shall be distinguished as follows:

Part I
Tow Truck Class Specifications
<section prefix="1" type="table">
<table class="table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="20px" /> 
  <col width="16.666666666666668%" /> 
  <col width="66.66666666666667%" /> 
  <col width="16.666666666666668%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="3" valign="top" class=""> <i>Class A Tow Truck or Car Carrier—Minimum Ratings:</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 1.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Gross vehicle weight ratings .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10,000 LBS.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 2.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Boom capacity .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">8,000 LBS.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 3.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Winching capacity .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">8,000 LBS.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 4.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Cable size and length .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3/8″&#215;100′</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 5.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Wheel lift retracted rating .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3,500 LBS.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 6.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Wheel lift extended ratings .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2,000 LBS.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 7.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Tow sling safe lift rating .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3,500 LBS.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 8.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Safety chains (2 EACH) .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3/8″ high test</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 9.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Cab to axle dimension .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">56″</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="3" valign="top" class=""><i>Class B Tow Truck—Minimum Ratings:</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 1.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Gross vehicle weight ratings .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">18,000 LBS.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 2.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Boom capacity .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">24,000 LBS.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 3.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Winching capacity .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">24,000 LBS.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 4.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Cable size and length .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">&#189;″&#215;200′</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 5.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Under-reach retracted rating .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10,500 LBS.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 6.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Under-reach extended ratings .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">8,500 LBS.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 7.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Tow sling safe lift rating .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">8,500 LBS.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 8.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Safety chains (2 EACH) .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">5/16″ ALLOY</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 9.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Cab to axle dimension .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">84″</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="3" valign="top" class=""><i>Class C Tow Truck—Minimum Ratings:</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 1.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Gross vehicle weight ratings .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">30,000 LBS.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 2.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Boom capacity .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">50,000 LBS.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 3.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Winching capacity .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">50,000 LBS.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 4.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Cable size and length .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">5/8″&#215;200′</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 5.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Under-reach retracted rating .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">25,000 LBS.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 6.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Under-reach extended ratings .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">12,000 LBS.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 7.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Tow sling safe lift rating .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">12,000 LBS.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 8.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Safety chains (2 EACH) .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">&#189;″ ALLOY</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 9.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Cab to axle dimension .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">144″</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="3" valign="top" class=""><i>Class D Tow Truck—Minimum Ratings:</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 1.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Gross vehicle weight ratings .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">52,000 LBS.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 2.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Boom capacity .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">70,000 LBS.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 3.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Winching capacity .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">70,000 LBS.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 4.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Cable size and length .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">&#190;″&#215;200′</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 5.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Under-reach retracted rating .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">45,000 LBS.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 6.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Under-reach extended ratings .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">15,000 LBS.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 7.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Tow sling safe lift rating .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">12,000 LBS.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 8.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Safety chains (2 EACH) .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">&#189;″ALLOY</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 9.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Cab to axle dimension .....</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">180″</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-462. Towing license required</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It shall be unlawful for any person to recover, tow or remove a vehicle or provide storage in connection therewith or to cause or permit any other person for compensation to recover, tow or remove a vehicle or provide storage in connection therewith, or to advertise or offer to recover, tow or remove a vehicle or provide storage in connection therewith, without first obtaining and maintaining a current and valid license pursuant to the provisions of this article; provided, however, that a property owner without a license may cause or permit the removal of a vehicle from his or her property in accordance with the provisions of this article. The provisions of this ordinance do not apply to persons who use a towing vehicle to transport their vehicles purely for personal, family, household or recreational use.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Nothing in this article shall be construed to prohibit the discharge or storage of a vehicle lawfully recovered, towed or removed in another County and lawfully transported into Miami-Dade County; nor shall anything in this article be construed to prohibit a vehicle owner or his authorized agent from requesting the services of a towing business not regularly doing towing business in Miami-Dade County, to remove the owner's vehicle to a location outside Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Nothing in this article shall be construed to prevent a natural person from working in an employment relationship for another person holding a valid license under this article; however, any person who is an independent contractor and not an employee of a licensed person is also subject to all the requirements and provisions of this article.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 89-67, § 1, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 90-29, § 1, 4-3-90; Ord. No. 93-130, § 1, 11-16-93; Ord. No. 95-184, § 1, 10-17-95)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-463. Application for towing license; fees</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Every application for a towing license shall be in writing, signed and verified by the applicant, and filed with the CSD together with an investigative, processing fee, or late fee as applicable, established by administrative order of the County Manager approved by the Commission. That application fee shall be deposited in a separate Miami-Dade County fund and shall be used exclusively to accomplish the purposes of this article. The amount of the application fee shall be reasonably related to the cost of the services and regulation provided. The statements contained in the application shall become a part of the towing license and may be modified only in accordance with the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Every application for a towing license shall be on a form prescribed by the CSD and shall contain all the information required by that form, including but not limited to:
<section prefix = "1">
Sufficient information to identify the applicant, including but not limited to, full legal name, date of birth or of formation of legal entity, telephone numbers, and all business and residence addresses. If the applicant is a corporation, the foregoing information shall also be provided for each corporate officer, director, resident agent and shareholder. If the applicant is a partnership, the foregoing information shall also be provided for each general and each limited partner. Post office box addresses shall not be accepted.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Documentation demonstrating that all corporate or partnership applicants are qualified to do business under the laws of Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Photocopy of the occupational license of the applicant.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Photocopy of the certificate of use and occupancy of the applicant, indicating authorization for the business use of the applicant, for each business address located in unincorporated Miami-Dade County and identified in the application.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
A list of all persons with any ownership interest in the applicant who have previously been denied a license.
(6
Any trade name under which the applicant operates, intends to operate, or has previously operated, and a description of proposed, existing and previous towing vehicles' colors and markings.
<section prefix = "7">
A description of the applicant's management plan, which shall include but not be limited to the following: location and description of all places of business, a description of all existing towing vehicles and equipment, a description of the plan and facilities for maintaining towing vehicles and equipment, a system for handling complaints and accidents, insurance coverage, and a description of any communication system.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
A description of nonconsent tower services proposed to be provided, including but not limited to days and hours of operation and types of towing and storage services to be provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
A record of all outstanding warrants of arrest; all misdemeanors committed within the preceding thirty-six (36) month period; and felonies of which the applicant has been convicted within the last five (5) years preceding the date of the application involving: criminal homicide; kidnapping; a sexual offense; an assaultive offense; robbery; burglary; arson; fraud; theft if the offense was committed against a person with whom the applicant came in contact with while engaged in the services regulated by this section; public indecency; possession of a weapon; and a violation of any laws regarding controlled substances.
Individual applicants shall obtain their fingerprints and photographs from the Miami-Dade Police Department and provide them with the application and, where civil rights have been restored or periods of incarceration or probation have been completed, as is further described in subsections 30-477(e)(1) and (2) below, provide such information with the application. In the case of a corporate or partnership applicant, all such information shall be provided by all corporate officers and directors, or partners, as the case may be, and by all stockholders who own, hold or control five (5) percent or more of issued and outstanding stock in the corporation or beneficial interest therein, and by all officers and directors of any corporate general partners of a partnership and by stockholders who own, hold or control five (5) percent or more of issued and outstanding stock in a corporate general partner, or beneficial interest therein.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Proof of insurance as required in Section 30-465 of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
The signature of each individual applicant, the signature of the president or vice-president of a corporate applicant, and the signature of all the general partners of a partnership applicant.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
An agreement on the part of the applicant to abide by the provisions of this article, ordinances of municipalities having jurisdiction and Miami-Dade County, and the laws of the State of Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
It shall be a violation of this section to fail to report to CSD any material change pertaining to the information supplied by the applicant or licensee for his or her license, including, but not limited to, changing the location of any of the applicant's place(s) of business.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
Each nonconsent tower who applies for a license shall provide with his or her application for a license a listing of all of his or her existing or proposed rates and charges in a format approved by the CSD.
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
Such additional information about the nonconsent tower applicant as the Director may deem appropriate.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 89-67, § 1, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 90-29, § 1, 4-3-90; Ord. No. 93-130, § 1, 11-16-93; Ord. No. 95-184, § 1, 10-17-95; Ord. No. 03-176, § 1, 7-22-03)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-464. Issuance of license; renewal</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Director is empowered to issue licenses to applicants which have met the standards and requirements for a towing license, and to promulgate rules, regulations and procedures for the application, issuance and revocation of such licenses.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Director shall review and investigate each application for a towing license and shall reject any application that is not properly filed or is incomplete or untrue in whole or in part, or which fails in any way to meet the requirements of subsection (c) of this section. An incomplete application shall be considered to be abandoned if an applicant fails to complete his or her application within sixty days from the date that the application was filed with the Director. An application submitted subsequent to the abandonment of a former application shall be treated as a new application.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
No towing license shall be issued to an applicant or renewed unless the applicant has completed the following:
<section prefix = "1">
Filed with the Director a true, correct and complete application on the form prescribed by the CSD, including all proofs of required insurance.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Paid the initial, renewal or late application fee, as applicable.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Submitted to a background investigation resulting in a determination by the Director that:
<section prefix = "a">
Neither the applicant, nor any officer, director or partner of the applicant, nor any stockholder owning, holding, controlling or having a beneficial interest in five (5) percent or more of the issued and outstanding stock of a corporate applicant or of a corporate general partner of a partnership applicant, has a currently suspended license, has had its license revoked by action of the Director within two (2) years of the date of application, or has outstanding and unsatisfied civil penalties imposed on account of violations of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Neither the applicant, nor any officer, director or partner of the applicant, nor any stockholder owning, holding, controlling or having a beneficial interest in five (5) percent or more of the issued and outstanding stock of a corporate general partner of a partnership applicant, has been convicted of one (1) or more of the felonies listed in Section 30-463(b)(9) within the preceding five (5) years; or that three (3) misdemeanors have been committed within the thirty-six (36) month period preceding the date of application as described in subsection 30-463(b)(9), unless the civil rights of such individual or applicant have been restored or that such person has successfully completed all sentences of incarceration, probationary periods, required rehabilitation activities and payment of all fines and penalties imposed. For applicants requesting renewal, the Director may only consider crimes committed after the date the applicant obtained his or her license, unless such crimes were not previously disclosed in the original application.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Each corporate or partnership applicant is qualified under the laws of Florida to do business under the trade name or names under which it has applied for a license.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
No fraud or willful or knowing misrepresentation or false statement was made in the application.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
No judgment against the applicant arising out of the activity of recovery, towing or removing a vehicle or providing storage in connection therewith remains unsatisfied, unless a stay or reversal of the judgment is procured through the courts.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
That there be no outstanding warrants of arrest against the applicant nor any officer, director or partner of the applicant nor any stockholder owning, holding, controlling or having a beneficial interest in five (5) percent or more of the issued and outstanding stock of a corporate general partner of a partnership applicant.
<section prefix = "3">
There are no (i) unpaid civil penalties; (ii) unpaid administrative costs of hearing; (iii) unpaid County investigative, enforcement, testing, or monitoring costs; or (iv) unpaid liens, any or all of which are owed to Miami-Dade County pursuant to the provisions of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Each towing license shall be on a form prescribed by the CSD and shall be signed by the Director. Each towing license shall contain, at a minimum, the name and address of the applicant, the dates the license remains in effect unless suspended or revoked, and a statement of such additional terms and conditions, restrictions and limitations as were authorized in the application and approval process. Violation of such a condition, limitation, or restriction of a license shall be a violation of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
All initial towing licenses shall be effective from their date of issuance to the date of birth of the applicant, if the applicant is a sole proprietor, and in the case of a corporation or partnership, from the date of formation of the legal entity. The fee for the initial application shall be established by administrative order of the County Manager and approved by the Commission. The CSD shall, for each initial application, prorate the fee from the date of its issuance to the date of birth or date of formation of the applicant, whichever is the case.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Prior to the expiration of the initial towing license or expiration of the annual license, whichever is the case, an applicant may apply for an annual towing license. As a part of the renewal process, the original application shall be updated and verified by the applicant on forms prescribed by CSD. Renewal applications shall also include such financial information as CSD shall deem necessary to consider the continued appropriateness of maximum fees established pursuant to Section 30-476. Each updated renewal application shall be submitted at least sixty (60) days prior to expiration of the current initial or annual license and shall be accompanied by a fee which shall be established by administrative order of the County Manager approved by the Commission. All renewal application fees shall be deposited with original application fees and other charges and fees under this article in a separate Miami-Dade County fund and shall be used exclusively to accomplish the purposes of this article. The amount of the renewal fee shall be reasonably related to the cost of the services and regulation provided, and shall be in addition to any other fees or charges required by this article. All annual towing licenses which are not renewed shall automatically expire upon the one (1) year anniversary of the date of issuance and all recovery, towing, removing and storage services permitted thereunder shall cease immediately. The Director shall deny each renewal application that is not timely, is not properly filed, is incomplete, is untrue in whole or in part, is unaccompanied by the required fee, or results in a determination by the Director that the applicant has failed to satisfy the requirements of subsection (c)(3) of this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
A license issued or renewed pursuant to the provisions of this article shall not be transferable, nor shall the ownership structure of the licensee be so modified as to constitute a change in the control or ownership of the license, without the prior written approval of the Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
There shall be no numerical limit on licenses issued pursuant to the provisions of this article.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 89-67, § 1, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 89-105, § 1, 11-7-89; Ord. No. 89-128, § 1, 12-19-89; Ord. No. 90-29, § 1, 4-3-90; Ord. No. 93-130, § 1, 11-16-93; Ord. No. 03-176, § 1, 7-22-03)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-465. Insurance requirements</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It shall be unlawful for any person for compensation or as part of a regularly conducted business activity to recover, tow, or remove a vehicle or to provide vehicle storage services in connection therewith until that person has filed with the Director and maintains in effect, for each towing vehicle operated by that person, an insurance policy or policies or certificates of insurance which shall indemnify or insure such person for its liability at a minimum:
<section prefix = "1">
For vehicles with a gross vehicle weight of less than eighteen thousand (18,000) pounds: automobile liability insurance covering each vehicle in an amount not less than fifty thousand dollars ($50,000.00) per person, one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00) per occurrence for bodily injury, and twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000.00) per occurrence for property damage or one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00) combined single limit.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
For vehicles with a gross vehicle weight of eighteen thousand (18,000) pounds or more, but less than thirty thousand (30,000) pounds: automobile liability insurance covering each vehicle in an amount not less than one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00) per person, three hundred thousand dollars ($300,000.00) per occurrence for bodily injury, and one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00) per occurrence for property damage or three hundred thousand dollars ($300,000.00) combined single limit.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
For vehicles with a gross vehicle weight of thirty thousand (30,000) pounds or more: automobile liability insurance coverage covering each vehicle in an amount not less than three hundred thousand dollars ($300,000.00) per person, five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000.00) per occurrence for bodily injury, and one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00) per occurrence for property damage or five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000.00) combined single limit.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
All insurance policies required shall be issued by insurance companies authorized and qualified to do business in the State of Florida. No policy shall be accepted which is of less than six (6) months' duration. Each policy shall contain a provision that the CSD must be notified in writing by mail by the insurance agent/company of any policy changes at least forty-five (45) days prior to the endorsement taking effect or at least ten (10) days prior to cancellation thereof for non-payment of premium, as applicable.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Failure to provide current certificates of insurance or policies or failure to maintain the required coverage for each vehicle shall result in automatic suspension of the towing license, which shall remain in effect until proof of compliance with this section is submitted to the Director and approved.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The insurance requirements of this article shall not apply to governmental entities which are self-insured.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 89-67, § 1, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 90-29, § 1, 4-3-90; Ord. No. 93-130, § 1, 11-16-93)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-466. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 03-176, § 1, adopted July 22, 2003, repealed section 30-466 in its entirety. Former section 30-466 pertained to denial of permits, appeal and review, and derived from Ord. No. 89-67, § 1, adopted July 11, 1989; Ord. No. 90-29, § 1, adopted April 3, 1990.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-467. Decals; vehicle standards</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It shall be unlawful to recover, tow or remove a vehicle or to store it in connection therewith unless the towing vehicle or equipment or car carrier used to provide such service displays in the lower left corner of the front window a current decal issued by the CSD.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Director is authorized to issue current licensee decals for each separate towing vehicle or equipment or car carrier, upon application by the licensee and completion of the following:
<section prefix = "1">
Inspection of vehicle records by personnel authorized by the CSD to determine ownership, or first-party lease held by the licensee, of the towing vehicle or equipment or car carrier.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Inspection by personnel authorized by CSD to assure that the non-governmentally owned towing vehicle or equipment or car carrier clearly displays on the front of the tow truck or car carrier body, the towing license number in letters at least three (3) inches high; and on the driver and passenger sides of the vehicle and/or doors, the licensee's name in letters at least three (3) inches high; and in letters at least one (1) inch high, the licensee's principal address and telephone number.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Inspection by personnel authorized by CSD to ascertain that the towing vehicle has the equipment required by rules to be promulgated by CSD and that such equipment is operable. If an inspection of the towing vehicle does not reveal that it meets the minimum ratings for the vehicle's class specifications, as contained in Section 30-461(22), the licensee must furnish the CSD a sworn statement that the towing vehicle meets the applicable minimum ratings.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
An application form completed by the licensee and approved by the Director which correctly indicates the year, make, model and vehicle identification number of the towing vehicle or equipment or car carrier.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Payment of a CSD decal fee set at an amount reasonably related to the costs of providing the services under this section. Such costs shall be set by administrative order of the County Manager approved by the Commission, and deposited and used in the same manner as other fees and charges under this article.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Decals shall be issued in numerical order, and each decal issued shall display its assigned number. Decals shall be issued with the initial license and shall be renewable annually in the same manner as original application is made.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The decal for each towing vehicle or equipment or car carrier shall be affixed by personnel authorized by the CSD, shall remain the property of the County, and shall at all times by displayed and available for inspection by any police officer or by personnel authorized by the CSD to perform enforcement duties.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 89-67, § 1, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 89-105, § 2, 11-7-89; Ord. No. 89-128, § 2, 12-19-89; Ord. No. 90-29, § 1, 4-3-90; Ord. No. 93-130, § 1, 11-16-93; Ord. No. 03-176, § 1, 7-22-03)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-468. Manifest or trip records</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It shall be unlawful for any person to recover, tow or remove a vehicle or provide storage in connection therewith unless the person providing such service shall maintain in his or her possession a manifest or trip sheet which shall include but not be limited to the following information:
<section prefix = "1">
Name of the licensee and of the natural person physically providing the service.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Decal number of the towing vehicle or equipment or car carrier used to provide the service.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Date and time that the service was requested.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Name, address and telephone number of the person requesting the service.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Date and time that the service was initiated.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Location at which the service originated.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Destination to which the vehicle being provided the service is taken.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Description of the vehicle being provided the service, including make, model, year, color, vehicle identification number and State license plate number, if any.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Description of services provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Cost(s) for the service(s) provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Any and all "load and offload" charges, including the name, badge number, and agency of the officer on the scene who approved these additional charges.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Date and time that the vehicle was delivered to the storage facility.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Each manifest or trip record shall be immediately available for inspection by police officers or by personnel authorized by the CSD to perform enforcement duties, at any time during the period of recovery, towing or removal of a vehicle.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Each licensee shall maintain for no less than three (3) years the original of each manifest or trip record. No person providing the service shall destroy, mutilate, alter or deface any manifest or trip record prior to the expiration of three (3) years without written approval of the CSD. All manifests and trip records shall be available for inspection by personnel authorized by the CSD or any police agency during regular business hours.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 89-67, § 1, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 90-29, § 1, 4-3-90; Ord. No. 93-130, § 1, 11-16-93; Ord. No. 03-176, § 1, 7-22-03)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-469. Towing safety standards</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful for any person to recover, tow or remove a vehicle by use of a towing vehicle, equipment or car carrier in a manner which violates the standards for use of such towing vehicle, equipment or car carrier as set by the manufacturer thereof. It shall be unlawful to tow without the use of safety chains.
It shall be unlawful to operate a tow truck if the vehicle has failed to pass the critical items of any vehicle inspection performed by personnel authorized by the CSD, or if the owner thereof has failed to correct other inspection deficiencies within the time period specified by the CSD, or is operating without the proper insurance coverage. When a vehicle has failed to pass inspection, inspection deficiencies have not been corrected or when the vehicle is operating without the proper insurance coverage, personnel authorized by the CSD may affix to the upper left corner of the vehicle windshield a notice stating the date of the inspection or action and the reasons for the inspection rejection or action. It shall be unlawful for the licensee or any other person other than personnel authorized by the CSD to remove this notice from the windshield of the vehicle.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-470. Records required</catch_line>
<text>
Each person regulated under this article who performs nonconsent tows shall maintain accurate and complete records of all financial and operating information as the CSD may require, including but not limited to manifests or trip records, invoices and statements for services rendered, and records of payments for services rendered. Such records shall be maintained in Miami-Dade County for at least three (3) years. The CSD shall be granted access to these records for inspection or copying, during regular business hours. All records and information inspected and not copied shall be confidential, except that records may be copied or made public for the purpose of license suspension or revocation proceedings.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-470.1. Prohibition on publication of advertising without towing license number</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
No person, firm, corporation or other legal entity may knowingly publish an advertisement which is primarily circulated, displayed, distributed or marketed within Miami-Dade County, which advertisement offers services regulated by Chapter 30, Article III "Towing of Motor Vehicles," Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, as it may be amended from time to time, unless the advertisement includes the license number issued by Miami-Dade County to that entity, with the words "M-D.C. Tow. Lic. No. ____________/____________/____________."
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Advertisement shall include, but not be limited to, announcements, listings, displays, entries or other written statements containing the name of the licensee or identifying the services offered by the licensee or by a person regulated by this chapter, and which are placed in a magazine or periodical, newspaper or inserts, audio broadcasting or telephone directory, or on towing vehicles or equipment, when such written statement describes or encompasses services regulated by Chapter 30, Article III "Towing of Motor Vehicles," Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 93-130, § 1, 11-16-93; Ord. No. 95-184, § 1, 10-17-95; Ord. No. 03-176, § 1, 7-22-03)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-471. Anti-discrimination</catch_line>
<text>
No licensee shall refuse or neglect to provide vehicle recovery, towing or removal services or storage services in connection therewith to any orderly person requesting such service and able and willing to pay for such services, on account of that person's race, sex, religion, national origin, age, marital status or handicap.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-472. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 03-176, § 1, adopted July 22, 2003, repealed section 30-472 in its entirety. Former section 30-472 pertained to the towing license requirement and derived from Ord. No. 89-67, § 1, adopted July 11, 1989.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-473. Nonconsent towing without prior consent of vehicle owner or duly authorized driver of vehicle</catch_line>
<text>
In addition to the other requirements of this article, no nonconsent tower shall recover, tow or remove a vehicle or provide storage in connection therewith without the prior express instruction of the vehicle owner or authorized driver, except in accordance with the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Only persons duly licensed under this article shall recover, tow or remove a vehicle or provide storage in connection therewith without the prior express instruction of the vehicle owner or authorized driver.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Persons duly licensed under this article may recover, tow or remove a vehicle without the prior express instruction of the vehicle owner or authorized driver upon the express instruction of a police officer and in accordance with the terms of any contracts or agreements between the licensee and the governmental entity in whose jurisdiction the police officer serves. Such contracts or agreements may provide terms and requirements in excess of the requirements provided by this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Persons duly licensed under this article may recover, tow or remove a vehicle without the prior express instruction of the vehicle owner or authorized driver, upon the express instruction of a property owner, or his authorized agent, on whose property the vehicle is disabled, abandoned or parked without authorization or whose operator is unwilling or unable to remove the vehicle, provided that the requirements of Sections 30-474, 30-475 and 30-476 are satisfied.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Persons who provide services pursuant to this section shall not pay or rebate money, or solicit or offer the rebate of money, or other valuable consideration, to obtain the privilege of rendering such services.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Persons who provide services pursuant to this section shall not do so when there is a living natural person occupying the vehicle.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Persons who provide services pursuant to this section shall transport the vehicle directly to the storage site of the person providing the service, or to such other location as a police officer authorizing the tow may expressly direct, and shall not keep the vehicle in any temporary holding area.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Persons who provide services pursuant to this section shall maintain a place of business. The place of business shall have a sign that clearly and conspicuously identifies the business to the public; and office space that has at least one (1) person on duty from 8:00 a.m. until 6:00 p.m., Monday through Friday, to answer telephone calls and to be open to serve the public. However, the office may be closed to observe all holidays observed by Miami-Dade County government. The place of business shall maintain a telephone communication system to answer telephone calls from the public twenty-four (24) hours a day.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Persons who provide services pursuant to this section shall file and keep on record with the CSD a complete copy of all current rates charged for the recovery, towing or removal of vehicles and storage provided in connection therewith. Such persons shall also display prominently at each vehicle storage site a schedule of all charges and rates for removal of vehicles at the request of property owners. That rate schedule shall be posted prominently in the area designated for the vehicle owner or his agent to transact business. Such area shall provide shelter, safety and lighting adequate for the vehicle owner or his or her authorized representative to read the posted rate schedule. Further, notice shall be posted advising the vehicle owner or his or her authorized representative of the right to request and review a complete schedule of charges and rates for towing services provided at police request for the jurisdiction in which the police order to tow was made.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Persons who provide services pursuant to this section shall advise any vehicle owner or authorized representative who calls by telephone prior to arriving at the storage site of the following:
<section prefix = "1">
Each and every document or other thing which must be produced to retrieve the vehicle;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The exact charges as of the times of the telephone call, and the rate at which charges accumulate after the call;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The acceptable methods of payment; and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The hours and days the storage site is open for regular business.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Persons who provide services pursuant to this section shall permit every vehicle owner or his or her authorized representative to inspect the towed vehicle immediately upon his or her arrival at the storage site and before payment of any charges. The vehicle owner or his or her authorized representative shall be permitted to remove from the vehicle any and all personal possessions inside but not affixed to the vehicle, including but not limited to radios and telephones, and the operator of the storage site shall assist any vehicle owner or authorized representative in doing so. No release or waiver of any kind which would release the authorized representative at the time of retrieval may be required as a condition of release of the vehicle.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Persons who provide services pursuant to this section shall accept payment for charges from the vehicle owner or authorized representative in any of at least two (2) of the following listed categories:
<section prefix = "1">
Cash, money order or valid traveler's check;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Valid bank credit card; or
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Valid personal check showing on its face the name and address of the vehicle owner or authorized representative.
A vehicle owner or authorized representative shall not be required to furnish more than one (1) form of picture identification when payment is made by valid bank credit card or personal check, and said presentation shall constitute sufficient identity verification.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Persons who provide services pursuant to this section shall display on the same sign as the rate schedule required by subsection (h) of this section the following statement:

To The Vehicle Owner
If you believe that you have been overcharged for the services rendered, you do not have to pay your bill to get your car. Instead, you have the right to post a bond in the Circuit Court, payable to (name of person providing service), in the amount of the final bill for services rendered, and file a complaint within five (5) days of the time you have knowledge of the location of the vehicle, and the Court will decide later who is right. If you show us a valid Clerk's certificate showing that you have posted a bond, we must release your vehicle to you immediately. This remedy is in addition to other legal remedies you may have. F.S. §§ 713.76, 713.78.
If you have a complaint about the way services were provided, you may call the Miami-Dade County Consumer Services Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
Persons who provide services pursuant to this section shall not use physical force or violence or threats of physical force or violence in dealing with the individuals responsible for administering this article or individuals who have had or are about to have their vehicles recovered, towed or removed or stored in connection therewith.
</section>
<section prefix = "n">
Nothing in this section shall prevent the County or any jurisdiction in it from providing additional or more restrictive requirements in contracts or arrangements under which police officers direct and authorize the recovery, towing or removal of vehicles or storage provided in connection therewith.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-474. Requirements for providing nonconsent tow services at request of property owners</catch_line>
<text>
Nonconsent towers duly licensed under this article may recover, tow or remove a vehicle or provide storage in connection therewith upon the instruction of a property owner, or his authorized agent, on whose property the vehicle is abandoned or parked without authorization, provided that the following requirements are satisfied:
<section prefix = "a">
Notice shall be prominently posted on the property from which the vehicle is proposed to be removed and shall fulfill the following requirements:
<section prefix = "1">
Notice, in the form of a sign structure, shall be prominently placed at each driveway access or curb cut allowing vehicle access to the property, within five (5) feet from the public right-of-way line. If there are no curbs or access barriers, signs shall be posted not less than one (1) sign each twenty-five (25) feet of lot frontage. The sign structure shall be permanently installed with the bottom of the sign not less than four (4) feet above ground level and the top of the sign not more than ten (10) feet above ground level, and shall be continuously maintained on the property for not fewer than twenty-four (24) hours before the towing or removal of vehicles.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The notice shall clearly display:
<section prefix = "a">
In not less than two (2) inches high, light-reflective letters on a contrasting background, that unauthorized vehicles will be towed away at the owner's expense; and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
In not less than four (4) inches high, light-reflective letters on a contrasting background the words "tow-away zone"; and
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
In not less than two (2) inches high, light-reflective letters on a contrasting background, the days of the week and hours of the day during which vehicles will be towed away at the owner's expense where the property owner selectively causes the towing of vehicles, depending on the day of the week and hour of the day the vehicle is parked; and
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
In not less than two (2) inches high, light-reflective letters on a contrasting background, the name and telephone number of the person performing the towing service, if there exists a written contract between the property owner and that person for the towing of vehicles; and
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
In not less than one (1) inch high, light-reflective letters on a contrasting background, the address of the storage site.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The posting of notice requirements of this section shall not be required where:
<section prefix = "a">
The property on which a vehicle is parked is property appurtenant to and obviously a part of a single-family type residence; or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Notice is personally given to the owner or operator of the vehicle that the property on which the vehicle is or will be parked is reserved or otherwise not available for unauthorized vehicles and is subject to being removed at the owner's expense; or
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The property on which a vehicle is parked is owned by a governmental entity and the towing is performed by a towing vehicle owned by the governmental entity in compliance with laws authorizing removal of the vehicle.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The property owner or his authorized agent shall provide express instruction to recover, tow or remove the vehicle and shall date and sign such instruction in the presence of the natural person recovering, towing or removing the vehicle. Neither the property owner nor his authorized agent shall be an officer, employee or agent of the person requested to recover, tow or remove the vehicle. No such instruction shall be considered to have been given by the mere posting of the notice as required by the preceding parts of this section. No such instruction shall be considered to have been given by virtue of the mere terms of any contract or agreement between a person providing towing services and a property owner. No such instruction shall be considered to have been given where the instruction occurs in advance of the actual unauthorized parking of the vehicle. No such instruction shall be considered to have been given where the instruction is general in nature and unrelated to specific, individual and identifiable vehicles which are already parked without authorization.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The person recovering, towing or removing a vehicle at the request of a property owner or his authorized agent shall, within thirty (30) minutes of the completion of the vehicle recovery, tow or removal, notify the Miami-Dade Police Department of the nature of the service rendered, the storage site of the vehicle, the time the service was rendered, and the make, model, color, vehicle identification number and license plate number of the vehicle.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Persons who provide services pursuant to this section shall not recover, tow or remove a vehicle or provide storage in connection therewith if the vehicle owner or other person legally authorized to control the vehicle arrives at the scene prior to recovery, towing or removal, except where:
<section prefix = "1">
The registered owner or other legally authorized person in control of the vehicle refuses or is unable to remove the vehicle; or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
A complete mechanical connection exists between the vehicle and the towing or removal apparatus and the registered owner or other person in control of the vehicle refuses to pay a reasonable service fee of not more than half of the posted rate for such towing services as required by this article.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Except as otherwise provided for in Section 715.07 Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time, persons who provide services pursuant to this section shall not store or impound a towed vehicle at a distance which exceeds a ten-mile radius of the location from which the vehicle was recovered, towed or removed unless no towing business providing services under this section is located within a ten-mile radius, in which case a towed or removed vehicle must be stored at a site within twenty (20) miles of the point of removal.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Persons who provide services pursuant to this section shall maintain one (1) or more storage sites, each of which shall be open for the purpose of retrieval of vehicles by owners or owners' authorized agents on any day that the person providing the service is open for towing purposes, from at least 8:00 a.m. to 6:00 p.m., Monday through Friday, and, when closed, shall have posted prominently on the exterior of the place of business a notice indicating a telephone number where the operator of the site can be reached at all times. Upon receipt of a telephoned request to open a site to retrieve a vehicle, the operator of the site shall return to the site within one (1) hour. Persons who provide services pursuant to this section shall release the vehicle to the owner or authorized agent within one-half (½) hour after request is made in person.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-475. Requirements for licensees and property owners pertaining to nonconsent tows from private property</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Each nonconsent tower must enter into a written contract with every owner of private property that authorizes the licensee to tow vehicles from its property. The licensee must keep on file each contract that is in effect with each property owner, or that was terminated within the previous twelve (12) months. The CSD, law enforcement officers, and the owner of the vehicle towed by the licensee may inspect and copy any such contract during business hours.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A property owner or his or her authorized representative may cause a vehicle parked without authorization upon the property owner's property to be recovered, towed or removed from such property by a person licensed pursuant to this article, and shall not incur liability for the costs of recovery, towing or removal or storage associated therewith, under the following circumstances:
<section prefix = "1">
When the property is appurtenant to and obviously a part of a single family residence property; or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
When notice is personally given to the vehicle owner or other authorized person in control of the vehicle that the are in which that vehicle is parked is reserved or otherwise unavailable for unauthorized vehicles and subject to being removed as the expense of the vehicle owner or authorized person in control of the vehicle; or
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
When the vehicle has been parked without authorization on the property for more than forty-eight (48) hours; or
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
In the case of any other unauthorized parking when notice is prominently posted on the property as provided in Section 30-474(a) of this article; or
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
When the vehicle has been parked on the property for the principal purpose of displaying such vehicle for sale.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
When any property owner or his or her authorized representative causes a vehicle to be recovered, towed, removed from his or her property and stored, he shall immediately upon request and without demanding compensation inform the vehicle owner or other authorized person in control of the vehicle of the name and address of the person that has recovered, towed or removed the vehicle.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
No property owner or authorized representative shall request the recovery, tow, removal or storage of a vehicle pursuant to this section until he or she has first ascertained from the person providing the service the current towing license number of that person.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Nothing in this section shall permit any property owner or authorized representative to request the recovery, tow or the removal of law enforcement, fire fighting, rescue squad, ambulance or other emergency vehicles marked as such.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Any person who improperly causes a vehicle to be recovered, towed, removed or stored shall be liable to the vehicle owner or his authorized representative for the costs of the services provided, any damages resulting from the recovery, towing, removal or storage and attorney's fees.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 89-67, § 1, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 93-130, § 1, 11-16-93; Ord. No. 94-108, § 2, 6-9-94; Ord. No. 03-176, § 1, 7-22-03)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-476. Maximum immobilization, nonconsent towing and storage rates for providing immobilization or tow services at the request of property owners or police agencies</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Commission shall by resolution, establish maximum rates for providing immobilization, recovery, nonconsent towing, removal and storage services at the request of a police agency, or a property owner or authorized representative, without the prior consent of the vehicle owner or other authorized person in control of the vehicle. The rates established shall be uniform throughout Miami-Dade County, both in incorporated and unincorporated areas, except where municipalities pursuant to Sections 125.0103 and 166.043, Florida Statutes, have established differing maximum rates for their jurisdictions. From time to time, the maximum rates established by the Commission may be altered, revised, increased or decreased.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Persons who provide nonconsent towing services shall not charge in excess of the maximum allowable rates established by the Commission. No person providing services pursuant to this section shall charge any type of fee other than the fees for which the Commission has established specific rates.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
In addition to the maximum rates that may be charged by persons providing services pursuant to this section, the County shall charge an administrative fee of $15 for each vehicle that is recovered, towed, removed, or stored at the request of the Miami-Dade County Police Department. Any administrative fee charged and collected on behalf of the County by a person providing services at the County's request is hereby ratified and confirmed. All administrative fees, as described above, imposed before the effective date of this ordinance are ratified, validated, and confirmed in all respects, from the date any such fee was charged, billed, or collected.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 89-67, § 1, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 93-130, § 1, 11-16-93; Ord. No. 99-70, § 1, 6-22-99; Ord. No. 03-165, § 1, 7-22-03; Ord. No. 03-176, § 1, 7-22-03)</history>
Annotation—AO of 5-3-88.
<catch_line>Sec. 30-476.1. Denial, revocation and suspension of licenses</catch_line>
<text>
The Director may deny, revoke, or suspend a license issued pursuant to the provisions of this article if the Director determines that the applicant or licensee has:
<section prefix = "a">
Violated any provision of this article, or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Misrepresented or concealed a fact on the application, renewal application or replacement application for a license, or
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Aided or abetted a person who has not obtained a license to evade or avoid the provisions of this article, or
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Engaged in any conduct as part of the performance of a contract for service which constitutes fraud, or
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Violated any condition, limitation, or restriction of a license imposed by the Director, or
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Was enjoined by a court of competent jurisdiction from engaging in the trade or business of towing or was enjoined by a court of competent jurisdiction with respect to any of the requirements of this article, or
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Failed to comply with the terms of a cease and desist order, notice to correct a violation, written assurance of compliance, or any other lawful order of the Director, or
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Was convicted of a violation of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
In addition to the foregoing, a license issued pursuant to this article shall be automatically suspended without a hearing when the CSD shall receive written notification that the licensee's officer, director or partner, or any other stockholder owning, holding, controlling or having beneficial interest in five (5) percent or more of the issued and outstanding stock of the licensee or of the issued and outstanding stock of a corporate partner of a partnership licensee, has been convicted of a felony as listed in Section 30-463(b)(9) or of three (3) misdemeanors after receiving a license. In addition to such suspension, the CSD shall forthwith initiate a hearing as hereinafter specified to consider revocation of such license. A licensee whose license has been suspended under this provision shall be entitled to reinstatement of his or her license upon proof that:
<section prefix = "1">
After a felony conviction, the licensee's civil rights have been restored or that the licensee otherwise qualifies for restoration of rights under Section 940.05, Florida Statutes; or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
After a conviction of any other criminal offense, that the person convicted has successfully completed all sentences of incarceration, probationary periods, required rehabilitation activities, and payment of all fines and penalties imposed in connection with such criminal offense.

Notwithstanding the foregoing, no revocation or suspension of a license by the Director shall be effective until the rendition of the appeal, if any, of such revocation or suspension pursuant to this section, or until the time period for filing such appeal has expired, whichever is later.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-477. Enforcement procedure; remedies; attorney's fees; costs; and penalties</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It shall be unlawful for any person to violate any of the provisions of this article. In addition to any other judicial or administrative remedies provided by law, rule, regulation, ordinance, or this article, the Director shall have the following judicial remedies available to enforce the provisions of this article:
<section prefix = "1">
The Director may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to seek temporary or permanent, prohibitory or mandatory injunctive relief to enforce compliance with or prohibit the violation of any of the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Director may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to impose and recover a civil penalty in an amount of not more than ten thousand dollars ($10,000.00) for each violation of any of the provisions of this article. Each day during any portion of which such violation occurs or continues to occur constitutes a separate violation. The right of trial by jury shall be available in any court to determine both liability for and the amount of the civil penalties to be imposed and recovered hereunder.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Director may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to seek restitution and other equitable relief:
<section prefix = "i">
To recover any sums and costs expended by the Director for tracing, investigating, preventing, controlling, abating or remedying any violation of any of the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
To provide restitution to any customers or consumers injured by any violation of any of the provisions of this article.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Upon the rendition of a judgment or decree by any of the courts of this state against any person and in favor of the Director under any of the provisions of this article, the trial court, or, in the event of an appeal in which the Director prevails, the appellate court, shall adjudge or decree against said person and in favor of the Director a reasonable sum as fees or compensation for the Director's attorney prosecuting the suit in which the recovery is had. Where so awarded, compensation or fees of the attorney shall be included in the judgment or decree rendered in the case. This provision shall apply to all civil actions, legal or equitable, filed after the effective date of this article by the Director, Cessation of any violation of any of the provisions of this article whatsoever, prior to rendition of a judgment or entry of a temporary or final decree, or prior to execution of a negotiated settlement, but after an action is filed by the Director under any of the provisions of this article, shall be deemed the functional equivalent of a confession of judgment or verdict in favor of the Director, for which attorney's fees shall be awarded by the trial court as set forth hereinabove.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All the judicial and administrative remedies in this article are independent and cumulative.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
In lieu of instituting judicial action the Director may enter into written assurances of compliance pursuant to Section 8A-82.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, with respect to the matters regulated under this article. Each violation of any of the terms and conditions of a verified, written assurance entered into pursuant to Section 8A-82.1 of the Code with respect to the matters regulated under this article shall constitute a separate offense under this article by the persons who executed the assurance, their respective officers, directors, agents, servants, and employees; and by those persons in active concert or participation with any of the foregoing persons and who receive actual notice of the assurance of compliance. Decisions, actions, and determinations of the Director, pursuant to this section shall not be subject to review pursuant to Section 30-481 of this Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
This article shall be enforced by personnel authorized by the CSD, the police forces of the various municipalities in Miami-Dade County and by the Miami-Dade Police Department. When specifically authorized by the Director, this article may be enforced by other Miami-Dade County personnel.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The CSD is authorized to enforce the provisions of this article by administrative fines in accordance with the provisions of Chapter 8CC or the Code of Miami-Dade County, for each violation. Each day of a continuing violation shall be deemed a separate violation.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Criminal penalties: If any person fails or refuses to obey or comply with or violates any of the provisions of this article, such person, upon conviction of such offense, shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment not to exceed sixty (60) days in the County Jail, or both in the discretion of the Court. Each day of continued violation shall be considered as a separate offense.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 89-67, § 1, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 90-29, § 1, 4-3-90; Ord. No. 93-130, § 1, 11-16-93; Ord. No. 95-184, § 1, 10-17-95; Ord. No. 03-176, § 1, 7-22-03)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-478. Scope of article</catch_line>
<text>
The provisions of this article shall be the exclusive regulations applicable to the immobilization, recovery, towing and removal of vehicles in Miami-Dade County and all storage provided therewith; except that Section 30-473, " Nonconsent Towing Without the Prior Consent of the Vehicle Owner or Duly Authorized Driver of Vehicle," Section 30-474 "Requirements for Providing Nonconsent Tow Services at Request of Property Owners," Section 30-475 "Requirements for Property Owners Requesting Nonconsent Tows From Property," and Section 30-479 "Requirements for immobilizing vehicles without prior consent of vehicle owner or duly authorized driver of vehicle," shall not apply in any municipality that has adopted and maintains in effect ordinances or regulations governing the same matters. Except as provided by this section, the regulations established by this article shall be applicable throughout Miami-Dade County both in the incorporated and unincorporated areas without regard to municipal boundaries, and shall not be subject to modification by any municipality. The provisions of this article shall not apply to the immobilization of a motor vehicle by a governmental agency, or person acting at the direction of a governmental agency, when such immobilization is authorized by a court order. Except as provided by this section, all municipal ordinances or resolutions contrary to this article are hereby superseded and rescinded.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-479. Requirements for immobilizing vehicles without prior consent of vehicle owner or duly authorized driver of vehicle</catch_line>
<text>
It is unlawful for a person providing immobilization services to immobilize a vehicle owned by another person which is parked on private property without permission or authority of the owner or duly authorized driver of that vehicle, unless the following requirements are satisfied:
<section prefix = "1">
The vehicle is unlawfully parked and notice shall be prominently posted on the property on which the vehicle is immobilized in accordance with the requirements set forth in Section 30-474 (a)(1) of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. The text of the notice shall clearly display, in light reflective letters on a contrasting background, the following information:
<section prefix = "a">
In letters at least two (2) inches high that unauthorized vehicles will be immobilized or towed away and the owners expense;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
In not less than four (4) inches high the words immobilization/tow away zone;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
In letters at least two (2) inches high the days of the week and hours of the day during which vehicles will be booted;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
In letters at least one (1) inch high the fee to unboot the vehicle;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
In letters at least one (1) inch high the name and address of the person performing the booting service;
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
In letters at least two (2) inches high the telephone number to call and the on-site location (if applicable) where a person can go to request the unbooting of the vehicle; and
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
In letters at least three-fourths of an inch high, CONSUMER SERVICES DEPARTMENT COMPLAINT NUMBER: (insert current telephone number).
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The vehicle is not occupied by a living natural person or animal.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The vehicle may not be a police, fire fighting, rescue squad, ambulance or other emergency vehicle marked as such.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The persons providing the immobilization service shall comply with Section 30-468 and Section 30-474(b) of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Immobilization shall be accomplished by placing a steel boot on the front wheel of the drivers side of the motor vehicle. The steel boot may be placed on any other wheel if placement on the front wheel on the driver side is not feasible.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Immediately after a vehicle is booted, the person booting such vehicle, the owner of the property where such vehicle was booted, or an employee or agent of such person or owner, shall affix at the rearmost portion of the window adjacent to the driver's seat of such vehicle, a sticker with a completely removable adhesive, measuring eight and one-half by eleven inches containing a warning that any attempt to move the vehicle may result in damage to the vehicle, and stating the name and business address of the person who booted such vehicle as well as a business telephone number which will facilitate the dispatch of personnel responsible for removing the boot.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
No release or waiver of any kind purporting to limit or avoid liability for damages to a vehicle that has been booted shall be valid. In addition, any person who booted a vehicle, or other person authorized to accept payment of any charges for such booting, shall provide a signed receipt to the individual paying the booting charges at the time such charges are paid. Such receipt shall state the name, business address, and business telephone number of the person who has booted such vehicle, and such receipt shall include a telephone number of the office within the Consumer Services Department responsible for receiving complaints with respect to booting.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
No charge shall be imposed for the booting of a vehicle unless and until the requirements of this section have been met, and any such unlawful charge shall be reimbursed by any person found to have violated this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Any person who had booted a vehicle shall release such vehicle as soon as practical, but not to exceed thirty (30) minutes of receiving a request for such vehicle's release; provided however, that payment of any charge for booting is made at or prior to the time of such vehicle's release. The owner or person in control of a vehicle which has been booted shall be permitted to pay any charge for booting at the location where such vehicle was booted and the person receiving payment for booting services shall accept payment for charges from the owner or duly authorized representative in accordance with the provisions of Section 30-473(k) of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
A person may not charge more than the maximum fee established pursuant to Section 30-476
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
The rebate or repayment of money or any other valuable consideration directly or indirectly from the individual or firm booting vehicles to the owners or operators of the premises from which the vehicles are immobilized, for the privilege of immobilizing those vehicles, is prohibited.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
The employees or agents of the booting business shall wear identification tags stating the full name of the booting business and the name of the employee or agent; no identification worn by the booting business' employees or agents shall use the words: "Enforcement," "Department," or "Police." Said identification tags shall be prominently displayed on the front left side of the employee or agent's shirt. All booting business vehicles shall display the company name (or name of joint venture, or individual owner or other entity ownership) on the driver and passenger side of the vehicle in letters at least three (3) inches high. The company's address (or address of joint venture, or individual owner or other entity ownership) and telephone number shall be displayed on the driver and passenger side of the vehicle in letters at least one (1) inch high. No booting business shall use the words "Enforcement," "Department," or "Police," in its advertising, signs, stickers or identifications.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Each person who performs immobilization must enter into a written contract with every owner of private property that authorizes the person to immobilize vehicles on their property. Each contract that is in effect or that was terminated within the previous twelve (12) months must be kept on file. The CSD, law enforcement officers, and the owner of the vehicle that was immobilized may inspect and copy such contract during business hours.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
Any person who improperly causes a vehicle to be immobilized shall be liable to the vehicle owner or his authorized representative for the cost of the services provided, any damages results from the immobilization, and the immobilization and attorney's fees.
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
The business providing the booting service shall first obtain and maintain a current and valid license issued by the Director in accordance with Section 30-463(a), (b)1—9 and 11—15 and subject to the provisions in Sections 30-464, 30-476.1 and 30-477 (any reference in these sections to towing shall mean "immobilization" or "booting").
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
The individual person who is employed to perform the booting service has first obtained and maintains a permit issued by the Director in accordance with Section 30-463(a), (b)(1), (9), (11), (12), (13) and (15), and subject to the provisions in Section 30-464 and 30-466 (any reference to towing license shall mean "immobilization permit").
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
The business providing the booting service carries at least twenty-five thousand ($25,000.00) in liability insurance which will cover any damage to the vehicle.
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
The business providing the booting service must comply with Section 30-462(a) and 30-470-1 of this article (any reference in these sections to towing shall mean "immobilization" or "booting").
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
Persons who provide services pursuant to this section shall not use profane language, physical force or violence or threats of physical force or violence in dealing with the individuals responsible for administering this article or individuals who have had or are about to have their vehicles booted or immobilized.
</section>
<section prefix = "20">
Persons who provide services pursuant to this section shall maintain a place of business. The place of business shall have a sign that clearly and conspicuously identifies the business to the public; and office space that has at least one person on duty from 8:00 a.m. until 6:00 p.m., Monday through Friday, to answer telephone calls and to be open to serve the public and records requests made pursuant to Section 30-470. However, the office may be closed to observe all holidays observed by Miami-Dade County government. The place of business shall maintain a telephone communication system to answer telephone calls from the public twenty-four (24) hours a day. The license issued by the Director shall be prominently displayed to the public at said business location.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-480. Director's duties, functions and powers</catch_line>
<text>
The duties, functions, powers and responsibilities of the Director shall include the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Enforce all of the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Upon receipt of complaints or upon the Director's initiative, investigate and inspect matters regulated hereunder.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Institute civil actions or proceedings to enforce all the provisions of this article and subpoena issued by the Director, including seeking mandatory and prohibitory injunctions, the imposition and recovery of civil penalties and such other remedies and attorney's fees as set forth in Section 30-477 of this Code. Such civil actions or proceedings may be instituted by the Director regardless of whether a cease and desist order or notice to correct the violation or other lawful order of the Director has been issued or other administrative proceeding is pending.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Prosecute through the State Attorney in the criminal courts for violations of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Deny, revoke, suspend and issue registration certificates and impose conditions, limitations, and restrictions upon same in accordance with Sections 30-464 of this Code. Notwithstanding the foregoing, no revocation or suspension of a registration certificate by the Director shall be effective until the rendition of the appeal, if any, of such revocation or suspension pursuant to Section 8A-481 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, or until the time period for filing such appeal has expired, whichever is later.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Issue a subpoena to compel the presence of any person or document or thing at any hearing, conference or proceeding authorized herein upon information or belief by the Director that a violation of any provision of this article has occurred or may occur.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Inquire into the practices, functions and policies of towers and make such recommendations to the Commission as the Director may deem necessary.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Administer oaths and certify official acts of the Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Investigate, upon the Director's initiative, the practices of any tower.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Apply to any judge of the circuit or county court, criminal or civil division, for the issuance of an administrative search warrant.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Conduct a program for monitoring consumer satisfaction levels in the field of towing and make such monitoring information available to the Commission and the public.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Render, in the Director's discretion, assistance and technical advice to towers.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
Institute informal conferences for discussing and resolving any matter covered by this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "n">
Publish and disseminate information to the public concerning towers.
</section>
<section prefix = "o">
Issue cease and desist orders, notices to correct violations, and any other lawful orders of the Director which shall briefly set forth the general nature of the violation of this article and specify the time within which the violation shall be rectified or stopped. If an order to cease and desist or notice to correct violations or any other lawful order of the Director is not obeyed, the Director shall have the power and authority to revoke or suspend the license, if any has been issued, or deny the issuance of a license and take such other action authorized by this article. Notwithstanding the foregoing, no revocation or suspension of a license by the Director shall be effective until the rendition of the appeal, if any, of such revocation or suspension pursuant to Section 8A-481 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, or until the time period for filing such appeal has expired, whichever is later. Orders to cease and desist, notices to correct violations, and any other lawful orders of the Director hereunder may be enforced by the institution by the Director of civil actions for mandatory and prohibitory injunctions, civil penalties and other remedies and attorney's fees as set forth in Section 30-477 of the Code of Miami-Dade County in a court of competent jurisdiction.
</section>
<section prefix = "p">
Enter into written assurances of compliance pursuant to Sections 8A-82.1 and 30-477 (d) of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, with respect to the matters regulated under this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "q">
The powers of the Director enumerated in this article shall be in addition to and not a limitation of any other powers of the Director pursuant to any other provisions of this article or any other provisions of law or ordinance.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30-481. Appeals from actions, decisions or determinations of the director; judicial review</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Any person regulated by this article who is aggrieved by any action, decision or determination of the Director pursuant to this article may request an administrative hearing before a hearing officer to appeal the action, decision or determination of the Director which resulted in the grievance. Appeal by administrative hearing of the action, decision or determination complained of shall be accomplished by filing a written request with the Director within fifteen (15) days after the date of the action, decision or determination complained of, a written notice of appeal which shall set forth the nature of the action, decision or determination to be reviewed and the basis for the administrative hearing. A timely request for administrative hearing shall be scheduled and heard by a Hearing Officer pursuant to Section 8CC of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. Customers shall not be deemed to be persons regulated by this article for the purposes of this section. The Hearing Officer shall set the matter for hearing on the earliest practicable regularly scheduled hearing date or as soon as possible, but no sooner than ten (10) days after the request has been filed and shall cause notice of the hearing to be served upon the aggrieved party by first class mail. The notice may include, but not be limited to, the applicable Sections of 8CC-6(b)(2) through (9) of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. The Hearing Officer shall hear and consider all relevant facts in accordance with the procedures set forth in Sections 8CC-6(e), (f), (g), (i), (j), (k), (l), (m)(2), and (n) of the Code of Miami-Dade County (any reference in these sections to Inspector shall mean "Director" and to violator shall mean "the person filing the appeal", and may affirm, modify or reverse the action, decision or determination appealed from. The decision of the Hearing Officer shall constitute final administrative review and no rehearing shall be permitted. Nothing herein shall be construed to prevent or prohibit the Director from instituting any civil or criminal action or proceeding authorized by this article at any time.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Director, the Miami-Dade County Consumer Advocate, or any person regulated by this article who is aggrieved by any decision of the Hearing Officer may appeal a final order of the Hearing Officer by filing a notice of appeal in the Circuit Court in and for Miami-Dade County, Florida, in accordance with procedures and within the time provided by the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure for review of administrative action. The words "action," "decision" and "determination" as used herein shall not include the filing or institution of any action, conference or proceeding by the Director in any court or otherwise. Customers shall not be deemed to be persons regulated by this article for the purposes of this section.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 03-176, § 1, 7-22-03)</history>
<catch_line>Secs. 30-482—30-500. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (4) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 88-7, § 1, adopted Feb. 16, 1988, repealed the provisions of former Art. III, §§ 30-461—30-463, relative to towing of motor vehicles, and enacted a new Art. III to read as herein set out in §§ 30-461—30-471. The provisions of former Art. III derived from Ord. No. 75-13, §§ 1—3, adopted Feb. 4, 1975. Subsequently, Ord. No. 89-67, adopted July 11, 1989, enacted a new article, §§ 30-461—30-478. (Back)
Annotation—AO of 5-3-88. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
