<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_LXXIX._MIAMI-DADE_COUNTY_ASIAN-A</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1086. Created</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created the Miami-Dade County Asian-American Advisory Board.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1087. Composition</catch_line>
<text>
The Miami-Dade County Asian-American Advisory Board shall be composed of twenty-six (26) members who shall be permanent residents and electors of the County and who shall have a knowledge of and interest in the county's Asian community. Each County Commissioner shall appoint two (2) members of the board, one of whom shall serve an initial term of one (1) year and one of whom shall serve an initial term of three (3) years. After the initial appointment, all members shall thereafter serve three-year terms.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1088. Membership; officers; meetings</catch_line>
<text>
The members of the board shall elect a chairperson, vice-chairperson, and such other additional offices as the Asian-American Advisory Board shall deem necessary. All officers shall serve at the will of the board. Fourteen (14) members of the board shall constitute a quorum necessary to hold a meeting and take any action. Members shall serve without compensation. The chairperson or vice-chairperson may call meetings of the board. Meetings may also be called by written notice signed by fourteen (14) members. The board at any duly noticed public meeting may fix and call a meeting on a future date. All meetings shall be public.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1089. Duties; powers; responsibilities</catch_line>
<text>
The board shall have the following duties, powers and responsibilities:
<section prefix = "1">
To serve in an advisory capacity to the County Commission, the County administration, the community, and all agencies and persons in Miami-Dade County, Florida, with respect to matters pertaining to the Asian community of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To formulate and recommend policies, plans, programs and services and to coordinate the activities of governmental entities and nongovernmental agencies pertaining to the Asian community.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
It is the express purpose of this board to serve as a medium for responsible persons to utilize and consult with in attempting to understand and address the various complex problems affecting the Asian community in Miami-Dade County and to make findings and recommendations to the County Commission and the County administration regarding such matters.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
To recommend solutions to the social, economic, cultural and political problems in the Asian community, as well as to serve as liaison between the Asian community and the Miami-Dade County community at large.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
To promote active participation of Asian-Americans in civic, cultural, commercial and community affairs.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
To encourage and attract Asian businesses to Miami-Dade County, to assist Asian businesses located in Miami-Dade County, and to promote economic development, especially job creation in Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
To foster relationships with public officials and maintain formal channels of communication so that Asian concerns are effectively transmitted and heard.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
To promote positive images and concepts of Asian and Asian-Americans as well as promote their many contributions to our society.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
To build coalitions with various community groups to address issues of common concern, such as advocating positive legislation regarding immigration and advocating legislation to strengthen the penalties for racially motivated crimes.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
To promote the cultural heritage of Asian-Americans.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
To encourage and assist in citizenship registration and voter registration.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
To eliminate ignorance and bigotry towards Asian-Americans.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
To conduct studies through fact-finding and analysis of problems encountered by Asian community members.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
The board shall report at least annually to the Commission as to its activities, findings and recommendations.
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
To perform such other duties as may from time to time be assigned to it by resolution of the County Commission.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1090. Supervision and Support</catch_line>
<text>
The Office of the Chairperson of the County Commission, County Attorney and Clerk of the Board shall provide appropriate support for the Asian-American Advisory Board. The Chairperson of the County Commission shall have the power to appoint employ, remove and supervise such assistants, employees, and personnel as deemed necessary to provide appropriate support to the Asian-American Advisory Board, and such assistants, employees, and personnel shall serve at the will of the Chairperson of the County Commission.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-1091—2-1100. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
</law>
