<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 14 FIRE PREVENTION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_III._SOUTH_FLORIDA_FIRE_PREVENTI</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-40. Short title; adoption by reference; applicability</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
The South Florida Fire Prevention Code is hereby adopted by reference as if fully set forth herein, as said code may be amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
The South Florida Fire Prevention Code may hereinafter be referred to as the "S.F.F.P.C."
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
The S.F.F.P.C. as amended from time to time, and this article, as amended from time to time, shall be applicable in both the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Dade County, Florida. All references in this article to the S.F.F.P.C. and this article shall be deemed respectively to refer to the S.F.F.P.C. as amended from time to time and this article as amended from time to time. All references in this article to the South Florida Building Code shall be deemed to refer to the South Florida Building Code as amended from time to time.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 87-89, § 3, 12-15-87)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-41. Intent; construction</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
The intent of this article and the S.F.F.P.C. is to protect the public health, safety and welfare by prescribing minimum standards for fire prevention and safety.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
This article and the S.F.F.P.C. are hereby determined to be remedial and essential to protect the public health, safety, and welfare.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
This article and the S.F.F.P.C. shall be liberally construed to protect the public health, safety, and welfare.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
This article and the S.F.F.P.C. shall not be construed to provide any cause of action or claim for relief of any kind whatsoever to any person other than the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, or both, and shall be retroactively applied to effectuate the foregoing.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 87-89, § 3, 12-15-87; Ord. No. 90-150, § 5, 12-18-90)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-42. Minimum fire safety standards</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
The requirements of the S.F.F.P.C. and this article shall be a minimum standard for the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
The requirements of the S.F.F.P.C. and this article shall not apply to buildings and structures subject to the uniform fire safety standards promulgated pursuant to Section 633.022, Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
The requirements of the S.F.F.P.C. and this article shall not apply to buildings and structures subject to the minimum fire safety standards adopted pursuant to Sections 394.879 and 396.176, Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
The requirements of the S.F.F.P.C. and this article shall be a minimum fire safety standard code. A municipality with fire safety responsibilities may adopt more stringent fire safety standards. Minimum fire safety standards shall be met by every occupancy, facility, building, structure, premises, device, or activity to which said standards apply.
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
The new building or structure requirements set forth in the S.F.F.P.C. and this article shall apply only to buildings or structures for which the building permit is issued on or after January 1, 1988.
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
Subject to the provisions of subsection (G) herein, the existing building or structure requirements set forth in the S.F.F.P.C. and this article shall apply to buildings or structures for which the building permit was issued or the building or structures were constructed prior to January 1, 1988.
</section>
<section prefix = "G">
With respect to existing buildings, the Legislature of the State of Florida has recognized that it is not always practical to apply any or all of the requirements of the S.F.F.P.C. and this article and that physical limitations may require disproportionate effort or expense with little increase in life safety.
<section prefix = "1">
Prior to applying the requirements of the S.F.F.P.C. and this article to an existing building, the chief fire official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, shall determine that a threat to life safety or property exists.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
If a threat to life safety or property exists the chief fire official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, shall apply the applicable requirements of the S.F.F.P.C. and this article to the extent practical to assure a reasonable degree of life safety and safety of property.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The chief of fire official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, shall fashion a reasonable alternative which affords an equivalent degree of life safety and safety of property.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The decisions of the chief fire official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, under subsection (G) may be appealed to the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "H">
Nothing in this section shall preclude a municipality, County, or special district from requiring a structure to be maintained in accordance with S.F.F.P.C. and this article.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 87-89, § 3, 12-15-87)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-43. Resolution of conflict of laws</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
In the event of a conflict between (i) the requirements of the South Florida Building Code, as same may be amended from time to time, and (ii) the requirements of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code and this article, as all of same may be amended from time to time, the conflict shall be resolved by agreement between the chief building code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, and the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, in favor of the requirement of either the South Florida Building Code or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code or this article which provides the greatest degree of life safety or alternatives which would provide an equivalent degree of life safety and equivalent method of construction.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Any decision made by the chief building code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, and the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, may be appealed to the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board.
<section prefix = "1">
If the decision of the chief building code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, and the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, is to apply the provisions of either the South Florida Building Code or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code or this article, the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board may not alter the decision unless the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board determines that the application of the South Florida Building Code or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code or this article is not reasonable.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
If the decision of the chief building code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, and the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, is to adopt an alternative to the South Florida Building Code, South Florida Fire Prevention Code, and this article, the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board shall give due regard to the decision rendered by the aforesaid officials and may modify that decision if the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board adopts a better alternative, taking into consideration all relevant circumstances.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
In any case in which the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board adopts alternatives to the decision of the chief building code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, and the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, such alternatives shall provide a degree of life safety and method of construction equivalent to the degree of life safety and method of construction provided by the decision of the aforesaid building code and fire code enforcement officials.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
In the event that the chief building code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, and the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, are unable to agree on a resolution of the conflict between the requirements of (i) the South Florida Building Code and (ii) the South Florida Fire Prevention Code and this article, the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board shall resolve the conflict in favor of the requirement which provides the greatest degree of life safety or alternatives which would provide an equivalent degree of life safety and an equivalent method of construction.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
In the event of any conflict between a requirement of (i) this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code and (ii) a requirement of Chapter 633, Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time, or the rules promulgated by the State Fire Marshal pursuant to Chapter 633, Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time, or the rules promulgated by the State Fire Marshal pursuant to Chapter 633, Florida Statutes, as said rules may be amended from time to time, the provision which established the most stringent standard shall prevail.
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
In the event of any conflict between a provision of (i) this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code and (ii) a provision of any other County or municipal ordinance, code or regulation, the provisions of subsections (A), (B) and (C) shall apply if the conflict is with a requirement of the South Florida Building Code, or, if the conflict is with a provision other than the South Florida Building Code, then the provision which establishes the most stringent standard shall prevail.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 87-89, § 3, 12-15-87)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-44. Uniform Fire Safety Standards</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Pursuant to Section 633.15, Florida Statutes, Chapter 633, Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time, and all the rules promulgated thereunder by the State Fire Marshal, as same may be amended from time to time, are hereby adopted by reference as if fully set forth herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Each jurisdiction within Dade County, Florida, with fire safety responsibilities shall enforce within its fire safety jurisdiction:
<section prefix = "i">
The uniform fire safety standards promulgated by the State Fire Marshal for those buildings set forth in Section 633.022(1)(b), Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
The minimum fire safety standards for mental health and alcohol treatment centers as adopted pursuant to Section 394.879, Florida Statutes, and Section 396.176, Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time; and
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
The fire safety standards for public schools adopted by the State Board of Education, as same may be amended from time to time.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 87-89, § 3, 12-15-87)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-44.1. Statutes adopted by reference</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Chapter 791, Florida Statutes, and all the rules and regulations promulgated thereunder, as all of same may be amended from time to time, are hereby adopted by reference as if fully set forth herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Section 806.10, Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time, is hereby adopted by reference is if fully set forth herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Section 806.101, Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time, is hereby adopted by reference as if fully set forth herein.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 87-89, § 3, 12-15-87)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-45. Chief fire official</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
For the purposes of this article and the South Florida Fire Prevention Code all references to the chief fire official with respect to the unincorporated area of Dade County shall mean the Director of the Metropolitan Dade County Fire Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
For the purposes of this article and the South Florida Fire Prevention Code all references to the chief fire official with respect to the incorporated areas of Dade County shall mean the Director of the Metropolitan Dade County Fire Department, the Fire Chief of the City of Miami Beach, the Director of the City of Miami Fire Rescue and Inspection Services Department, the Fire Chief of the City of Hialeah, or the Fire Chief of the City of Coral Gables, within their respective areas of fire safety and prevention responsibilities.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 87-89, § 3, 12-15-87)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-46. Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Established. There is hereby created and established the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Membership. This Board shall consist of thirteen (13) members appointed by the County Commission. In order to secure representative membership upon the Board, the Commission shall appoint one (1) architect, one (1) engineer, one (1) property manager, one (1) representative from the fuel industry, one (1) representative from the fire insurance industry, one (1) licensed general contractor possessing a current certificate of competency, two (2) persons who are serving different jurisdictions in the fire fighting service of such jurisdictions, the County Manager or his designee, one (1) representative of the Dade County League of Cities, Inc., one (1) safety engineer certified by a professional safety engineering society, one (1) city or county administrator, and one (1) educator who has expertise in the development of a fire science curriculum. Three (3) members shall be appointed for a term of one (1) year, three (3) members shall be appointed for a term of two (2) years, and three (3) members shall be appointed for a term of three (3) years. Thereafter, all members shall be appointed for a term of three (3) years.
<section prefix = "1">
When the jurisdiction of the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board is exercised pursuant to Section 14-46(D)(2) of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, Florida, with respect to those duties and responsibilities of the local administrative Board specifically described in Section 553.73(8)(c), Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time, the membership of the Board shall consist of the eleven (11) members set forth in Section 14-46(B) above as well as the following eleven (11) members of the Dade County Board of Rules and Appeals who shall be designated by the Chairman of the Dade County Board of Rules and Appeals:
<section prefix = "i">
One (1) nonprofessional person;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Two (2) representatives of the fire service;
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
One (1) master plumber;
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
One (1) mechanical engineer;
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
One (1) master electrician;
</section>
<section prefix = "vi">
One (1) structural engineer;
</section>
<section prefix = "vii">
One (1) developer;
</section>
<section prefix = "viii">
Two (2) general contractors;
</section>
<section prefix = "ix">
One (1) architect.
The aforesaid persons in (i) through (ix) shall be voting ex officio members of the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board only when the jurisdiction of the Board is exercised as set forth hereinabove for those duties and responsibilities set forth in Section 553.73(8)(c), Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time. Service on the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board by members of the Dade County Board of Rules and Appeals ex officio as set forth above shall not be deemed to be service on two (2) County Boards simultaneously for the purposes of Section 2-11.38 of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, Florida.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Organization of the Board; quorum; Secretary. The members of the Board shall elect a chairperson and such other officers as may be deemed necessary or desirable, all of whom shall serve at the will of the Board. A majority vote of the members present shall be necessary to take any action. Seven (7) members of the Board shall constitute a quorum necessary to hold a meeting and take any action. The Director of the Metropolitan Dade County Fire Department or his designee shall be Secretary of the Board and shall be responsible for the custody of all minutes and records of the Board. The Secretary of the Board shall not be entitled to vote on any matter before the Board by reason of holding the office of Secretary. The Chairperson or his designee may call meetings of the Board; seven (7) members may call a meeting upon signing a written notice; and the Board at any meeting may call meetings for any future dates. Minutes shall be kept of all meetings of the Board.
<section prefix = "1">
When the jurisdiction of the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board is exercised as set forth in (B)(1) above: A majority vote of the twenty-two (22) members present shall be necessary to take any action; the presence of twelve (12) of the twenty-two (22) members shall constitute a quorum necessary to hold a meeting and take any action; and twelve (12) members may call a meeting upon signing a written notice. In all other respects the organization of the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board shall remain the same as set forth in (C) above.
[(2)
Reserved.]
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
Duties and powers of the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board. The Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board shall have the following duties, functions, powers, and responsibilities:
<section prefix = "1">
To exclusively hear and determine appeals by any person aggrieved by any action or decision of any fire official of any jurisdiction in Dade County, Florida, with respect to this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or any municipal ordinance, code, or regulation which regulates fire prevention or fire safety. Notwithstanding any provision of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, Florida, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, any municipal ordinance, or any other County ordinance, no other County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board, except as provided for code enforcement by Chapter 162, Florida Statutes, or by Chapter 8CC of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, Florida, may hear or determine any matter which the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board has the power to hear and determine pursuant to this subsection. The Board shall have the power and authority to affirm, modify, or reverse the action or decision which was appealed.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To exclusively perform the duties and responsibilities of the local administrative Board described in Section 553.73(8)(b) and Section 553.73(8)(c), Florida Statutes, as all of same may be amended from time to time. Notwithstanding any provision of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, Florida, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, any municipal ordinance, or any other County ordinance, no other County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board, may hear or determine any matter which the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board has the power to hear and determine pursuant to this subsection. The Board shall have the power and authority to adopt alternatives and resolve conflicts as provided by the aforesaid provisions of Florida law, as amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
To exclusively hear and determine appeals by any person aggrieved by the decisions or actions of the chief fire official, or his designee, of any jurisdiction in Dade County, Florida, with respect to existing buildings as provided by Section 633.025(8), Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time. Notwithstanding any provision of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, Florida, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, any municipal ordinance, or any other County ordinance, no other County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board, may hear or determine any matter which the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board has the power to hear and determine pursuant to this subsection. The Board shall have the power and authority to affirm, modify, or reverse the action of decision which was appealed.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
To exclusively perform the duties of the local authority as set forth in Section 633.022(2)(b), Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time, by authorizing alternatives to the uniform fire safety standards as set forth in Section 633.022(2)(b), Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time. Notwithstanding any provision of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, Florida, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, any municipal ordinance, or any other County ordinance, no other County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board, may hear or determine any matter which the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board has the power to hear and determine pursuant to this subsection. The Board shall have the power and authority to adopt alternatives as provided by the aforesaid provision of Florida law, as amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
To exclusively perform the duties of all jurisdictions with fire safety responsibilities in Dade County, Florida, as set forth in Section 633.025(5), Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time, by establishing alternative requirements to the requirements of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or other more stringent fire safety standards adopted by a municipality, as set forth in Section 633.025(5), Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time. Notwithstanding any provision of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, Florida, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, any municipal ordinance, or any other County ordinance, no other County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board, may hear or determine any matter which the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board has the power to hear and determine pursuant to this subsection. The Board shall have the power and authority to adopt alternative requirements as provided by the aforesaid provision of Florida law, as amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
To exclusively hear and determine appeals by any person aggrieved by the actions or decisions of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer established by this article, as amended from time to time. Notwithstanding any provision of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, Florida, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, any municipal ordinance, or any other County ordinance, no other County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board, may hear or determine any matter which the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board has the power to hear and determine pursuant to this subsection. The Board shall have the power and authority to affirm, modify, or reverse the action or decision which was appealed.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Upon the request of any chief fire official or his designee of any jurisdiction in Dade County, Florida, to render advice to the requesting party on any fire safety or fire prevention matters in Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
To exclusively hear and determine, after notice to municipality, whether or not fire safety standards adopted by a municipality are more stringent than the fire safety standards set forth in this article and the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, as all of same are amended from time to time. Notwithstanding any provision of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, Florida, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, any municipal ordinance, or any other County ordinance, no other County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board, may hear or determine any matter which the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board has the power to hear and determine pursuant to this subsection. The Board shall have the power and authority to order the chief fire official, or his designee, of the municipality or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, or both, to enforce the fire safety standards which are the most stringent.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
To exclusively hear and determine, after notice of the affected County department or County Board, whether or not a provision of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, Florida, other than the South Florida Building Code, conflicts with the provisions of this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, as all of same may be amended from time to time, and, if such conflict exists, to determine which provision established the most stringent standard. Notwithstanding any provision of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, Florida, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, any municipal ordinance, or any other County ordinance, no other County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board, may hear and determine any matter which the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board has the power to hear and determine pursuant to this subsection. The Board shall have the power and authority to order the chief fire officials, or their designees, of all jurisdiction in Dade County, Florida, and the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, to enforce the fire safety standards which are the most stringent.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Upon the request of the Board of County Commissioners, to render advice to the Board of County Commissioners or such other persons as the Board of County Commissioners may direct, on any fire prevention or fire safety matters in Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
To issue subpoenas to compel the presence of a witness or documents or other items at any proceeding of the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board authorized under this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, as all of same may be amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
To adopt, promulgate, amend and rescind such rules of procedure and evidence as may be necessary to exercise the Board's authority, provided, however, that no such rules shall conflict with the provisions of this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, as all of same may be amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
The powers enumerated in this section shall be in addition to and not a limitation of or in derogation of any other powers granted to the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board by any other provision of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or by State law, rule or regulation, as all of same may be amended from time to time. Notwithstanding any provision of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, Florida, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, any municipal ordinance or any other County ordinance, except as provided in subsection (1) herein, no other County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board shall exercise any of the powers granted to the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board by this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code or by State law, rule, or regulation, as all of same may be amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
To designate one (1) or more persons to be members of one (1) or more technical advisory panels to advise the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board on technical matters related to fire prevention or fire safety. The members of such panels shall be persons technically skilled and qualified to render advice on particular matters of fire prevention or fire safety pending before the Board. The members shall serve at the will of the Board and shall furnish advice and information of a technical nature to the Board for so long a period of time as the Board may request it. All such advice and information given by the panel or any member thereof shall be in the form of testimony either in person or by deposition before the Board at a regularly scheduled meeting and subject to cross-examination at the deposition and meeting by any interested party. The members of the panels shall not be deemed County officers or employees. Members of the panels may be compensated by the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
To require and administer oaths or affirmations to witnesses in any proceeding of the Board.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 87-89, § 3, 12-15-87; Ord. No. 94-7, § 1, 1-18-94)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-47. Repeal of conflicting or inconsistent municipal and County laws</catch_line>
<text>
This article and the South Florida Fire Prevention Code are intended and shall be construed as constituting minimum standards for all governmental units in Dade County with respect to fire prevention and safety standards, in accordance with the provisions of Section 1.01(A)(18) of the Home Rule Charter of Government for Dade County, Florida. To the extent of the minimum standards herein provided, all County and municipal ordinance, County and municipal resolutions, municipal charters, special laws applying only to Dade County or any general law which the County Commission is authorized by the constitution to supersede, nullify or amend, and any part of any such ordinance, resolution, charter, or law in conflict with or inconsistent with the minimum fire prevention and safety standards herein established are hereby repealed and superseded.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-48. Appeals from actions or decisions</catch_line>
<text>
Any person aggrieved by any action or decision described in Section 14-46(D)(1), (2), (3), (4), (5), (6), (8), and (9) of this Code may appeal to the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board by filing with the Secretary of said Board a written notice of appeal within fifteen (15) days after the date of the action or decision which is the subject of the appeal. Filing of a written notice of appeal shall not stay the effect of any such action or decision which is the subject to the appeal. The written notice of appeal shall set forth concisely the date and nature of the action or decision to be reviewed as well as the reasons or grounds for the appeal. The Secretary of the Board shall set each such appeal for hearing at the earliest practicable Board meeting date available and shall provide written or oral notice of the hearing to the appellant and to the person whose action or decision is the subject of the appeal. The Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board shall hear and consider all facts material and relevant to the appeal and shall render a decision as soon as reasonably practicable. Irrelevant, immaterial or unduly repetitious evidence of a type commonly relied upon by reasonably prudent persons in the conduct of their affairs shall be admissible, whether or not such evidence would be admissible in a trial in the courts of Florida. Any part of the evidence may be received in written form, and all testimony of parties and witnesses shall be made under oath or affirmation. Hearsay evidence may be used for the purpose of supplementing or explaining other evidence, but it shall not be sufficient in itself to support a decision of the Board unless it would be admissible over objection in civil actions. The Chairperson of the Board or the attorney of the Board or a Notary Public shall have the power to administer oaths or affirmations. Subpoenas may be issued by the Chairperson of the Board or another member of the Board designated by the Chairperson, upon the written request of any party or upon the Chairperson's or Board's own motion, to compel the presence of a witness or documents or other items at any proceeding of the Board authorized under this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, as all of same may be amended from time to time. The Chairperson of the Board or another member of the Board designated by the Chairperson, may permit discovery, on the written request of any party or upon the Board's own motion, by any means available to the courts and in the manner provided in the Florida Rules of Civil Procedure, including the imposition of sanctions, except contempt. Any person subject to a subpoena may, before compliance and on timely petition, request the Board to invalidate the subpoena on the grounds that it was not lawfully issued, is unreasonably broad in scope, or requires the production of irrelevant material. Any party or the Board may seek enforcement of a subpoena, order directing discovery, or order imposing sanctions issued hereunder by filing a petition for enforcement in the Circuit Court of Dade County, Florida. A failure to comply with an order of the Court shall result in a finding of contempt. However, no person shall be in contempt while a subpoena is being challenged as provided herein. The Court may award to the prevailing party all or part of the costs and attorneys fees incurred in obtaining the Court order. A party shall have the opportunity to respond, to present evidence and argument on all issues involved, conduct cross-examination and submit rebuttal evidence. When appropriate, the general public may be given an opportunity to present evidence. If the Board intends to consider such evidence, then all parties shall be given an opportunity to cross-examine, challenge, and rebut the evidence. When official recognition is requested, the parties shall be notified and given an opportunity to examine and contest the matter requested to be officially recognized. All decisions of the Board, pursuant to Section 553.73, Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time, shall be in writing and be binding upon all persons but shall not limit the authority of the State Fire Marshal pursuant to Section 633.161, Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time. All decisions of the Board, pursuant to Section 553.73, Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time, of general application shall be indexed by the Secretary of the Board by building and fire code sections and shall be available for inspection and copying during normal business hours. Similarly, all decisions of the chief building code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, and the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, pursuant to Section 553.73, Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time, shall be in writing and be binding upon all persons but shall not limit the authority of the State Fire Marshal pursuant to Section 633.161, Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time, and said decisions of general application shall be indexed by the Secretary of the Board by building and fire code section and shall be available for inspection and copying during normal business hours. All decisions of the Board shall be in writing, shall set forth the reasons for the decision, and shall be signed by the Chairperson of the Board or other member of the Board designated by the Chairperson or in the absence of the Chairperson, a member of the Board designated by the Board. The decision of the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board shall constitute final administrative review and no rehearing or reconsideration shall be considered. Any person aggrieved by any decision of the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board on an appeal may seek judicial review in accordance with the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-49. South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
There is hereby created and established the position of South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer. The South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer shall be appointed by the County Manager after considering the recommendations of the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board. Said officer shall be exempt from the classified service and shall serve at the will of the County Manager. The Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board shall supervise the activities of said officer and may recommend the replacement of said officer.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
The County Manager may appoint and employ personnel to assist the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, subject to the appropriation of funds and approval of salaries by the Board of County Commissioners. Such personnel may include members of a South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Team who shall work under the direct supervision of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer. The Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board may recommend persons to the County Manager for appointment to the aforesaid team.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
The South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer or his designees shall have the following powers, duties and responsibilities:
<section prefix = "1">
To perform inspections of any property or premises or thing in the unincorporated and incorporated areas of Dade County for the purpose of determining whether or not the jurisdiction having fire safety and fire prevention responsibilities is adequately or uniformly enforcing the provisions of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, this article, fire safety standards adopted by a municipality which are more stringent than the fire safety standards in this article or in the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or in the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time. No such inspection shall occur unless the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, is notified of the inspection prior to the occurrence in the inspection.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To order any person within any jurisdiction in Dade County, Florida, to comply with the provisions of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, this article, any fire safety standards adopted by a municipality which are more stringent than the fire safety standards in this article or in the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or in the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time. Such order shall superseded and nullify the particular orders or actions of the fire officials of the particular jurisdiction; however, no such order shall be issued until the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, is afforded a reasonable period of time to obtain compliance. Said reasonable period of time shall be determined by and in the sole discretion of the South Florida Fire Prevention Enforcement Officer. The South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer shall provide a copy of the order to the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, and to the governing body of the particular jurisdiction.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
To report to the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board all actions taken by the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer and Team on no less than a monthly basis.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
To report, on no less than an annual basis, to the Board of County Commissioners, all activities of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer and Team.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The powers enumerated in this section shall be in addition to and not a limitation of or in derogation of any other powers granted to the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer by any other provision of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code or by state law, rule or regulation, as all of same may be amended from time to time. No other County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board shall exercise any of the powers granted to the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer by this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or by State law, rule or regulation, as all of same may be amended from time to time.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 87-89, § 3, 12-15-87)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-50. Remedies cumulative and independent</catch_line>
<text>
All the judicial and administrative remedies in this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, municipal ordinances, County ordinances, State laws, and rules and regulations, as all of same may be amended from time to time, are independent and cumulative.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-51. Strict liability</catch_line>
<text>
Whenever a violation of this article or of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code or of a more stringent municipal fire safety standard occurs or exists, any person, individually or otherwise who has a legal, beneficial or equitable interest in the facility or instrumentality causing or contributing to the violation or who has a legal, beneficial, or equitable interest in the real property upon which such facility or instrumentality is located shall be jointly and severally liable for said violation regardless of fault and regardless of knowledge of the violation. This provision shall be construed to impose joint and several liability, regardless of fault and regardless of knowledge of the violation, upon all persons, individually or otherwise, who, although no longer having any such legal, beneficial or equitable interest in said facility or instrumentality or real property, did have such an interest at any time during which such violation existed or occurred or continued to exist or to occur. This provision shall be liberally construed and shall be retroactively applied to protect the public health, safety, and welfare and to accomplish the purposes of this article and the South Florida Fire Prevention Code.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-52. Criminal penalty</catch_line>
<text>
If any person shall fail or refuse to obey or comply with, or violates any of the provisions of this article or of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code or of a more stringent fire safety standard or any lawful order of the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or any lawful order of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, or his designee, or any condition, limitation or restriction which is part of a permit issued or rendered under and pursuant to this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, such person, upon conviction of such offense, shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00), or by imprisonment not to exceed sixty (60) days in the County Jail, or both in the discretion of the court. Each day of each continued violation shall be considered as a separate offense.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-53. Permits</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
No person shall operate, utilize or occupy, or cause, allow, let, permit or suffer to be operated, utilized or occupied any facility, instrumentality or real property, in the unincorporated or incorporated areas of Dade County, which is required to obtain a permit issued by the Fire Department having jurisdiction pursuant to this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code without such a valid permit or in violation of any condition, limitation or restriction which is part of such a permit.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
The criterion for issuance of a permit by the Fire Department having jurisdiction shall be compliance with the provisions of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code or, within a municipality, any fire safety standards adopted by a municipality which are more stringent than the fire safety standards in this article or in the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or in the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time. The Fire Department having jurisdiction may require conditions, limitations and restrictions as part of any permit if said conditions, limitations, or restrictions are consistent with this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, and, within a municipality, any fire safety standards adopted by a municipality which are more stringent than the fire safety standards in this article or in the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or in the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
The Fire Department having jurisdiction may deny the issuance of, suspend or revoke any permit for failure to comply with the provisions of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or, within a municipality, any fire safety standards adopted by a municipality which are more stringent than the fire safety standards in this article, or in the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or in the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
The Fire Department having jurisdiction may deny the issuance of any such permit or revoke or suspend any such permit for failure to comply with the conditions, limitations and restrictions of any such permit.
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
No such permits shall be required for the aforesaid facilities, instrumentalities and real property existing on the effective date of this section until one hundred twenty (120) days from the effective date of this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
All applications for permits pursuant to this section shall be on a form prescribed by the Fire Department having jurisdiction and accompanied by the required fee. The fees shall be established by administrative order of the County Manager and approved by the Board of County Commissioners for permits within the jurisdiction of the Metropolitan Dade County Fire Department. The fees shall be established by the governing body of the City of Miami Beach, the City of Miami, the City of Hialeah and the City of Coral Gables for such permits within the respective jurisdictions of the aforesaid municipalities.
</section>
<section prefix = "G">
The permit fees payable hereunder shall be deposited in a separate County fund, or, in the case of the aforesaid municipalities, in separate municipal funds, to be used exclusively by the Fire Department of the jurisdiction to pay for the costs of the following:
<section prefix = "1">
Investigation, preparation, and prosecution of civil and criminal actions, pursuant to this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, to enforce the provisions of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code and, in the case of the aforesaid municipalities, fire standards adopted by the municipality which are more stringent than the provisions in this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Monitoring, permitting, and inspection of facilities, instrumentalities, and real property to determine and seek to insure compliance with this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, and, in the case of the aforesaid municipalities, fire standards adopted by the municipality which are more stringent than this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Responding to and attempting to resolve citizen complaints against violations or possible violations of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, and in the case of the aforesaid municipalities, fire standards adopted by the municipality which are more stringent than this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Fire safety and prevention planning, protection, and programming.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "H">
No part of such separate County and separate municipal funds shall be used for purposes other than the aforesaid. The amount of said fees shall be reasonably regulated to the cost of the services and regulation provided.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 87-89, § 3, 12-15-87)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-53.1. Plan review</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
No County or municipal officer, agent, employee, agency, or Board shall issue any permit for construction, erection, alteration, repair, or demolition until the chief building code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, in conjunction with the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, has reviewed the plans and specifications for such proposal and both of the aforesaid code enforcement officials, or their designees, have determined that the plans are in compliance with the South Florida Building Code, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, this article, the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, and any fire safety standards adopted by the municipality which are more stringent than the fire safety standards in this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Any building or structure which is exempt from the County or municipal building permit process shall not be required to have its plans reviewed pursuant to (A) above.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Industrial construction on sites where design, construction, and fire safety are supervised by appropriate design and inspection professionals and which contain adequate in-house Fire Departments and rescue squads shall not be exempt from review of plans and inspections.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
The County or municipality shall issue a permit to construct, erect, alter, repair, or demolish any building where the plans and specifications for such proposal comply with the South Florida Building Code, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, this article, the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, and any fire safety standards adopted by the municipality which are more stringent than the fire safety standards in this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
The chief building code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, shall require of every threshold building that all plans for the building which are required to be signed and sealed by the architect or engineer of record contain a statement that, to the best of the architect's or engineer's knowledge, the plans and specifications comply with the South Florida Building Code, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, this article, the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, and any fire safety standards adopted by the municipality which are more stringent than the fire safety standards in this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
Nothing in this section shall be construed to alter or supplement the provisions of Part IV of Chapter 553, Florida Statutes, relating to factory-built housing.
</section>
<section prefix = "G">
One- and two-family detached residential dwelling units shall not be subject to plan review by the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "H">
One- and two-family detached residential dwelling units shall be subject to inspection by the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or by the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, or both, pursuant to Chapter 633, Florida Statutes, this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or as provided by law, as all of same may be amended from time to time.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 87-89, § 3, 12-15-87)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-54. Consent agreements</catch_line>
<text>
The chief fire enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, may, in the official's or his designee's discretion, and the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer may, in the officer's discretion, terminate an investigation or an action commenced under the provisions of this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code upon execution of a written consent agreement between the chief fire enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or the South Florida Dire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, and the persons who are the subject of the investigation or action. The consent agreement shall provide written assurance of voluntary compliance by said persons with the applicable provisions of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, and in the case of a municipality, fire safety standards adopted by the municipality which are more stringent than the provisions in this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time. The consent agreement may, in the discretion of the chief fire code enforcement official, or his designee, or in the discretion of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, provide the following: Posting of a surety, bond, or other security to assure compliance; costs and expenses of the Fire Department having jurisdiction or of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer for investigation, enforcement, testing, monitoring, and litigation, including attorneys' fees; civil penalties; remedial or corrective action. An executed written consent agreement shall not be evidence of a prior violation of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or, in the case of a municipality, of any municipal ordinance. Such consent agreement shall not be deemed to impose any limitation upon any investigation or action of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer or chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, in the enforcement of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code or, in the case of a municipality, any municipal ordinance. The consent agreement shall not constitute a waiver of or limitation upon the enforcement of any federal, State or local laws and ordinances. Executed written consent agreements are hereby deemed to be lawful orders of the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer. Each violation of any of the terms and conditions of an executed written consent agreement shall constitute a separate offense under this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, and, in the case of a municipality, an applicable municipal ordinance, by the persons who executed the consent agreement, their respective officers, directors, agents, servants, employees, and attorneys; and by those persons in active concert or participation with any of the foregoing persons and who receive actual notice of the consent agreement. Each day during any portion of which each such violation occurs constitutes a separate offense under this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, and in the case of a municipality, any applicable municipal ordinance. Decisions and actions of the chief fire code enforcement official, or his designee, or of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, pursuant to this section or the written consent agreements provided herein, shall not be subject to review by the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board or by any other County or municipal Board, officer, agent or employee.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-55. Attorneys' fees</catch_line>
<text>
Upon the rendition of a judgment or decree by any of the courts of this state against any person in favor of the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or in favor of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, to enforce any of the provisions of this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, the trial court, or, in the event of an appeal in which the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, prevails, the appellate court shall adjudge or decree against said person and in favor of the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, a reasonable sum as fees or compensation for the attorney of the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or for the attorney of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, who prosecuted the suit in which the recovery was had. Where so awarded, compensation or fees of the attorney shall be included in the judgment or decree rendered in the case. This provision shall apply to all pending or prospective civil actions, legal or equitable, filed by the chief fire code enforcement official of any jurisdiction in Dade County, or his designee, or by the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, to enforce the provisions of this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code or any more stringent municipal fire safety standard. Cessation, correction or remediation of any violation of the provisions of this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code or of any more stringent fire safety standard whatsoever, prior to rendition of a judgment or of a temporary or final decree, or prior to execution of a negotiated settlement, but after an action is filed by the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or by the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, to enforce the provisions of this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code or a more stringent municipal fire safety standard, shall be deemed the functional equivalent of a confession of judgment or verdict in favor of the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, for which attorneys' fees shall be awarded by the trial court as set forth hereinabove.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-56. Enforcement; procedure; remedies</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
It shall be unlawful for any person to violate or to permit, allow, let or suffer any violation of: Any of the provisions of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or any fire safety standard of a municipality which is more stringent in accordance with Section 633.025(5), Florida Statutes, as all of same may be amended from time to time; any condition, limitation or restriction which is part of a permit issued pursuant to this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, as all of same may be amended from time to time; lawful orders of the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee; lawful orders of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer; and consent agreements. In addition to any other judicial or administrative remedies provided by this article or by the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, or both, shall have the following judicial remedies:
<section prefix = "1">
To institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to seek temporary or permanent, prohibitory or mandatory injunctive relief to enforce compliance with or prohibit the violation of: Any of the provisions of this article or of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, as all of same may be amended from time to time; any lawful order of the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee; any lawful order of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer; any fire safety standard of a municipality which is more stringent in accordance with Section 633.025(5), Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time; any condition, limitation, or restriction which is part of a permit issued pursuant to this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, as all of same may be amended from time to time; or any consent agreement.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to impose and recover a civil penalty in an amount of not more than twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000.00) for each violation of: Any of the provisions of this article or of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, as all of same may be amended from time to time; any lawful order of chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee; any lawful order of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer; any fire safety standard of a municipality which is more stringent in accordance with Section 633.025(5), Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time; any condition, limitation, or restriction which is part of a permit issued pursuant to this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, as all of same may be amended from time to time; or any consent agreement.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
To institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to seek restitution and other equitable relief to recover any sums expended and costs incurred for:
<section prefix = "i">
Tracing, investigating, preventing, controlling, abating, or remedying violations of: This article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code and fire safety standard adopted by a municipality which are more stringent in accordance with Section 633.025(5), Florida Statutes, as all of same may be amended from time to time; or any lawful order of the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee; or any lawful order of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer; or any condition, limitation, or restriction which is a part of a permit issued pursuant to this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, as all of same may be amended from time to time; or any consent agreement.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Restoration of the air, waters, property, animal life, aquatic life and plant life within the County or municipality of their former condition.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Each day during any portion of which such violation occurs or continues to occur constitutes a separate violation. The right of trial by jury shall be available in any court to determine both liability for and the amount of the civil penalties to be imposed and recovered hereunder.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 87-89, § 3, 12-15-87)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-57. Civil penalty and restitution fund</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
The sums recoverable by the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or by the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer pursuant to Section 14-56(A)(2) and (3) shall be deposited (i) in a separate County fund for sums recovered by the chief fire code enforcement official of the Metropolitan Dade County Fire Department, or his designee, with respect to both the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Dade County under the fire safety jurisdiction of the Metropolitan Dade County Fire Department as well as sums recovered by the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer with respect to both the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Dade County, or (ii) in separate municipal funds for sums recovered by the chief fire code enforcement official, or his designee, of the following municipalities: The City of Miami Beach, the City of Miami, the City of Hialeah, and the City of Coral Gables.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
The aforesaid separate County and separate municipal funds shall only be used to pay for the following:
<section prefix = "1">
Tracing, investigating, controlling, abating, and remedying violations of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code and, in the case of the aforesaid municipalities, fire standards adopted by the municipality which are more stringent than the provisions in this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Restoration of the air, waters, property, animal life, aquatic life and plant life within the County or municipality to their former condition.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Fire safety and prevention, planning, protection, and programming.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Responding to and attempting to resolve citizen complaints against violations or possible violations of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, and, in the case of the aforesaid municipalities, fire standards adopted by the municipality which are more stringent than this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or the rule and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Investigation, preparation, and prosecution of civil and criminal actions, pursuant to this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, to enforce the provisions of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code and, in the case of the aforesaid municipalities, fire standards adopted by the municipality which are more stringent than the provisions in this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
No part of such separate County and separate municipal funds shall be used for purposes other than the aforesaid.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-58. Standards</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
The following standards of the National Fire Protection Association, Battery-March Park, Quincy, MA 02269, are hereby adopted by reference as if fully set forth herein:
<section prefix = "1">
NFPA 1-1982, Fire Prevention Code, which shall only apply to combustible fibers.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
NFPA 10-1991, Standard for Portable Fire Extinguishers.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
NFPA 11-1988, Standard for Low Expansion Foam and Combined Agent Systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
NFPA 11A-1988, Standard for Medium and High Expansion Systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
NFPA 12-1989, Standard on Carbon Dioxide Extinguishing Systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
NFPA 12A-1989, Standard on Halon 1301 Fire Extinguishing Systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
NFPA 12B-1990, Standard on Halon 1211 Fire Extinguishing Systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
NFPA 13-1989, Standard for the Installation of Sprinkler Systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
NFPA 13A-1987, Inspection, Testing and Maintenance of Sprinkler Systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
NFPA 13D-1989, Standard for the Installation of Sprinkler Systems in One- and Two-Family Dwellings and Mobile Homes.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
NFPA 13R-1989, Installation of Sprinkler Systems in Residential Occupancies up to Four Stories in Height.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
NFPA 14-1990, Standard for the Installation of Standpipe and Hose Systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
NFPA 15-1990, Standard for Water Spray Fixed System for Fire Protection.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
NFPA 16-1991, Standard for the Installation of Deluge Foam-Water Sprinkler and Foam Water Spray Systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
NFPA 16A-1988, Standard for the Installation of Closed-Head Foam-Water Sprinklers and Foam-Water Spray Systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
NFPA 17-1990, Standard for Dry Chemical Extinguishing Systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
NFPA 17A-1990, Wet Chemical Extinguishing Systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
NFPA 20-1990, Standard for the Installation of Centrifugal Fire Pumps.
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
NFPA 22-1987, Standard for Water Tanks for Private Fire Protection.
</section>
<section prefix = "20">
NFPA 24-1987, Standards for the Installation of Private Fire Service Mains and Their Appurtenances.
</section>
<section prefix = "21">
NFPA 26-1988, Supervision of Valves Controlling Water Supplies for Fire Protection.
</section>
<section prefix = "22">
NFPA 30-1990, Flammable and Combustible Liquids Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "23">
NFPA 30A-1990, Automotive Service Station Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "24">
NFPA 31-1987, Standard for the Installation of Oil Burning Equipment.
</section>
<section prefix = "25">
NFPA 32-1990, Standard for Dry Cleaning Plants.
</section>
<section prefix = "26">
NFPA 33-1989, Standard for Spray Application Using Flammable and Combustible Materials.
</section>
<section prefix = "27">
NFPA 34-1989, Standard for Dipping and Coating Processes Using Flammable Combustible Liquids.
</section>
<section prefix = "28">
NFPA 35-1987, Standard for the Manufacture of Organic Coatings.
</section>
<section prefix = "29">
NFPA 40-1988, Standard and Handling of Cellulose Nitrate Motion Picture Film.
</section>
<section prefix = "30">
NFPA 40E-1986, Standard for the Storage of Pyroxylin Plastics.
</section>
<section prefix = "31">
NFPA 43A-1990, Standard for the Storage of Liquid and Solid Oxidating Materials.
</section>
<section prefix = "32">
NFPA 43B-1986, Standards for Storage of Organic Peroxide Formulation.
</section>
<section prefix = "33">
NFPA 43C-1986, Standards for Storage of Gaseous Oxidizing Material.
</section>
<section prefix = "34">
NFPA 43D-1986, Standard for Storage of Pesticides in Portable Containers.
</section>
<section prefix = "35">
NFPA 45-1986, Standard of Fire Protection for Laboratories Using Chemicals.
</section>
<section prefix = "36">
NFPA 46-1990, Storage of Forest Products.
</section>
<section prefix = "37">
NFPA 49-1991, Hazardous Chemicals Data.
</section>
<section prefix = "38">
NFPA 50-1990, Bulk Oxygen Systems at Consumer Sites.
</section>
<section prefix = "39">
NFPA 50B-1989, Liquefied Hydrogen Systems at Consumer Sites.
</section>
<section prefix = "40">
NFPA 51-1987, Standard for the Design and Installation of Oxygen-Fuel Gas Systems for Welding, Cutting and Allied Processes.
</section>
<section prefix = "41">
NFPA 51A-1989, Acetylene Cylinder Charging Plants.
</section>
<section prefix = "42">
NFPA 51B-1989, Standard for Fire Prevention and Use of Cutting and Welding Processes.
</section>
<section prefix = "43">
NFPA 52-1988, Compressed Natural Gas Vehicular Fuel Systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "44">
NFPA 54-1988, National Fuel Gas Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "45">
NFPA 58-1989, Standard for the Storage and Handling of Liquefied Petroleum Gases.
</section>
<section prefix = "46">
NFPA 61A-1989, Standard for the Prevention of Fire and Dust Explosions in Facilities Manufacturing and Handling Starch.
</section>
<section prefix = "47">
NFPA 61B-1980, Standards for the Prevention of Fires and Explosions in Grain Elevators and Facilities Handling Bulk Raw Agricultural Commodities.
</section>
<section prefix = "48">
NFPA 61C-1989, Standard for the Prevention of Fire and Dust Explosions in Feed Mills.
</section>
<section prefix = "49">
NFPA 61D-1989, Standard for the Prevention of Fire and Dust Explosion in the Milling of Agriculture Commodities for Human Consumption.
</section>
<section prefix = "50">
NFPA 65-1989, Standard for the Processing and Finishing of Aluminum.
</section>
<section prefix = "51">
NFPA 69-1986, Explosion Venting Systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "52">
NFPA 70-1990, National Electrical Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "53">
NFPA 71-1989, Standard for the Installation, Maintenance and Use of Central Station Signaling Systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "54">
NFPA 72-1990, Standard for the Installation, Maintenance and Use of Local Protective Signaling Systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "55">
NFPA 72E-1987, Standard on Automatic Fire Detectors.
</section>
<section prefix = "56">
NFPA 72G-1989, Guide for the Installation, Maintenance and Use of Notification Appliances for Protective Signaling Systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "57">
NFPA 72H-1988, Guide for Testing Procedures for Local, Auxiliary, Remote Station and Proprietary Protection Signaling Systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "58">
NFPA 74-1989, Standard for the Installation, Maintenance and Use of Household Fire Warning Equipment.
</section>
<section prefix = "59">
NFPA 75-1989, Standard for the Protection of Electronic Computer/Data Processing Equipment.
</section>
<section prefix = "60">
NFPA 80-1990, Standard for Fire Doors and Windows.
</section>
<section prefix = "61">
NFPA 82-1990, Standard on Incinerators, Waste and Line Handling Systems and Equipment.
</section>
<section prefix = "62">
NFPA 85A-1987, Standard for the Prevention of Furnace Explosions in Fuel Oil and Natural Gas-Fired Single Burner Boiler-Furnaces.
</section>
<section prefix = "63">
NFPA 85B-1989, Standard for the Prevention of Furnace Explosions in Natural-Fired Multiple Burner Boiler-Furnaces.
</section>
<section prefix = "64">
NFPA 85D-1989, Standard for the Prevention of Furnace Explosion in Fuel Oil-Fired Multiple Burner Boiler-Furnaces.
</section>
<section prefix = "65">
NFPA 85E-1985, Standard for the Prevention of Furnace Explosions in Pulverized Coal-Fired Multiple Burner Boiler-Furnaces.
</section>
<section prefix = "66">
NFPA 85F-1988, Standard for the Installation and Operation of Pulverized Fuel Systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "67">
NFPA 85G-1987, Furnace Implosions in Multiple Burner Boiler-Furnaces.
</section>
<section prefix = "68">
NFPA 86-1990, Standard for Ovens and Furnaces, Design, Location and Equipment.
</section>
<section prefix = "69">
NFPA 88A-1985, Standard for Parking Structures.
</section>
<section prefix = "70">
NFPA 88B-1985, Standard for Repair Garages.
</section>
<section prefix = "71">
NFPA 90A-1989, Standard for the Installation of Air Conditioning and Ventilating Systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "72">
NFPA 90B-1989, Standard for the Installation of Warm Air Heating and Air Conditioning Systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "73">
NFPA 91-1990, Standard for the Installation of Blower and Exhaust Systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "74">
NFPA 92B-1991, Smoke Management Systems in Mall Atria and Large Areas.
</section>
<section prefix = "75">
NFPA 96-1991, Standard for the Installation of Equipment for the Removal of Smoke and Grease-Laden Vapors from Commercial Cooking Equipment.
</section>
<section prefix = "76">
NFPA 97M-1988, Glossary of Terms Relating to Chimneys, Vents, and Heat-Producing Appliances.
</section>
<section prefix = "77">
NFPA 99-1990, Standard for Health Care Facilities.
</section>
<section prefix = "78">
NFPA 99B-1990, Hypobaric Facilities.
</section>
<section prefix = "79">
NFPA 101-1991, Safety to Life From Fire In Buildings and Structures.
</section>
<section prefix = "80">
NFPA 101M-1988, Manual on Alternative Approaches to Life Safety.
</section>
<section prefix = "81">
NFPA 102-1986, Standard for Assembly Seating, Tents and Air-Supported Structures.
</section>
<section prefix = "82">
NFPA 110-1988, Standard for Emergency and Standby Power Systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "83">
NFPA 120-1988, Standard for Coal Preparation Plants.
</section>
<section prefix = "84">
NFPA 150-1991, Fire Safety in Racetrack Stables.
</section>
<section prefix = "85">
NFPA 211-1988, Standard for Chimneys, Fireplaces, Vents and Solid Fuel Burning Appliances.
</section>
<section prefix = "86">
NFPA 214-1988, Water Cooling Towers.
</section>
<section prefix = "87">
NFPA 220-1985, Standard on Types of Building Construction.
</section>
<section prefix = "88">
NFPA 231-1990, Standard for Indoor General Storage.
</section>
<section prefix = "89">
NFPA 231C-1991, Standard for Rack Storage of Materials.
</section>
<section prefix = "90">
NFPA 231D-1989, Standard for Storage of Rubber Tires.
</section>
<section prefix = "91">
NFPA 231E-1989, Storage of Baled Cotton.
</section>
<section prefix = "92">
NFPA 231F-1987, Standard for Storage of Rolled Paper.
</section>
<section prefix = "93">
NFPA 232-1986, Standard for the Protection of Records.
</section>
<section prefix = "94">
NFPA 241-1989, Standard for Safeguarding Building Construction and Demolition Operations.
</section>
<section prefix = "95">
NFPA 251-1990, Standard Methods of Fire Tests of Building Construction and Materials.
</section>
<section prefix = "96">
NFPA 252-1990, Standard Methods of Fire Tests of Door Assemblies.
</section>
<section prefix = "97">
NFPA 253-1990, Standard Method of Fire Tests for Critical Radiant Flux of Floor Covering Systems Using a Radiant Heat Energy Source.
</section>
<section prefix = "98">
NFPA 255-1990, Standard Method of Test of Surface Burning Characteristics of Building Materials.
</section>
<section prefix = "99">
NFPA 256-1987, Standard Methods of Fire Tests of Roof Coverings.
</section>
<section prefix = "100">
NFPA 257-1985, Standard for Fire Tests of Window Assemblies.
</section>
<section prefix = "101">
NFPA 259-1987, Standard Test Method for Potential Heat of Building Materials.
</section>
<section prefix = "102">
NFPA 303-1990, Fire Protection Standards for Marinas and Boatyards.
</section>
<section prefix = "103">
NFPA 307-1990, Standard for the Construction and Fire Protection of Marine Terminals, Piers and Wharves.
</section>
<section prefix = "104">
NFPA 327-1987, Standard Procedure for Cleaning or Safeguarding Small Tanks and Containers.
</section>
<section prefix = "105">
NFPA 385-1990, Standard for Tank Vehicles for Flammable and Combustible Liquids.
</section>
<section prefix = "106">
NFPA 386-1990, Standard for Portable Shipping Tanks for Flammable and Combustible Liquids.
</section>
<section prefix = "107">
NFPA 395-1988, Standard for Storage of Flammable and Combustible Liquids on Farms and Isolated Construction Projects.
</section>
<section prefix = "108">
NFPA 407-1990, Aircraft Fuel Servicing.
</section>
<section prefix = "109">
NFPA 409-1990, Aircraft Hangars.
</section>
<section prefix = "110">
NFPA 416-1987, Construction and Protection of Airport Terminal Buildings.
</section>
<section prefix = "111">
NFPA 418-1990, Roof-Top Heliport Construction and Protection.
</section>
<section prefix = "112">
NFPA 480-1987, Storage, Handling and Protecting of Magnesium.
</section>
<section prefix = "113">
NFPA 490-1986, Code for the Storage of Ammonium Nitrate.
</section>
<section prefix = "114">
NFPA 491M-1991, Hazardous Chemical Reactions.
</section>
<section prefix = "115">
NFPA 495-1990, Manufacture, Transportation, Storage and Use of Explosive Materials.
</section>
<section prefix = "116">
NFPA 501A-1987, Standard for Firesafety Criteria for Mobile Home Installations, Sites and Communities.
</section>
<section prefix = "117">
NFPA 501C-1990, Standard for Firesafety Criteria for Recreational Vehicles.
</section>
<section prefix = "118">
NFPA 501D-1990, Standards for Firesafety Criteria and Recreational Vehicle Parks and Campgrounds.
</section>
<section prefix = "119">
NFPA 651-1987, Standard for the Manufacture of Aluminum and Magnesium Powder.
</section>
<section prefix = "120">
NFPA 654-1988, Prevention of Fire and Dust Explosions in Chemical, Dye, Pharmaceutical and Plastic Industries.
</section>
<section prefix = "121">
NFPA 655-1988, Prevention of Sulfur Fires and Explosions.
</section>
<section prefix = "122">
NFPA 664-1987, Prevention of Fires and Explosions in Wood Processing and Wood Working Facilities.
</section>
<section prefix = "123">
NFPA 701-1989, Standard Methods of Fire Tests for Flame Resistant Textiles and Films.
</section>
<section prefix = "124">
NFPA 703-1985, Standard for Fire Retardant Impregnated Wood and Fire Retardant Coatings for Building Materials.
</section>
<section prefix = "125">
NFPA 704-1990, Standard System for the Identification of the Fire Hazards of Materials.
</section>
<section prefix = "126">
NFPA 907M-1988, Investigation of Fires of Electrical Origin.
</section>
<section prefix = "127">
NFPA 1123-1990, Standard for Public Display of Fireworks.
</section>
<section prefix = "128">
NFPA 1221-1988, Standard for the Installation, Maintenance and Use of Public Fire Service Communications.
</section>
<section prefix = "129">
NFPA 1962-1988, Standard for the Care, Use and Maintenance of Fire Hose.
</section>
<section prefix = "130">
NFPA 1963-1985, Screw Threads and Gaskets for Fire Hose Connections.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
The following standards of the American National Standards Institute, Inc., 1430 Broadway, New York, N.Y. 10018, are hereby adopted by reference as if fully set forth herein:
<section prefix = "1">
Identification of Piping Systems, ANSI A13.1-1981
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Safety Code for Fixed Ladders, ANSI A14.3-1974
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Safety Code for Elevators and Escalators, ANSI A17.1-1984
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Standard for Compressed Gas Cylinder Valve, Outlet and Inlet Connections, ANSI B-57 I 1965
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Power Piping, ANSI B31.1-1983
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Fuel Gas Piping, ANSI B31.2-1968
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Chemical Plant and Petroleum Refinery Piping, ANSI B31.3-1984
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Liquid Petroleum Transportation Piping Systems, ANSI B31.4-1979
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Gas Transmission and Distribution Piping Systems, ANSI B31.8-1982
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Building Services Piping Code, ANSI B31.9-1982
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Manual for Determining the Remaining Strength of Corroded Pipelines, ANSI B31G-1984
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Refrigeration Piping, ANSI B31.5-1983
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Safety Code for Mechanical Refrigeration, ANSI 15-1978
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
The following standards of the American Society of Mechanical Engineers, 345 East 47th Street, New York, N.Y. 10017, are hereby adopted by reference as if fully set forth herein:
<section prefix = "1">
Safety Code for Elevators and Escalators, A17.1-1984
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Unfired Pressure Vessel Code 1980
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
The following standards of the Underwriters Laboratories, Inc., 1285 Walt Whitman Road, Melville, Long Island, N.Y. 11747, are hereby adopted by reference as if fully set forth herein:
<section prefix = "1">
UL647-1983, Standard for Unvented Kerosene-Fired Room Heaters and Portable Heaters.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
The following standards of the Compressed Gas Association, Inc., 1235 Jefferson Davis Highway, Arlington, VA 22202, are hereby adopted by reference as if fully set forth herein:
<section prefix = "1">
CGA Pamphlet V-5, Standard for Noninterchangeable Low-Pressure Connections for Medical Gases, Air, and Suction
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
CGA Pamphlet G-1, Acetylene
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
CGA Pamphlet G-2, Anhydrous Ammonia
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
CGA Pamphlet G-3, Sulphur Dioxide
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
CGA Pamphlet G-4, Oxygen
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
CGA Pamphlet G-5, Hydrogen
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
CGA Pamphlet P-1, Safe Handling of Compressed Gases
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
CGA Pamphlet P-2, Characteristics and Safe Handling of Medical Gases
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
CGA Pamphlet V-5, Diameter-Index Safety System
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
The following standards of the American Petroleum Institute, 2101 L Street, N.W., Washington D.C., are hereby adopted by reference as if fully set forth herein:
<section prefix = "1">
API 620-1990 Rules for Design and Construction of Large, Welded, Low-Pressure Storage Tanks
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
API 1604-1987, Removal and Disposal of Used Underground Petroleum Storage Tanks
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "G">
The following standards of the American Society for Testing Materials, 1916 Race Street, Philadelphia PA, 19103, are hereby adopted by reference as if fully set forth herein:
<section prefix = "1">
ASTM B88-81, Seamless Copper Tube
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
ASTM D56-77, Flash Point by Tag Closed Tester
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
ASTM D86-62, Standard Method of Test for Distillation of Petroleum Products
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
ASTM Flash and Fire Points by Cleveland Cup
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
ASTM D93-75, Flash Point by Pensky-Maltens Closed Tester
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
ASTM D323-72, Vapor Pressure of Petroleum Products
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
ASTM D3243-73, Flash Point of Aviation Turbine Fuels by Setaflash Closed Tester
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
ASTM D3278-73, Flash Point of Liquids by Setaflash Closed Tester
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
ASTM E84-81a, Surface Burning Characteristics of Building Materials
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
ASTM E136-79, Non-Combustibility of Elementary Materials
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "H">
The following standards of the Institute of Makers of Explosives, 1575 I Street, N.W., Washington, D.C. 20005, are hereby adopted by reference as if fully set forth herein:
<section prefix = "1">
Pamphlet No. 1, Standard Storage Magazine
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Pamphlet No. 20, Radio Frequency Radiation Hazard in Use of Electric Blasting Caps
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "I">
The following standards of the Fertilizer Institute, 1015—18th Street, N.W., Washington, D.C. 20006, are hereby adopted by reference as if fully set forth herein:
<section prefix = "1">
Definition and Test Procedures for Ammonium Nitrate Fertilizer
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "J">
The following standards of the Architectural Fabric Structures Institute, 1800 Pickwick Avenue, Glenview, IL 60025-1377, are hereby adopted by reference as if fully set forth herein:
<section prefix = "1">
ASI-1977, Air Structures Design and Standards Manual.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 87-89, § 3, 12-15-87; Ord. No. 90-150, § 2, 12-18-90; Ord. No. 92-35, § 1, 5-5-92)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-59. Alternative requirements</catch_line>
<text>
References in this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code to provisions and standards shall be deemed to include any alternative requirements or any alternatives authorized pursuant to law and ordinance.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-60. Submission to legislature</catch_line>
<text>
The Dade County Board of Rules and Appeals is hereby directed to send a certified copy of this article and a certified copy of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code to the Legislature of the State of Florida on the effective date of this Ordinance Number 87-89.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-61. Search warrants</catch_line>
<text>
The chief fire code enforcement officials of the jurisdictions in Dade County, Florida, having fire safety responsibilities, or their respective designees, and the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, or his designee, are hereby authorized and empowered to seek all search warrants reasonable and necessary to carry out their respective responsibilities, powers and duties set forth in this article and the South Florida Fire Prevention Code in accordance with the requirements of the Constitutions of the United States of America and the State of Florida.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-62. Inspections; inspection warrants</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Any duly authorized representative of the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, may, at any reasonable time, enter, monitor, sample, test, and inspect, as often as may be necessary, any property, premises, building or place, public or private, residential or nonresidential, owner-occupied or nonowner occupied, within the jurisdiction, for the purpose of: Ascertaining and causing to be corrected any conditions which may cause or contribute to a fire; or which conditions may endanger life and property due to fire; to enforce the provisions of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, and any municipal ordinance containing fire safety standards which are more stringent than the foregoing; and to investigate the cause, origin, circumstances of every fire occurring within the jurisdiction which is suspicious in nature or which involves the loss of life or injury to person or by which property has been damaged.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
No person shall refuse reasonable entry or access to the duly authorized representative who requests entry for any of the purposes set forth in (A) above and who presents appropriate credentials identifying himself.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
No person shall obstruct, hamper, or interfere with any such inspection, entry, monitoring, testing, or sampling.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
An inspection, entry, monitoring, testing and sampling, pursuant to this section may be conducted only after:
<section prefix = "1">
Consent for the entry, inspection, testing, monitoring and sampling is received from the owner or person in charge of the property, building, premises or place; or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
An inspection warrant as provided in this section or by law is obtained.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
An inspection warrant as authorized by this article may be issued by a judge of any County Court or Circuit Court of this State which has jurisdiction of the place or thing to be searched.
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
Upon proper affidavit being made, an inspection warrant may be issued pursuant to the provisions of this article for the following causes shown:
<section prefix = "1">
When it is reasonable to believe that the properties or items to be inspected may be connected with or contain evidence of the violation of any of the provisions of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, or any fire safety standard of a municipality which is more stringent than the foregoing; or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
When the inspection sought is an integral part of a scheme of systematic routine or area inspections based upon reasonable legislative or administrative standards and neutral criteria.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "G">
Before issuing an inspection warrant, the judge shall examine on oath or affirmation the applicant and any other witness and shall satisfy himself of the existence of cause as set forth in (F) above for granting such application.
</section>
<section prefix = "H">
If the judge is satisfied that cause for the inspection warrant exists, the judge may issue the warrant particularly describing the place, dwelling, item, structure or premises to be inspected and designating on the warrant the purpose and limitations of the inspection.
</section>
<section prefix = "I">
An inspection warrant shall be effective for the time specified therein, but not for a period of more than fourteen (14) days unless it is extended or renewed by the judge who signed and issued the original warrant upon satisfying himself that such extension or renewal is in the public interest. Such inspection warrant must be executed and returned to the judge by whom it was issued within the time specified in the warrant or within the extended or renewed time. After the expiration of such time, the warrant, unless executed, is void.
</section>
<section prefix = "J">
An inspection pursuant to an inspection warrant shall not be made by means of forcible entry, except that the judge may expressly authorize a forcible entry when facts are shown which are sufficient to create a reasonable suspicion of a violation which, if such violation existed, would be an immediate threat to health or safety or when facts are shown establishing that reasonable attempts to serve a previous warrant have been unsuccessful.
</section>
<section prefix = "K">
Each jurisdiction in Dade County with fire safety responsibilities shall prepare and institute a fire safety and fire prevention inspection program for routine and area inspections within each such jurisdiction based upon specific, objective and neutral criteria and standards contained in written plans prepared by each of said jurisdictions. No inspection warrant shall be issued within the jurisdiction based upon cause under (F)(2) of this section, unless and until the written plan of the jurisdiction aforesaid is approved by the Board of County Commissioners by ordinance.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 87-89, § 3, 12-15-87)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-63. Orders</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Whenever evidence has been received establishing that a violation of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, or any fire safety standards of a municipality which are more stringent than any of the foregoing, has occurred or may reasonably be expected to occur, the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, or both, may issue, in their discretion, a notice to correct the violation or a citation to cease the violation and cause the same to be served upon the violator by personal service or certified mail to the violator's last known address or post office box or by posting a copy in a conspicuous place at the premises of the violation. Failure to claim the certified mail shall be deemed to be complete and proper service. Such notice or citation shall briefly set forth the general nature of the violation and specify a reasonable time within which the violation shall be rectified or stopped. Reasonable time herein means the shortest practicable time to rectify or stop the violation. Such notice or citation may require the violator to restrict, cease or suspend use or operation of the facility or premises. Any orders hereunder may be enforced as provided in Section 14-56 of this article. This provision shall not be construed to require the issuance or service of a notice of violation or citation to cease or other order prior to initiating proceedings against a violator pursuant to Section 14-56 of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
For the purposes of this article, a violator shall mean the owner, lessee and any other person responsible for the condition of the premises. In the case of a corporation it shall also mean the resident agent, any director or officer. In the case of a partnership it shall also mean any partner.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 87-89, § 3, 12-15-87)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-64. Correction of violations</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
When a violation of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal or any fire safety standard of a municipality more stringent than any of the foregoing, has occurred or continues to exist or when there is a reasonable likelihood of imminent endangerment to life or property because of a threatened violation of any of the foregoing provisions, the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, or both, in their discretion, may:
<section prefix = "1">
Take any action necessary to prevent such a violation, and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Trace, investigate, control, abate and remedy such a violation, and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Restore the air, waters, property, animal life, aquatic life and plant life within the County or municipality to their former condition.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
This section shall not be construed to provide a defense to or otherwise relieve or limit the liability or responsibility of any person who violated or is violating the particular provisions of law or ordinance aforesaid. Any sums expended may be recovered as provided by Section 14-56(A)(3)(i) and (ii).
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 87-89, § 3, 12-15-87)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-65. Liens</catch_line>
<text>
Owners of real property shall be liable for the sums expended by the County or municipality pursuant to Section 14-64 of this article when the violation occurred or continued to exist or appeared imminent upon the real property aforesaid, regardless of fault and regardless of knowledge of the aforesaid violation. All sums expended by the county or municipality pursuant to Section 14-64 of this article shall constitute and are hereby imposed as special assessments against the real property aforesaid, and until fully paid and discharged or barred by law, shall remain liens equal in rank and dignity with the lien of County or municipal ad valorem taxes and superior in rank and dignity to all other liens, encumbrances, titles and claims in, to or against the real property involved. All such sums shall become immediately due and owing to the County or municipality upon expenditure by the County or municipality and shall become delinquent if not fully paid within sixty (60) days after the due date. All such delinquent sums shall bear a penalty of fifteen (15) percent per annum. Unpaid and delinquent sums, together with all penalties imposed thereon, shall remain and constitute special assessment liens against the real property involved for the period of five (5) years from the due date thereof. Said special assessment liens may be enforced by the County or municipality by any of the methods provided in Chapter 85, Florida Statutes, or, in the alternative, foreclosure proceedings may be instituted and prosecuted by the County or municipality pursuant to the provisions of Chapter 173, Florida Statutes, or the collection and enforcement of payment thereof may be accomplished by any other method provided by law. All sums recovered by the County or municipality pursuant to this provision shall be deposited by the County or municipality into the fund from which said sums were expended.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-66. Fire alarms</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Purpose. The purpose of this section is to seek to obtain proper installation, operation, maintenance, testing, and supervision of fire alarm systems and to seek to obtain compliance with Chapter 633, Florida Statutes, the Florida Fire Prevention Code, the Florida Administrative Code Rule 69A-48 and Rule 69A-60, NFPA 72 (2002 Edition) National Fire Alarm Code, NFPA 13 (2002 Edition) Standard for the Installation of Sprinkler Systems and this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Scope of regulation. The provisions of this section shall apply to all fire alarm systems, except one- and two-family dwelling unit fire alarm systems, within the geographical area of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Definitions applicable to Section 14-66 and Section 14-67 of this Code.
<section prefix = "a">
Alarm Signal. A signal indicating an emergency that requires immediate action including, but not limited to, a signal indicative of fire.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Annunciator. A unit containing one or more indicator lamps, alphanumeric displays, or other equivalent means in which each indication provides status information about a circuit, condition, or location.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Authority Having Jurisdiction (AHJ). The chief fire official responsible for approving equipment, materials, an installation, or a procedure.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Central Station. A supervising station that is listed for central station service.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Central Station Fire Alarm System. A system or group of systems in which the operations of circuits and devices are transmitted automatically to, recorded in, maintained by, and supervised from a listed central station that has competent and experienced servers and operators who, upon receipt of a signal, take such action as required by this Code. Such service is to be controlled and operated by a person, firm, or corporation whose business is the furnishing, maintaining, or monitoring of supervised fire alarm systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Central Station Service. The use of a system or a group of systems in which the operations of circuits and devices at a protected property are signaled to, recorded in, and supervised from a listed central station that has competent and experienced operators who, upon receipt of a signal, take such action as required by this Code. Related activities at the protected property, such as equipment installation, inspection, testing, maintenance, and runner service, are the responsibility of the central station or a listed fire alarm service local company.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Certificate (Certificated). Posted verification of a systematic program that uses randomly selected follow-up inspections of the certificated systems installed under the program that allows the listing organization to verify that a fire alarm system complies with all the requirements of NFPA 72 (2002 Edition) National Fire Alarm Code. A system installed under such a program is identified by the issuance of a certificate and is designated as a certificated system.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Combination System. A fire alarm system in which components are used, in whole or in part, in common with a non-fire signaling system.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Fire Department Notification. The immediate and automatic notification of the local fire jurisdiction by electronic means in accordance with NFPA 72 (2002 Edition) National Fire Alarm Code, that a fire alarm signal has been reported to the fire alarm system.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Evacuation Signal. A distinctive signal intended to be recognized by the occupants as requiring evacuation of the building or zone.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Fire Alarm Control Unit (Fire Alarm Control Panel). A system component that receives inputs from automatic and manual fire alarm devices and might supply power to detection devices and to a transponder(s) or off-premises transmitter(s). The control unit might also provide transfer of power to the notification appliances and transfer of condition to relays or devices connected to the control unit. The fire alarm control unit can be a local fire alarm control unit or a master control unit.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Fire Alarm Signal. A signal initiated by a fire alarm-initiating device such as a manual fire alarm box, automatic fire detector, water flow switch, or other device in which activation is indicative of the presence of a fire or a fire signature.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
Fire Alarm System. A system or portion of a combination system that consists of components and circuits arranged to monitor and annunciate the status of fire alarm or supervisory signal-initiating devices and to initiate the appropriate response to those signals.
</section>
<section prefix = "n">
Listed. Equipment, materials, or services included in a list published by an organization that is acceptable to the authority having jurisdiction and concerned with evaluation of products or services, that maintains periodic inspection of production of listed equipment or materials or periodic evaluation of services, and whose listing states that either the equipment, material, or service meets appropriate designated standards or has been tested and found suitable for a specified purpose.
</section>
<section prefix = "o">
Master Control Unit (Panel). A control unit that serves the protected premises or portion of the protected premises as a local control unit and accepts inputs from other fire alarm control units.
</section>
<section prefix = "p">
Nuisance Alarm. Any alarm caused by mechanical failure, malfunction, improper installation, or lack of proper maintenance, or any alarm activated by a cause that cannot be determined.
</section>
<section prefix = "q">
Placard (Placarded). A means to signify that the fire alarm system of a particular facility is receiving central station service in accordance with NFPA 72 (2002 Edition) National Fire Alarm Code by a listed central station or listed fire alarm service-local company that is part of a systematic follow-up program under the control of an independent third-party listing organization or a nationally recognized testing laboratory.
</section>
<section prefix = "r">
Proprietary Supervising Station. A location to which alarm or supervisory signaling devices on proprietary fire alarm systems are connected and where personnel are in attendance at all times to supervise operation and investigate all signals.
</section>
<section prefix = "s">
Proprietary Supervising Station Fire Alarm System. An installation of fire alarm systems that serves contiguous and noncontiguous properties, under one ownership, from a proprietary supervising station located at the protected property, or at one of multiple non-contiguous protected properties, at which trained, competent personnel are in constant attendance.
</section>
<section prefix = "t">
Protected Premises. The physical location protected by a fire alarm system.
</section>
<section prefix = "u">
Protected Premises (Local) Fire Alarm System. A protected premises system that sounds an alarm at the protected premises as the result of the manual operation of a fire alarm box or the operation of protection equipment or systems including, but not limited to, water flowing in a sprinkler system, the discharge of carbon dioxide, the detection of smoke, or the detection of heat.
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
Remote Supervising Station Fire Alarm System. A system installed in accordance with this Code to transmit alarm, supervisory, and trouble signals from one or more protected premises to a remote location where appropriate action is taken.
</section>
<section prefix = "w">
Runner. A fire alarm service technician who is qualified to inspect, test and maintain fire alarm systems in accordance with NFPA 72 (2002 Edition) National Fire Alarm Code, who is licensed pursuant to Chapter 489 Part II, Florida Statutes, and who is available at all times to respond to signals at a protected premises.
</section>
<section prefix = "x">
Runner Service. The service provided by a runner at the protected premises, including resetting and silencing of all equipment transmitting fire alarm or supervisory signals to an off-premises location and the restoration or repair of the fire alarm system.
</section>
<section prefix = "y">
Signal. A status indication communicated by electrical or other means.
</section>
<section prefix = "z">
Sprinkler system. For fire protection purposes, an integrated system of underground and overhead piping designed in accordance with fire protection engineering standards. The installation includes one or more automatic water supplies. The portion of the sprinkler system aboveground is a network of specially sized or hydraulically designed piping installed in a building, structure, or area, generally overhead, and to which sprinklers are attached in a systematic pattern. The valve controlling each system riser is located in the system riser or its supply piping. Each sprinkler system riser includes a device for actuating an alarm when the system is in operation. The system is usually activated by heat from a fire and discharges water over the fire area.
<section prefix = "aa">
Supervision. The monitoring of supervisory signals by qualified personnel from an approved monitoring facility in compliance with NFPA 72 (2002 Edition) National Fire Alarm Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "bb">
Supervisory Signal. A signal indicating the need for action in connection with the supervision of guard tours, the fire suppression systems or equipment, or the maintenance features of related systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "cc">
Supervising Station. A facility that receives signals and at which personnel are in attendance at all times to respond to these signals.
</section>
<section prefix = "dd">
Supervisory Service. The service required to monitor performance of guard tours and the operative condition of fixed suppression systems or other systems for the protection of life and property.
</section>
<section prefix = "ee">
Third-Party Verification Organization. An independent organization providing published standards for the operation and administration of a listed central station service program that is acceptable to the authority having jurisdiction and that operates in accordance with NFPA 72 (2002 Edition) National Fire Alarm Code in providing a system for the verification and listing of fire alarm systems for central station service and which provides a certificate or placard indicating compliance.
</section>
<section prefix = "ff">
Trouble Signal. A signal initiated by the fire alarm system or device indicative of a fault in a monitored circuit or component.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Runner Service and Service Contracts. All fire alarm systems shall be required to have in effect at all times a service contract with a licensed fire alarm service contractor, a listed fire alarm service-local company or a listed central station to provide all maintenance, service and testing as required by this Code.
<section prefix = "a">
The service contract shall include a provision for runner service available to respond to the protected premises at any and all times within two (2) hours of notification of the runner service of any alarm or supervisory signal, and within four (4) hours of notification of any trouble signal. Existing fire alarm systems shall comply with Section 14-66(4) of this Code not later than five hundred forty-five (545) days after the effective date of this ordinance. The authority having jurisdiction shall have the authority to extend the time for compliance with Section 14-66(4) of this Code for existing fire alarm systems to not later than one thousand ninety-five (1,095) days after the effective date of this ordinance if the authority having jurisdiction determines that compliance within five hundred forty-five (545) days is not reasonable under all the facts and circumstances.
<section prefix = "1">
The runner shall restore the fire alarm system to complete working order.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
In the event that the runner cannot restore the fire alarm system to complete working order, the building, structure, or occupancy may be subject to certain limitations, conditions, and restrictions, including fire watch requirements, as determined by the authority having jurisdiction.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Posting requirements. A fire alarm user shall conspicuously post at the main entrance to the alarm user's premises a notice stating: (1) the name of an individual or alarm company able and authorized to enter the premises and deactivate the alarm; (2) emergency telephone numbers by which those individuals can be reached at all times; and (3) the name and address of the alarm user. The information must be kept current and failure to update this information within forty-eight (48) hours of any change constitutes a violation of this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The runner at all times shall be provided with a key or other means of accessing the fire alarm control panel at any time.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The licensed fire alarm service contractor, listed fire alarm service-local company or listed central station shall provide to the authority having jurisdiction written notification in such form and manner as approved by the authority having jurisdiction not less than thirty (30) days prior to the termination, cancellation, or expiration of the service contract and shall not terminate the services required by the contract for any reason until thirty (30) days after said notification has been received by the authority having jurisdiction.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Serviceability. All fire alarm systems shall be maintained fully functional at all times and all deficiencies shall be reported to the authority having jurisdiction in writing in accordance with Florida Administrative Code Rule 69A-48, and shall be repaired not later than four (4) hours after the fire alarm system is out of service or not later than a time determined by the authority having jurisdiction.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Evacuation Signals. All fire alarm systems providing evacuation signals shall provide audible notification signals at the sound pressure levels required in NFPA 72 (2002 Edition) National Fire Alarm Code.
<section prefix = "a">
Existing fire alarm systems not meeting a minimum sound pressure level of at least 15 dBA above the average ambient sound level, or 5 dBA above the maximum sound level having a duration of at least sixty seconds, whichever is greater, measured 1.5 meters above the floor in the occupiable area, using the A-weighted scale (dBA), may be required by the authority having jurisdiction to upgrade the audibility of the fire alarm system to meet all of the requirements set forth in NFPA 72 (2002 Edition) National Fire Alarm Code. The minimum sound level in sleeping rooms or areas with all intervening barriers closed shall be 70 dBA. Fire alarm systems not meeting the 70 dBA standard may be required by the authority having jurisdiction to upgrade the audibility of the system to meet the requirements set forth in NFPA 72 (2002 Edition) National Fire Alarm Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
If the authority having jurisdiction reasonably believes that an existing fire alarm system does not provide adequate sound pressure levels to accomplish evacuation notification then the authority having jurisdiction may, in the discretion of the authority having jurisdiction, require that the user of the existing fire alarm system provide to the authority having jurisdiction a signed, written report in such form and manner as approved by the authority having jurisdiction from a fire alarm contractor licensed to service fire alarm systems in Miami-Dade County setting forth the sound pressure levels (dBA) throughout the building. The fire alarm system user shall provide the signed, written report to the authority having jurisdiction not later than sixty (60) days after receipt of written notification from the authority having jurisdiction to provide the signed written report.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Annunciators and Fire Alarm Control Units. All protected premises shall be required to have the fire alarm control unit or a remote annunciator located in the building lobby near the main entrance, or, if there is no main entrance or lobby, in a common area where the fire alarm control unit or remote annunciator can be seen and heard by the occupants of the building, structure, or occupancy, or shall be located in another location approved by the authority having jurisdiction.
<section prefix = "a">
Existing remote supervising station fire alarm systems which are otherwise in compliance with this section may be exempted from the provisions of Section 14-66(7) of this Code by the authority having jurisdiction when it is determined by the authority having jurisdiction that a reasonable degree of safety is provided without the addition of a remote annunciator.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Supervising Stations. All supervising stations shall be listed by a third-party verification organization acceptable to the authority having jurisdiction.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
New Installations. All new fire alarm systems and all new sprinkler systems with supervision or emergency forces notification shall meet the requirements for central station service or proprietary supervising station fire alarm systems and shall be either a certificated or placarded central station fire alarm system as set forth in NFPA 72 (2002 Edition) National Fire Alarm Code or a listed proprietary supervising fire alarm system.
<section prefix = "a">
Verification of compliance with the requirements of this section with respect to the installation of new fire alarm systems, as implemented in accordance with the applicable code(s), specifications, or other criteria applicable to the specific installation, shall be certified by a third-party verification organization acceptable to the authority having jurisdiction and shall be evidenced by a certificate or placard.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The user of all new fire alarm systems and new sprinkler systems with supervision or emergency forces notification shall at all times conspicuously post a certificate or a placard on or within thirty-six (36) inches of the fire alarm control unit, as set forth in NFPA 72 (2002 Edition) National Fire Alarm Code.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Upgrades, Renovation, Additions, Repairs, or Modernization. Any upgrade, renovation, addition, repair, or modernization of any existing fire alarm system which includes the replacement of the master control unit with anything other than the exact make and model as the existing master control unit or which includes the addition of a fire alarm control panel which will provide or replace any of the functions of the existing master control unit, except notification, shall be required to have the complete fire alarm system in compliance with all the requirements for new installations. If an upgrade, renovation, addition, repair, or modernization includes greater than one-half of the entire fire alarm system, then the entire fire alarm system shall be required to be in compliance with Section 14-66 (9) of this Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Proprietary Supervising Station Fire Alarm Systems.
<section prefix = "a">
All proprietary supervising station fire alarm systems shall be listed by a third party verification organization.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Existing proprietary supervising station fire alarm systems shall comply with subsection (11)(a) hereinabove not later than five hundred forty-five (545) days after the effective date of this ordinance.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
False Alarms, Inoperable Systems, Remedy of Existing Systems. Any existing fire alarm system determined by the authority having jurisdiction to be inoperable for any reason, unless the system has been reported to the authority having jurisdiction and is in the process of actively being repaired, or a fire alarm system which has caused more than four nuisance alarms within any three hundred sixty-five (365) day period, shall be required to upgrade the fire alarm system to be in compliance with the new fire alarm requirements set forth in NFPA 101 (2003 Edition) Life Safety Code and Section 14-66(9) of this Code.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 08-27, § 1, 3-4-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 14-67. Sprinkler systems, fire pumps, and other extinguishing systems</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Purpose. The purpose of this section is to seek to obtain proper installation, operation, maintenance, testing, and supervision of sprinkler systems, fire pumps, and other fire extinguishing systems, and to seek to obtain compliance with Chapter 633, Florida Statutes, the Florida Fire Prevention Code, the Florida Administrative Code Rule 69A-48 and Rule 69A-60, NFPA 72 (2002 Edition) National Fire Alarm Code, NFPA 13 (2002 Edition) Standard for the Installation of Sprinkler Systems, NFPA 13R (2002 Edition) Standard for the Installation of Sprinkler Systems in Residential Occupancies up to and Including Four Stories in Height, and this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Scope of Regulations. The provisions of this section shall apply to all sprinkler systems, except one- and two-family dwelling unit sprinkler systems, within the geographical area of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
New Sprinkler Systems. All new sprinkler systems shall be supervised in accordance with NFPA 72 (2002 Edition) National Fire Alarm Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Compliance with Section 14-66 Sprinkler systems, fire pumps and other extinguishing systems required to be supervised in accordance with NFPA 72 (2002 Edition), by any applicable code, or this section shall be installed, maintained, serviced and operated in accordance with all applicable codes and standards and Section 14-66 of this Code.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 08-27, § 1, 3-4-08)</history>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (3) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 87-89, § 1, adopted Dec. 15, 1987, repealed the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Code and § 2 of said ordinance enacted the South Florida Fire Prevention Code. Ord. No. 87-89, § 3, adopted Dec. 15, 1987, amended Art. III, relative to the Dade County Fire Prevention Code, in its entirety to read as herein set out. Formally, Art. III was composed of §§ 14-40—14-47 as derived from Ord. No. 66-31, §§ 1—8, adopted July 26, 1966; Ord. No. 68-6, § 1, adopted Feb. 6, 1968; and Ord. No. 78-30, §§ 1, 2, adopted April 18, 1978. (Back)
Cross reference— Building code, Ch. 8; explosives, Ch. 13. (Back)
State Law reference— Minimum fire safety standards, F.S. § 633.025. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
