<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="2">ARTICLE_VI._MIAMI-DADE_WATER_AND_SEWER_A</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-91. When service charge billings are due; penalties for delinquency</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Water and sewer charges for service rendered by the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department (hereinafter called "Department") shall be billed to customers for such reasonable periods as the County Manager may from time to time establish. If such charges are not fully paid by said customers on or before the past due dates set forth on customers' bills, a ten (10) percent late charge may be added to the water and sewer bill and imposed upon the customer by the Department in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Manager. Unpaid balances of said customers for such charges and late charges shall be subject to an interest charge at the rate of eight (8) percent per annum. Imposition of said interest charge shall commence sixty (60) days after the final bill date for water and sewer charges.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Water and sewer charges and late charges, together with any interest charges, shall be debts due and owing the Department and all of same shall be recoverable by the County or its assignee, on behalf of the Department, in any court of competent jurisdiction.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 84-10, § 1, 2-7-84; Ord. No. 08-22, § 1, 2-7-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-92. Delinquent account notification service for rental property</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Department shall establish procedures to notify property owners and/or managers of delinquent accounts.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Subscribers to this service shall pay in advance an annual fee of three dollars ($3.00) per monthly account and two dollars and fifty cents ($2.50) per quarterly account.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Tenants who reside in multi-unit property served by one meter may establish a bridge account with the Department for water and sewer service for a period not to exceed one year where the property owner's account is terminated for nonpayment. The Department shall establish procedures for the administration of bridge accounts with tenants that meet specified conditions.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 84-2, §§ 1, 2, 1-17-84; Ord. No. 12-78, § 1, 10-2-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-93. Water and sewer charges to constitute a lien</catch_line>
<text>
Except as otherwise provided by this article, all charges, late charges and interest accruing thereupon, for water and sewer service rendered by the Department after the effective date of Ordinance No. 84-10 to any real property which remain unpaid sixty (60) days after the final bill date for water and sewer charges shall become a lien against and upon the real property to which such water and sewer service has been furnished to the same extent and character as a lien for a special assessment. Until fully paid and discharged, said charges, late charges, and interest accrued thereupon shall be, remain, and constitute a special assessment lien equal in rank and dignity with the liens of County ad valorem taxes and superior in rank and dignity to all other liens, encumbrances, titles and claims in, to or against the real property involved for the period of twenty (20) years from the date said charges become a lien as set forth in this section. Said liens may be enforced and satisfied by the County, on behalf of the Department, pursuant to Chapter 173, Florida Statutes, as it may be amended from time to time, or by any other method permitted by law. The lien provided for herein shall not be deemed to be in lieu of any other legal remedies for payment available to the County and Department, including but not limited to suspension and termination of water service.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-94. Recording of liens</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
For water and sewer service charges for service rendered during the period of February 13, 1981, through December 31, 1984, which become more than sixty (60) days past due and unpaid, the Department shall cause to be filed in the office of the Clerk of the Circuit Court of Miami-Dade County, Florida, on or before June 30, 1985, a notice of lien or statement showing a legal description of the property against which the lien is claimed, its location by street and number, the name of the owner, an accurate statement of the water and sewer service charges then unpaid, and a copy of such notice of lien shall be mailed within a reasonable time to the owner of the property involved as shown by the records of the Tax Collector of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County. If the Department fails to file a notice of lien on or before June 30, 1985, for water and sewer service charges becoming more than sixty (60) days past due during said period of February 13, 1981, through December 31, 1984, the lien shall not be enforceable by the County. Thereafter, no lien shall be enforceable by the County unless a notice of lien is filed by the County. Liens imposed prior to February 17, 1984, shall not be enforced.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Liens may be discharged and satisfied by payment to the Department of the aggregate amounts specified in the notice of lien, together with interest accrued thereon, and all filing and recording fees. When any such lien has been fully paid and/or discharged, the Department shall cause evidence of the satisfaction and discharge of such lien to be filed with the office of the Clerk of the Circuit Court of Miami-Dade County, Florida. Any person, firm, or corporation or legal entity, other than the present owner of the property involved, who fully pays any such lien shall be entitled to receive an assignment of the lien and shall be subrogated to the rights of the County in respect of the enforcement of such lien.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 84-10, § 1, 2-7-84; Ord. No. 84-68, § 1, 7-17-84; Ord. No. 08-22, § 1, 2-7-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-95. Minimum lien amount</catch_line>
<text>
Notwithstanding other provisions to the contrary herein, the Department shall have the discretion not to file notices of lien for water and sewer service charges, late charges and interest accrued in an amount less than one hundred dollars ($100.00). However, if the Department elects not to file a notice of lien, said charges and interest accrued shall remain as automatic liens as provided in Section 32-93, and as debts due and owing the Department in accordance with Section 32-91, herein.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-96. Evidence of water and sewer service</catch_line>
<text>
The water and sewer service rendered by the Department, as measured by water meters, shall be prima facie evidence of the quantity of water delivered to the customer and of sewage collected from the customer.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-97. Water and sewer certificates of amounts due</catch_line>
<text>
The Department is authorized and directed to execute and deliver upon request written certificates certifying the amount of water and sewer service charges, late charges and interest accrued thereon, which are due and owing to the County and Department, for any real property which is subject to payment of water and sewer charges or the Department may certify that no such charges, late charges or accrued interest are due and owing. Said certificates shall be binding upon the County and the Department.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-98. Application to Metro-Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Utility and other acquisitions of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County</catch_line>
<text>
The provisions of this article shall be applicable to the water and sewer systems owned by Metropolitan Miami-Dade County and operated by the Department, including the Metro-Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Utility, and shall also be applicable to any other water or sewer utility which may be acquired by the County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-99. Department as collection agent</catch_line>
<text>
The Department is hereby designated and made the agent of Miami-Dade County for the purpose of collecting the debts owed to the Department.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-100. Administrative procedures</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager shall establish appropriate procedures for administration of the provisions of this article.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-101. One-Time Lifetime Credit for Customers</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
The Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department is hereby given discretion to provide a one-time lifetime billing adjustment to a customer who disputes a high bill that is not the result of a concealed or visible leak. The Director's discretion to grant such a credit will be based on his assessment that there are extreme circumstances affecting the customer's account that merit a credit. If awarded, similar to the credit provided in the Department's Rules 2.10(1)(e) and 3.10(1)(e), such credit will be a 50 percent credit to the water portion of the customer's high bill above the customer's last yearly average consumption and a 100 percent credit to the sewer portion of the customer's high bill above the customer's last yearly average consumption.
<section prefix = "a">
For purposes of this section, the term "extreme circumstances" is defined as those situations in which a customer receives a bill that exceeds six (6) times the past year's average, as applicable, monthly or quarterly consumption but is unable to show the Department that the high bill is due to a leak, concealed or visible, and cannot otherwise explain the high water bill.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
In order to be considered for the one-time lifetime billing adjustment that the Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department has been given discretion to grant, a customer seeking a one-time lifetime adjustment for extreme circumstances must be in good standing with the Department.
<section prefix = "a">
For purposes of this section, a customer in "good standing" is defined as a customer who has not had the water disconnected for nonpayment or his/her account placed in collection during the previous 12 months.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
In order to request a one-time lifetime billing adjustment, a customer must submit their request on a form proscribed by the Department; and must provide the Department with a notarized affidavit stating that a licensed plumber has checked the residence (inside and out) for leaks (both concealed and visible); that the customer did not leave a hose running inadvertently or otherwise allow water to flow for any period of time; and that there have been no changes in water usage within the household during the billing period (i.e., new landscaping, guests visiting, major household repairs or construction that required increased water usage, problems with one's pool or sprinkler system, or water theft). Additionally, the customer's licensed plumber must also execute the notarized affidavit before the customer submits it to the Department for consideration for a one-time lifetime adjustment.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Department shall keep track of adjustments to ensure that a customer receives only one lifetime adjustment based on extreme circumstances.
<section prefix = "a">
For residential customers, only one lifetime adjustment will be available to the property owners based on the name(s) appearing on the deed; thus, if there is more than one property owner reflected on a deed, only one lifetime adjustment will be available to the deedholders collectively.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
In the case of renters, the one-time lifetime adjustment is limited to one per person for their lifetime regardless of where they are residing. Individuals who have received a one-time lifetime adjustment while renting will not be entitled to any further adjustments under this section, even if they subsequently become property owners or relocate to a different rental property.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
With regard to commercial entities (corporations, LLCs, partnerships, etc.), each commercial entity and all related parties will be limited to one lifetime adjustment collectively in the commercial context. For purposes of this section, "related parties" shall mean entities, their principals, corporate officers and managers that have a direct or indirect ownership interest in another entity. Notwithstanding the foregoing, no more than one lifetime adjustment may be awarded in connection with a commercial property every five years regardless of what commercial entity occupies the property.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The Department will provide a report to the Board of County Commissioners on a quarterly basis, which sets forth a detailed accounting of the one-time lifetime adjustments under R1164-04 and this section of the Code per year.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Nothing in this section shall affect the Department's Rules and Regulations that address the procedures and credits allowed when a concealed or visible leak has been discovered in connection with a single-family residential customer's account.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 11-98, § 1, 12-6-11)</history>
<catch_line>Secs. 32-102—32-120. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (8) ---
Editor's note— At the discretion of the editor, Ord. No. 84-2, adopted Jan. 17, 1984, and 84-10, adopted Feb. 7, 1984, have been codified as Art. VI. Ord. No. 84-2 did not expressly amend the Code; Ord. No. 84-10 amended Ch. 2, Art. XXXVII, but did not assign specific section numbers. Said ordinances have been included in Art. VI to keep related material together. (Back)
Annotation—AO 4-78. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
