<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_LXIII._MIAMI-DADE_COUNTY_BLACK_A</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-831. Created</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created the Miami-Dade County Black Affairs Advisory Board.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-832. Composition</catch_line>
<text>
The Miami-Dade County Black Affairs Advisory Board shall be composed of thirteen (13) members who shall be permanent residents and electors of the County and who shall have a knowledge and interest in the County's Black community. Each County Commissioner shall appoint one member of the board. Appointments after the initial three-year term shall be for a term of three (3) years. Notwithstanding Section 2-11.38.2(b) of the Miami-Dade County Code, a Commissioner may reappoint an existing member to serve in excess of the eight (8) year term limit, provided that said member has demonstrated exceptional dedication and service to the board and that the reappointment is presented to the Board of County Commissioners in the form of a resolution and approved by a two-thirds (2/3) vote of the full membership of the Board of County Commissioners.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-833. Membership; officers; meetings</catch_line>
<text>
The members of the board shall elect a chairperson and vice-chairperson, who shall serve at the will of the board. A majority of the appointed members shall constitute a quorum to hold a meeting and take any action. All board action shall be by majority vote. Members shall serve without compensation. The chairperson or vice-chairperson may call meetings of the board. Meetings may also be called by written notice signed by a majority of members appointed. The board at any duly noticed meeting may fix and call a meeting on a future date. All meetings shall be public.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-834. Duties; powers and responsibilities</catch_line>
<text>
The board shall have the following duties, powers and responsibilities:
<section prefix = "1">
To serve in an advisory capacity to the County Commission, the County administration, the community, and all agencies and persons in Miami-Dade County, Florida, in respect to matters pertaining to the Black community of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To formulate and recommend plans and programs for coordination of the activities of governmental entities and nongovernmental agencies pertaining to the Black community.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
It is the express purpose of this board to serve as a medium for responsible persons to utilize and consult with in attempting to understand and solve the many complex programs involved with the Black community in Miami-Dade County and to make findings and recommendations to the County Commission and the County administration regarding such matters.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The board shall annually report to the Commission as to its findings and recommendations.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
To perform such other duties as may from time to time be assigned to it by resolution of the County Commission.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-835. Supervision and Support</catch_line>
<text>
The Office of the Chairperson of the County Commission, County Attorney and Clerk of the Board shall provide appropriate support for the Black Affairs Advisory Board. The Chairperson of the County Commission shall have the power to appoint, employ, remove and supervise such assistants, employees, and personnel as deemed necessary to provide appropriate support to the Black Affairs Advisory Board, and such assistants, employees, and personnel shall serve at the will of the Chairperson of the County Commission.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-836—2-850. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (82) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 94-137, adopted July 12, 1994, amended the Code by the addition of provisions which have been included herein at the discretion of the editor as Art. LXIII, §§ 2-831—2-835. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
