<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_IX._SECURITY_AT_MIAMI-DADE_WATER</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-170. Legislative intent</catch_line>
<text>
The intent of the County Commission in enacting this Article is to accomplish the following goals and purposes at the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department.
<section prefix = "1">
Improve security.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Retain certain of the present identification procedures, and adopt certain new procedures providing greater security protection.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Establish rules and regulations governing security at Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department facilities.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Protect the public health, safety and welfare by preventing crime, detecting, arresting and prosecuting violators of Article IX of Chapter 32 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-171. Definitions; applicability of Article provisions; disclaimer of liability; right of access of public officers and employees; offenses and penalties</catch_line>
<text>
The following definitions shall apply in this Article:
<section prefix = "1">
Authorized shall mean acting under or pursuant to a written contract, license, permit, instruction or other evidence of right issued by the Board or the Manager or his designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Board shall mean the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
County shall mean the County of Miami-Dade in the State of Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Department shall mean the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Director shall mean the administrative head of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, the assistant or acting Director, appointed by the County Manager.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Law Enforcement Officer shall mean any person employed and vested with the police power of arrest under federal, State or County authority.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Operational directives shall refer to instructions, directives, rules and regulations pertaining to the operation of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department prepared and promulgated from time to time by the Director. When approved by the Board of County Commissioners, these operational directives shall have the same force and effect as County ordinances.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Person shall be as defined in Section 1.01(3), Florida Statutes, and shall include municipal, governmental and public bodies and their agents, when such bodies or agents are using the water and sewer facilities.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Restricted area shall mean any sensitive area operated, maintained or occupied by WASD that is deemed to have critical security or public safety status by the Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
WASD shall mean the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
WASD Facility shall include, but not be limited to, water treatment and supply plants, wastewater treatment plants, office buildings, wellfields, pump stations, and any other facility operated, maintained or occupied by WASD.

32-171.1 Applicability of Article IX of Chapter 32 provisions.
<section prefix = "a">
Any permission granted to a person, corporation, partnership, or other legal entity by the Board, County Manager or Director, directly or indirectly, expressly or by implication, to enter upon a WASD facility or restricted area, is conditioned upon compliance with this Article and operational directives and the payment of any and all fees or charges established and payable to the County; such fees and charges shall include any and all fees or charges established or approved by the Board or the County Manager and entry on WASD property by any person shall be deemed to constitute an agreement by such person to comply with such rules and regulations and to pay any such fees and charges.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
It shall be unlawful for any person to do or commit any act forbidden by or to fail to perform any act required by these rules and regulations or to fail to pay any fees established and payable pursuant to this Article.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Department, through its Director, may from time to time cause to be issued operational directives applicable to WASD property. If any such operational directive contains a requirement that fees and charges be paid for any operation or use of a WASD facility or property as defined in the operational directive, such fees and charges shall be established in accordance with the provisions of this Article.

32-171.2 WASD liability. The County assumes no responsibility or liability for any loss, injury or damage to persons or property at a WASD facility.
32-171.3 Access of public employees and law enforcement officers. Authorized County employees, law enforcement officers, and employees of local, state and federal regulatory agencies shall have free and full access to and from any and all WASD facilities to make inspections and/or enforce the provisions of this Article. No person shall obstruct or interfere with any Law Enforcement Officer, employees of local state or federal regulatory agencies, or any designated County or Department employee conducting such inspection and/or enforcement or in the performance of any other power or duty required of such officer or employee.
32-171.4 Offenses and penalties. Every person who violates any provision of this Article shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00), or imprisonment in the Miami-Dade County Jail for a period of not more than sixty (60) days, or both.
32-171.5 Emergencies. The Director is empowered to take such action as the Director deems necessary when an emergency exists at a WASD facility or property which, in the Director's judgment, presents an immediate threat to public health, security, safety or welfare, or to the operation of a WASD facility or property; provided, however, that in the exercise of such power the Director shall promptly notify the governmental agency(ies) or County department(s) having been assigned by the Board or County Manager primary responsibility for the handling and resolution of such emergency, and provided further that the Director's power herein granted shall cease upon the assumption of jurisdiction over such emergency by the governmental agency(ies) or County department(s) and such assumption of responsibility shall not be inconsistent with the requirements of any emergency procedure or program for a WASD facility or property adopted and approved by the Board. No action shall knowingly be taken by the Director hereunder or by any County department(s) contrary to any regulation or order of the Federal, State or County agency having appropriate jurisdiction.
32-171.6 Trespassing. Whoever, without being fully authorized, licensed or invited, willfully enters or remains on a WASD facility or property, or a portion thereof, or having been authorized, licensed or invited to a WASD facility or property, or portion thereof, is warned or ordered by authorized Department personnel or a law enforcement officer to depart, and refuses to do so, commits the offense of trespass.
32-171.7 Other laws. All applicable provisions of the laws of the State of Florida, now in existence or hereafter enacted, are hereby adopted by reference as part of these rules and regulations.
32-171.8 Jurisdiction. The violation of any provision hereof shall be triable in the Miami-Dade County Court.
32-171.9 Severability. If any provision of these rules and regulations or the application thereof to any person or circumstances is held invalid, the remainder of these rules and regulations and the application of such provision to other persons or circumstances shall not be affected thereby.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-172. Identification cards for persons</catch_line>
<text>
32-172.1
Persons who may enter restricted area. No person shall have entry to any restricted area unless such person possesses a current WASD issued identification card authorizing such access or whose access is otherwise expressly authorized under this Article. Identification cards shall be worn conspicuously on the outer garment of the bearer, in plain view above the waist.
32-172.2
Plan for issuance. The Director shall devise, maintain and, as required, revise a plan for the issuance of identification cards to all WASD employees and non-WASD employees working in a restricted area.
Such plan shall provide for ready identification of various clearance levels based on the most appropriate color scheme as determined by the Director. Such color scheme shall specifically identify limited and unlimited security access for WASD employees, non-restricted public access, and distinguish various levels of access for consultants, contractors, contract employees, public officials, and other public employees.
With the exception of temporary identification cards, each identification card shall:
<section prefix = "a">
Be issued for a period not to exceed one (1) year;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Contain a photo of the cardholder
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Contain a physical description of the cardholder, to include but not be limited to height, weight, and date of birth of cardholder;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Contain the name, title, and employer, or in the case of a WASD employee the employing division or section, of cardholder; and
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Contain a unique serial number not to be repeated on any other identification card.

32-172.3
Employees who are required to maintain an operational license to operate, or have direct oversight or control over the operation of any Water or Wastewater Treatment Facility, or who are critical to security or public safety at any Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Facility, shall be classified as exempt employees if agreed to in the applicable Collective Bargaining Agreement and to the extent allowed by law shall be required to submit to both a Federal and State Criminal Background Check and an annual Drug and Alcohol Screening test consistent with Miami-Dade County Personnel Policies and Procedures and applicable Collective Bargaining Agreements. Such positions shall include Water/Wastewater Division Chiefs, Assistant Superintendents, Chief Water Treatment Plant Operators, Chief Wastewater Treatment Plant Operators, Treatment Plant Operator 1, Treatment Plant Supervisors and Treatment Plant Operator 2. Said employees who fail the criminal or drug screening provisions shall be subject to existing Miami-Dade County Personnel Policies and Procedures.
32-172.4.
Application.
<section prefix = "a">
The application for a permanent identification card is to be a public record filed in writing, maintained in WASD's employment records and shall contain the applicant's:
<section prefix = "1">
Full current name and any previous names and aliases used:
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Current residential address and all residential addresses within the past (5) years;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Date and place of birth;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Current employer and any previous employer within the past five (5) years;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Social Security number and driver's license number as well as copies of each to be made by WASD Security Division personnel from original documents;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Specific reason for entry into the restricted areas;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
A photo of applicant taken by the Department at the time of application submission;
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Fingerprints authenticated by the Miami-Dade Police Department on an identification record form furnished by the Director of the Miami-Dade Police Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Prior felony convictions or entries of findings of guilt (whether pursuant to a plea of guilty or nolo contendere or a judgment of conviction entered by a court of competent jurisdiction);
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Signed authorization to conduct a criminal, financial or other background check on the applicant; and
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Signatures of applicant and employer for non-WASD employees or immediate supervisor for WASD employees.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Pending final action on an application for an identification card or for individuals at a WASD facility for no more than five (5) total days per calendar year, the Director or his or her designee may issue a temporary identification card to non-WASD employees.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
In addition to the information required in subsection (a) above, the Director may require the applicant to produce such further facts and evidence as may be necessary to determine whether or not the applicant possesses the qualifications necessary for an identification card.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The making of a false statement in the application for an identification card under this section shall be grounds for refusal to issue the card and also shall be a violation of this Article.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The Director may conduct or request Miami-Dade Police Department ("MDPD") to conduct a criminal and/or financial background check on any applicant and may conduct or require such other background checks as the Director deems necessary.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Any applicant for a WASD identification card who, within the last five (5) years, (i) has had a felony conviction or (ii) against whom a finding of guilty has been entered on a felony charge shall not be issued an identification card for any restricted area except in the case of a Grandfathered Applicant, whose access shall be governed by subsection (g).
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Any Grandfathered Applicant for a WASD identification card who within the last two (2) years, (i) has had a felony conviction or (ii) against whom a finding of guilty has been entered on a felony charge for the following crimes: (a) theft, (b) smuggling, (c) the possession with intent to sell or distribute, sale, or trafficking of narcotics or any other controlled substance, (d) dishonesty, fraud, or misrepresentation, (e) felony theft under Chapter 812, Florida Statutes, or its federal counterpart, or (f) any violent crime committed with a weapon; or (g) any crime directly related to the Grandfathered Applicant's position of employment, shall not be issued an identification card for access to any restricted area. If a conviction or a finding of guilty on one of the above-listed crimes has occurred more than two (2) years but less than five (5) years from the effective date of this article, the Director has the discretion to issue an identification card to a Grandfathered Applicant under such terms and conditions as the Director deems appropriate to meet the Department's security needs.
A "Grandfathered Applicant" for purposes of this subsection means a person employed at WASD as of the effective date of this article or who, prior to the effective date of this article, was employed at WASD.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Any applicant denied an identification card based on subsection (f) or (g) above may appeal the decision to an appeals committee. The appeals committee shall consist of five members, a member of the Miami-Dade Police Chiefs' Association, excluding the Director of the Miami-Dade Police Department, on a rotating basis, each member to serve for a period of one (1) year, a member of Miami-Dade County Inspector General's Office, a representative of the employee's employer or, at the employer's option, the association representing the employer, the WASD Director or his or her designee, and a union, labor or employee representative. The appeals committee shall determine whether the employee shall be issued an identification card based on procedures issued by the County Manager in an administrative order.
32-172.5
Identification card for persons. Identification cards issued by the Department shall at all times remain the property of the County. As such, the Department shall at all times have the right to confiscate or demand return of the identification card of any person who violates the provisions of this Article and to demand the return of the identification card of all persons employed by a company violating this Article or whose lease, contract, permit or license agreement with the County allowing use of a WASD facility has expired or has been canceled or is terminated. The identification card shall be valid for one (1) year from the date of issuance, unless sooner canceled or surrendered. Application for or acceptance of a card or pass under Section 32-172 or entry into any restricted area by any person shall subject such person to the reporting requirements of Section 32-172.5.
32-172.6
Report of changes in data on application for identification card for a person. Any holder of a personal identification card shall report in writing to the Director (i) immediately any felony arrests, convictions, or findings of guilt, and (ii) within ten (10) days of the change any other change of data in an application for a personal identification card. Failure to report such changes within the time provided or the making of a false statement in any change in information submitted shall constitute grounds for suspending the use of the card; false statements or material omissions in the change information shall be a violation of this Article. The Director or his designee may suspend or revoke the use of the card based on any felony arrest, conviction, finding of guilt or other just cause, and may reinstate the use of the card when, in his discretion, circumstances warrant, provided, however, that such power to suspend, revoke or reinstate may not be exercised in conflict with a decision of the appeals committee as set forth in Section 32-172.3 (h). Any person whose identification card has been suspended or revoked may appeal the decision to the appeals committee set forth in Section 32-172.3 (h).
32-172.7
Denial of identification card. An application for an identification card to enter into any restricted area shall be denied by the Director if the applicant refuses to answer or falsely answers any questions listed in Section 32-172 or refuses to produce documents to verify statements made on the application.
32-172.8
Identification card or pass for a person; Loss, transfer, alteration or possession of altered identification cards, passes or department documents.
<section prefix = "a">
A person who has lost his or her valid identification card, after identifying himself or herself to the satisfaction of the WASD Security Division, shall be issued a new identification card after such person submits a completed application for a replacement card and, upon payment of a replacement charge as set by Administrative Order.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
An identification card for a person shall not be transferable at any time for any purpose.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
No person shall retain or have in his or her possession and shall promptly return to the Director or his or her designee, any card, permit, pass, badge or other means of identification issued by the Director after it has expired or when such person is no longer employed at the WASD facility or upon request by the Director or his or her designee that it be returned or when otherwise required by ordinance or otherwise. Such retention shall constitute a violation of this Article.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
No person shall forge, counterfeit, alter, erase, obliterate or transfer any identification card, permit, pass, lease, record, form, badge or other instrument or document issued or maintained by the County Manager or Director, pursuant to this Article. No person shall have in his possession any forged, counterfeited, altered, erased, obliterated or transferred identification card, permit, pass, lease, record, form, badge or other instrument or document issued or maintained by the County Manager or Director pursuant to this Article. No person shall have in his possession the identification card of another individual.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
In the event that any person who has an application on file for an identification card enters a restricted area without valid identification card or being otherwise authorized, such person may have the identification card or other authorization under this Article suspended or revoked.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-173. Administrative Review procedure</catch_line>
<text>
32-173.1
Administrative review. Any person, including the County, aggrieved with any action or inaction by the Director and/or the Department, may file a written request with the County Manager within ten (10) days of the action or inaction. Such person shall be entitled to an appeal before a hearing examiner assigned by the County Manager or his designee from a list supplied by the American Arbitration Association. Such hearing examiners may be paid a fee for their services but shall not be deemed County officers or employees within the purview of Sections 2-10.2, 2-11.1 or otherwise. The hearing examiner shall conduct a hearing after notice and shall transmit his findings of facts, conclusions, and any recommendations together with a transcript of all evidence taken before him and all exhibits received by him, to the Manager who may sustain, reverse or modify the action at issue. Such hearings shall be conducted insofar as is practicable in accordance with the rules of civil procedure governing the procedure in the Circuit Court, except as may be provided in this Code or by rules adopted by the Board of County Commissioners. Any interested party may procure the attendance of witnesses and the production of records at such hearings in the manner provided by Section 2-50. Any person appearing before a hearing examiner under the provisions of this section has the right, at his own expense, to be accompanied, represented and advised by counsel or other qualified representative. (Counsel shall mean a member of the Florida Bar).
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-174. Identification</catch_line>
<text>
32-174.1.
Identification cards. Failure to produce identification cards by all persons required to possess identification cards pursuant to this Article within a WASD facility shall be cause for immediate removal from the WASD facility and shall be grounds for such further actions as may be authorized by law.
32-174.2.
Duty to report violations. All law enforcement officers and persons required to possess identification cards pursuant to this Article shall be under a continuing duty to promptly report the presence of (1) any unauthorized persons in a restricted area and (2) any unauthorized person on a WASD facility without a conspicuously-placed identification card.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-175. Fees</catch_line>
<text>
The fee schedule for all identification cards required by this Article shall be set and established by an administrative order of the County Manager and approved by the Board of County Commissioners.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-176. False Reports or Threats</catch_line>
<text>
No person shall make any threat involving the operations, including but not limited to, water and wastewater treatment at a WASD facility, or any false report regarding the conduct of operations at any WASD facility.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-177. Forgery and counterfeit</catch_line>
<text>
No person shall make, possess, use, offer for sale, sell, barter, exchange, pass or deliver any forged, counterfeit, or falsely altered pass, permit, identification badge, certificate, placard, sign or other authorization purporting to be issued by or on behalf of the Department, nor shall any information electronically or magnetically encoded thereof be knowingly altered or erased.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-178. Audits by Inspector General's Office</catch_line>
<text>
The Office of the Miami-Dade County Inspector General (IG) shall, on a random basis, perform audits and monitor compliance with the provisions of this Article. The Inspector General shall submit a report and appropriate recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners following such audits. However, the Inspector General shall have the discretion to exclude from such reports any information that may compromise security at a WASD facility or affect the public's safety.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 32-179—32-200. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
</law>
