<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXXIII(K)._STANDARD_URBAN_CENTER</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.81. Purpose and applicability</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
The Comprehensive Development Master Plan (CDMP) contains directives to promote urban centers in places where mass transit, roadways, and highways are highly accessible. The CDMP provides for three types of urban centers: community (CUC), metropolitan (MUC) and regional (RUC).
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
The regulations in this article shall apply to urban centers, as defined in the CDMP. Specifically, these standard regulations apply to the Urban Center Districts provided for in this code that were created after the effective date of this ordinance (July 27, 2005). Each Urban Center District, as adopted by the Board of County Commissioners by separate ordinances, shall contain a set of regulating plans and additional regulations addressing unique circumstances that, in conjunction with this article, shall control development in each particular urban center.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
The standard regulations contained in this chapter and Chapter 18-A, Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall apply to this article, except as otherwise added to or modified herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
The area within the boundaries of an urban center is divided in three Sub-districts: Core, Center and Edge. The highest density and intensity within an urban center shall be allocated to the Core Sub-districts, a mixed-use area adjacent to the transit station(s) or major transit stop(s). The densities and intensities shall then gradually decrease from the Core to the Center Sub-district where mixed-uses are still permitted and then further decrease to the Edge Sub-district which is characterized by single uses, including low density residential.
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
In the case of multiple-phase development, each phase of the development, whether standing independently or in conjunction with existing developed or proposed future contiguous phases, shall meet all the requirements of this article and of the additional requirements and of the regulating plans provided in each Urban Center Districts. In addition, construction of each phase shall be directed first toward the street of higher hierarchy as provided in the Urban Center Districts; and the minimum building frontage length requirements may be disregarded in approving each individual phase, provided that the building frontage length requirements are met at the conclusion of all phases.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 05-143, § 1, 7-7-05)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.82. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
Terms used throughout this article shall take their commonly accepted meaning unless otherwise defined in Chapters 18-A, 28 or 33 of the Code of Miami-Dade County. Terms requiring interpretation specific to this article are as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
Accessory Building: An enclosed building that is subordinate to and not the main or principal building on a lot or parcel and that is used as a dwelling unit, garage, storage shed, or similar use.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Accessory Structure: An unenclosed structure that is subordinate to and not the main or principal building on a lot or parcel and that is used: as a garden feature, such as a fountain, gazebo or cabana; for recreation, such as a pool or hard courts; for the accommodation of mechanical equipment, such as a pump, a/c compressor or electrical generator units; or uses similar to the foregoing.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Anchor point: The location depicted on the Open Space Plan on which some portion of a plaza, green, or square must be situated.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Bike lane: A corridor dedicated specifically for bicycle use.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Block: A combination of contiguous building lots, the perimeter of which abuts public street(s), private street(s) or easement(s) or designated open space(s).
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Block face: The public street, private street or easement line that delineates a block edge.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Boulevard: A public street, private street or easement flanked with a landscaped median, sidewalks, on-street parking, street trees and buildings.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Building Frontage: The portion of the building required to be located along the build-to line.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Building placement diagrams: Diagrams that provide a schematic representation of the permissible footprints and profiles of structures by land use and Sub-district.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Build-to line: A line parallel to the block face, along which a building shall be built.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Busway: A restricted access right-of-way for the exclusive use of buses.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Clear zone: An area within the curb radius, which shall be kept clear of all objects to a prescribed height to provide vehicle clearance.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Close: A landscaped median divided street with a closed turning area in one end and an intersecting street on the other (see Fig. 1).


Fig. 1: Close
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
Colonnade: A roofed structure, extending over a private walkway that is open to the street and sidewalk except for supporting columns or piers.
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
Community Garden: Open space set aside for the cultivation and harvesting of produce such as flowers, fruits and vegetables.
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
Courtyard House: A single-family dwelling containing a court or atrium. The court shall be enclosed on at least three sides by habitable space and shall provide penetrable openings such as windows and doors between the interior of the dwelling and the court. A Courtyard house may occupy the full width of the lot (see Fig. 2).


Fig. 2: Courtyard House
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
Designated open space: An outdoor, at-grade space including greens, squares, plazas and colonnades as indicated on the Designated Open Space Plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
Entertainment Center: An enclosed building or open lot area designated for amusement, entertainment, cultural, ecological, or historical complex (or any combination thereof) that is open to the public, including without limitation: buildings for public assembly; mechanical rides; games and contests; exhibits and demonstrations; art exhibits and musical shows; retail sales; marketplaces, including second-hand sales; food services, including fast food restaurants; and water attractions.
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
Fenestration: Design and position of windows, entrances, and other structural openings in a building.
</section>
<section prefix = "20">
Floorplate: The shape and size of any given floor of a building. The floorplate that touches the ground is called the footprint, after the shape it leaves on the land.
</section>
<section prefix = "21">
Forecourt: The front yard area defined by three sides of the principal building and a low garden wall parallel to the street making the space suitable for gardens and outdoor seating (see Fig. 3). At street corners, the forecourt edges are defined by two (2) principal building walls and a low garden wall parallel to the street (see Fig. 4).


Fig. 3: Interior Lot Forecourt


Fig. 4: Corner Lot Forecourt
</section>
<section prefix = "22">
Front Property Line: The property line abutting the higher ranking street in accordance with the urban centers Street Types Regulating Plan. For equal ranking streets, either frontage may be designated as the front property line.
</section>
<section prefix = "23">
Green: An outdoor open space that shall not be hard surfaced for more than twenty (20) percent of the area exclusive of dedicated streets. The landscapes shall consist primarily of lawn, trees, and garden structures (see Fig. 5).


Fig. 5: Green
</section>
<section prefix = "24">
Greenway or linear park: An outdoor open space along a natural edge, including without limitation, a river front, a canal, a scenic road, or other route. Greenways provide passage for pedestrians or bicycles and are used to link nature reserves, cultural features, other parks, and open spaces and/or historic sites.
</section>
<section prefix = "25">
Habitable Space: Building space the use of which involves regular human presence. Habitable space shall not include areas devoted to parking, storage, or warehouses.
</section>
<section prefix = "26">
Home Office: A professional office use within a residential use, as provided in Section 33-25.1 of this code.
</section>
<section prefix = "27">
Irregularly shaped lot: A lot in areas designated Residential (R) and Residential Modified (RM) with an irregular shape due to its location on a corner or intersection or at the end of a grouping of single-family detached or attached units. The dimensions of the front yard of such lot shall be similar to the dimensions of the front yards of adjacent homes.
</section>
<section prefix = "28">
Live-work building: A mixed-use building type with residential dwellings located above work spaces.
</section>
<section prefix = "29">
Main street: A vehicular and pedestrian thoroughfare lined primarily with mixed-use buildings, as depicted on the Street Types Regulating Plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "30">
Minor street: A street that is predominantly residential in character as depicted on the Street Types Regulating Plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "31">
Mixed-use building: A building that includes a combination of two or more vertically integrated uses, such as retail and/or office uses on the ground floor, with residential uses above.
</section>
<section prefix = "32">
Off-street parking: Garage parking or surface parking not on a public or private street.
</section>
<section prefix = "33">
On-street parking: Parking on a public or private street.
</section>
<section prefix = "34">
Outdoor Market: An outdoor commercial establishment where produce, hand-made crafts and other items are offered for sale.
</section>
<section prefix = "35">
Pedestal: The bottom portion of a building that creates the street frontage.
</section>
<section prefix = "36">
Pedestrian passages: Interconnected paved walkways that provide pedestrian passage through blocks and that connect directly with the network of sidewalks and open spaces.
</section>
<section prefix = "37">
Penthouse: Topmost built area of a building with a floorplate area less than that of the tower below.
</section>
<section prefix = "38">
Permeable Materials: Materials used for paving parking lot and roadway surfaces that allow stormwater run-off to infiltrate the ground, such as porous concrete, porous asphalt, concrete, brick, stone or similar materials.
</section>
<section prefix = "39">
Plaza: An outdoor open space fronted by mixed-use, retail, and office uses. A minimum of fifty (50) percent and a maximum of seventy-five (75) percent of the plaza's area, exclusive of dedicated streets, shall be hard surfaced. The landscape of plazas shall consist primarily of hard-surfaced areas, permanent architecture or water-oriented features, and trees that are placed in an orderly fashion and that are regularly spaced as shown below (see Fig. 6).


Fig. 6: Plaza
</section>
<section prefix = "40">
Residential Building Type: One of the following residential building types permitted in the Urban Center or Area Districts: single-family detached; duplex; rowhouse; courtyard house; sideyard house; urban villa, and apartment.
</section>
<section prefix = "41">
Rowhouse: A single-family attached dwelling unit of a group of three (3) or more units, each separated from the adjoining unit by a common party fire wall. Each common party fire wall shall extend to the roof line or above the roof of units that it serves and shall have no openings therein. Each rowhouse unit shall be serviced with separate utilities and shall otherwise be independent of any other unit.
</section>
<section prefix = "42">
Service road: A private or public vehicular passageway providing primary, secondary, or service access to the sides or rear of building lots.
</section>
<section prefix = "43">
Setback Area: The area between the street, either public or private, and the build-to line.
</section>
<section prefix = "44">
Sideyard house: A single-family dwelling that provides an extensive porch oriented toward a side yard; the side yard is screened from the view of the street by a six (6) foot masonry wall along the build-to line (see Fig. 7).


Fig. 7: Sideyard House
</section>
<section prefix = "45">
Site Improvements: Improvements to a site including, but not limited to: buildings, walls, signage, paved areas and installed landscaping.
</section>
<section prefix = "46">
Square: An outdoor open space that shall be flanked by streets on at least three (3) sides and shall not be hard-surfaced for more than fifty (50) percent of the area exclusive of dedicated streets. Squares shall be located according to the Designated Open Space Plan, and their landscapes shall consist primarily of hard-surfaced walks, lawns, and trees that are placed in an orderly fashion and that are regularly spaced (see Fig. 8).


Fig. 8: Square
</section>
<section prefix = "47">
Storefront: The first story portion of a mixed-use building consisting of habitable space used for business, office, or institutional purposes.
</section>
<section prefix = "48">
Story: an enclosed floor level within a building containing habitable space.
</section>
<section prefix = "49">
Street: Any thoroughfare, such as a public street, private street, or easement that affords primary access to abutting property.
</section>
<section prefix = "50">
Street network: A system of intersecting and interconnecting streets and service roads.
</section>
<section prefix = "51">
Street Type Development Parameters: The design criteria that establish the required elements for the placement and size of the following: sidewalks; curbs and gutters; parking; medians; bike lanes; traffic lanes; street trees; and landscape strips in the street.
</section>
<section prefix = "52">
Street vista: A view through or along a street centerline terminating with the view of a significant visual composition of an architectural structure or element. Street Vistas are indicated on the Open Space Regulating Plan by arrows; direction of the vista is indicated by the direction of the arrow. Garages and blank walls are not significant visual compositions.
</section>
<section prefix = "53">
Tower: The middle portion of a building above the pedestal and below the penthouse.
</section>
<section prefix = "54">
Urban Center District: A zoning district established for a CDMP-designated urban center. A zoning district established for the unincorporated portion of a CDMP-designated urban center or for an area encompassing more than one CDMP-designated urban center, may also be referred to as an Urban Area District.
</section>
<section prefix = "55">
Urban Villa: A single-family dwelling where the primary structure shall be built in close proximity to the front property line as depicted in the building placement diagrams in this article. Walled courts, patios or roof terraces may be used to provide open space. Vehicular parking areas and driveways shall be screened from the view of the street by garage doors and/or walls.
</section>
<section prefix = "56">
Weather Protection Features: Architectural features that provide protection from the sun and rain, including without limitation, colonnades, awnings, bus shelters, or projecting roofs.
</section>
<section prefix = "57">
Work-force Housing Unit or WHU: A dwelling unit, the sale, rental or pricing which is restricted to households whose income is up to one hundred forty (140) percent of the most recent median family income for the County reported by the U.S. HUD as maintained by the Department of Planning and Zoning.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.83. Uses</catch_line>
<text>
No land, body of water, or structure shall be used or permitted to be used, and no structure shall be hereafter erected, constructed, reconstructed, moved, structurally altered, or maintained for any purpose in the Urban Center (UC) or Urban Area (UA) Districts, except as provided in this article. The uses delineated herein shall be permitted only in compliance with the Regulating Plans and standards provided in this article. The following regulations outline permitted uses in the R (Residential), RM (Residential Modified), MC (Mixed-Use Corridor), MM (Mixed-Use Main Street), MO (Mixed-Use Optional), MCS (Mixed-Use Special), MCI (Mixed-Use Industrial), ID (Industrial District) and I (Institutional) Land Use Areas.
<section prefix = "A">
Land Uses in General.
<section prefix = "1">
Outdoor uses/enclosed uses. All uses shall be conducted within completely enclosed buildings, except outdoor uses expressly permitted in this article. Materials and products shall be stored within an enclosed building or within an area completely enclosed within walls having a life expectancy of twenty (20) years or more from the date of installation. Storage shall not be visible above the height of the walls. Commercial vehicles shall be stored or parked within an enclosed building or an area enclosed by a fence, wall, or hedge, and out of the view from adjacent properties.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Density Calculation.
<section prefix = "a">
Density averaging shall be permitted when a unified development is located on one or more parcels, with different land uses or Sub-district designations, under the same ownership.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A single accessory dwelling unit permitted with a single-family residence shall not count towards the minimum required and maximum permitted density thresholds.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Work-force Housing. Unless otherwise specified in the District regulations, all residential or mixed-use developments that: (a) are located within the Core or Center Sub-districts of an urban center district adopted by the Board or County Commissioners after July 10, 2007, and (b) have more than four (4) residential units, shall provide a minimum of twelve and a half (12.5) percent of their units as Work-force Housing Units.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Mixed Use. The vertical or horizontal integration of residential, business and office, and institutional uses shall be permitted as provided herein. Vertical integration allows any combination of primary uses, with business uses typically located on the ground floor and office and/or residential uses on the upper floors. Horizontal integration allows any combination of parcels with different primary uses within the same block.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Temporary Uses. Temporary uses including seasonal tent sales; stands for the sale of flowers, fruit and similar uses; and festivals and farmers' markets are permitted in the MC, MO, MM, MCS, MCI, ID and I categories, subject to the following conditions:
<section prefix = "a">
Except for the following, no temporary use shall be permitted for more than fourteen (14) consecutive days and the time between temporary activities shall be at least three times as long as the duration of the last event.
<section prefix = "i">
A temporary use for the sale of holiday related items such as holiday trees, fireworks, and similar items shall be permitted for thirty (30) consecutive days leading up to the holiday date.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
A temporary use that occurs on two (2) or less consecutive days shall be permitted weekly.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
When applicable, a Zoning Improvement Permit (ZIP) and Certificate of Use shall be obtained. A site plan shall be submitted with the ZIP application indicating, at a minimum;
<section prefix = "i">
Location of temporary activities and structures, which shall not be subject to the Building Placement Standards set forth in Section 33-284.85 of this article;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Anticipated number of patrons;
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Location of parking facilities;
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
Temporary street closures;
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
Hours of operation;
</section>
<section prefix = "vi">
Location and description of lighting and amplification devices.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Outdoor festivals and farmers' markets shall be restricted to daylight hours unless written waivers of objection for the specific use and hours of operation are obtained from all property owners within five hundred (500) feet. The Director may reduce or expand the notification requirement based on potential visual, noise or traffic impacts to adjacent properties.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
A carnival or circus, that involves an amusement ride, acrobatic apparatus, or trained animal, shall only be permitted if approved upon public hearing.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Unusual and New Uses. Except as expressly permitted in this article, unusual and new uses, as outlined in Section 33-13 of this chapter, shall only be permitted if approved upon public hearing.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Land Use Groups. The uses listed following each group in this section shall be permitted in the land use categories shown in Table (C) subject to the provisions noted for each land use category. Uses provided in Table (C) below not listed in this subsection shall be permitted subject to the provisions noted for each land use area. The Director shall have the authority to determine that a use not specifically enumerated below may nevertheless be permitted in a land use category because it is similar to an enumerated use.
<section prefix = "1">
Accommodation Uses: Facilities that provide short-term lodging including hotels, motels, rooming houses, bed and breakfasts, and similar uses.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Automotive Uses: Establishments specializing in the service or repair of automobiles; automobile tire sales and replacement; automobile parts sales and installation; sales of new and used automobiles; and gas stations or other form of stations used for the powering/charging of automobile vehicles.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Child Care Facilities: Child care facilities shall be those defined in Article XA of this chapter and shall be subject to the requirements therein, as applicable; except that child care facilities shall provide recreation areas in accordance with Section 33-284.86(D)(2) of this article. Where conflicts exist, the provisions of this article shall apply.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Civic Uses: Uses that are accessible to the public and serves the religious, recreational, educational, cultural and/or governmental needs of the community. Civic uses include, but are not limited to: convention halls or meeting halls; private clubs; libraries; schools; police stations; fire stations; post offices; clubhouses; religious buildings; museums; athletic facilities; auditoriums theaters, movie theaters, and other visual and performance arts buildings; and governmental facilities. The architecture of a civic use building shall reflect its civic nature. The sale of alcohol, if provided, shall be ancillary to the primary civic use and shall comply with Article X of this Chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Private Colleges/Universities: Facilities that serve the educational needs of the adult population. This group shall include universities; colleges; commuter colleges; trade schools; and similar uses.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Commercial Parking Garage: Structures that provide parking as the primary on-site use. These facilities offer short-term parking of vehicles and may charge a fee for such use. This group includes: shared parking facilities; shuttle parking facilities; and transit park-and-ride facilities. This group shall not include parking facilities that are ancillary to another on-site use.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Health Care Services: A facility that provides out-patient health care services to the local community. These facilities shall include: clinics; doctor's office; dentist's offices; federally qualified health centers; urgent care facilities; diagnostic centers including sleep centers; and similar uses. These facilities shall not provide in-patient care.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Drive-Through Facilities: Drive-through facilities associated with a retail use, personal service establishment or restaurant.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Entertainment Use: Uses in this group shall include: nightclubs; arcades; movie theaters; performance theaters; radio, movie and/or television studios; billiard halls; skating rinks; bingo halls; piano bars; adult entertainment uses (as defined in Section 33-259.1 of this chapter); bowling alleys; and similar uses. The sale of alcohol, if provided, shall be ancillary to the primary entertainment use and shall comply with Article X of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Food/Beverage Establishments: This group shall include: full service restaurants; fast food restaurants; bars and pubs; and similar uses. The sale of alcohol, if provided, shall comply with Article X of this chapter, except that full-service restaurants serving alcoholic beverages shall be exempt from Sections 33-150(A) and 33-150(B) of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
General Retail/Personal Service Establishments: Establishments that provide goods and services geared toward an individual consumer. This group shall include businesses such as: banks; beauty parlors; adult day care; bakeries; bookstores; apparel stores; grocery stores; pharmacies; tailor shops; health clubs; gift shops; indoor pet care centers/boarding and indoor kennels (soundproofed and air-conditioned building required); vehicle retail showrooms; and similar uses. This group shall also include schools offering instruction in dance, music, martial arts and similar activities, but this group shall not include colleges/universities. Except as otherwise authorized in this article, uses enumerated in the BU-3 zoning district shall only be permitted in the MCS and MCI categories and shall be subject to the public hearing and spacing requirements set forth in Section 33-255 of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Group Residential Home: A dwelling unit licensed by the State of Florida Department of Children and Families that serves resident clients and provides a living environment for unrelated residents who operate as a functional equivalent of a family. Uses in this group shall include: nursing homes, assisted living facilities; congregate living facilities; foster care facilities; community residential homes; group homes; and other similar uses. Services that support the daily operation of group homes are permitted and shall include dining facilities, doctor's offices, nurse's offices, staff offices, recreation rooms, and similar facilities and services.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Industrial Uses: The Industrial Use group shall include uses permitted in Section 33-259 of this chapter, unless specifically prohibited by this chapter. Residential spacing requirements shall not be required for uses in this group.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
Live/work Units: An individual residential unit integrated with a general retail/personal service establishment, professional business office, or workshop.
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
Professional Business Offices: Facilities used primarily for the business of professionals with only limited transactions occurring on-site. This group shall include offices for: accountants; architects; appraisers; attorneys; consulates; financial firms; insurance adjusters; realtors; medical offices and other uses found by the Director to be similar.
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
Residential Uses: Single-family detached homes, urban villas, courtyard houses, sideyard houses, duplexes, rowhouses, apartments (including student housing), and other similar uses. Home offices as provided in Section 33-25.1 of this chapter shall be permitted.
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
Workshop: an enclosed workplace on the ground floor area of a building used as an office or for the manufacturing of artifacts and crafts utilizing only hand held and/or table mounted electrical tools.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Table of Permitted Uses. Unless the regulations for a specific urban center district provide otherwise, the Land Use Groups in paragraph (B) of this section shall be permitted in the R (Residential), RM (Residential Modified), MC (Mixed-Use Corridor), MM (Mixed-Use Main Street), MO (Mixed-Use Optional), MCS (Mixed-Use Special), MCI (Mixed-Use Industrial), ID (Industrial District) and I (Institutional) land use categories in accordance with the following table:
<section prefix="1" type="table">
<table class="thead2 table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="25%" /> 
  <col width="8.333333333333334%" /> 
  <col width="8.333333333333334%" /> 
  <col width="8.333333333333334%" /> 
  <col width="8.333333333333334%" /> 
  <col width="8.333333333333334%" /> 
  <col width="8.333333333333334%" /> 
  <col width="8.333333333333334%" /> 
  <col width="8.333333333333334%" /> 
  <col width="8.333333333333334%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " rowspan="2" colspan="1" valign="top" class="">LAND USE GROUP</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " colspan="9" valign="top" class="">LAND USE CATEGORY</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">R<sup>[3][4]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">RM<sup>[3][4]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">MC<sup>[1][3]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">MM<sup>[1][3]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">MO<sup>[1][3]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">MCS<sup>[1][3]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">MCI<sup>[1][3]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">ID</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">I</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Residential Uses:</td> 
   <td style="" colspan="9" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> Single-Family:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> Duplex:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> Multi-Family Apartments:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[2]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[2]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[2]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[2]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[2][5]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Live/Work Units:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[17]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[17]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Civic Uses:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> Religious Facilities:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> Schools (K—12):</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[7]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[7]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[7]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[7]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[7]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[7]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[7]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[7]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[7]</sup> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> Hospitals:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">SE</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">SE</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">SE</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">SE</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">SE</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">SE</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Group Residential Home:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[6]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[6]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[6]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[6]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[6]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[6]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[6]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Health Care Services:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">SE</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">SE</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">General Retail/Personal Service Establishments:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[8]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[8]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[8]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[8]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[8]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[8]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> Liquor Package Stores:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[11]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[11]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[11]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[11]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[11]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Automotive Uses:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> Gas/Service Stations:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[10]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[10]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[10]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Professional Business Offices:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Industrial Uses:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Colleges and Universities:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Entertainment Uses:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[16]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[16]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[16]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[16]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[16]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[16]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Accommodation Uses:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[12]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[12]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[12]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[12]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[12]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[12]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[12]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Child Care Facilities:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[15]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[15]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Food/Beverage Establishments:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[13]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[13]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[13]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[13]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[13]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[13]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Drive-Through Facilities:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[9]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[9]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[9]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[9]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[9]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[9]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Commercial Parking Garage:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[14]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[14]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[14]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[14]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">P<sup>[14]</sup> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 
P:
Permitted Use, although specific uses may require approval as special exception
SE:
Special Exception - only permitted if approved upon public hearing
[#]
Footnote (as provided below)

Footnotes:
<section prefix = "1">
The vertical integration of uses shall be required in the MM category and shall be encouraged in the MC, MO, MCS, and MCI categories. When residential uses are provided in the MM category, uses other than residential shall be required on the first floor.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Residential uses shall be permitted in noted categories, either alone or when vertically integrated with other lawful uses; except that developments with more than fifty (50) residential units shall provide a minimum of ten (10) square feet of retail space for each residential unit.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Accessory structures shall be permitted as ancillary to the noted uses.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
For single-family homes in the R and RM categories, an accessory building may be used as a dwelling unit only if: (a) it contains a maximum of six hundred (600) square feet of habitable space; and (b) it is maintained under the same ownership as the single family home.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The following limited residential uses shall be permitted in the ID category when fronting an "A" Street and when buffered from an industrial use by a street, a service road, or a live-work unit:
<section prefix = "a">
In the Edge Sub-district, the residential uses permitted in the R category at a minimum density of six (6) dwelling units per net acre and a maximum density of eighteen (18) dwelling units per net acre.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
In the Center Sub-district, the residential uses permitted in the RM category at a minimum density of twelve (12) dwelling units per net acre and a maximum density of thirty-six (36) units per net acre.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
In the R category, group residential homes shall meet the requirements outlined in Section 33-199(10) of this chapter. In the RM, MC, MM, MO, MCS, and MCI categories, group residential homes shall meet the following requirements:
<section prefix = "a">
Three (3) occupants shall be deemed to be one (1) dwelling unit, and the maximum number of dwelling units allowed shall be equal to the permitted residential density.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The proposed group residential home shall not be located within a radius of one thousand two hundred (1,200) feet of another existing, unabandoned, legally established group residential home. The 1,200-foot distance requirement shall be measured by following a straight line from the nearest portion of the structure of the proposed use to the nearest portion of the structure of the existing use.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Schools shall be subject to the requirements of Article XA or XI of this chapter, as applicable; except that non-public educational facilities shall provide recreation areas in accordance with Section 33-284.86(D)(2) of this article. Where conflicts exist, the provisions of this article shall apply.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
General retail and personal service establishment shall be limited to forty thousand (40,000) square feet of ground floor area; a greater ground floor area for such uses shall only be permitted if approved as a special exception.
<section prefix = "a">
Indoor pet kennels shall be permitted subject to the following conditions: (i) all kennel buildings shall be soundproofed and air-conditioned; (ii) where outside exercise runs are provided, a landscaped buffer or decorative masonry wall shall enclose the runs, and use of the runs shall be restricted to use during daylight hours; (iii) where outside exercise runs are not provided, an outside area shall be designated for dogs (or cats) to relieve themselves, and that area shall be enclosed by a landscape buffer or masonry wall; (iv) an administrative site plan review (ASPR) shall be required, and the site plan shall show all fencing, berms, and soundproofing designed to mitigate the noise impact of the kennel on the surrounding properties.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Vehicle Retail Showrooms shall only be permitted in accordance with the conditions set forth in Section 33-253(9.5) of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The following uses shall only be permitted if approved as special exceptions: on-site storage of vehicles; and outdoor pet kennels subject to the conditions set forth in Section 33-255(9.1) of this chapter, except that ASPR shall not be required if a site plan is approved upon public hearing.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Drive-through facilities shall be permitted in all Sub-districts, provided that such facilities are concealed from streets by buildings or walls. Said walls shall be six (6) feet in height (except that in the ID category, walls shall be eight (8) feet in height) and shall be placed at the build-to line.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Gas/Service stations shall:
<section prefix = "a">
Be permitted in the MCS category in all Sub-districts and in the MCI and Industrial (ID) categories in the Center and Edge Sub-districts; and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Be exempt from the minimum height requirements; and
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Provide a continuous street facade consisting of buildings or walls along all streets except driveways. When provided, walls shall not exceed three and a half (3.5) feet in height and shall be a minimum of seventy-five (75) percent opaque. The main building shall provide a minimum of forty (40) percent of building frontage along the front property line.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Liquor package stores shall be permitted only in the Core and Center Sub-district and only in compliance with Article X of this chapter and all other applicable regulations of this code.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
In the RM category, accommodation uses shall be permitted only in conjunction with an owner-occupied residence; the total number of units shall not exceed the density permitted by the land use designation. In the MM, MC, MO, MCS, MCI, and ID categories, hotel/motel uses shall not exceed seventy-five (75) units per net acre or the maximum density permitted by the land use category, whichever is greater. For all density calculations required by this subsection, one hotel room shall equal one dwelling unit.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Outdoor table service and outside walk-up window service in conjunction with restaurants and coffee houses may be provided subject to the following requirements:
<section prefix = "a">
The restaurant furniture located on the sidewalk shall maintain a minimum five (5) foot wide obstacle-free corridor for pedestrian circulation along the sidewalk.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Alcoholic beverages may be served outdoors only where such service is strictly incidental to the service of food.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
Commercial parking garages shall meet the requirements of Section 33-284.86(F)(6) of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
In the R and RM categories, child care uses shall be subject to the requirements for such uses in the RU-1 District, as set forth in Section 33-199 of this chapter, except that the total number of children may exceed five (5) if approved as a special exception.
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
Adult entertainment uses, as defined in Section 33-259.1 of this chapter, shall be prohibited in all land use categories except MCI and ID. In the MCI and ID categories, such adult entertainment uses shall only be permitted if approved as special exceptions.
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
Only the following uses shall be permitted in connection with a residence in a live-work unit in the MCI and ID land use categories:
<section prefix = "a">
Antique shops
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Art goods stores, artist studios, galleries
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Artisanal use
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Bait and tackle shops
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Bakeries
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Cabinet shops
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Dance studios
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Dry cleaning and dyeing establishments
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Engines, sales and service
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Glass installation
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Health and exercise clubs
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Interior design shops
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
Leather goods manufacturing, excluding tanning
</section>
<section prefix = "n">
Locksmith shops, sharpening and grinding shops
</section>
<section prefix = "o">
Mail order office, including storage of products
</section>
<section prefix = "p">
Office uses
</section>
<section prefix = "q">
Photography labs
</section>
<section prefix = "r">
Pottery shops
</section>
<section prefix = "s">
Printing shops
</section>
<section prefix = "t">
Restaurants, excluding drive-through service
</section>
<section prefix = "u">
Secondhand stores
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
Shoe stores and shoe repair shops
</section>
<section prefix = "w">
Upholstery and furniture shops
</section>
<section prefix = "x">
Wholesale salesrooms
</section>
<section prefix = "y">
Other similar uses as determined by the Director.

</section>
</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.84. Regulating Plans</catch_line>
<text>
A set of Regulating Plans shall be provided with each adopted Urban Center or Area District. The Regulating Plans shall consist of a series of controlling plans that include the following:
<section prefix = "A">
The Street Types Plan, which establishes a hierarchy of street types in existing and future locations that shall be provided and shown in all development plans.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
The Sub-districts Plan, which delineates three (3) sub-districts: Core, Center and Edge. These Sub-districts shall regulate the allowable intensity of development in accordance with the Comprehensive Development Master Plan and this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
The Land Use Plan, which delineates the areas where specified land uses and development of various types and intensities shall be permitted.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
The Building Heights Plan, which establishes the minimum and maximum allowable number of stories and permits developments to reach CDMP Urban Center intensity ranges.
<section prefix = "1">
Developments in Community Urban Centers shall meet the intensity range by:
<section prefix = "a">
Providing the required minimum/maximum number of stories; or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Providing a minimum of one (1) story and the following applicable minimum floor-area ratio:
<section prefix = "i">
In the Edge Sub-district, a minimum floor area ratio of one-half (0.5);
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
In the Center Sub-district, a minimum floor area ratio of one (1); and
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
In the Core Sub-district a minimum of floor area ratio of one and one-half (1.5).
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Developments in Metropolitan Urban Centers shall meet the intensity range by:
<section prefix = "a">
Providing the required minimum/maximum number of stories; or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Providing a minimum of one (1) story and the applicable minimum floor-area ratio:
<section prefix = "i">
In the Edge Sub-district, a minimum floor area ratio of one and one-half (1.5);
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
In the Center Sub-district, a minimum floor area ratio of one and three-quarters (1.75); and
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
In the Core Sub-district, a minimum floor area ratio of three (3).
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
The Designated Open Space Plan, which designates open spaces, which shall be shown in all development plans. The designated open spaces shall be controlled by anchor points.
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
The New Streets Plan, which shows the location and the number of new streets needed to create the prescribed network of streets within each Urban Center or Area District. All new A streets shall be required in the same general location as shown on the New Streets Plan. All B streets shall be located as provided in Section 33-284.86(C) of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "G">
The Bike Route Plan, which depicts the designated bike routes, including the bike facility requirements if any, which shall be shown in all development plans.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.85. Building Placement Standards</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
The diagrams in paragraph (G) of this section establish the Building Placement Standards by land use category. Building frontage and setback areas shall be required as illustrated in the Building Placement Standards Diagrams.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Where Building Placement Standards Diagrams reference a Frontage Table, such table specific to each Urban Center or Area District shall be provided in the regulations for each individual District. It is provided, however, that colonnades may be placed on the property line regardless of any such frontage requirements. Unless otherwise provided, the colonnade height and width shall be in accordance with Section 33-284.86(B) of this article. When a Frontage Table is not provided in the individual Urban Center or Area District regulations, building setbacks shall be required as set forth in the following table:
Standard Frontage Table
<section prefix="2" type="table">
<table class="thead2 table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="25%" /> 
  <col width="25%" /> 
  <col width="25%" /> 
  <col width="25%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " rowspan="2" colspan="1" valign="top" class="">STREET TYPE</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " colspan="3" valign="top" class="">DISTRICT REQUIREMENT</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">CORE<br />(Build-to line)</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">CENTER<br />(Build-to line)</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">EDGE<br />(Build-to line)</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Major Roadway</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10′ *</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10′ *</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">15′</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Minor Roadway</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10′ *</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10′ *</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">15′</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Main Street</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6′ *</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10′ *</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">15′</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Service Road</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0′ (min)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0′ (min)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0′ (min)</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Pedestrian Passage</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0′ (min)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0′ (min)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0′ (min)</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="4" valign="top" class="">* Where a colonnade is provided, the build-to line shall be zero (0) feet.</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 

</section>
<section prefix = "C">
In all Sub-districts, mixed-use, non-residential, and multi-family, developments shall comply with the following:
<section prefix = "1">
Minimum building frontage requirements may be met by a single building, multiple buildings or multi-phased developments, and such requirements shall apply along the front property line only.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Where a minimum number of stories is required, said stories above the second story may be set back further than the requirements set forth in the Building Placement Standards Diagrams.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
To articulate the building facade, fifty (50) percent of the portion of the building required to be located along the build-to line may be recessed up to two (2) feet. Further, once the minimum building frontage requirement is met, the remainder of the building may be set back from the build-to line.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
A portion of the building may be set back up to twenty-five (25) feet to accommodate a forecourt.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Belfries, chimneys, spires/steeples, and other such non-habitable structures shall comply with Section 33-55 of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Accessory buildings shall follow parking and/or allowable building area setbacks provided in the Building Placement Standards Diagrams.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
In all Sub-districts, accessory buildings for rowhouse, courtyard, sideyard, single-family detached, duplex and urban villa shall follow the accessory building/dwelling/parking area setbacks provided in the Building Placement Standards Diagrams.
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
In all Sub-districts, for all land use categories, accessory structures shall be permitted provided that they do not encroach on the front and side street setbacks.
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
The table below identifies the Building Placement Standards that apply to each Land Use Category:
<section prefix="3" type="table">
<table class="thead3 table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="16.666666666666668%" /> 
  <col width="8.333333333333334%" /> 
  <col width="8.333333333333334%" /> 
  <col width="8.333333333333334%" /> 
  <col width="8.333333333333334%" /> 
  <col width="8.333333333333334%" /> 
  <col width="8.333333333333334%" /> 
  <col width="8.333333333333334%" /> 
  <col width="8.333333333333334%" /> 
  <col width="8.333333333333334%" /> 
  <col width="8.333333333333334%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " rowspan="3" colspan="1" valign="top" class="">BUILDING<br />PLACEMENT<br />STANDARD</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " colspan="10" valign="top" class="">LAND USE CATEGORY</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">Metro-politan Centers</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " colspan="9" valign="top" class="">Metropolitan and Community Centers</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">MM<br />MC<br />MCS<br />MO</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">R</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">RM</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">MC</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">MM</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">MO</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">MCS</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">MCI</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">ID</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">I</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1. Mixed Use, Multi-Family</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2. Mixed Use, Multi-Family</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3. Industrial</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">4. Rowhouse, Multi-Family</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">5. Rowhouse</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6. Courtyard, Sideyard</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">7. Single-family</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">8. Single-family</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">9. Duplex</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10. Duplex</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">11. Civic</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">12. Urban Villa</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">X</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="11" valign="top" class="">X: Standard is applicable in the indicated Land Use Category</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 
</section>
<section prefix = "G">
Building Placement Standards Diagrams.
<section prefix = "1">
Mixed Use, Multi-Family:

<section prefix = "a">
Building Frontage Required: Seventy (70) percent minimum at build-to line. Minimum frontage requirement applies along the front property line only.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Build-to lines or street setback requirements shall be measured from the edge of sidewalk.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All on-site parking shall be accessed from a service road or the lowest ranking street.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The vehicular entry width permitted shall be a maximum of thirty-three (33) feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The minimum interior side/rear setback for the pedestal, tower, and penthouse shall be zero (0) feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Where a wall or fence is used to screen parking areas along streets, a five (5) foot landscape strip with a hedge shall be required in front of the wall or fence.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Colonnades shall be two (2) stories high and a minimum of fifteen (15) feet deep. The colonnade depth shall not exceed the colonnade height. The exterior of the colonnade shall be no closer than two (2) feet from the curb line.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Mixed Use, Multi-Family:


<section prefix = "a">
Building Frontage Required: Seventy (70) percent minimum at build-to line in all Sub-districts. Minimum frontage requirement applies along the front property line only.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Build-to lines or street setback requirements shall be measured from the edge of sidewalk.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The interior side/rear setbacks shall be as shown above.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
When provided, the front setback shall be hard surfaced and finished to match the adjoining sidewalk. A minimum of five (5) feet clear width within the setback shall be kept unobstructed for pedestrians.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
All on-site parking shall be accessed from the service road or lowest ranking street.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Where a wall or fence is used to screen parking areas along streets, a five (5) foot landscape strip with a hedge shall be required in front of the wall or fence.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Above the fourth story the setback shall be from the property line.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Industrial:


<section prefix = "a">
Building Frontage Required: Twenty-five (25) percent minimum at build-to line. Minimum frontage requirement applies along the front property line only.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Build-to lines or street setback requirements shall be measured from the edge of sidewalk.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
For industrial uses, any part of the build-to line not occupied by a building shall have an eight (8) foot high masonry wall, not pierced except to provide pedestrian and vehicular ingress/egress.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
For all other uses permitted in the ID category, walls, fences and hedges shall be provided in accordance with Section 33-284.86(H) of this article, and where a wall or fence is used to screen parking areas along streets, a 5-foot landscape strip with a hedge shall be required in front of the wall or fence.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The interior side/rear setbacks shall be as shown above.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
When provided, the front setback and side street setback shall be landscaped or hard surfaced and finished to match the adjoining sidewalk.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Above the fourth story the setback shall be from the property line.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
All on-site parking shall be accessed from a service road or from the lowest ranking street.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Rowhouse, Multi-Family:


<section prefix = "a">
Building Frontage Required: Seventy (70) percent minimum at build-to line. Minimum frontage requirement applies along the front property line only.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Front and side street setback requirements shall be measured from the edge of sidewalk.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All on-site parking shall be accessed from the service road or lowest ranking street.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The front setback and, when provided, the side street setback shall be landscaped.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Where a wall or fence is used to screen parking areas along streets, a five (5) foot landscape strip with a hedge shall be required in front of the wall or fence.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Above the fourth story the setback shall be from the property line.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Rowhouse:


<section prefix = "a">
Building Frontage Required: One hundred (100) percent at build-to line except at end of building groups. Minimum frontage requirement applies along the front property line only.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Front and side street setback requirements shall be measured from the edge of sidewalk.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
For Rowhouses all on-site parking shall be accessed from the service road.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The front setback and, when provided, the side street setback shall be landscaped.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Common parking facilities shall be permitted.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Courtyard, Sideyard:


<section prefix = "a">
For Sideyard and Courtyard Houses, all on-site parking shall be accessed from the service road.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Front and side street setback requirements shall be measured from the edge of sidewalk.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Any part of the build-to line not occupied by a building shall have a masonry wall with a minimum height of forty-two (42) inches and a maximum height of seventy-two (72) inches, not pierced except to provide pedestrian and vehicular ingress/egress.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The front setback and, when provided, the side street setback shall be landscaped.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Single-Family:


<section prefix = "a">
All on-site parking shall be accessed from the service road, where provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Front and side street setback requirements shall be measured from the edge of sidewalk.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
For lots with frontages between fifty (50) and seventy-five (75) feet, the minimum interior side setback shall be ten (10) percent of the lot frontage; for lots with frontage greater than seventy-five (75) feet, the interior side setback shall be a minimum of seven and a half (7.5) feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The front and side street setback shall be landscaped.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Single-Family:


<section prefix = "a">
All on-site parking shall be accessed from the street as shown above.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Front and side street setback requirements shall be measured from the edge of sidewalk.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The front and side street setback shall be landscaped.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Any part of the build-to line not occupied by a building shall have a masonry wall with a minimum height of forty-two (42) inches and a maximum height of seventy-two (72) inches, not pierced except to provide pedestrian and vehicular ingress/egress.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Driveways between the front property line and build-to line shall be a maximum of ten (10) feet wide.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Duplex:


<section prefix = "a">
All on-site parking shall be accessed from the service road.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Front and side street setback requirements shall be measured from the edge of sidewalk.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The front and side street setback shall be landscaped.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Duplex:


<section prefix = "a">
This building standard shall only be permitted on existing platted lots less than twelve thousand (12,000) square feet in area.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Front and side street setback requirements shall be measured from the edge of sidewalk.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All on-site parking shall be accessed from the street as shown above.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Any part of the build-to line not occupied by a building shall have a masonry wall with a minimum height of forty-two (42) inches and a maximum height of seventy-two (72) inches, not pierced except to provide pedestrian and vehicular ingress/egress.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Driveways between the front or side street property lines and build-to line shall be a maximum of ten (10) feet wide.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The front and side street setback shall be landscaped.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Civic:


<section prefix = "a">
All on-site parking shall be accessed from the service road, where provided. For properties without an adjoining service road, parking may be accessed from the street through a driveway as shown above.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Build-to lines and street setback requirements shall be measured from the edge of sidewalk.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
When on-site parking is provided, the off-street parking spaces shall be placed to the rear of the building.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Civic uses shall not be required to comply with height requirements indicated on the Building Heights Plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
When provided, the front and side street setback areas shall be treated as a green or plaza. When treated as a plaza, the setback area shall not be required to be fronted by mixed-use, retail, or office uses. When treated as a plaza or green, the plaza or green shall be in addition to any designated open space required by the regulating plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Where a wall or fence is used to screen parking areas along streets, a five (5) foot landscape strip with a hedge shall be required in front of the wall or fence.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Urban Villa:


<section prefix = "a">
Building Frontage Required. Eighty (80) percent minimum at build-to line. Minimum frontage requirement applies along the front property line only. At least fifty (50) percent of Urban Villas along a block face shall provide a walled court or patio between the front property line and the building face; maximum setback shall be fifteen (15) feet only where such court or patio is provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Front and side street setback requirements shall be measured from the edge of sidewalk.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Parking shall be accessed from the street as shown above. Garage entrances accessed from the front property line shall be a maximum of ten (10) feet in width and no further than ten (10) feet from the front property line. Walled courts or patios shall not be used for parking.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The minimum height for an Urban Villa shall be two (2) stories.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The front setback, and when provided, the side street setback, shall be landscaped.

 
</section>
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 05-143, § 5, 7-7-05; Ord. No. 06-10, § 2, 1-24-06; Ord. No. 07-93, § 3, 7-10-07; Ord. No. 07-169, § 8, 11-6-07; Ord. No. 08-102, § 2, 9-2-08; Ord. No. 12-86, § 4, 10-2-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.86. General Requirements</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Lots and blocks. The following shall be required:
<section prefix="4" type="table">
<table class="thead1 table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
  <col width="25%" /> 
  <col width="25%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">Size (Square Feet)</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">Frontage (Feet)</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="3" valign="top" class=""> <i>Minimum Lot Requirements</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Rowhouse</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1,200*</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">20</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1,250*</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">18</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Courtyard house and Sideyard house</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3,000*</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">35</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Single-family detached</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">5,000**</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">50</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">4,375***</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Urban villa</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">30</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Duplex</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">7,500</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">75</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Duplex on parcels with less than 12,000 square feet****</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">40</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Live-work units</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1,700</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">20 (max 40)</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Irregularly shaped lots</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">15****</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="3" valign="top" class="">All lots shall share a frontage line with a street or a designated open space</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="3" valign="top" class="">* service roads are required in all Sub-districts when these types are provided.<br />** when service roads are not provided.<br />*** when service roads are provided.<br />**** parcels established prior to the effective date of this ordinance.</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="3" valign="top" class=""> <i>Block Requirements</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="3" valign="top" class="">Unless otherwise provided in the Regulating Plans the perimeter of a block shall not exceed 1,600 feet, and the maximum length of a block shall be: </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">In the Edge Sub-district</td> 
   <td style="" colspan="2" valign="top" class="">660 feet</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">In the Core and Center Sub-districts</td> 
   <td style="" colspan="2" valign="top" class="">500 feet</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Buildings.
<section prefix = "1">
Storefronts shall be provided on the first floor of mixed-use buildings, and shall be directly accessible from a street frontage or a designated open space as follows:
<section prefix = "a">
For properties with two or more frontages, storefronts shall be located on a minimum of two frontages, with priority given to frontages on a designated open space and the highest ranking street.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Storefronts shall have a transparent clear glazed area of not less than seventy (70) percent of the facade area and shall be occupied by habitable uses that generate pedestrian activity and provide surveillance of the street. Security enclosures, if any, shall be of the mesh type that pedestrians can see through, and shall be located behind storefront displays.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
All colonnades shall comply with the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Finished floor elevation of the colonnade shall match the adjoining sidewalk.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Colonnades shall have a minimum unobstructed clear height of ten (10) feet and a minimum clear width of ten (10) feet. Awnings shall be permitted but shall not count towards the required colonnades. Colonnades shall not cause roof drainage into the street. Colonnades shall be attached to buildings. In no instance shall the depth of a colonnade exceed the colonnade's height.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Freestanding colonnades shall not satisfy the build-to line requirement.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
A minimum of thirty (30) percent of all building streetwalls shall be fenestrated with windows. Mirror type glass shall be prohibited. All glazing shall be of a type that permits view of human activities and spaces within the structure. Colonnade column spacing, windows, and doors shall be proportioned such that the height of each opening is greater than its width. At least fifty (50) percent of the area of security screens and gates shall be transparent.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The height of an accessory building shall not exceed the height of the principal building.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
An open, covered, or paved connection between an accessory building and a single-family detached house, urban villa, courtyard house, sideyard house, duplex, or rowhouse may be built within the minimum required ten (10) foot spacing as shown in the Building Placement Standards set forth in Section 33-284.85 of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Weather protection features shall be required when storefronts are provided in the MM, MC, MO, MCS, and MCI categories. In the ID category, weather protection features shall be required when the front setback is hard surfaced.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Awnings, balconies, stoops, stairs, open porches, and bay windows shall be permitted to extend into the minimum required setbacks, to a maximum of:
<section prefix="5" type="table">
<table class="thead2 table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="25%" /> 
  <col width="25%" /> 
  <col width="25%" /> 
  <col width="25%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " colspan="2" valign="top" class="">Front, Rear, Side Street Setback</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">Interior Side</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">In a setback of<br />10 feet or less</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">In a setback of<br />greater than 10 feet</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Bay windows</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3 feet</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3 feet</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3 feet</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Balconies</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6 feet</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6 feet</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3 feet</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Awnings</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6 feet</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6 feet</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3 feet</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Stoops</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6 feet</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6 feet</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3 feet</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Stairs</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6 feet</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">8 feet</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3 feet</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Porches*</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6 feet</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">8 feet</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3 feet</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="4" valign="top" class="">* The encroachment of porches shall be permitted in conjunction with residential units, including multifamily residential developments. Ground floor porches provided for multifamily residential developments shall be enclosed on at least two (2) sides by a minimum three (3) foot high wall or metal fence. </td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 
Roof eaves, chimneys, signs, and ramps may encroach into all setbacks. Porticoes, canopies, and colonnades shall be guttered, and drainage shall be deposited onsite.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Where a zero (0) foot setback is permitted, roof eaves, bay windows, and balconies may encroach beyond the property line a maximum of three (3) feet, except when abutting private property. In all Sub-districts, awnings may encroach into the street no more than six (6) inches from the face of the curb. All street encroachments shall be a minimum of eleven (11) feet above the sidewalk.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
In the Edge Sub-district, accessory buildings shall be permitted to have balconies or bay windows that encroach a maximum of three (3) feet into the rear yard setback.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Service areas shall be located out of the view from adjacent properties or from the street and shall be screened by a wall or fence in accordance with Subsection (H) below.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
The primary entrance of a building shall provide access to a street or a designated open space. The primary entrance to the upper levels of a mixed-use building with colonnades shall be through the colonnaded area along the front property line.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Each story shall have a maximum height of sixteen (16) feet, as measured from floor to floor. Any height above sixteen (16) feet shall count as an additional story, except as follows:
<section prefix = "a">
Buildings with less than six (6) stories may have a single story with a maximum height of thirty (30) feet, provided that no mezzanine area intended for commercial use exceeds ten (10) percent and no mezzanine area intended for residential use exceeds eighty (80) percent of the floor area of that story. Multiple levels of parking shall be permitted within this single story provided that they are in compliance with Subsection (F)(6) below.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Buildings with six (6) or more stories, may have two stories with a maximum height of thirty (30) feet, provided that no mezzanine area intended for commercial use exceeds ten (10) percent and no mezzanine area intended for residential use exceeds eighty (80) percent of the floor area of a story. Multiple levels of parking shall be permitted within these two stories provided that they are in compliance with Subsection (F)(6) below.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Notwithstanding the building heights regulating plans, rowhouses may have up to three (3) stories.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
A live-work unit shall have two components: a workshop and a residential unit. The workshop shall be located on the first floor and shall be directly accessible from the primary street frontage or a designated open space. The workshop's facade shall have a transparent clear glazed area of not less than seventy (70) percent of the facade. The residential component of a live-work unit shall connect internally with the work component.
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
Projects with fifty (50) or fewer single-family units shall have a minimum of three (3) substantially different front elevations. Projects with more than fifty (50) and up to one hundred (100) single-family units shall have a minimum of five (5) substantially different front elevations and shall provide, within each block, a minimum of two (2) different single-family building types. Projects with more than one hundred (100) single-family units shall have a minimum of five (5) substantially different front elevations and shall provide, within each block, a minimum of three (3) different single-family building types. Substantially different front elevations shall include variations in fenestration, material, and color.
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
Rowhouses shall provide a minimum of fifteen (15) feet between building groups and the length of a building group shall not exceed two hundred forty (240) feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
Floorplates above eight (8) stories shall not exceed twenty thousand (20,000) square feet. Cantilever balconies shall not count towards floor plate calculation.
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
Civic use designated parcels and lots with less than twenty-five thousand (25,000) square feet shall not be required to comply with the minimum height requirement on the Building Heights Plan.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Streets, Service Roads and Utilities. All streets and service roads shall comply with the Street Types parameters as set forth in this section.
<section prefix = "1">
Typical Minor Street Illustration.

*
Refer to column B in the Street Types Table for required landscape elements.
**
Curb and gutter between the sidewalk and parking/travel lanes may be utilized in place of the valley gutter illustrated.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Typical Two-Lane Boulevard Street Illustration.


*
Refer to column B in Street Types Table for required landscape elements.
**
Curb and gutter between the sidewalk and parking/travel lanes may be utilized in place of the valley gutter illustrated.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Typical Four-Lane Boulevard Street Illustration.


*
Refer to column B in Street Types Table for required landscape elements
**
Curb and gutter between the sidewalk and parking/travel lanes may be utilized in place of the valley gutter illustrated
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Street Types Development Parameters.
<section prefix="6" type="table">
<table class="thead2 table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="10%" /> 
  <col width="10%" /> 
  <col width="10%" /> 
  <col width="10%" /> 
  <col width="10%" /> 
  <col width="10%" /> 
  <col width="10%" /> 
  <col width="10%" /> 
  <col width="10%" /> 
  <col width="10%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">Street Type</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " colspan="9" valign="top" class="">Required Elements</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">A. Sidewalk (Min.) [a, h]</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">B. Landscape [b, c, d]</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">C. Curb/Gutter [e]</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">D. Parking Lane [f]</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">E. Bike Lane [g]</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">F. Travel Lanes [h]</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">G. Additional Travel/Turn Lanes (Min.)</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">H. Curb/Gutter</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">I. Median (Min.)</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Type 1 Boulevard (Parking both sides) <i>Core/Center</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">9' (Core)<br />8' (Center)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Tree grates; tree planters; continuous landscape strip (Center only)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">7'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Required where indicated on Bike Route Plan</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">11'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10' where provided</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6'</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Type 1 Boulevard (Parking both sides) <i>Edge</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Continuous landscape strip</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">7'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Required where indicated on Bike Route Plan</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">11'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10' where provided</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6'</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Type 2 Boulevard (No Parking) <i>Core/Center</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">9' (Core)<br />8' (Center)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Tree grates; tree planters; continuous landscape strip (Center only)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Required where indicated on Bike Route Plan</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">11'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10' where provided</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6'</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Type 2 Boulevard (No Parking) <i>Edge</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Continuous landscape strip</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Required where indicated on Bike Route Plan</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">11'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10' where provided</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6'</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Type 3<br />Minor Street (Parking both sides) <i>Core/Center</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">9' (Core)<br />8' (Center)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Tree grates; tree planters; continuous landscape strip (Center only)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">7'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Required where indicated on Bike Route Plan</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10' where provided</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Type 3<br />Minor Street (Parking both sides) <i>Edge</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Continuous landscape strip</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">7'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Required where indicated on Bike Route Plan</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10' where provided</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Type 4<br />Minor Street (Parking one side) <i>Core/Center/Edge</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">9' (Core)<br />8' (Center)<br />6' (Edge)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Tree grates, tree planters, continuous landscape strip (Center, Edge only)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">7' on one side</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Required where indicated on Bike Route Plan</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10' where provided</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Type 5<br />Minor Street (No Parking) <i>Core/Center</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">9' (Core)<br />8' (Center)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Tree grates; tree planters; continuous landscape strip (Center only)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Required where indicated on Bike Route Plan</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10' where provided</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Type 5<br />Minor Street (No Parking) <i>Edge</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Continuous landscape strip</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Required where indicated on Bike Route Plan</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10' where provided</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Type 6<br />Minor Street (Canal Side) <i>Core/Center</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">9' (Core)<br />8' (Center)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Tree grates; tree planters; continuous landscape strip (Center only)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">7' on side opposite canal</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Required where indicated on Bike Route Plan</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10' where provided</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Type 6<br />Minor Street (Canal Side) <i>Edge</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Continuous landscape strip</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">7' on side opposite canal</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Required where indicated on Bike Route Plan</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10' where provided</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Type 7<br />Service Road <i>Core/Center/Edge</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Type 8<br />Pedestrian Passage <i>Core/Center/Edge</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10'</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Tree grates; tree planters</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="10" valign="top" class="">N/A: Not Applicable<br />[#] Footnote (as provided below)</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 

Footnotes:
<section prefix = "a">
Landscape area is exclusive of the minimum sidewalk width.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Street trees shall have a minimum caliper of six (6) inches at time of planting.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Permanent irrigation is required.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Tree grates shall have a minimum area of twenty-four (24) square feet; tree planters shall have a minimum area of thirty-two (32) square feet; continuous landscape strips shall have a minimum width of six (6) feet in the Core and Center Sub-districts, eight (8) feet in the Edge Sub-district.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
In all Sub-districts, curbs and gutters shall be provided at all intersections and roadway edges of arterials, boulevards and Main Street; in Core and Center Sub-districts, curbs and gutters shall be provided at all intersections and roadway edges of minor streets.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
On-street parking shall count towards the minimum required parking.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Bike lanes shall be four (4) feet in width when adjacent to curb or swale; five (5) feet in width when adjacent to a parking lane.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
The minimum required width of one-lane/one-way travel lanes shall be determined by the Department of Public Works and Waste Management and Fire Rescue Department on a case-by-case basis during the Administrative Site Plan Review process (ASPR).
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
The use of permeable materials to pave private street sidewalks, on-street parking, and vehicular drives is permitted. Use of permeable materials to pave public street sidewalks, on-street parking and vehicular drives shall require approval from the Director of the Department of Public Works and Waste Management.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
All streets shall be located according to the New Streets Plan.
<section prefix = "a">
All new A streets shall be in the same general location shown on the New Streets Plan and may be modified with respect to alignment, provided that the final realignment does not compromise street connectivity. No new A streets shall be deleted.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
B streets and service roads shown on the New Streets Plan are encouraged to promote connectivity and to conform with block length requirements. New B streets and service roads may be modified or deleted as provided in paragraph (6) below.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All streets shall allow general public access. Privately built streets shall provide an approved plat restriction to allow general public access. No gates that impede through traffic are permitted along A or B streets.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
[Modification approval.] The Director shall approve the modification of A or B streets or service road or the deletion of a B street if the following conditions are satisfied:
<section prefix = "a">
The modification/deletion has been approved by the Director of the Public Works and Waste Management Department who shall review the proposed modification for traffic and safety issues.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The modification/deletion does not diminish the general size and location of an open space shown in the Designated Open Space Plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The modification/deletion maintains connectivity to the surrounding area.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The modification/deletion enhances pedestrian safety.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The modification/deletion is compatible with the surrounding area.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The modification/deletion allows for the appropriate use of private property.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
[Design compliance.] The design of new streets and modifications of existing streets shall comply with the following requirements:
<section prefix = "a">
Streets shall be in accordance with the Street Types Development Parameters criteria set forth in this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
All streets and service roads shall connect to other streets or service roads. Dead-end streets and T-turnarounds shall only be permitted temporarily for new streets when the adjacent property is not platted, not developed, or both. When the adjacent property is platted or developed, a street shall connect to existing development and the dead-end street or T-turnaround removed.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Cul-de-sacs shall be prohibited, except that a close shall be permitted when:
<section prefix = "i">
A street is interrupted by a natural barrier such as a river, protected land, or similar natural resource designated by Miami-Dade County or any government agency responsible for the protection of such natural resources; and
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Such agency prohibits the street to continue through said natural resource; and
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Existing development adjacent to or near the natural resource does not provide a means for the street to connect to the existing or proposed street network.
The median of such a close shall be landscaped. The landscaped area shall be maintained by a special taxing district, homeowner's association or other mechanism acceptable to the Department of Public Works and Waste Management to positively provide for the proper and continuous payment of maintenance without expense to general taxpayers.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
All sidewalks shall provide the following:
<section prefix = "i">
Minimum width of six (6) feet, unless a different width is required by the Street Types Development Parameters set forth in this section;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Minimum unobstructed area of sixty (60) inches;
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Where a colonnade is required, free and clear use of a continuous unobstructed area of at least sixty (60) inches within the colonnade; and
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
No utility poles, fire hydrants or any other temporary or permanent structures within the unobstructed area.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Where on-street parking is provided, parking lanes shall be no closer than twenty-five (25) feet from the intersection measured from the outermost corner of the nearest corner property line.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Maximum curb radii at intersections shall not be larger than required for the safe travel of emergency and service vehicles.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Curbs and gutters shall be provided as follows:
<section prefix = "i">
All Sub-districts: At all intersections and roadway edges of arterials, boulevards and Main Street.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Core and Center Sub-districts: At all intersections and roadway edges of minor streets.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Edge Sub-district: Not required, except when indicated by the urban center street type development parameters.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Utilities other than fire hydrants shall run underground.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Buildings placed at the end of a Street Vista may provide one additional story above that otherwise permitted by the Building Heights Regulating Plan; such additional story shall occupy up to fifteen (15) percent of the floor area of the story immediately below.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Service roads may occur within buildings.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Service road access from the front property line shall be limited to one (1) point of access for every two hundred fifty (250) feet of frontage.

</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
Open Spaces and Recreation Areas.
<section prefix = "1">
Open spaces under this article shall be classified as (a) designated or (b) private open spaces.
<section prefix = "a">
Designated open spaces shall be subject to the following requirements:
<section prefix = "i">
The general location, area, and dimensions shall conform with the Designated Open Space Plan. The street area on the side adjoining the designated open space and consisting of the curb, street tree landscape strip and sidewalk shall count towards the square footage of the open space.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Designated open spaces shall include the anchor point depicted on the Regulating Plan, and shall be provided at grade level.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Provided that all other parameters on the Designated Open Space Plan are met and that an individual/developer owns the entire designated open space area and an adjacent area, the final location of the designated open space may be pivoted around its anchor point onto such adjacent area, allowing the area previously designated as open space to be developed as permitted in the land use regulating plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
Designated open spaces shall be provided in the form of squares, greens, or plazas as provided in the Designated Open Space Plan. Golf courses and parking lot buffers shall not count towards the designated open space requirement. Fifty (50) percent of an area designated as open space may contain a lake.
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
No replatting or other land subdivision shall divide property in such a way that required designated open space is avoided or its location changed.
</section>
<section prefix = "vi">
Designated open spaces shall be shaded, and their ground surface shall be a combination of paving materials, lawn, or groundcover.
</section>
<section prefix = "vii">
If a lot or group of lots is designated entirely as open space in the Designated Open Space Plan, half of the lot or group shall be developable in a contiguous pattern and at a density in compliance with its land use designation for the entire parcel. Two (2) additional stories above the number of stories permitted by the Sub-districts and Building Heights Plans shall be permitted. Under this circumstance, the developable portion shall not be required to comply with the private open space requirement for residential development provided herein.
viii.
If a lot or group of lots is designated partially as open space in the Designated Open Space Plan, the portion not designated as open space shall be developable in a contiguous pattern at a density/intensity which will equal the density/intensity permitted by the land use designation for the entire parcel. Up to an additional two (2) stories above the number of stories permitted by the Sub-districts and Building Heights Plans shall be permitted to allow the increased density/intensity only.
<section prefix = "ix">
Around designated open spaces, the building's frontage, height and placement shall be in accordance with the Building Placement Standards set forth in Section 33-284.85 of this article.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Private open spaces shall be subject to the following requirements:
<section prefix = "i">
Private open spaces shall be provided in the form of colonnades, courtyards, terraces, lawns, community gardens, and landscaped roof terraces/gardens on buildings or garage structures. Designated open spaces shall count towards the private open space requirement. Lakes, golf courses, and parking lot buffers shall not count towards the open space requirement.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
All residential developments, except for multi-family residential and live-work units, shall provide a minimum of four hundred (400) square feet of private open space per lot, in the form of courtyards, terraces, or lawns.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
All multi-family residential, nonresidential and mixed-use developments shall reserve a minimum of ten (10) percent of the site for common, private open space.
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
Private open spaces shall be shaded, and their ground surface shall be a combination of paving materials, lawn, ground cover, flowers, fruits or vegetables. Enclosures of private open spaces shall comply with subsection (H) below.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Community gardens shall be permitted in all land use categories to satisfy private open space requirements, subject to the following restrictions:
<section prefix = "i">
Cultivated and harvested products may only be sold at permitted farmers markets and at grocery stores.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
The raising or sale of livestock or poultry is prohibited.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Only handheld tools shall be permitted in the cultivation and harvesting process. Use of heavy agriculture equipment is prohibited.
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
All tools, equipment and products used to grow and harvest plant material shall be stored in an enclosed structure subject to the Building Placement Standards set forth in Section 33-284.85 of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
Gardens shall only be tended between sunrise and sunset.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Recreation Areas. Educational and child care facilities located within an Urban Center District shall be exempt from the outdoor recreation area requirements of Section 33-151.18(a) of this chapter and shall be required to provide indoor and/or outdoor recreation areas subject to the following requirements:
<section prefix="7" type="table">
<table class="thead1 table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
  <col width="66.66666666666667%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">Categories</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">Required Recreation Area (**)</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Child care/day nursery/kindergarten and preschool and after-school care</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">22.5 square feet per child calculated in terms of half of the proposed maximum number of children for attendance at the school at one (1) time. </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Elementary school (grades 1—6)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">250 square feet per student for the first 30 students; thereafter, 150 square feet per student. </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Junior and senior high school (grades 7—12)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">400 square feet per student for the first 30 students; 150 square feet per student for the next 300 students; thereafter, 75 square feet per student. </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="2" valign="top" class="">* Where there are category combinations, each classification shall be calculated individually<br />** Recreation Area consists of indoor and outdoor recreation areas. Indoor-recreation areas may consist of indoor playgrounds, indoor pools, gymnasiums and/or indoor ball courts and/or similar indoor recreation facilities. Outdoor recreation areas may include rooftop facilities. </td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
Landscape. Except as provided herein, landscape shall be provided as required by Chapter 18A of this code. In the Core and Center Sub-districts, landscape shall be provided as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
Street trees shall be planted at a maximum of twenty-five (25) feet average on center, with a minimum six (6) inch diameter at breast height. Unless otherwise indicated by the Urban Center District or Area street type parameters, street trees shall be planted in one or more of the following methods of installation as required by Section 33-284.86(C)(4) above;
<section prefix = "a">
Tree grates. Trees are planted within openings on the sidewalk. The openings shall be covered by permanently installed grates perforated to permit natural irrigation. The grates shall be installed flush with the surrounding sidewalk.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Tree planters. Trees are planted within a raised planter located on the sidewalk. The planter shall be defined on all sides by a permanent masonry structure to consist of a minimum six (6) inch raised curb. The area within the planter, in addition to the required trees, shall be planted with ground cover, shrubs, or other appropriate plant material.

</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Continuous landscape strips. Trees are planted in the area between the curb or roadway edge and the sidewalk. This area, in addition to the required trees, shall be planted with grass.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
For all land uses except for single-family or duplex, tree requirements for private property shall be based on sixteen (16) trees per net acre of lot area and, in addition to the placement on the lot, may be placed in greens, squares, plazas and medians within the Urban Center District or Area.

</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
Parking. Except as provided herein, parking shall be provided as required by Section 33-124 of this chapter.
<section prefix = "1">
Multi-story parking garages, parking lots, and on-street parking shall count toward all parking requirements except for the parking requirements of detached single-family residences, courtyard and sideyard houses, rowhouses, urban villa, or duplexes.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
At a minimum, parking shall be provided as follows:
Single-Family Residential (off-street):
Single-family detached: 2 spaces/unit Courtyard or sideyard house: 2 spaces/unit Rowhouse or urban villa: 2 spaces/unit Duplex: 2 spaces/unit

Multi-Family Residential:
1 spaces/1 bedroom unit 1.5 spaces/2 bedroom unit 1.75 spaces/3 or more bedroom units

Housing for the elderly: 0.5 spaces/unit
Hotel/Motel: 1 space/first 40 guest rooms and 1 additional space/ every 2 guest rooms or suites thereafter
General Retail/Personal Services and Entertainment Uses: 1 space/250 square feet of gross floor area
Professional Business Offices and Health Care Services: 1 space/400 square feet of gross floor area
Food/Beverage Establishments: 1 space/ 50 square feet of patron area
Industrial: shall comply with Section 33-124 of this chapter.
Live-work units:
(1) Residential component: 2 spaces/unit, and (2) Workshop component: 1 space/325 square feet of workshop area

Live-work buildings:
(1) Residential component: shall comply with the multi-family residential requirements described in this subsection, and (2) Work space, nonresidential component: shall comply with Section 33-124, of this chapter.

Civic uses: shall comply with Section 33-124 of this chapter.
All other uses shall comply with the parking standards provided in Section 33-124 of this chapter. Educational and child care facilities located within a mixed-use building shall be exempt from the auto-stacking requirements of Section 33-151.18(c) of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Parking reduction. Development meeting certain criteria shall be permitted to reduce the number of parking spaces required. Specific use, location, and parcel requirements and permitted reductions are provided in the following table:
<section prefix="8" type="table">
<table class="thead2 table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="20%" /> 
  <col width="40%" /> 
  <col width="13.333333333333334%" /> 
  <col width="13.333333333333334%" /> 
  <col width="13.333333333333334%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " rowspan="2" colspan="1" valign="top" class="">Use</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " rowspan="2" valign="top" class="">Location, Parcel Requirement</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " colspan="3" valign="top" class="">Permitted reduction of required parking as otherwise provided in this section</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">Core</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">Center</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">Edge</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="5" valign="top" class=""> <i>Group 1: Work-force reduction</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Work-force housing units (WHU) as defined in this article</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">No location limitation</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">25%*</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">25%*</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">25%*</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="5" valign="top" class=""> <i>Group 2: Location reduction</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Nonresidential, mixed-use, multi-family residential</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Within five hundred (500) feet of a bus stop or rail station serviced by premium transit</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">50%</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">50%</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Nonresidential, mixed-use, multi-family residential</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Within one-quarter (&#188;) mile of a bus stop or rail station serviced by premium transit</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">30%</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">30%</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Nonresidential, mixed-use, multi-family residential</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Within one-half (&#189;) mile of a bus stop or rail station serviced by premium transit</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10%</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10%</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="5" valign="top" class=""> <i>Group 3: Parcel size reduction</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Mixed-use</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Parcels less than fifteen thousand (15,000) square feet</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">40%</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">40%</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Mixed-use</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Parcels between fifteen thousand (15,000) and thirty thousand (30,000) square feet</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">30%</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">30%</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Mixed-use</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Parcels greater than thirty thousand (30,000) square feet</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">20%</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10%</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="5" valign="top" class="">* Percentage reduction applies only to those spaces required by WHU restricted residential units<br />N/A: Not Applicable </td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 
Developments meeting more than one of the use, location, and parcel criteria shall be permitted to combine each permitted reduction; the combined reduction shall be calculated by reducing the first applicable criteria from each group in the order of the table above.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Mixed-use, multi-family residential, or non-residential developments in all Sub-districts may provide the required parking off-site, where the off-site parking is within seven hundred fifty (750) feet of the development and in a land use designation that is similar to or higher intensity than the land use designation of the development being served. Any certificate of use for mixed-use, multi-family residential, or nonresidential development shall immediately terminate in the event such parking area is not available. An applicant for approval of a mixed-use, multi-family residential or nonresidential development with off-site parking shall execute and record in the public records of this County a declaration of restrictions approved by the Director covenanting that such development shall cease and terminate upon the elimination of such parking area, and that no development requiring such parking shall be made of such property until the required parking area is available and provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Except for detached single-family homes, courtyard or sideyard houses, and duplexes, all parking may be in the form of parking garage structures or parking lots which shall be located in the rear or on one side of the building, and shall be screened from the street. Parking is not permitted in setback areas required along street frontages.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Parking garage structures shall be screened by a liner building containing a minimum depth of twenty (20) feet of habitable space for all stories along the primary frontage, and for parcels with three (3) or more frontages, on at least two (2) frontages. For all other frontages, architectural features of a parking structure shall appear consistent and harmonious with that of habitable space. On parcels having a lot depth at any one point of less than one hundred fifty (150) feet, as measured from the front property line, a liner building shall only be required on the ground floor. No vehicles parked within the structure shall be visible from the street.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Mechanized parking shall be allowed for mixed-use, nonresidential, and multi-family developments and, when provided, shall be exempt from the provisions of Section 33-122 of this code. For the purpose of this article, mechanized parking shall be defined as a mechanism with vertical and horizontal transport capability that provides for automobile storage and retrieval. A mechanized parking space shall be counted toward the parking requirements of this section. When provided, mechanized parking shall comply with the following:
<section prefix = "a">
A queuing analysis is submitted and approved during the Administrative Site Plan Review process.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Parking lots shall provide for vehicular connectivity to adjacent parking areas.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
The use of permeable materials for paving parking lots shall be permitted in the urban center districts.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Parking for individuals with disabilities shall comply with the Florida Building Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Parking for persons transporting strollers shall comply with Section 33-122.2 of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Individual parking garages for single-family homes shall count towards the parking requirement.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
In the Edge Sub-district, parking for detached single family homes and duplexes on platted lots of 12,000 square feet or less shall be subject to the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Where there is no service road, parking shall be in the form of individual garages or carports accessed through a driveway from the street. When provided, attached garages and carports shall be located as provided in the Building Placement Standards set forth in Section 33-284.85 of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Along the front property line the maximum width of the driveways in front of the build-to line shall be ten (10) feet. On any other frontage the maximum width of the driveway shall be twenty (20) feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The parking area shall be screened at the build-to line through the use of walls, hedges, or fences in accordance with Subsection (H) below and the Building Placement Standards set forth in Section 33-284.85 of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The sidewalk shall be continuous and remain at a constant level at all instances where a driveway intersects it.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
Required parking for single-family homes, courtyard or sideyard houses, duplexes, urban villas and rowhouses may be provided in a tandem configuration.
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
Where a wall or fence is used for screening parking areas along streets, a five (5) foot landscape strip with a hedge shall be required in front of the wall or fence.
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
The provisions of Section 33-131 of this chapter shall not apply to the required parking for mixed-use and nonresidential developments.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "G">
Lighting.
<section prefix = "1">
Street lighting shall comply with the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Street lighting shall be provided in these areas: commercial and live-work unit driveways and parking areas, sidewalks and pedestrian passages, commercial establishment entryways, recreation areas, and multi-family residential common areas and entryways.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Outdoor lighting of these areas shall comply with Section 33-4.1 of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All light fixtures shall be of a pedestrian scale, with a maximum height of eighteen (18) feet and a maximum spacing between fixtures of sixty (60) feet or such other spacing as may be required by the Department of Public Works and Waste Management, whichever is the most restrictive.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The type and spacing of light fixtures shall be approved by the Department of Public Works and Waste Management or its successor. Approval shall be based on uniformity of types, location, right-of-way width, and luminosity.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Weather and vandalism resistant covers shall protect all light fixtures.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Streetlamps shall be installed on both sides of streets.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Cobra-head lights shall not be permitted.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Open parking lot, access road, and service road lighting shall be provided as required in Section 8C-3 of this Code. Lighting fixtures in these areas shall have a maximum height of eighteen (18) feet above grade.
_____
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "H">
Walls, fences, and hedges. The following shall be permitted:
<section prefix="9" type="table">
<table class="thead1 table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="20%" /> 
  <col width="30%" /> 
  <col width="30%" /> 
  <col width="20%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">Location</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">Type and Material</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">Spacing</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">Height</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" rowspan="3" colspan="1" valign="top" class="">Around perimeter of designated open space</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Walls: masonry. Fences: wood, electrostatic plated aluminum, or wrought iron.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Max. 3'—6&quot;</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" rowspan="2" colspan="1" valign="top" class="">Hedges and shrubs</td> 
   <td style="" rowspan="2" valign="top" class="">Max. 48&quot; O.C.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">At time of planting<br />Min. 18&quot;</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Max. 3'—6&quot;</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" rowspan="3" colspan="1" valign="top" class="">In front of the build-to line (BL): Along front (F), side street (SS), and interior side (IS) </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Walls: masonry. Fences: wood, electrostatic plated aluminum, or wrought iron.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Max. 3'—6&quot;</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" rowspan="2" colspan="1" valign="top" class="">Hedges and shrubs</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">At time of planting<br />Min. 18&quot;</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Max. 48&quot; O.C.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Max. 3'—6&quot;</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" rowspan="4" colspan="1" valign="top" class="">Behind the build-to line (BL): Along interior side (IS) and rear (R) property lines</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Walls: masonry. Fences: wood, electrostatic plated aluminum, or wrought iron</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Max. 72&quot;</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" rowspan="2" colspan="1" valign="top" class="">Hedges and Shrubs</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">At time of planting<br />Min. 18&quot;</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Max. 48&quot; O.C.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Max. 96&quot;</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Chain Link</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" rowspan="2" colspan="1" valign="top" class="">Along the build-to line (BL)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Walls: masonry. Fences: wood, electrostatic plated aluminum, or wrought iron</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Max. 72&quot;</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Hedges and shrubs</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Max. 48&quot; O.C.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Max. 72&quot;</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" rowspan="2" colspan="1" valign="top" class="">Parking Areas Along Streets</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Walls: masonry. Fences: wood, electrostatic plated aluminum, or wrought iron</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Min. 3'—6&quot;</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Hedges and shrubs</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Max. 48&quot; O.C.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Service Areas</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Walls: masonry. Fences: wood, electrostatic plated aluminum, or wrought iron</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Height required to mitigate the visual impact of service area features</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Construction Areas</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Chain Link</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">N/A</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="4" valign="top" class="">Min.: Minimum<br />Max.: Maximum<br />N/A: Not Applicable<br />O.C.: On Center</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 

Note:
Hedges and shrubs shall be subject to Chapter 18A of this Code.
Additional requirements for walls, fences and hedges may be included in the Building Placement Standards set forth in Section 33-284.85 of this article, and in the event of a conflict, the Building Placement Standards shall govern.

</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 05-143, § 6, 7-7-05; Ord. No. 06-10, § 3, 1-24-06; Ord. No. 07-93, § 4, 7-10-07; Ord. No. 07-169, § 9, 11-6-07; Ord. No. 08-102, § 3, 9-2-08; Ord. No. 12-86, § 5, 10-2-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.87. Signs</catch_line>
<text>
Except as provided herein, the definitions set forth in Section 33-84 of this chapter shall apply. In the event of a conflict, the provisions of this section shall govern.
<section prefix = "A">
For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:
<section prefix = "1">
Digital technology (signs): Electronic technology that allows for changes to a sign copy resulting from digital data input. Included in this technology are signs that use series of lights, including light emitting diodes (LED), fiber optics, or other similar technology.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Nits: Luminance is the measure of the light emanating from an object with respect to its size and is the term used to quantify electronic sign brightness. The unit of measurement for luminance is nits (nt), which is the total amount of light emitted from a sign divided by the surface area of the sign [candelas per square meter (cd/m2)].
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Temporary Signs in MUCs and CUCs. Temporary signs (Class A) shall be permitted in compliance with Section 33-99 of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Permanent Point of Sale Signs. Permanent point of sale signs (Class B) shall be permitted as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
The following permanent point of sale signs are permitted in all Sub-districts in conjunction with permitted business and industrial uses: flat attached, hanging, awning, cantilever, projecting, and monument. No other detached sign shall be permitted except monument signs.
<section prefix = "a">
Projecting signs shall be mounted and perpendicular to the building.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The copy of an awning sign shall only be located on the valance of the awning.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The bottom of a hanging sign shall be located at a minimum height of eight (8) feet from the finished floor.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Monument signs, which are freestanding, 2-faced signs, shall have a base at least seventy-five (75) percent of the horizontal width of the sign and located directly on the ground or a maximum of twelve (12) inches above grade.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Cantilever signs are mounted on those portions of the building that project horizontally.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Maximum size, location, and number of signs shall be as follows:
<section prefix="10" type="table">
<table class="thead1 table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="25%" /> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
  <col width="25%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">Sign<br />Type</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">Size</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">Number<br />of Signs</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Flat Attached, Cantilever, Projecting*</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10% of wall area**</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Not limited</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Hanging, Awning</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6 sq. ft.</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Not limited</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Monument</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">25 sq. ft. maximum for first 50 feet of street frontage plus .75 sq. ft. for each additional foot of street frontage to a maximum of 40 sq. ft. per sign face. </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">One per street frontage</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="3" valign="top" class="">* Each side of a projecting sign with multiple faces shall count toward the maximum permitted sign area.<br />** Where a building may be occupied by multiple tenants, the permitted sign area that results from the percentage of wall area is shared among all tenants. A sign survey shall be required at time of permitting to demonstrate compliance with the maximum sign area permitted. In all Sub-districts, for flat attached signs only, up to thirty (30) percent of the sign may be illuminated using digital technology. </td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Illumination/lighting shall comply with the following:
Flat attached, cantilever, and projecting signs utilizing flashing, moving, intermittent, chasing, or rotating lights shall be permitted in conjunction with convention halls or meeting halls and auditoriums, theaters, movie theaters, athletic facilities, museums, and other visual and performance arts buildings.
Where digital technology is allowed, it shall be provided in compliance with the following:
<section prefix = "a">
No auditory message or mechanical sounds shall be emitted from the sign.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The sign shall not display any illumination that moves, appears to move, blinks, fades, rolls, dissolves, flashes, scrolls, shows animated movement, or changes in intensity during the static display period.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All digital signs shall be modulated so that, from sunset to sunrise, the brightness shall not be more than 500 Nits. Sunset and sunrise times are those times established by the Miami office of the National Weather Service. At all other times, the maximum brightness levels shall not exceed 5,000 Nits. All digital signs shall have installed ambient light monitors and at all times shall allow such monitors to automatically adjust the brightness level of the sign based on ambient light conditions.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The message display shall not change more often than once each eight seconds, with all moving parts or illumination moving or changing simultaneously.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Any digital sign that malfunctions, fails, or ceases to operate in its usual or normal programmed manner shall immediately revert to a black screen and shall be restored to its normal operation conforming to the requirements of this section within twenty-four (24) hours.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Maximum heights shall be as follows:
<section prefix = "a">
Six (6) feet above grade to top of sign for monument signs; except, for signs associated with nonconforming structures located on corner parcels fronting major or minor roads identified on the Land Use Plan, one monument sign may be constructed at a maximum height of twelve (12) feet above grade to top of sign in lieu of two six-foot signs;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
No height limits for flat attached, cantilever, or projecting signs;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
For signs painted on the facade of a building or on the valance of an awning, the copy shall not exceed one (1) foot.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
No setback is required for any sign. Cantilever, projecting, and awning signs may encroach into any required setback. Awning signs and projecting signs attached to awnings may encroach into the right-of-way. Where a zero (0) foot setback is permitted, cantilever and projecting signs may encroach into the right-of-way up to three (3) feet. Signs encroaching into the right-of-way shall be a minimum of eleven (11) feet above the sidewalk.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
Directional Signs. Directional signs, to direct traffic flow and locate entrances and exits shall be permitted on private property in connection with any permitted use. Detached directional signs shall not exceed three (3) square feet in area; directional signs attached to buildings shall not exceed twelve (12) square feet in area. The maximum height of a detached directional sign shall be ten (10) feet. Directional signs shall be shown and approved on site plans which indicate sign size, location, copy, etc.
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
Flags. Each parcel may display no more than three (3) flags and three (3) flagpoles. Flagpoles shall not exceed seventy (70) feet in height. Flag dimensions shall be proportional to the pole such that the hoist side of the flag is not more than fifty (50) percent of the vertical height of the flagpole. For purposes of this section, "flag" means any fabric or bunting containing colors, patterns, or symbols.
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
Prohibited Signs. The following types of outdoor signs shall be prohibited:
<section prefix = "1">
Revolving, rotating, and other moving signs.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Backlit signs of any type.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Banners.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Roof signs.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Balloon signs.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Class C commercial signs or other outdoor advertising, except those within bus shelters.

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.88. Review Procedure/Administrative Site Plan and Architectural Review</catch_line>
<text>
Except for individual single-family homes and duplexes, all applications for development approval within an Urban Center District that are not otherwise permitted as nonconforming uses or structures shall comply with the requirements of this article and with the site plan and architectural review criteria contained herein. Developments shall be processed and approved administratively as follows:
<section prefix = "A">
Administrative site and architectural plan review. The Department shall review plans, including the exhibits listed below for completeness and compliance with the provisions of this article, including the Regulating Plans, and for compliance with the site plan review criteria provided herein. Additionally, all applications shall be reviewed by the following departments of Miami-Dade County and other public entities for potential impacts on infrastructure and other services resulting from the application: Department of Public Works and Waste Management or its successor, Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources or its successor, Miami-Dade Fire Rescue Department or its successor, and the Miami-Dade County School Board. In the event the application indicates impacts on services and infrastructure provided by any of the foregoing, the applicant shall meet with the affected department or entity to discuss potential mitigation of the impacts and shall submit evidence to the Department of such discussion. The Director shall issue a final decision within twenty-one (21) days of the date of submission of the completed application. The applicant shall have the right to extend the twenty-one (21) day period by an additional twenty-one (21) days upon timely request made in writing to the Department. The Department shall have the right to extend the twenty-one (21) day period by written notice to the applicant that additional information is needed. Denials shall be in writing and shall specifically set forth the grounds for the denial. Any final decision of the Director may be appealed in accordance with the procedures established in this chapter for appeals of administrative decisions.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Applications for administrative site plan and architectural review under this article shall be accompanied by exhibits prepared by registered architects and landscape architects which shall be submitted to the Department and shall include the following:
<section prefix = "1">
Site plan(s) including:
<section prefix = "a">
Sub-district location;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Street layouts and designations as per this article;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Locations, shape, size, and height of existing buildings;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Building exterior finish material;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Indication of street vistas;
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Lot lines, setbacks and build-to lines;
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Location of open spaces including anchor points if applicable;
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Location of on-street and off-street parking including type of permeable materials if used on parking lots, loading facilities, and waste collection areas;
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Indication of signage;
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Indication of any site or building design methods used to conserve energy;
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Locations of backflow prevention devices and connections; and
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Indication of the placement and type(s) of lighting fixtures illuminating roadways and parking areas.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Landscape plans, including specifications of species of plant material, location, and size in accordance with this article and Chapter 18A of this code.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Street cross-sections, including adjacent buildings and open space.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Floor plans, elevations, and sections of all buildings, including total gross square feet of area for each floor and all dimensions relating to the requirements of this article. A pattern book may be submitted for detached and attached single-family units including, at a minimum, unit plans and elevations, elevation of unit groupings, and typical design details such as street lamps, benches, fencing, and paving details.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Figures indicating the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Gross and net acreage;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Total square footage for each use by type;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Total number of dwelling units;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Amount of passive and active open space in square feet; and
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Such other design data as may be needed to evaluate the project's compliance with the requirements of this article and Chapter.

</section>
</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.89. Zoning relief from certain requirements</catch_line>
<text>
Relief from the following requirements of this article shall be permitted only pursuant to the standards and requirements of Section 33-311(A)(4)(a) of this code:
<section prefix = "1">
Minimum and maximum densities;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Required liner buildings used to screen parking;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Colonnade regulations, including minimum horizontal and vertical clearances;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Provision of A streets;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Requirements for street trees, greens, plazas, squares and medians;
<section prefix = "7">
Maximum size of blocks;
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Curb requirement in the Core and Center sub-district; and
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Signage.

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.89.1. Special Exceptions Procedures</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Requests for special exceptions as permitted in this article shall be in accordance with Section 33-311(A)(3) of this Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Standards for Site Plan Review. To ensure compatibility with the surrounding area, the following site plan review standards shall be utilized by the Director, the Community Zoning Appeals Board, and the Board of County Commissioners in the consideration of requests for special exceptions pursuant to this article:
<section prefix = "1">
Except for street tree requirements, developments shall provide two (2) times the landscaping required by this article and applicable Chapter 18A (Landscape Code) regulations.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The proposed development's scale and architecture shall be compatible with buildings in the surrounding area. Building height transitions shall be used when the proposed permitted maximum height for a development is greater than existing or proposed buildings in the adjoining or adjacent neighborhood.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The development shall meet the standards and criteria of the urban center's land use category designation and Building Placement Standards as provided in this article, and shall meet all other requirements for such particular use set forth in this chapter.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 12-86, § 9, 10-2-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.89.2. Nonconforming Lots, Uses and Structures</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Purpose/Applicability.
<section prefix = "1">
Nothing contained in this article shall be deemed or construed to prohibit the continuation of a legally established non-conforming use, structure, or occupancy, as those terms are defined in Sections 33-1, 33-34, and 33-35 of this chapter. The intent of this Section is to encourage nonconformities to ultimately be brought into compliance with current regulations. This section shall govern in the event of conflicts with other regulations of this code pertaining to legally established nonconforming uses, structures, and occupancies.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The term "nonconformity" shall refer to a use, building, or lot that does not comply with the regulations of this article. Only legally established nonconformities shall have rights under this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
For purposes of this section, the term "expansion" shall mean an improvement, addition, enlargement, extension, or modification to a structure that increases the square footage of the structure.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
For the purposes of this section, "legally established" shall apply to the following circumstances:
<section prefix = "a">
A lot that does not meet the lot frontage, lot width, lot depth, and/or lot area requirements of the current zoning district, provided that such lot met the regulations in effect at the time of platting.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A site or improvement that is rendered nonconforming through the lawful use of eminent domain, an order of a court of competent jurisdiction, or the voluntary dedication of property.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
An existing use which conformed to the code at the time it was established.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
A building and/or site improvement that was permitted in accordance with regulations in effect at the time of permitting or that was approved pursuant to a public hearing.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
A building and/or site improvement that had received final site plan approval through a public hearing pursuant to this chapter or through administrative site plan review or had a valid building permit.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Discontinuation of the use, structure, or occupancy would abrogate a vested right as determined by Sections 2-114.1 to 2-114.4 of this Code.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Nonconforming Lots, Uses and Structures.
<section prefix = "1">
Nonconforming Lots.
<section prefix = "a">
Development on a legally established, nonconforming lot that does not meet the lot frontage and/or lot area requirements of this article shall be permitted, provided that the development meets all other requirements of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Expansions to structures on legally established, nonconforming lots shall be permitted in accordance with this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Variances from other requirements of this article shall require a public hearing, pursuant to this article and Section 33-311 of this chapter.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Nonconforming Uses.
<section prefix = "a">
A legally established nonconforming use may continue. Expansions to a structure containing a nonconforming use shall require Administrative Site Plan Review [see Subsection (C)] below.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
If a nonconforming use is discontinued for a period of more than one year, the use may not be reestablished. A use shall be considered discontinued once the activities or commerce, essential to the continuation of the use are abandoned. Discontinuance due to acts of force majeure shall not constitute abandonment, provided that a good faith effort is made to reestablish the use.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Expansions of nonconforming single-family and two-family residences shall be permitted and shall not require Administrative Site Plan approval, provided that the project complies with the Building Placement Standards for single-family detached or duplex lots set forth in Section 33-284.85 of this article.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Nonconforming Structures.
<section prefix = "a">
To prevent changes in regulation from unduly burdening property owners, legally established, nonconforming structures may continue to be used and maintained. Expansions, repairs, alterations, and improvements to nonconforming structures shall be permitted only in accordance with the following provisions:
<section prefix = "i">
Internal and external repairs, alterations, and improvements that do not increase the square footage of the nonconforming structure shall be permitted and shall not be subject to the requirements of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Expansions to a nonconforming structure shall be permitted as follows:
<section prefix = "a">
If the total square footage of the proposed improvement is less than fifty (50) percent of the structure's net square footage at the time it became nonconforming, the improvement shall require Administrative Site Plan Review [see Subsection (C) below].
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
If the total square footage of the proposed improvement is equal to or exceeds fifty (50) percent of the structure's net square footage at the time it became nonconforming, the entire structure and site improvements shall be brought into compliance with current regulations.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Once the cumulative total of additional square footage of improvements equals to fifty (50) percent of the structure's net square footage at the time it became nonconforming, no additional expansions shall be permitted and the entire structure and site improvements shall be brought into compliance with current regulations.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
For the purposes of this article, net square footage shall refer to the square footage indicated on the building permit or determined through equivalent evidence.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
If a nonconforming structure is damaged by fire, flood, explosion, wind, war, riot or any other act of force majeure, repairs shall be subject to the following provisions:
<section prefix = "i">
If the repair/replacement cost is less than fifty (50) percent of the value of the structure based upon the average of two (2) independent appraisals, the structure may be reconstructed up to the same building height and within the same building footprint existing prior to the damage, provided that an application for final building permit has been submitted within twelve (12) months of the date of such damage unless extended by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
If the repair/replacement cost is equal to or exceeds fifty (50) percent of the building's value based upon the average of two (2) independent appraisals, the building and site improvements shall be brought into compliance with current regulations.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Routine internal and external maintenance, repairs and material replacement such as re-roofing, painting, window or door replacement, mechanical equipment repair and replacement, plumbing and electrical maintenance, and similar repair, maintenance and replacements shall be permitted and shall not be subject to the requirements of this Article.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
If a nonconforming building is deemed to be unsafe pursuant to Chapter 8 of this Code, and demolition is required, the building shall be rebuilt in accordance with current regulations.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
In addition to the requirements of this section, all repairs, improvements and expansions to a nonconforming building shall comply with the Florida Building Code.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Administrative Site Plan Review Standards.
<section prefix = "1">
Where Subsection (B) above permits the expansion of a nonconforming use or structure subject to administrative review, the project shall be reviewed according to the plan review standards outlined in this sub-section. The intent of the plan review shall be to allow for the continuation of viable uses and structures while seeking opportunities to lessen the adverse impacts of proposed expansions and encouraging nonconformities to ultimately be brought into compliance.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Expansions to nonconforming single-family and two-family residences are permitted and shall not require Administrative Site Plan Review (ASPR) approval, provided said expansion complies with the single-family detached or duplex lot criteria indicated in the building placement standards of this article. One-family and two-family residences that were rendered nonconforming due to the assignment of a nonresidential land use designation shall be permitted to continue and expand in accordance with Subsection (B) above. The expansion shall not require ASPR approval provided said expansion meets the applicable single-family detached or duplex lot criteria indicated in the building placement standards of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Expansions permitted under Subsection (B) above subject to the Administrative Site Plan Review (ASPR) process, shall be permitted by the Department upon a showing that the project satisfies all of the following criteria:
<section prefix = "a">
The expansions will not cause adverse impacts, such as traffic, noise, dust, odors and parking congestion, on surrounding properties or significantly change the character of the area.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The expansion shall comply with the setback requirements applicable only to the expanded area, as indicated in the Building Placement Standards set forth in Section 33-284.85 of this article. Other requirements set forth in Section 33-284.85 such as building frontage may be waived by the Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The number of parking spaces necessitated by the expansion is provided in accordance with the minimum number of parking spaces requirements in Section 33-284.86(F)(2).
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The expansion shall comply with the street tree requirement in this article and with the parking lot buffers requirement in Chapter 18A (Landscape Code).
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
If the project does not meet the aforementioned criteria, it shall be permitted if approved upon public hearing. At public hearing, additional conditions may be imposed to enhance compatibility of the project with the surrounding area, including without limitation, the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Limit the manner in which the use is conducted, including restricting hours of operation and other restraints, to minimize adverse impacts such as noise, vibration, air pollution, glare and odor.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Specify additional screening or open space to minimize impacts to surrounding properties or the character of the area.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Restrict the height, size, or location of a building or other structure.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Require additional right-of-way dedication or road improvements.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Restrict the number, size, location, height or lighting of signage.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Limit the location and intensity of outdoor lighting or require its shielding.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Restrictions to protect existing natural, cultural and historical resources.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Impose additional restrictions necessary to protect existing natural, cultural, and historical resources.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Impose additional conditions necessary to further the intent and purpose of this article and the Comprehensive Development Master Plan.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 12-86, § 10, 10-2-12; Ord. No. 13-43, § 14, 5-7-13)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-284.90. Conflicts with other chapters and regulations</catch_line>
<text>
This article shall govern in the event of conflicts with other zoning, subdivision, or landscape regulations of this code, or with the Miami-Dade Department of Public Works Manual of Public Works.
</text>
</law>
