<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XLIII._MIAMI-DADE_COUNTY_ADVISOR</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-401. Created</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created the Miami-Dade County Advisory Committee on Immigration.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-402. Purposes</catch_line>
<text>
The purposes of the Committee shall be to assess the impact of immigrant groups on the County's infrastructure, to develop methods of assimilating and acculturing immigrants within Miami-Dade County, to assess the economic costs of immigration and recommend alternative strategies for cost recovery.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-403. Powers</catch_line>
<text>
The Committee shall have the following powers:
<section prefix = "1">
To identify refugee and immigrant groups.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To define refugee and immigrant status.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
To quantify cost of service delivery systems impacted by various classifications of refugees and immigrants.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
To quantify cost of resettlement, assimilation and acculturation.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
To indemnify funding sources to recover these costs and make sure that Miami-Dade County receives reimbursement.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
To liaise with the federal and State governments concerning appropriate legislation.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
To direct staff to study the impact of legislation and to develop programs.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
To do any and all other tasks relating to refugees and immigrants which the Board of County Commissioners assigns.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-404. Membership</catch_line>
<text>
The Committee shall be co-chaired by Commissioners Barbara M. Carey, Jorge E. Valdes, and Harvey Ruvin. The members of the committee shall be Mrs. Roxcy Bolton, T. Willard Fair, Rep. Dante Fascell or designee, Mrs. Toni Gary, Dr. Michael Krop, Mayor Raul Martinez, Mrs. M. Athalie Range, Hon. Abe Resnick, Perry Rivkind, Hon. Harvey Ruvin, Dr. Artistides A. Sosa, Msgr. Bryan Walsh, Father Tom Wenski and Hon. Gerald T. Wetherington. Staff members of the Committee shall be the County Manager and the County Attorney, or their designees. Each member shall serve for a term of four (4) years. The Board of County Commissioners may, by motion, appoint additional or successor members and may remove members with or without cause at any time.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-405. Staff support</catch_line>
<text>
The Office of County Manager shall provide staff support to this Committee. The Committee shall provide an annual report to the Board of County Commissioners.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-406—2-420. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (67) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 88-96, adopted Oct. 4, 1988, amended the Code, but did not specify the manner of codification. At the discretion of the editor, §§ 1—5 of said Ord. No. 88-96 have been included herein as Art. XLIII, §§ 2-401—2-405. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
