<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_CXVI._NORTHEAST_DADE_AREA_MUNICI</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1761. Creating of the Northeast Dade Area Municipal Advisory Committee; composition</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created a Northeast Dade Area Municipal Advisory Committee consisting of a minimum of no less than seven (7) members and no more than eleven (11) members. The initial members as well as any vacancies on the Northeast Dade Area Municipal Advisory Committee shall be those members appointed pursuant to memorandum to be issued by the County Commissioner for the District. The members of the committee shall select officers from the membership as desirable or necessary.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1762. Purposes</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
To review the possible incorporation of the generally described area:
<section prefix="1" type="table">
<table class="table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="60px" /> 
  <col width="100%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">North:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">NE 215th Street or County Line Road</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">East:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">the Florida East Coast Railway along West Dixie Highway</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">South:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">the City of North Miami Beach</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">West:</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Interstate 95 from NE 215th Street south to the Snake Creek Canal.</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To prepare an advisory report that shall address the results of the study prepared by County staff as well as incorporation concerns of members of the Board of County Commissioners and the manner in which those concerns may be alleviated in the event Northeast Dade Area is incorporated as a new municipality.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-104, § 2, 5-13-04)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1763. Duties and Responsibilities</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
The committee shall conduct no less than two duly advertised public hearings at which the residents of the area shall have the opportunity to express their views and concerns regarding the proposed incorporation of the Northeast Dade Area.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Prior to the first public hearing, the committee shall have reviewed the tape of the County Commission workshop on incorporation held on January 14, 1999, and shall be familiar with written materials concerning incorporation presented to the Board of County Commissioners at that time and at any subsequent meeting or workshop.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The committee's responsibilities shall terminate upon submission of its report to the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-104, § 3, 5-13-04)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1764. Code provision waived</catch_line>
<text>
The requirement of Section 2-11.37(c) of the Code of Miami-Dade County is hereby waived.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1765. Simultaneous service</catch_line>
<text>
Notwithstanding the provisions of Section 2-11.38 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, a member of a Community Council may simultaneously serve on the Northeast Dade Area Municipal Advisory Committee.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-1766—2-1770. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (125) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 04-104, §§ 1—5, adopted May 13, 2004, did not specifically amend the Code. Hence, its inclusion herein as article CXVI, sections 2-1761—2-1765, was at the discretion of the editor. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
