<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 7 BOATS, DOCKS AND WATERWAYS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_IV._BARGES</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 7-55. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
Miami Harbor. For purposes of this article, the term "Miami Harbor" shall include all navigable waters within the confines of Dade County.
Storm warning. [A "storm warning" is] a warning issued by the U.S. Weather Bureau that one (1) or more of the following dangerous weather conditions are expected in a specified coastal area in twenty-four (24) hours or less:
<section prefix = "a">
Tropical storm. A tropical cyclone with closed isobars and highest wind speeds of thirty-four (34) to sixty-three (63) knots (thirty-nine (39) to seventy-three (73) mph) inclusive.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Whole gale. Winds in the range of fifty-five (55) to seventy-three (73) miles per hour (forty-eight (48) to sixty-three (63) knots).

Hurricane warnings. [A "hurricane warning" is] a warning issued by the U.S. Weather Bureau that one (1) or more of the following dangerous effects of a hurricane are expected in a specified coastal area in twenty-four (24) hours or less:
<section prefix = "a">
Hurricane force winds (seventy-four (74) miles per hour or higher).
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Dangerously high water or a combination of dangerously high water and exceptionally high waves, even though winds expected may be less than hurricane force.

Barges. [A "barge" is] any vessel without sail or internal motive power of its own intended to be utilized by being towed by another vessel.
Undocumented barge. [An "undocumented barge" is] any barge which is not required to have, and does not have, a valid marine document issued by the U.S. Coast Guard or Bureau of Customs.
Open water. ["Open water" is] all navigable water in Dade County not protected from wind and wave action on all points of the compass, including all of Biscayne Bay except sheltered coves.
Sheltered waters. ["Sheltered waters" are] all navigable waters in Dade County protected from wind and wave action on all sides including the upper reaches of the Miami River and excluding all of Biscayne Bay except sheltered coves.
Safe anchorage. ["Safe anchorage" is] a place for anchorage or mooring that is sheltered from the action of wind and wave, and provides adequate holding power for anchors or mooring lines utilized.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 7-56. Penalties for violation of article</catch_line>
<text>
Any person, including specifically but not limited to, the officers and managing agents of any entity, agency or corporation, private or public, who knowingly fails or refuses to obey or comply with, or wilfully violates, any of the provisions of this article, upon conviction of such offense, shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00), or by imprisonment not to exceed sixty (60) days in the County Jail, or both, in the discretion of the court. Each day of continued violation shall be considered as a separate offense. In addition or alternatively by direction of the County Commission, the provisions of this article may be enforced by injunction or other appropriate civil action.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 7-57. Administration by Dade County Seaport Director</catch_line>
<text>
The Dade County Seaport Director is hereby designated as the County's chief administrative officer regarding interpretation of this article and shall make recommendations for enforcement thereof. All owners of barges covered by this article will be required to notify the Seaport Director of their name and address and of the identification and the proposed safe anchorage of their barges upon issuance of storm or hurricane warnings.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 7-58. Undocumented barges required to display identification</catch_line>
<text>
Commencing with the effective date of this article [thirty (30) days after July 25, 1967], all undocumented barges, as defined herein, located in the navigable waters of Dade County shall conspicuously display identification including a name or number and the name of the owner of said barges. The letters and numerals of the identification provided must be at least three (3) inches in height with black on white background so as to be clearly visible from a distance of at least two hundred (200) feet. It shall be unlawful for any undocumented barge, not displaying acceptable identification as required hereunder, to be located on the navigable waters of Dade County subsequent to the effective date of this article.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 7-59. Mooring and anchoring</catch_line>
<text>
Mooring and anchoring of barges in the navigable waters of Dade County shall continue to be in accordance with accepted practices and regulations except as provided herein. Owners of barges shall take action to insure that their barges are moved from open waters to areas of safe anchorage in sheltered waters, as defined herein, immediately upon the issuance of a storm or hurricane warning which includes the area of Dade County in which the barges are located. The practice of scuttling as an aid in securing an anchored or moored barge will be permitted provided that the barge is hard aground in water not ordinarily used by other craft and is properly marked according to current federal regulations so as not to constitute a menace to navigation.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 7-60. Variances</catch_line>
<text>
In the event the application of any one (1) or more of the requirements established by this article as applied to a particular case, in light of the particular circumstances, is demonstrated to be either unreasonable, arbitrary or not in the public interest and if it be found that such requirement results in undue hardship to some person, the Board of County Commissioners may, after public notice and hearing at the petition of such person, grant a variance from the application of such regulation for that particular case.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (5) ---
Editor's note— Article IV, §§ 7-55—7-60, is derived from Ord. No. 67-51, §§ 1—6, adopted July 25, 1967, effective thirty (30) days after enactment. Section 8 of said ordinance authorized its inclusion as a part of this Code. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
