<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_CXXXIII._MIAMI-DADE_HOUSING_CIVI</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2052. Creation and Purpose</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created the advisory board called the "Miami-Dade Housing Civil Rights Oversight Board" (hereinafter "Oversight Board"). The purpose of the Oversight Board is to monitor the compliance with the Fair Housing Act and other housing-related civil rights laws, regulations, ordinances and the County's antidiscrimination policies by the Miami-Dade Public Housing Agency, the Department of Housing and Community Development, and other County departments which administer housing programs and to report on such compliance to the Board of County Commissioners annually.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2053. The Board Composition</catch_line>
<text>
The Oversight Board shall consist of ten (10) members as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
Four (4) members shall be appointed by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
One (1) representative of each of the following organizations:
<section prefix = "a">
Housing Opportunities Project for Excellence, Inc., and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Overall Tenant Advisory Council, Inc.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
One (1) representative from the following County departments:
<section prefix = "a">
Miami-Dade Commission on Human Rights,
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Miami-Dade Public Housing Agency,
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Miami-Dade Economic Advocacy Trust; and
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The Department of Housing and Community Development.

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2054. Terms, Reappointment, Vacancies and Attendance</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
All members shall serve two-year terms, except that the length of the terms of the initial appointees shall be adjusted to stagger the terms.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A member may be reappointed; however, a member may not serve more than four (4) consecutive terms. A member who has served four (4) consecutive terms is eligible to be appointed again after a two-year hiatus from the Oversight Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
A member may be removed for failure to comply with the attendance requirements set out in Section 2-11.39 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida as amended, or for any other reason as established in the Oversight Board Bylaws.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 09-107, ยง 3, 12-1-09)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2055. Organization, Procedure and Orientation</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Bylaws. The Oversight Board shall make and adopt bylaws for its guidance, operation, governance and maintenance, provided such bylaws, and any amendments thereto, are consistent with federal and state laws and county ordinances, rules, regulations, policies and procedures and have been approved for form and legal sufficiency by the County Attorney's Office.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Officers. Immediately after the members are appointed, the members of the Oversight Board shall elect a chair, a vice chair and other officers as designated in the bylaws. Officers shall be elected for a two-year term.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Committees. The Oversight Board may establish through its bylaws such committees as it considers necessary to address the core mission of the Oversight Board. The bylaws shall also allow for the creation of ad hoc committees as necessary.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Meetings.
<section prefix = "1">
Meetings shall be conducted upon the call of the chairperson; however, the Oversight Board shall meet on a regular basis as determined in the bylaws during the County's fiscal year.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
All Oversight Board meetings must be timely noticed at least seven (7) but not more than thirty (30) days prior to the meeting. Such notice shall be provided to the media and a copy shall be maintained at the Miami-Dade Commission on Human Rights. However, if immediate action is necessary to address a matter of imminent harm to public health, safety and welfare, the Oversight Board may schedule a meeting with no less than twenty-four (24) hours notice.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Minutes shall be kept of all meetings of the Oversight Board and such minutes shall be available for inspection by any interested person.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
All meetings shall be open to the public.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Quorum. A quorum of the Oversight Board shall be one-half of the total number of members seated on the Oversight Board plus one.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Inquiries and Communications. All inquiries or communications from the Oversight Board or any of its members to the Miami-Dade Commission on Human Rights or to the County shall be made through the Chair of the Oversight Board, Informal communications may be made freely from the Miami-Dade Commission on Human Rights to the Oversight Board members, in a manner that is consistent with the Sunshine Law.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Orientation. All new members of the Oversight Board shall receive sufficient training and orientation to enable them to perform their duties.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 09-107, ยง 4, 12-1-09)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2056. Powers and Duties</catch_line>
<text>
The Oversight Board shall have the following powers and duties:
<section prefix = "1">
To advise the Board of County Commissioners regarding compliance by the Miami-Dade County Public Housing Agency, the Miami-Dade County Department of Housing and Community Development and other County departments that administer housing programs with the Fair Housing Act and other housing-related civil rights laws, regulations, ordinances and the County's antidiscrimination policies;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To provide advice to the Board of County Commissioners, the Mayor and the County Manager regarding housing discrimination issues in Miami-Dade County;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
To approve and provide a report annually to the Board of County Commissioners regarding compliance of the Miami-Dade Public Housing Agency, the Miami-Dade County Department of Housing and Community Development, and other County departments that administer housing programs with the Fair Housing Act and other housing-related civil rights laws, regulations, ordinances and the County's antidiscrimination policies.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2057. Applicability of Federal, State and County Laws</catch_line>
<text>
The Oversight Board shall be subject to and governed by: Chapter 286 of Florida Statutes, ("Sunshine Law"); Chapter 119 of Florida Statutes ("Public Records Act"); Chapter 112, Part III of Florida Statutes ("Code of Ethics for Public Officers and Employees"); Section 2-11.1 of Miami-Dade County Code ("Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance"); Article IB of Miami-Dade County Code ("Standards for Creation and Review of Boards Generally") and the Home Rule Charter.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2058. Staff Support</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager's Office shall designate appropriate staff to support the Oversight Board.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-2059. Legal Counsel</catch_line>
<text>
The County Attorney's Office shall provide legal counsel, as needed, to the Oversight Board.
</text>
</law>
