<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XIII._TRAFFIC_AND_TRANSPORTATION</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-95. Short title</catch_line>
<text>
This article shall be known and may be cited as the "Miami-Dade County Traffic and Transportation Department Article."
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-95.1. Traffic and Transportation Department created; duties, powers</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created and established the Miami-Dade County Traffic and Transportation Department.
The Traffic and Transportation Department is hereby empowered and shall have the duty and responsibility to perform, under the administrative direction and supervision of the County Manager, and in accordance with policies adopted by the Board of County Commissioners, the following functions:
<section prefix = "a">
Master plan. To provide, develop, maintain, improve, implement and enforce a comprehensive master plan for the control, regulation and appropriate movement of traffic for Miami-Dade County, Florida, including both the incorporated and unincorporated areas thereof.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Traffic-control devices. The planning, installation, operation and maintenance of all traffic control devices, including but not limited to, traffic signals, signs, markings and street name signs on all public streets.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Street uses, traffic regulations. To determine and designate arterial streets, residential streets, parkways, play streets, bus streets, scenic routes, bus routes, truck routes, one-way streets, alleys, service roads, speed zones, stop signs, crosswalks, safety zones, truck loading zones, passenger loading zones, taxi zones, bus loading zones, no-parking zones, restricted parking zones, time limit parking zones, school crossing zones, automatic signal devices, pedestrian signals, channelization, pavement markings, warning signs, yield right-of-way signs, advisory speed signs, turn restrictions, regulation and routing of overweight vehicles.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Traffic engineering. The Department shall have exclusive jurisdiction in respect to all matters of traffic engineering within the territorial areas of Miami-Dade County, subject only to the jurisdiction of the state road department in respect to state highways. For the purposes of this article, "traffic engineering" shall mean that phase of engineering which deals with the planning and geometric design of streets, highways, roads, alleys, or other places used for travel or parking of motor vehicles, and abutting lands, and with traffic operation thereon, as the use thereof is related to the safe, convenient, economical and feasible transportation of persons and goods.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Designation of lanes. To mark lanes upon the roadway of any street where it is deemed and determined that regular alignment of traffic is necessary in the interest of safety and efficiency, including no-passing lanes designated and indicated by double yellow lines. Where such traffic lanes have been marked, it shall be unlawful for the operator of any vehicle to fail or refuse to keep such vehicle within the boundaries of any such lane, except when lawfully passing another vehicle, where permitted, or preparatory to making a lawful turning movement.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Promulgation of regulations; control device testing. The department is hereby empowered to make all regulations necessary to effectuate the provisions of this article and the provisions of Chapter 30 of this Code, and to make temporary or experimental regulations, consistent with this article, to cover emergencies or special conditions. No such traffic regulation shall be effective or in force and effect until and unless adequate signs, signals or other notices or warnings are erected clearly indicating such regulation. The department may test traffic control devices under actual conditions of traffic.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Municipal traffic markings. The department shall assume full responsibility for the operation, maintenance and replacement of all existing signs signals, and markings now in use in the several municipalities, provided that the Traffic Director may at his discretion remove, change, or replace any such installation.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
All night parking. The Traffic Director shall have the power and authority to prohibit all night parking upon any public street or portion thereof, and to prohibit the all night parking of trucks or other vehicles bearing commercial signs or advertising upon public streets in residential areas, and cause to be erected signs or markings giving notice of such traffic regulations, whenever such prohibition is necessary in the interest of public safety.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
General. It shall be the general duty of the Department to plan and determine the installation and proper timing of all traffic control devices; to plan and direct the operation and movement of traffic on all public streets within Miami-Dade County; to conduct investigations of traffic conditions; to cooperate with other county, municipal and state officials and make recommendations for the improvement of traffic movement and conditions, including improvements in streets; and to perform duties and functions necessary to provide traffic engineering on a County-wide basis, commensurate with the provisions of this article.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-96. Powers of Traffic Engineer assumed by Department</catch_line>
<text>
In addition to the powers, duties, and functions hereinabove vested in the Traffic and Transportation Department, such Department shall have and exercise all powers conferred upon the County Traffic Engineer by the provisions of Chapter 30 of this Code, not inconsistent with the provisions of this article.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-96.1. Jurisdiction declared exclusive; tampering with control devices prohibited</catch_line>
<text>
From and after September 16, 1960, all traffic engineering services shall be performed by the traffic and transportation department, and such department shall have exclusive jurisdiction over all traffic control devices in both the incorporated and unincorporated areas of the county, and shall have exclusive jurisdiction to exercise the powers, duties and functions set forth herein. All municipalities in Miami-Dade County are prohibited from exercising any such powers, duties and functions, and shall not interfere with the performance thereof by said county department; provided, however, that the County Manager or designee, in his/her sole discretion, may authorize municipalities, which desire and are equipped and able to perform certain traffic engineering functions, to assume, together with all liability and without additional cost to the County, through an individual Intergovernmental Agency Agreement, and for local municipal streets only, the installation and maintenance of regulatory and street name signs, warning signs, construction warning signs, markings and barricades, pavement markings, traffic maintenance and traffic calming devices, all as may be specifically provided in the Agreement and subject to performing appropriate traffic engineering studies if required by such Agreement. The Department shall, however, retain exclusive jurisdiction over the permanent closure of access to any road or street. It shall be unlawful for any person, firm, corporation, or other legal entity, including municipal corporations, to change, modify, install, remove, damage, deface or destroy any traffic control device, unless authorized to do so by the traffic and transportation department, or by an Intergovernmental Agency Agreement.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-97. Limitations on jurisdiction over parking, parking meters</catch_line>
<text>
The Department shall not have any jurisdiction, power or authority in respect to offstreet parking in any municipality, unless requested to assume jurisdiction thereof by appropriate resolution adopted by the governing body of the municipality. The Department shall have exclusive jurisdiction in respect to the installation, location and regulation of parking meters only within the unincorporated areas of the County. The Department shall have exclusive jurisdiction over the installation, location and regulation of parking meters and parking within the boundaries of any municipality only in respect to public roads designated as arterial streets by the Traffic Director and shown upon appropriate maps prepared by and signed by the Traffic Director and furnished to the municipalities affected thereby, unless requested to assume jurisdiction of parking meters and parking on other municipal streets by appropriate resolution adopted by the governing body of the municipality.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-97.1. Jurisdiction over street lighting limited to unincorporated areas</catch_line>
<text>
The installation and maintenance of street lighting devices and facilities within the boundaries of any municipality is hereby declared to constitute a municipal function, and shall be performed and accomplished by each municipality. The powers, duties and functions of the traffic and transportation department shall be limited to street lighting within the unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-98. Existing control devices declared effective until changed</catch_line>
<text>
All traffic control devices installed, existing, operated or in force and effect on September 16, 1960, shall remain in full force and effect and shall be observed, complied with and obeyed, until modified, changed or removed by the Traffic and Transportation Department.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-98.1. Director designated head; organization; administration; personnel</catch_line>
<text>
The head of this Department shall be the direction of the Traffic and Transportation Department, who shall be appointed by and serve at the will of the County Manager. The organization and operating procedures of the Department shall be prescribed by administrative orders and regulations of the County Manager. The County Manager shall appoint such employees and other personnel as may be necessary to efficiently operate the department, except that personnel within the classified service shall be employed in accordance with controlling civil service rules and regulations. The salaries and compensation, except for employees within the classified service, shall be fixed and established by resolution adopted by the County Commission upon recommendation of the County Manager. All transfers of municipal employees and municipal equipment, property, material and supplies shall be accomplished in accordance with the controlling provisions of the charter, subject to budget limitations, and in accordance with policies adopted by the County Commission.
</text>
The head of this Department shall be the direction of the Traffic and Transportation Department, who shall be appointed by and serve at the will of the County Manager. The organization and operating procedures of the Department shall be prescribed by administrative orders and regulations of the County Manager. The County Manager shall appoint such employees and other personnel as may be necessary to efficiently operate the department, except that personnel within the classified service shall be employed in accordance with controlling civil service rules and regulations. The salaries and compensation, except for employees within the classified service, shall be fixed and established by resolution adopted by the County Commission upon recommendation of the County Manager. All transfers of municipal employees and municipal equipment, property, material and supplies shall be accomplished in accordance with the controlling provisions of the charter, subject to budget limitations, and in accordance with policies adopted by the County Commission.
<catch_line>Sec. 2-98.2. Violations; signs must be legible; enforcement by municipal police; jurisdiction of metropolitan court</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful for any person to violate, ignore, or fail to observe or obey any traffic-control device, sign, marking or traffic regulation provided for herein, provided that no provisions of this article for which signs or markings are required shall be enforced against an alleged violator, if at the time and place of the alleged violation an official sign or marking was not sufficiently legible to be seen by an ordinarily observant person. It shall be the duty of all municipal police officers to enforce the provisions of this article, applicable to traffic-control devices, signs and markings, within the municipality wherein they are employed, and all violations thereof shall be prosecuted in the metropolitan court.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-98.3. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 68-70, § 1, enacted Nov. 19, 1968, repealed former § 2-98.3 which derived from Ord. No. 62-31, § 3, enacted July 17, 1962, which transferred the functions of the Miami-Dade County Traffic and Transportation Department to the Public Works Department as a branch thereof.

</EditorsNote>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (24) ---
Editor's note— Prior to the reinclusion of Ord. No. 60-25 as Art. XIII, former Art XIII, relative to the Traffic and Transportation Department had derived from Ord. No. 57-28, §§ 20.01—20.05, enacted Dec. 10, 1957. Provisions relative to nuisance abatement which were previously designated as Art. XIII, §§ 2-95—2-98.3 have been redesignated as Art. XIIIA, §§ 2-98.4—2-98.10 hereof. (Back)
Cross reference— Transportation master plan adopted, § 2-115.4; traffic and motor vehicles, Ch. 30. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
