<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XLI._MIAMI-DADE_COUNTY_TRAUMA_AD</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-391. Created; purpose</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created and established the Miami-Dade County Trauma Advisory Committee whose purpose shall be to advise the Board of County Commissioners on all matters pertaining to the provision of transportation and medical care to victims of trauma and to assist in the coordination of all efforts made by the public and private sectors to enhance the availability and quality of such care.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-392. Terms and conditions of membership</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Committee shall be composed of twenty-nine (29) voting members appointed to staggered two-year terms pursuant to resolution of the Board of County Commissioners. Two (2) members shall be active in organizations that support the interests of consumers; and two (2) members shall be appointed as governmental representatives from Monroe County, Florida, such appointments to be the Project Director of the Upper Keys Health Care Taxing District and the Director of the Public Safety Division of Monroe County. Additionally, the Public Health Trust Trauma Committee and the Miami-Dade Fire Board shall each appoint one nonvoting ex officio member to the Miami-Dade County Trauma Advisory Committee. Each member shall serve a two-year term; provided, however, that of the initial Committee members, twelve (12) members shall be appointed for one-year terms. No member of the Committee shall be permitted to serve more than three (3) consecutive and complete terms. Section 2-11.38.2 of the Miami-Dade County Code shall govern terms of membership on the Committee.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Prior to the annual expiration date of members' terms, the County Manager shall submit to the Board of County Commissioners a recommended list of individuals to serve on the Committee, which said list may be augmented by individual County Commissioners. This list shall be in compliance with the requirements of Sections 2-11.38 and 2-11.38.1 of the Miami-Dade County. The list shall be broad-based and shall include a representative selection of individuals who have demonstrated familiarity with and interest in issues relating to the provision of trauma care. Each individual on the list shall have a reputation for integrity and service to the citizens of Miami-Dade County. In the event that the Board does not approve a sufficient number of recommendations from the list to fill available positions on the Committee, the County Manager shall provide the Board with additional recommendations until such time as all the available positions are filled. All vacancies occurring on the Committee shall be filled in the same manner either at the time of the annual appointment process or at a time specifically set by the Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Any member of the Committee who fails to meet the requirements of Section 2-11.38 or 2-11.39 of the Miami-Dade County Code shall immediately forfeit membership on the Committee, unless said requirements are waived as provided. Any member of the Committee may be removed from office by two-thirds vote of the entire membership of the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Members of the Committee shall serve without compensation. The Board of County Commissioners may provide funds for appropriate and necessary expenses incurred by the Committee or any of its members in the performance of Committee functions; provided, however, that no such funds will be expended without prior approval of the Board.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 88-84, § 2, 9-6-88; Ord. No. 89-14, § 1, 3-7-89; Ord. No. 90-75, § 1, 7-24-90; Ord. No. 91-86, § 1, 7-23-91)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-393. Organization; staff support</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Committee shall select one of its members as Chairman and shall adopt a schedule of regular meetings. A majority of the members of the Committee shall constitute a quorum. No recommendations shall be forwarded nor action taken by the Committee unless first approved by a majority of a quorum attending a regularly scheduled or specially called meeting of the Committee. Special meetings of the Committee may be called by the Chairman and otherwise shall be called upon the written request of five (5) Committee members. All meetings of the Committee shall be public and written minutes shall be maintained.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The County Manager shall designate and make available staff support through the County Manager's office for the purpose of assisting the Committee in the fulfillment of its stated function.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 88-84, § 3, 9-6-88)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-394. Functions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Committee, in conjunction with the County Manager's office, shall advise the Board of County Commissioners and shall make recommendations with respect to establishment and implementation of Miami-Dade County's overall plans for the care of victims of trauma. The Committee's recommendations shall be in the areas of:
<section prefix = "1">
Coordination with all public and private entities and organizations which are concerned with provision of trauma care;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Formulation of legislative, programmatic and funding agendas needed to address present and future trauma care needs of the community;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Establishment of suggested administrative and medical policies and protocols to enhance the efficiency and quality of trauma care;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Overseeing the development of the State mandated trauma medical services plan;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Performance of any other advisory function assigned to the Committee by the Board.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Committee is advisory only and shall not have the power or authority to commit Miami-Dade County or any of its agencies to any policies, to incur any financial obligation or to create any liability, contractual or otherwise, on the part of the County or any of its agencies.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Chairman, or his designee, shall present to the Board of County Commissioners on an annual basis a written report describing the Committee's activities. The Chairman, or his designee, may also appear as needed before the Board to present any matters pertinent to the Committee's concerns.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 88-84, § 4, 9-6-88)</history>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (65) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 88-84, adopted Sept. 6, 1988, amended the Code, but did not specify the manner of codification. At the discretion of the editor, §§ 1—4 of said Ord. No. 88-84 have been included herein as Art. XLI, §§ 2-391—2-394. (Back)
Cross reference— Ambulances and medical transportation vehicles, Ch. 4. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
