<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXXII._AVIATION_DEPARTMENT</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-278. Department established; general responsibilities</catch_line>
<text>
An Aviation Department is hereby established, which shall be responsible for the administration of all projects of the Board of County Commissioners which have been or will be established pursuant to Chapter 71-249, Laws of Florida, and its predecessor enactments, excepting those projects which the County Manager may, by appropriate administrative order, transfer to other departments of Miami-Dade County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-279. Appointment, term, qualifications of Aviation Director</catch_line>
<text>
The head of the Aviation Department is the Aviation Director who shall be appointed by the Manager and shall serve at the Manager's will. The Aviation Director shall have had training and experience in airport operations.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-280. Duties of Director</catch_line>
<text>
The Director, as executive head of the Department, shall under the supervision of the Manager direct all its administrative, operational and technical activities. In addition to the duties imposed on him elsewhere in this law, it shall be his duty to carry out whatever additional functions the County Manager assigns to him.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-281. Department organization and operating procedures</catch_line>
<text>
The organization and operating procedures of the Department shall be prescribed in administrative orders and regulations of the Manager. The Manager is hereby authorized to transfer all or any part of the duties of the Aviation Department to such other Departments of Miami-Dade County as he deems proper, by appropriate administrative order. Should he deem it proper, the County Manager is hereby authorized to transfer all or any part of the duties of any other department of Miami-Dade County to the Aviation Department, by appropriate administrative order. All transferred duties shall be compatible with the other duties of the department or departments affected by any such transfer.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-282. Appointment, compensation of personnel</catch_line>
<text>
The Manager shall appoint such employees and other personnel as may be necessary to operate the Department. The salaries and compensation of all personnel, except employees within the classified service, shall be fixed by the County Commission upon recommendation of the Manager.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-283. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Section 2-283, relating to officers and employees of the Port Authority as of February 6, 1973, has been deleted as obsolete. The section was derived from Ord. No. 73-8, § 1, adopted Feb. 6, 1973.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-284. Effect upon Port Authority trust agreement</catch_line>
<text>
Any functions imposed on the Chairman and the Director of the Miami-Dade County Port Authority by the trust agreement dated as of October 1, 1954, as amended, by and between said authority and the Chase Manhattan Bank (now The Chase Manhattan Bank (National Association)), as trustee and the First National Bank of Miami, as co-trustee, securing bonds of the County of Miami-Dade issued thereunder and by any and all resolutions securing bonds of the County of Miami-Dade issued by the Board of Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, acting as Miami-Dade County Port Authority, shall be performed by the Mayor and the County Manager, or his designee, respectively, of said County. Nothing contained in this article shall impair in any way the covenants and agreements made by the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, acting as Miami-Dade County Port Authority, in said trust agreement and said resolutions with the holders of the bonds of the County of Miami-Dade issued thereunder and the terms of such covenants and agreements shall prevail over any conflicting provisions of this article.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-285. County Manager's authority as to contracts for the Aviation Department</catch_line>
<text>
Notwithstanding any other provision of the Miami-Dade County Code to the contrary, the County Manager shall have the following authority:
<section prefix = "1">
As to any Aviation Department contract to which Sections 2-8.2, 2-8.2.3 or 2-8.2.4 are applicable, the County Manager may advertise any competitive contract in which appropriate contract measures as provided in Sections 2-8.2(3)(c), 2-8.2.3(3)(c), and 2-8.2.4(3)(c) have been specified; issue bid and proposal documents including addenda thereto; receive, open and review bids and proposals; issue notices to proceed after award; advertise, select committees for, and negotiate professional services agreements under Section 2-10.4 of the Code; issue amendments to any professional services agreement after award by the Board, including any professional services agreement that relates to a construction or project contract which has been increased in scope hereunder or by approval by the Board (subject, however, to any limitations on such authority as may be contained in the statutory and code provisions applicable to competitive selection of professional services); and perform all the foregoing for professional services agreements not subject to Section 2-10.4; provided however, that the authority in this subsection (1) is subject subsection (4) of this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The County Manager may provide in the bid specifications and contract documents that the contract time may be extended and that liquidated damages for failure to comply therewith may be waived before or after the specified date for completion of the contract;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The County Manager may negotiate and settle contractor claims, and issue change orders for additional work under contracts and amendments for professional services agreements; as to any specific contract or agreement, change orders or amendments thereto shall not exceed five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000.00) in cumulative dollar amount and shall not exceed fifteen (15) percent of the contract price in cumulative percentage amount; provided however, that the foregoing limitation shall not apply to any change order or amendment related to environmental remediation or health requirements, and the foregoing change orders and amendments shall require ratification by the Board; provided further, that the County Manager may reduce in any amount the scope and compensation payable under any contract and grant compensable and non-compensable time extensions thereunder.
(3.1)
The provisions of subsection (3) above notwithstanding, the County Manager shall have the authority to issue change orders or amendments provided that the cumulative effect of any such change orders and amendments to a specific contract or agreement does not exceed twenty (20) percent of the original amount of such contract or amendment, and further provided that the consulting engineer (under the existing trust indenture), the Aviation Director, and the Miami-Dade Aviation Consultants (DAC) concur in such action, that the change order or amendment is submitted to the County Commission for ratification within one hundred eighty (180) days. The County Manager shall report on a monthly basis to the Aviation Operations Committee of the County Commission on his actions taken in exercising the authority delegated to him hereunder. the County Manager shall not have delegated authority hereunder to issue any change order or amendment that is the result of design errors or omissions, and any such change order or amendment shall require prior County Commission approval.
Note—Ord. No. 95-210, amended § 2-285 by the addition of subsection (3.1) and § 3 of said ordinance provided sunset provisions which provided that the provisions of subsection (3.1) of Section 2-285 shall stand repealed twelve (12) months from its effective date (adopted Nov. 21, 1995, effective 10 days after the date of enactment.)
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
All actions taken by the County Manager under this section shall not require review by any Committee, but the County Manager shall obtain approval of the Board to execute any contract or agreement submitted under subsection (1);
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
For any lease with an airport tenant, the County Manager may authorize reimbursement for construction and other costs for the tenant's relocation of all or a portion of its premises, preparation of premises for occupancy, or making emergency repairs, provided the tenant obtains competitive bids for construction work, follows the procedures in Section 2-10.4 for obtaining professional services covered therein, complies with contract measures as approved by the County Manager, and complies with direction otherwise provided by the Aviation Department;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Subject to ratification of the Board, the County Manager may execute all standard form federal grant documents or state joint participation agreements, including acceptance of grant or joint participation commitments required to be imposed by federal or state law as a condition to the County's receiving grant or joint participation benefits;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
The County Manager may delegate authority for execution by the Aviation Director or his immediate designee of actions and authorizations permitted hereunder; and
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
For all Aviation Department contracts subject to Section 2-8.3 of the Code, the County Manager may waive the provisions of Section 2-8.3 to the extent provided in the solicitation documents.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
The County Manager shall prepare and submit to the County Commission for approval, an Administrative Order which shall establish procedures to expedite the review and approval of change orders, including total quality management techniques and concurrent review by departmental and consultant staff.

</section>
</text>
Notwithstanding any other provision of the Miami-Dade County Code to the contrary, the County Manager shall have the following authority:
<section prefix = "1">
As to any Aviation Department contract to which Sections 2-8.2, 2-8.2.3 or 2-8.2.4 are applicable, the County Manager may advertise any competitive contract in which appropriate contract measures as provided in Sections 2-8.2(3)(c), 2-8.2.3(3)(c), and 2-8.2.4(3)(c) have been specified; issue bid and proposal documents including addenda thereto; receive, open and review bids and proposals; issue notices to proceed after award; advertise, select committees for, and negotiate professional services agreements under Section 2-10.4 of the Code; issue amendments to any professional services agreement after award by the Board, including any professional services agreement that relates to a construction or project contract which has been increased in scope hereunder or by approval by the Board (subject, however, to any limitations on such authority as may be contained in the statutory and code provisions applicable to competitive selection of professional services); and perform all the foregoing for professional services agreements not subject to Section 2-10.4; provided however, that the authority in this subsection (1) is subject subsection (4) of this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The County Manager may provide in the bid specifications and contract documents that the contract time may be extended and that liquidated damages for failure to comply therewith may be waived before or after the specified date for completion of the contract;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The County Manager may negotiate and settle contractor claims, and issue change orders for additional work under contracts and amendments for professional services agreements; as to any specific contract or agreement, change orders or amendments thereto shall not exceed five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000.00) in cumulative dollar amount and shall not exceed fifteen (15) percent of the contract price in cumulative percentage amount; provided however, that the foregoing limitation shall not apply to any change order or amendment related to environmental remediation or health requirements, and the foregoing change orders and amendments shall require ratification by the Board; provided further, that the County Manager may reduce in any amount the scope and compensation payable under any contract and grant compensable and non-compensable time extensions thereunder.
(3.1)
The provisions of subsection (3) above notwithstanding, the County Manager shall have the authority to issue change orders or amendments provided that the cumulative effect of any such change orders and amendments to a specific contract or agreement does not exceed twenty (20) percent of the original amount of such contract or amendment, and further provided that the consulting engineer (under the existing trust indenture), the Aviation Director, and the Miami-Dade Aviation Consultants (DAC) concur in such action, that the change order or amendment is submitted to the County Commission for ratification within one hundred eighty (180) days. The County Manager shall report on a monthly basis to the Aviation Operations Committee of the County Commission on his actions taken in exercising the authority delegated to him hereunder. the County Manager shall not have delegated authority hereunder to issue any change order or amendment that is the result of design errors or omissions, and any such change order or amendment shall require prior County Commission approval.
Note—Ord. No. 95-210, amended § 2-285 by the addition of subsection (3.1) and § 3 of said ordinance provided sunset provisions which provided that the provisions of subsection (3.1) of Section 2-285 shall stand repealed twelve (12) months from its effective date (adopted Nov. 21, 1995, effective 10 days after the date of enactment.)
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
All actions taken by the County Manager under this section shall not require review by any Committee, but the County Manager shall obtain approval of the Board to execute any contract or agreement submitted under subsection (1);
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
For any lease with an airport tenant, the County Manager may authorize reimbursement for construction and other costs for the tenant's relocation of all or a portion of its premises, preparation of premises for occupancy, or making emergency repairs, provided the tenant obtains competitive bids for construction work, follows the procedures in Section 2-10.4 for obtaining professional services covered therein, complies with contract measures as approved by the County Manager, and complies with direction otherwise provided by the Aviation Department;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Subject to ratification of the Board, the County Manager may execute all standard form federal grant documents or state joint participation agreements, including acceptance of grant or joint participation commitments required to be imposed by federal or state law as a condition to the County's receiving grant or joint participation benefits;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
The County Manager may delegate authority for execution by the Aviation Director or his immediate designee of actions and authorizations permitted hereunder; and
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
For all Aviation Department contracts subject to Section 2-8.3 of the Code, the County Manager may waive the provisions of Section 2-8.3 to the extent provided in the solicitation documents.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
The County Manager shall prepare and submit to the County Commission for approval, an Administrative Order which shall establish procedures to expedite the review and approval of change orders, including total quality management techniques and concurrent review by departmental and consultant staff.

</section>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-285.1. Mayor's authority as to contracts relating to the North Terminal Development Project at Miami International Airport</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
With respect to contracts assigned to Miami-Dade County pursuant to Resolution R-735-05, or other contracts previously procured by American Airlines and previously assumed by Miami-Dade County via action of the Board of County Commissioners, or contracts to finish work begun but left incomplete as of August 1, 2005, or contracts related to the construction, design, or construction management of the North Terminal Development which were awarded by the Board of County Commissioners prior to May 1, 2008, and notwithstanding and prevailing over any other provision of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida to the contrary, the Mayor and the Airport Director, shall have the authority to: extend the contract time and waive liquidated damages for failure to comply therewith before the specified date for completion of the contract provided good cause exists and the contract provides that after the expiration of the contract time the County may extend the contract time or waive liquidated damages; and may otherwise modify the contract terms, may increase or reduce in any amount the scope and compensation payable under any contract, and may grant compensable and non-compensable time extensions. Additionally, to the extent that a contract listed above has expired, and such contract was competitively procured and contains no minority goals or measures, the County Mayor, and the Airport Director, may recommend to the Board of County Commissioners that a contract be re-awarded to the firm holding such expired contract, and such request will be heard by the full Board of County Commissioners without need for prior Committee Approval. The authority delegated in this section is intended to be supplemental to, and shall not limit, authority otherwise granted to the Mayor, County Manager, or Airport Director by ordinance or by administrative order.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The authority in this Subsection is subject to the following limitations:
<section prefix = "a">
Any amendment in excess of ten million dollars in value shall be subject to the prior approval of the Board of County Commissioners, but shall not require prior committee approval.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Any exercise of authority to this section shall be subject to the budget approved by the Board for the North Terminal Development Project as a whole.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Any exercise of authority pursuant to this Section shall require ratification by the Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Nothing in this section shall affect the requirements of State law for the competitive purchase of goods and services, including those related to public construction work and those contained in the Consultants Competitive Negotiation Act.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Any exercise of authority pursuant to this section shall be in conformity with the policies and procedures which may be established by implementing order to be approved by this Board. The implementing order shall contain guidelines for the exercise of the authority conferred under this section, and shall specifically provide for the application of County policies with respect to contracting, including but not limited to procedures for bid protests, inclusion of small business measures, community business enterprises, community small business enterprises, community workforce, and responsible wages. The provision of the Code relative to such programs shall not be applicable to the contracts specified herein except as specifically provided for in the implementing order.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Nothing in this section shall affect the process for settlement of construction disputes relating to the North Terminal Development approved by separate resolution of the Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
The provisions of this Ordinance shall not apply except to those contracts listed in Resolution R-735-05, or other contracts previously procured by American Airlines and previously assumed by Miami-Dade County via action of the Board of County Commissioners, or contracts to finish work begun but left incomplete as of August 1, 2005, or contracts related to the construction, design, or construction management of the North Terminal Development which were awarded by the Board of County Commissioners prior to May 1, 2008.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 08-87, § 1, 7-1-09)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-286. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 95-127, adopted July 11, 1995 and Ord. No. 95-134, adopted July 25, 1995, which enacted Section 2-286 provided that said section would expire after a term of three years. Former Section 2-286 pertained to the county manager's authority as to tenant or user projects or program of projects.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-286.1. County Manager's authority for retail activities at Miami International Airport</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The County Manager shall implement retail activities (which shall be defined as including retail, food, and beverage products and services) at Miami International Airport envisioned in the Retail Concessions Master Plan, dated May 1995, as it may be administratively amended from time to time. Notwithstanding any other provisions of the Code, and notwithstanding any prior resolution or administrative order approved by the Board, including, but not limited to, Resolutions No. R. 1586-72 and 1587-72, and Administrative Orders No. 3-2, 3-4, and 3-16, the provisions of which resolutions and administrative orders are hereby waived, the County Manager shall have the following authority as to retail activities at the Airport:
<section prefix = "1">
Maintain close working relationships with the signatory air carriers at the Airport to obtain their input into the retail activities at the Airport, and execute amendments to airline agreements so as to permit negotiation of concessions at the Airport;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Issue invitations for bids, requests for qualifications, and requests for proposals for concessions, activities, services or goods related to retail activities at the Airport, provided, however, that to the extent permitted by state law and by contract, such invitations and requests in the discretion of the County Manager may be limited to retail or suppliers, including a single retailer or supplier, whom the County Manager determines will best meet the goals of the Retail Concessions Master Plan;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Enter into negotiations with a single retail concession provider, or competitive negotiations with two (2) or more retail concession providers, whom the County Manager in his discretion determines will best meet the goals of the Retail Concessions Master Plan. If the proposed concession will be exclusive, the County Manager is authorized to comply with all requirements of Section 125.012(17), Florida Statutes;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Negotiate and settle all claims arising out of the foregoing leases and concession agreements;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
To the extent permitted by ordinance and other law, establish Disadvantaged Business Enterprise goals and set asides for concessions;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
For any agreement with a concessionaire or tenant, authorize reimbursement or rental credit for construction and other costs for relocation of all or a portion of its premises, preparation of its premises for occupancy, and making changes or emergency repairs to the premises in any manner necessary or reasonably required to meet the requirements of the retail activities; provided that the concessionaire or tenant shall comply with the County's competitive bidding requirements, the essential requirements of Section 2-10.4, DBE contract measures, and any other directions provided by the County Manager;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
For all the foregoing leases and concession agreements subject to Section 2-8.3 of the Code, waive the provisions of Section 2-8.3 to the extent provided in the solicitation documents;
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Extend any concession, management agreement or agreement related to the retail activities on a month-to-month basis for so long as may be needed to avoid disruption of concession services to passengers, and
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Delegate authority for execution of actions or authorizations permitted hereunder to the Aviation Director or his or her designee.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The County Manager may exempt from the County's classified service such Aviation Department employees as determined by the County Manager to be necessary or reasonably required for the efficient management or administration of retail activities at the Airport.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
From the day on which any advertisement of a competitive contract is placed by the County Manager until the day the County Manager's notice of intent is filed with the Clerk, neither the bidder nor any one on its behalf shall have any contact with the County Manager, any County Commissioner, or any member of their staff, except for any person specifically designated by the County Manager in the contract documents or otherwise, or except in response to any inquiry or contact initiated by the County Manager.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 95-138, § 1, 7-25-95; Ord. No. 97-157, § 1, 9-23-97)</history>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 95-138, § 1, adopted July 25, 1995, amended the Code by the addition of § 2-286, which provisions have been redesignated at the discretion of the editor as § 2-286.1
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-287—2-290. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (53) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 73-8, § 1, adopted Feb. 6, 1973, amended Ch. 2 of this Code by adding Art. XXXII, §§ 2-278—2-284. (Back)
Annotation—AO 9-1 (Back)
Cross reference— Aviation Department rules and regulations, Ch. 25. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
