<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXIX._MIAMI-DADE_COUNTY_HEALTH_F</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-260. Declaration of need</catch_line>
<text>
The Board of County Commissioners hereby finds and declares that there is a need for a Miami-Dade County Health Facilities Authority to function in Miami-Dade County so as to assist in the development and maintenance of the health facilities of Miami-Dade County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-261. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
The following terms, whenever used in this article, shall have the following meanings unless a different meaning clearly appears from the context:
<section prefix = "a">
Authority means the Miami-Dade County Health Facilities Authority.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Bonds or revenue bonds means revenue bonds of the Authority issued under the provisions of this article, including revenue refunding bonds, notwithstanding that the same may be secured by mortgage or the full faith and credit of a health facility.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Certificate of need means a written advisory statement issued by the [State] Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services, having as its basis a written advisory statement issued by an areawide council and, where there is no council, by the [State] Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services, evidencing community need for a new, converted, expanded, or otherwise significantly modified health facility.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Enabling act means Part III, Chapter 154, Florida Statutes, as maybe amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Health facility means any private corporation organized not for profit and authorized by law to provide hospital, adult congregate living or nursing home care services in accordance with Florida law.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Project means any structure, facility, machinery, equipment or other property suitable for use by a health facility in connection with its operations or proposed operations, including without limitation, real property therefor; a clinic, computer facility, dining hall, firefighting facility, fire prevention facility, food service and preparation facility, health-care facility, long-term care facility, hospital, interns' residence, laboratory, laundry, maintenance facility, nurses' residence, nursing home, nursing school, office, parking area, pharmacy, recreational facility, research facility, storage facility, utility, or X-ray facility, or any combination of the foregoing; and other structures or facilities related thereto or required or useful for health-care purposes, the conducting of research, or the operation of a health facility, including facilities or structures essential or convenient for the orderly conduct of such health facility and other similar items necessary or convenient for the operation of a particular facility or structure in the manner for which its use is intended. "Project" shall not include such items as fuel, supplies, or other items which are customarily deemed to result in a current operating charge.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Real property includes all lands, including buildings, structures, improvements, and fixtures thereon; any property of any nature appurtenant thereto or used in connection therewith; and every estate, interest, and right, legal or equitable, therein including any such interest for a term of years.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-262. Creation, exercise of authority deemed public function; membership, etc.; organization, meetings</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Creation. The Date County Health Facilities Authority is hereby created and established and, in accordance with Section 154.207, Florida Statutes, is constituted a public instrumentality. The exercise by said Authority of the powers conferred by Section 154.201 to 154.246, inclusive, Florida Statutes, shall be deemed and held to be the performance of an essential public function.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Membership, etc. The Authority shall consist of five (5) persons who are residents of Miami-Dade County, appointed by the Board of County Commissioners.
<section prefix = "1">
Term of office, filling vacancies; reappointment; removal. Of the members first appointed, one (1) shall serve for one (1) year, one (1) for two (2) years, one (1) for three (3) years, and two (2) for four (4) years, in each case until his successor is appointed and has qualified. Thereafter the Board shall appoint, for terms of four (4) years each, a member or members to succeed those whose terms expire. The Board shall fill any vacancy for an unexpired term. A member of the Authority shall be eligible for reappointment. Any member of the Authority may be removed by the Board for misfeasance, malfeasance, or willful neglect of duty.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Oath; compensation; ethical considerations. Each member of the Authority, before entering upon his duties, shall take and subscribe the oath or affirmation required by the State Constitution. A record of each oath shall be filed in the Department of State and with the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners. The members of the Authority shall receive no compensation for the performance of their duties hereunder, but each member shall be paid necessary expenses incurred while engaged in the performance of such duties. Service as a member of the Authority by a trustee, director, officer, or employee of a health facility shall not, in and of itself, constitute a conflict of interest. However, any member of the Authority who is employed by, or receives income from, a health facility under consideration by the Authority shall not vote on any matter related to such facility. Members shall comply with the Miami-Dade County financial disclosure requirements.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Organization; meetings. The Authority, at its initial meeting, and annually thereafter, shall elect one (1) of its members as Chairman and one (1) as Vice-Chairman. Three (3) members of the Authority shall constitute a quorum, and the affirmative vote of a majority of the members present at a meeting of the Authority shall be necessary for any action taken by the Authority. No vacancy in the membership of the Authority shall impair the right of a quorum to exercise all the rights to perform all the duties of the Authority. The initial meeting of said Authority shall be at 9:00 a.m., on November 13, 1979, at 1 S.E. 3rd Avenue, City of Miami, in Miami-Dade County, Florida. If fewer than three (3) members are present at said meeting, the members who are present may adjourn the meeting from time to time until at least three (3) members shall be present.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 79-92, § 3, 10-16-79)</history>
Note—See editor's footnote to this Art. XXIX of Ch. 2
<catch_line>Sec. 2-263. Powers and duties</catch_line>
<text>
The Miami-Dade County Health Facilities Authority shall have all the powers conferred upon it by the enabling act, Part III of Chapter 154, Sections 154.201 through 154.245, Florida Statutes, incorporated herein by reference, as the same shall be amended from time to time, and by other provisions of law, including, but not limited to, Part I of Chapter 163, Sections 163.01 through 163.04, Florida Statutes, as the same shall be amended from time to time, which powers shall include, but are not limited to, the following:
<section prefix = "1">
To adopt an official seal and alter the same at its pleasure;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To maintain an office at such place or places in Miami-Dade County as it may designate;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
To sue and be sued in its own name and to plead, and be impleaded;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
To acquire by purchase, lease, gift, or otherwise, or to obtain options for the acquisition of, any property, real or personal, improved or unimproved, for the acquisition, construction, operation or maintenance of any project;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
To construct, acquire, own, lease, repair, maintain, extend, expand, improve, rehabilitate, renovate, furnish and equip projects and to pay all or any part of the costs thereof from the proceeds of bonds of the Authority or from any contribution, gift, or donation or other funds made available to the Authority for such purpose;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
To make and execute agreements of lease, contracts, deeds, mortgages, notes and other instruments necessary or convenient in the exercise of the powers and functions conferred upon the Authority by this article;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
To sell, lease, exchange, mortgage, transfer, or otherwise dispose of, or to grant options for any such purposes with respect to any project, or any real or personal property or interest therein;
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
To pledge or assign any money, rents, charges, fees or other revenues and any proceeds derived from sales of property, insurance, or condemnation awards;
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
To fix, charge and collect rents, fees and charges for the use of any project;
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
To issue bonds for the purpose of providing funds to pay all or any part of the cost of any project and to issue refunding bonds;
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
To employ consulting engineers, architects, surveyors, attorneys, accountants, financial experts, Executive Director, and such other employees and agents as may be necessary in its judgment and to fix their compensation;
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
To acquire existing projects and to reimburse any health facility for the cost of such project in accordance with an agreement between the Authority and the health facility; however, no such reimbursement shall exceed the total cost of the project as determined by the health facility and approved by the Authority;
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
To acquire existing projects and to refund outstanding obligations, mortgages, or advances issued, made or given by a health facility for the cost of such projects;
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
To charge to, and equitably apportion among, health facilities approved for loans, its administrative costs and expenses incurred in the exercise of the powers and duties conferred by this article;
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
To mortgage any project and the site thereof for the benefit of the holders of the bonds issued to finance such project;
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
To issue negotiable revenue bonds of the Authority for the purpose of paying all or any part of the cost of any project or projects for which a certificate of need has been obtained, or for the purpose of paying all or any part of the cost of acquiring existing or completed health facility projects. To issue negotiable bond anticipation notes and to renew the same from time to time. The maximum maturity of any anticipation note, including renewals thereof, shall not exceed five (5) years from the date of issue of the original note. The revenue bonds and notes of every issue authorized and any anticipation notes issued pursuant to this subsection shall be in accordance with the terms and provisions outlined in Section 154.219, Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
To keep a record of all its proceedings and be custodian of all books, documents and papers filed with it and of its minute book or journal and official seal. The Authority shall cause copies to be made of all its minutes and other records and documents and shall give certificates under its official seal to the effect that such copies are true copies, and all persons dealing with said Authority may rely upon such certificates.
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
To make a report to the Board of County Commissioners, within the first ninety (90) days of each calendar year, of the authority's activities for the preceding calendar year. Each such report shall set forth a complete operating and financial statement covering its operations during the year.
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
To do all things necessary to carry out the above powers and purposes of the Miami-Dade County Health Facilities Authority.

The County Commission may, at its discretion, amend the foregoing powers and duties of the Authority as long as the amended powers and duties do not impair the contractual obligations to the holders of any bonds theretofore issued by the Authority and then outstanding.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-263.1. Administrative procedures for project evaluation</catch_line>
<text>
The Authority shall promulgate written administrative procedures, subject to final approval by the County Commission, that will be uniformly used to evaluate proposed projects. These administrative procedures shall include, but not be limited to, the following:
<section prefix = "1">
Certificate of need; review by Health Council of South Florida, Inc. The Authority shall require a certificate of need for all new project applications as prescribed by Section 154.245, Florida Statutes, as said status may be amended from time to time, and in addition request a review and comment from the Health Council of South Florida, Inc., prior to acting on any applications for the issuance of revenue bonds for refinancing or refunding purposes. Comments received from the Health Council of South Florida, Inc., within thirty (30) days of request shall be considered by the Authority in making its decision on the application. If such comment has not been received thirty (30) days from the date of a formal written request, the Authority may act as though the application was favorably considered by the Health Council of South Florida, Inc.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
[Reserved]
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Service priorities. The guidelines shall include a priority for those institutions who currently provide or present a plan to provide services including, but not limited to:
<section prefix = "a">
Services rendered to patients eligible for all or partial County support in County-sponsored institutions; and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Uncompensated services rendered under County/public health trust decentralization programs.
The services referred to in this paragraph shall be in addition to services mandated under the Hill-Burton program or other State or federally mandated programs.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Applicant expenses; review by County Manager or his designee. The applicant shall bear all costs and expenses incurred incident to the preparation of its application. The Authority shall provide for the timely review of each project by the County Manager in such a way as to minimize the expenditure of funds by the applicant should the review prove to be unfavorable. If the initial review is favorable, the applicant shall proceed with finalizing the bond issue for final approval by the Commission.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-263.2. Approval of bonds and notes by County Commission</catch_line>
<text>
The sale of the bonds and notes authorized to be issued by the Authority pursuant to this article shall be subject to the approval of the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida, prior to the validation requirements of subsection 2-263.3(d).
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-263.3. Revenue bonds generally</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Applicability of Uniform Commercial Code. All bonds issued under the provisions of this article shall have, and are hereby declared to have, all the qualities and incidents, including negotiability, of investment securities under the Uniform Commercial Code, but on provision of such code respecting the filing of a financing statement to perfect a security interest shall be deemed necessary for, or applicable to, any security interest created in connection with the issuance of any such bonds.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Nonliability of County, State. All revenue bonds issued under the provisions of this article shall not be deemed to constitute a debt, liability or obligation of Miami-Dade County or the State or any political subdivision thereof, or a pledge of the faith and credit of Miami-Dade County or the State or any political subdivision thereof, but shall be payable solely from the revenues provided therefor. All such revenue bonds shall contain on the face thereof a statement to the effect that the Authority shall not be obligated to pay the same or the interest thereon except from the revenues of the project or the portion thereof for which they are issued and that neither the faith and credit nor the taxing power of Miami-Dade County or of the State or of any political subdivision thereof is pledged to the payment of the principal of or the interest on such bonds. The issuance of revenue bonds under the provisions of this article shall not directly, indirectly, or contingently obligate Miami-Dade County or the State or any political subdivision thereof to levy or to pledge any form of taxation whatever therefor or to make any appropriation for their payment.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Investment in, use as security by public officers, fiduciaries, etc. Bonds issued by the Authority under the provisions of this article are hereby made securities in which all public officers and public bodies of the State and its political subdivisions and all insurance companies, trust companies, banking associations, investment companies, executors, administrators, trustees, and other fiduciaries may properly and legally invest funds, including capital in their control or belonging to them. Such bonds are hereby made securities which may properly and legally be deposited with and received by any State or municipal officer or any agency or political subdivision of the State for any purpose for which the deposit of bonds or obligations of the State is now or may hereinafter be authorized by law.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Validation. Bonds issued under the provisions of this article shall be validated in the manner prescribed by Chapter 75, Florida Statutes.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 79-92, § 5(A), (B), (D), (E), 10-16-79)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-263.4. Refunding revenue bonds</catch_line>
<text>
The Authority is hereby authorized to provide for the issuance of revenue bonds for the purpose of refunding any of its revenue bonds then outstanding, including the payment of any redemption premium thereon and any interest accrued or to accrue to the earliest or subsequent date of redemption, purchase, or maturity of such revenue bonds. The proceeds of any such revenue bonds issued for the purpose of refunding outstanding revenue bonds may, in the discretion of the Authority, be applied to the purchase or retirement at maturity or redemption of such outstanding revenue bonds either on their earliest or any subsequent redemption date, or upon the purchase or at the maturity thereof, and may, pending such application, be placed in escrow to be applied to such purchase or retirement at maturity or redemption on such date as may be determined by the Authority. Any such escrowed proceeds, pending such use, may be invested and reinvested in direct obligations of the United States, in any obligations of which the principal and interest are unconditionally guaranteed by the United States, in certificates of deposit or time deposits secured by direct obligations of the United States, or in any obligations of which the principal and interest are unconditionally guaranteed by the United States, maturing at such time or times as shall be appropriate to assure the prompt payment, as to principal, interest, and redemption premium, if any, of the outstanding revenue bonds to be so refunded. The interest, income, and profits, if any, earned or realized on any such investment may also be applied to the payment of the outstanding revenue bonds to be so refunded. After the terms of the escrow have been fully satisfied and carried out, any balance of such proceeds and interest, income, and profits, if any, earned or realized on the investments thereof may be returned to the Authority for use by it in any lawful manner. All such revenue bonds issued for the purposes of refunding shall be subject to the provisions of this article in the same manner and to the same extent as other revenue bonds issued pursuant to this article.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-263.5. Charging, payment of expenses</catch_line>
<text>
The Authority shall charge each project for all the Authority's administrative costs and expenses incurred in the exercise of the powers and duties conferred by this article. No Miami-Dade County funds from any source shall be utilized by the Authority without prior approval of the Board of County Commissioners.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-263.6. Tax exemption; limitations on exemptions</catch_line>
<text>
The exercise of the powers granted by this article will be in all respects for the benefit of the people of this County, for the increase of their commerce, welfare and prosperity, and for the improvement of their health and living conditions. Since the operation and maintenance of a project by a health facility will constitute the performance of an essential public function, neither the Authority nor a hospital institution shall be required to pay any taxes or assessments upon or with respect to a project or any property acquired by the Authority under the provisions of this article or upon the income therefrom, and any bonds issued under the provisions of this article, their transfer, and the income therefrom, including any profit made on the sale thereof, shall at all times be free from taxation of every kind by the State, Miami-Dade County, and municipalities and other political subdivisions in the State, except that such income shall be subject to the tax imposed pursuant to the provisions of Chapter 220, Florida Statutes. Nothing in this section shall be construed as exempting from taxation or assessments the leasehold interest of any health facility organized for profit. If any project or any part thereof shall be occupied or operated by any health facility organized for profit pursuant to any contract or lease with the Authority, the property interest created by such contract or lease shall be subject to taxation to the same extent as other privately owned property.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-263.7. Reports</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Value of County-supported services at County institutions, uncompensated services. The Authority shall include the value of the services described in paragraph 2-263.2(3) as a part of its annual report to the County Commission as specified in paragraph 2-263.1(18).
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Use of bond proceeds. Each health facility receiving proceeds from any bonds issued hereunder shall advise the Authority in writing, within the first ninety (90) days of each calendar year during which its bonds remain outstanding, of the manner in which its patients have benefited from the issuance of the bonds.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 79-92, § 6(D), (F), 10-16-79)</history>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (50) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 79-92, §§ 1—9, adopted Oct. 16, 1979, did not expressly amend this Code; hence, codification as Art. XXIX of Ch. 2, §§ 2-260—2-263.7, is at the discretion of the editor. Section 10 of Ord. No. 79-92 provides as follows: (Back)
"Section 10. Charter. (Back)
"The County Clerk of this Board shall send a certified copy of this ordinance to each of the above named members of said Authority as official notice of his appointment. This ordinance shall constitute the charter of said Authority and shall be effective on the tenth day after its enactment by this Board." (Back)
Cross reference— Public health department, § 2-74 et seq.; public health trust, Ch. 25A. (Back)
State Law reference— Health Facilities Authority Law, F.S. § 154.201 et seq. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
