<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XCVIII._MIAMI-DADE_COUNTY_YOUTH_</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1431. Creation and purpose</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created the Miami-Dade County Youth Crime Task Force. The purpose of this Task Force is to advise the Board of County Commissioners on matters related to youth crime, youth weapons crime and youth crime prevention.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1432. Membership</catch_line>
<text>
The Task Force shall consist of the following appointments:
<section prefix = "a">
Mayor of Miami-Dade County;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Two Members of the Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Assistant County Manager for Public Safety;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Representative from the Miami-Dade County Legislative Delegation;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Director of Miami-Dade Police Department;
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Coordinator, Neighborhood Resource Team, Miami-Dade Police Department;
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Chief of the City of Miami Police Department;
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Chief of Police for Miami-Dade Public Schools;
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Superintendent of Miami-Dade Public Schools;
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Chief of the Juvenile Division, State Attorney for Miami-Dade County;
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Chief of the Juvenile Division, Public Defender's Office of Miami-Dade County;
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Juvenile Court Judge, 11th Judicial Circuit;
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
Deputy Division Director of Operations, Department of Children and Families;
</section>
<section prefix = "n">
Senior Juvenile Justice Manager, Florida State Department of Juvenile Justice, District XI;
</section>
<section prefix = "o">
Director Delinquency Prevention Services, Miami-Dade County Department of Human Services;
</section>
<section prefix = "p">
Director of Miami-Dade Juvenile Assessment Center;
</section>
<section prefix = "q">
Director of the Children's Services Council;
</section>
<section prefix = "r">
Director of Metro-Miami Action Plan (MMAP);
</section>
<section prefix = "s">
The President of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), Florida State Conference Branch;
</section>
<section prefix = "t">
Up to eleven (11) members who work for or serve on the board of directors of an organization that works with youth and/or crime prevention recommended by the County Manager and appointed by the Board of County Commissioners;

The appointments listed in Section 2-1432(a) through (s) may be served by a designee. If the appointment is served by a designee that person serves in the full capacity of the appointment, with all its duties and responsibilities, and not as a proxy. The appointment of a designee by a Task Force member shall be in writing to the Clerk of the Board.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1433. Organization</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Officers. Members of the Task Force shall elect one (1) of its members as chairperson, one (1) of its members as vice-chairperson and any such other officers as the Task Force determines to be necessary and appropriate.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Meetings. The Task Force shall conduct at least four (4) meetings per annum. All meetings of the Task Force shall be public and written minutes shall be maintained. No recommendations shall be forwarded nor action taken by the Task Force unless first approved by a majority of a quorum attending a regularly scheduled meeting or specially called meeting of the Task Force.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Reserved.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Attendance. Attendance requirements for members shall be in accordance with Section 2-11.39, as amended, of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Special or Emergency Meeting. The chairperson or five (5) members of the Task Force upon written request to the chairperson may call for a special or emergency meeting.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Committee. The Task Force may appoint committees to accomplish its tasks. Members of a committee may consist of members of the Task Force and/or other persons with specialized knowledge that would benefit the committee.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Bylaws. The Task Force may create bylaws in order to operate and conduct its business.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Staff Support. The Task Force shall have assistance from staff designated by the county manager. The staff shall: maintain and keep the records of the Task Force; prepare, in cooperation with the chairperson, the agenda for each meeting; be responsible for the preparation of such reports, minutes, documents, resolutions or correspondence as the Task Force may direct; and generally administer the business and affairs of the Task Force, subject to budgetary limitations.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 02-131, § 3, 7-23-02)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1434. Powers and Duties</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Task Force shall have the following powers and duties:
<section prefix = "1">
To serve in an advisory capacity to the Board of County Commissioners with respect to matters of youth crime, youth weapons violence and youth crime prevention.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To study the problems of youth crime and youth weapons violence in Miami-Dade County and to analyze possible solutions to these problems with particular emphasis on studying crime prevention programs which have significantly reduced youth crime in other communities and cities.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
To develop an overall countywide plan for the prevention of youth crime and youth weapons violence in Miami-Dade County in cooperation with other planning agencies and entities.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
To submit a written report to the Board of County Commissioners with its countywide plan and recommendations to address youth crime and youth weapons violence.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
To recommend guidelines and criteria to be included in competitive solicitation processes for the allocation of youth crime prevention funding, review any and all proposals submitted through such competitive solicitation process and provide recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners or the Alliance for Human Services for the award of such youth crime prevention funding.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Task Force is advisory only and shall not have the power or authority to commit Miami-Dade County or any of its agencies or instrumentalities to any policies, to incur any financial obligation or to create any liability, contractual or otherwise, on behalf of Miami-Dade County or any of its agencies or instrumentalities.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 02-131, § 4, 7-23-02)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1435. Compensation</catch_line>
<text>
The members of the Task Force shall serve without compensation but shall be entitled to reimbursement for necessary expenses incurred in the discharge of their duties.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1436. Applicability of State and County laws</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Task Force shall be regulated by the Standards for Creation and Review of Boards Generally Ordinance (Sections 2-11.36 et. al. of the Code of Miami-Dade County), Chapter 286 of Florida Statutes (the "Sunshine Law") and Chapter 119 of Florida Statutes (the "Public Records Law"). However, members of the Youth Crime Task Force may sit on more than one (1) County advisory board, but no more than two (2) County advisory boards.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Methods of organization and conduct of business shall be governed by Mason's Manual of Legislative Procedure (1953 Edition).
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Task Force members shall be regulated by the State of Florida Code of Ethics for Public Officers and Employees and the Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics ordinance.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 02-131, § 6, 7-23-02)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1437. Section 2-11.37(c) waived for this article.</catch_line>
<text>
Section 2-11.37(c) of the Miami-Dade County Code which requires six (6) weeks between first reading and public hearing for consideration of an advisory board ordinance shall be waived for this article.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-1438—2-1440. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (107) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 02-131, §§ 1—7, adopted July 23, 2002, did not specifically amend the Code. Hence, its inclusion herein as article XCVIII, §§ 2-1431—2-1437, was at the discretion of the editor. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
