<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_CXVIII._OFFICE_OF_INTERGOVERNMEN</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1781. Creation</catch_line>
<text>
This Board hereby creates the Office of Intergovernmental Affairs ("Office").
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1782. Budget and Director</catch_line>
<text>
The Board shall provide the Office of Intergovernmental Affairs with a budget and staffing allowance. There shall be a Director, who shall head the Office of Intergovernmental Affairs and shall have the power to appoint, employ, and remove such assistants, employees and personnel as deemed necessary for the efficient and effective administration of the affairs of the Office. An appropriate salary and benefits package for the Director shall be recommended by the Director of the Employee Relations Department and subject to approval by the Mayor or designee and the Chair or designee. The approval or disapproval by the Chair or designee shall prevail in the event both the Mayor or designee and the Chair or designee do not approve or disapprove the recommendation. If the recommendation is not so approved, then the Director of the Employee Relations Department shall provide a new recommendation subject to approval process set forth above.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1783. Appointment of a Director</catch_line>
<text>
The Director of the Office of Intergovernmental Affairs shall be appointed by a majority vote of the full membership of the Board then in office, utilizing the selection process described in Section 2-1784.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1784. Director Selection Process</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
The Chair and the Board shall solicit and receive applications for the position of Office Director. The Board shall be provided with the names and background materials of all qualified candidates. By ballot determination, the full Board shall identify recommended candidates to interview (preferably no less than the top three (3)).
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Mayor or a designee appointed by the Mayor may interview applicants and provide written recommendations to the Board or, in the alternative the Mayor may join the Board at such time as the Board interviews the recommended candidates.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Board shall appoint the Director by a majority vote of the entire Board.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-219, § 4, 12-16-04)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1785. Minimum Qualifications of the Director</catch_line>
<text>
The Director shall have relevant experience working in the federal or state legislative process or representing either public or private entities at the federal or state level, or some combination of the above.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1786. Term of Office</catch_line>
<text>
The Director shall serve at the pleasure of the Board and may be removed from office with or without cause by a vote of two-thirds of the entire Board.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1787. Functions</catch_line>
<text>
The Office of the Intergovernmental Affairs shall perform the following functions within the scope of authority set forth in Section 2-1788 below:
<section prefix = "1">
Coordinate the County's intergovernmental relations at the federal, state, and local levels.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Manage the County's federal and state governmental representation and consulting services contracts and report issues relating to conflicts of interest as they pertain to contract lobbyists.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Prepare annual federal and state legislative packages pursuant to Section 2-1789 below.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Report to the Board on a timely basis and otherwise comply with the reporting requirements set forth in Section 2-1790 below.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Coordinate meetings and facilitate relationships between the Board and the Miami-Dade County state and federal legislative delegations no less than once each quarter pursuant to Resolution No. 1060-93.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
On a continuing basis, advise the Board, Mayor, County Manager, and County Departments of the filing, progress and amendment of bills, appropriations, and legislative reports and projects that may affect the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Raise, discuss and recommend any legislative action that may benefit the County given the current legislative trends and dynamics, including actions related to both substantive legislation and appropriations.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1788. Scope of Authority</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
The Office of Intergovernmental Affairs shall not initiate any funding request or legislation (including both bills and amendments) at the federal or state level that has not been approved by the Board in the federal or state legislative package, respectively, or by resolution. Notwithstanding, nothing contained herein shall limit the Office from responding to any issues that may arise over the course of the legislative process that affects revenues and cost shifts to the County or that affects the local home rule authority of the County. See Resolution No. 232-01.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
In the event it is not feasible to convene the Board to provide direction on a pending legislative issue, the Director shall consult with the Mayor or designee and the Chair or designee, with input from the County Manager and County Attorney, to provide direction on urgent legislative issues until such time as the Board meets and provides policy direction. The County Manager shall provide recommendations as to department budgetary and operational impacts to the Mayor and Chair or their designees in such circumstances. The policy direction of the Chair or designee will prevail in the event of a conflict between the Mayor and the Chair or their designees.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-219, § 8, 12-16-04)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1789. Federal and State Legislative Packages</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
The Office of Intergovernmental Affairs shall prepare federal and state legislative packages for the Board's consideration and approval. The Office shall prepare such packages in a timely manner based on legislative requests submitted by the Mayor, members of the Board, the County Manager, and County departments and instrumentalities.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Office shall prepare and submit to the Board for approval an annual timetable for preparation, consideration and approval of the federal and state legislative packages. Such timetable shall ensure that the Board has the ability to approve the packages a sufficient amount of time before appropriations and bill filing deadlines so the Office can seek legislative sponsors. The Office shall have a continuing obligation to advise the Board of changing legislative circumstances related to initiatives set forth in the federal and state legislative packages over the course of the legislative process. The Board shall have the continuing authority to amend and revise the federal and state legislative packages by resolution to add, revise or remove legislative policy directions.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-219, § 9, 12-16-04)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1790. Reporting</catch_line>
<text>
The Office shall communicate with the Board and be available to meet with the Board upon request during each legislative Board meeting during the Congressional session and while the Florida Legislature is in session and meeting in committee. The Office shall report to and meet with the Board during the remainder of the year on at least a monthly basis. The Office shall prepare and submit annual federal and state legislative reports to the Board in a timely manner identifying issues that passed or were considered affecting the County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1791. Relationship to Mayor, Board, County Manager and County Attorney</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
The Mayor shall be the official spokesperson on behalf of the County for federal and state legislative issues that have been adopted by resolution and/or included in the legislative packages approved by the Board. The Mayor shall submit all legislative requests to the Office of Intergovernmental Affairs for inclusion in the federal and state legislative packages pursuant to the timetable set forth in Section 2-1789 and shall respond to requests for information and direction from the Office on a timely basis.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Board shall provide policy direction to the Office of Intergovernmental Affairs on legislative issues. Members of the Board shall submit all legislative requests for inclusion in the federal and state legislative packages pursuant to the timetable set forth in Section 2-1789 and shall respond to requests for information and direction from the Office on a timely basis. No member of the Board shall be precluded from speaking and lobbying on behalf of the County in support of the federal or state legislative issues that have been adopted by Board resolution and/or included in the federal and state legislative packages approved by the Board. The Chair or a member of the Board designated by the Chair shall serve as liaison to the County Manager on behalf of the Board in monitoring the Office.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Notwithstanding that the Office shall report directly to the Board, the County Manager shall monitor and work closely with the Director of Intergovernmental Affairs to ensure that the policy direction of the Board is carried out. The County Manager's Office and all County departments shall respond to annual federal and state legislative requests to the Office pursuant to the timetable set forth in Section 2-1789. The County Manager and all County departments shall promptly respond to requests from the Office for information and review for fiscal and operational impact on departments.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The County Attorney's Office shall provide legal support to the Office.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-219, § 11, 12-16-04)</history>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (127) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 04-219, §§ 1—11, adopted Dec. 16, 2004, did not specifically amend the Code. Hence, its inclusion herein as article CXVIII, sections 2-1781—2-1791, was at the discretion of the editor. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
