<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 20 MUNICIPALITIES</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_IV._COMMUNITY_COUNCILS</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 20-40. Community Councils; creation and purposes</catch_line>
<text>
There are hereby established and created Community Councils to serve the unincorporated Miami-Dade County. Community Councils are established for the following purposes:
<section prefix = "1">
Providing the residents of unincorporated Miami-Dade County with increased governmental accountability, and responsiveness in decision-making processes for the delivery of municipal-type services;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Improving the effectiveness of services by making them more responsive to community desires and needs;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Retaining efficiencies of services by maintaining economies of scale;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Maintaining the ability to match unincorporated area needs with available resources; and
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Fostering a sense of community identity, inclusiveness and empowerment.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 20-41. Community Councils; responsibilities</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Community Councils shall perform the duties and responsibilities of Community Zoning Appeals Boards as set forth in Section 33-306 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Community Councils may, at their option, perform the following duties and responsibilities:
<section prefix = "1">
Planning.
<section prefix = "a">
Compile profiles of their respective community's social, physical and economic conditions to assist them in performing their duties;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Prepare an annual statement of community needs including development patterns and regulations, public facilities and services to assist the Council;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Make recommendations to the Planning Advisory Board and Board of County Commissioners on proposed Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan amendments that impact each Council's area; and
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Make recommendations to the County Commission on the location and siting of specific public facility and infrastructure projects.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Protection of persons and property programming.
<section prefix = "a">
Recommend policies to coordinate the Fire Rescue District and Police Department in the enhancement of public safety and protection of property in the council area through improved communications and service needs assessments.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Budgeting.
<section prefix = "a">
Make recommendations to the County Manager and County Commission on priorities for community facilities and services and on community based organization grants for the council area; and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Make recommendations to the County Manager and County Commission on revenue needs including unincorporated area property taxes millages and special taxing districts.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Communication.
<section prefix = "a">
Conduct forums on council area issues to facilitate the exchange of information between residents, property owners, businesses, institutions and County Officials and Administrators;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Disseminate information about council area related organizations, programs and activities; and
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Coordinate with Miami-Dade County's Team Metro in the exercise of that agency's responsibilities within the council area.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
No member of a Community Council shall appear at any public hearings or meetings before the Board of County Commissioners or any other federal, state, or local board or tribunal, to advocate concerning any zoning application that was heard by, or that could reasonably be expected to be heard by, any Community Council.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 96-126, § 1, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 05-139, § 1, 7-7-05)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 20-42. Community Councils; configuration</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
There shall be no more than (10) Community Councils each of which shall have jurisdiction within its boundary within the unincorporated area. Council areas should be large enough to reasonably accommodate local zoning issues without unduly increasing staffing requirements. The boundaries of Community Councils' jurisdiction, to the extent feasible, shall coincide with those of groupings of Census Designated Places.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Each Community Council area shall contain no more than six (6) subareas. The boundaries of these subareas, to the extent feasible, shall coincide with those of existing election precincts. Enclave areas that are fully surrounded by municipal boundaries and are not large enough to be subareas shall be part of the nearest subarea.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
The boundaries and numerical designations of the Community Councils and of the subareas within them are depicted and described in Attachment I attached hereto and incorporated herein by reference [which can be found in the County Clerk's office]. These boundaries may be amended from time to time by resolution of the County Commission after public hearing. The names of the Community Councils shall be designated by the respective Community Council.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
Notwithstanding anything in this Code to the contrary, when, as a result of municipal incorporation or annexation, a Community Council does not have enough members in office to act, the Board of County Commission may by resolution after public hearing, reassign the remaining areas of the affected Community Council to a different Community Council and modify the total number of Councils accordingly.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 96-126, § 1, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 97-16, § 2, 2-25-97; Ord. No. 97-163, § 1, 9-23-97; Ord. No. 01-17, § 1, 1-23-01; Ord. No. 04-101, § 1, 5-11-04)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 20-43. Community Councils; membership</catch_line>
<text>
Except as provided in subsection (E), Community Councils shall have seven (7) members, six (6) of whom shall be elected at large within the council area and one (1) of whom shall be appointed by the Board of County Commissioners as follows:
<section prefix = "A">
Elected Council Members.
<section prefix = "1">
Elected Council Members shall, for at least six (6) months prior to qualifying, have been resident electors of the council area for which they are qualifying, and, for at least three (3) years prior to qualifying, resident electors of Miami-Dade County. Additionally, each elected Council Member seeking to represent a subarea shall, for three (3) months prior to qualifying, have been a resident elector of the separate subarea of the council area for which the Member is qualifying. At the time of qualifying candidates shall submit proof of residency for the prescribed period to the supervisor of elections. Proof of residency shall establish that the qualifying candidate has met the residency requirements for the required period. Any person misrepresenting their residency shall, upon conviction, be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment not to exceed sixty (60) days in the County jail or both, at the discretion of the court. No Council Member shall be employed by Miami-Dade County or be a member of the County Commission.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The term of office of Community Council members shall be for four (4) years. It is provided, however, that when a Community Council has been modified to establish new subareas or at large areas, in the initial election of Council Members, those members representing even-numbered subareas shall serve a two-year term and those members representing odd-numbered subareas or at large areas shall serve a four-year term so as to create staggered terms. Thereafter all Council Members shall serve four-year terms. When a subarea is dissolved and is replaced by an at large area, the at large representative shall serve until expiration of the term of office that was provided for the dissolved subarea. It is further provided that when a Community Council consisting of one (1) subarea is created in the initial election three (3) seats shall be designated as two-year terms and three (3) seats shall be designated as four-year terms so as to provide staggered terms. Thereafter, all Council members shall serve four-year terms.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
All elections for Community Council Members shall be non-partisan. The initial general election for Council Members shall be held at the time of the 1996 General Election. Subsequent elections of Council Members shall be held in each even numbered year, in conjunction with state primary elections. The terms of Council Members shall commence on the second Tuesday next succeeding the date provided for the state general election.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
All candidates for Community Councils shall qualify with the Clerk of the Circuit Court no earlier than the 72nd day and no later than noon of the 70th day prior to the date of the election at which he or she is a candidate, in the manner provided by law or ordinance. Each candidate shall pay a filing fee of one hundred dollars ($100.00).
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
All elections for Community Councils shall be canvassed by the County Canvassing Board as provided under the election laws of this state.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
The election ballot for the Council Member of each council area shall contain the names of all qualified candidates for election for Council positions from each subarea and shall instruct the electors to cast one (1) vote for the subarea position for which an election is being held. The candidate receiving the greatest number of votes shall be duly elected to that Council Seat. If there is a tie vote among the two (2) candidates receiving the greatest number of votes, there shall be a run-off election.
The ballot for any run-off election for a Council Seat shall contain the names of the two (2) candidates for the Council Seat who received the most votes. The ballot shall instruct electors of the council area to cast one (1) vote for each subarea position. The candidate for each Council Seat receiving the most votes in such run-off election shall be duly elected to that Council Seat. Provided, however, where there are fewer than six (6) subareas in a council area the number of persons to be elected from each subarea shall be as follows:
<section prefix = "a">
Where there are five (5) subareas the electors of the entire council area shall elect one (1) member from each subarea and one (1) member at large.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Where there are four (4) subareas the electors of the entire council area shall elect one (1) member from each subarea and two (2) members at large.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Where there are three (3) subareas the electors of the entire council area shall elect two (2) members from each subarea.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Where there are two (2) subareas the electors of the entire council area shall elect three (3) members from each subarea.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Where there is one (1) subarea there shall be six (6) members elected from the subarea.
Where there is more than one (1) position available in a subarea for election, the candidates with the largest number of votes shall be elected to those positions. In the event that a subarea election has positions for both expired and unexpired terms, the candidates elected with the least number of votes shall fill the positions for the unexpired terms. It is provided, however, where the number of persons qualifying for a Community Council election is equal to the number of positions both for expired and unexpired terms the candidates filling the unexpired terms shall be determined by lot.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Vacancies. The County Commissioner whose district encompasses the greatest total population within the Community Council area, based on population data from the decennial Census, shall fill any vacant Council positions, by the appointment of an individual meeting the qualifications provided in subsection (1) above from a list of one or more names supplied by the Community Council. A person appointed shall serve until the earlier of the following: (1) the next primary election; or (2) expiration of the term of office for which the appointment is made. This limitation on term length shall apply to any person appointed by either a Community Council or a County Commissioner, whether appointed prior to or after the effective date of this ordinance. A person elected at such county-wide election shall serve for the remainder of the unexpired term. It is provided, however, in the event there is an insufficient number of Community Council Members in office to constitute a quorum, the County Commissioner whose district encompasses the greatest total population within the Community Council area, based on population data from the decennial Census, shall appoint a sufficient number of members necessary to constitute a quorum. Further, should any Community Council fail to supply a list of one or more names for any vacant Council position within ninety (90) days from the date such position becomes vacant or that the names supplied within such time period are not acceptable to the appointing County Commissioner, the County Commissioner whose district encompasses the greatest total population within the Community Council area, based on population data from the decennial Census, shall appoint an individual meeting the qualifications set forth in subsection (1) above to fill such vacancy, except that such County Commissioner may appoint any resident elector within the council area, regardless of whether that elector resides within the subarea represented by the vacant position. In the event any Council Member no longer resides in a Council subarea for a subarea position or Council area for an at large position, that person shall be deemed to have tendered their resignation from such Council; provided, however, any Council Member who, as a result of a modification to the configuration of a Council subarea pursuant to Section 20-42, is no longer qualified to be an elected member of such Council, shall be permitted to complete the term of office commenced prior to the subarea boundary modification.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Appointed Council Members.
<section prefix = "1">
The County Commissioners shall appoint one (1) member to each Community Council following each election of Council Members. Each appointed Community Council Member shall have been for at least six months prior to appointment a resident elector of the Council area, and, for at least three (3) years, a resident elector of Miami-Dade County. No appointed Council Member shall be employed by Miami-Dade County or be a member of the County Commission. These members shall be appointed by the County Commissioner whose district includes the greatest total population within the Community Council area, based on population data from the decennial Census. Appointments shall be confirmed by a majority of the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The term of each appointed Council Member shall be four (4) years; provided, however, the term of each member expires when the Commissioner who appointed that member leaves office. Each member shall hold office until a successor has been duly appointed, qualified and confirmed. Vacant Council Member positions shall be filled for the unexpired term in the same manner as other appointed Council Members.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Organizational meeting. The first organizational meeting of each Community Council shall take place on the 30th day, or as soon thereafter as is practical, after the date of the general election. In the event of a tie vote for one (1) or more Council seats in the general election such Community Council shall meet on the 30th day, or as soon thereafter as is practical, after the date of the run-off election. At the organizational meeting, or as soon thereafter as is practical, each Community Council shall elect a chair and vice-chair from its members who shall serve a one-year term.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
Reimbursements of expenses. All Council Members shall serve without compensation but shall be entitled to reimbursement for necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties, upon approval of the County Commission.
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
Reassignment of Community Council Members. When, as a result of incorporation or annexation, subareas or portions thereof are reassigned to a different Community, elected or appointed Council Members who continue to reside in the unincorporated area, whether at-large or subarea representatives representing the reassigned areas, shall serve as additional members to the reassigned Community Council. The reassigned Council Members shall serve until the next first state primary election.
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
Community Councils shall have the following nonvoting members when acting as Community Zoning Appeals Boards:
<section prefix = "1">
A representative appointed by the School Board of Miami-Dade County, who may attend those meetings at which a Board considers a zoning action that would, if approved, increase residential density on the property that is the subject of the application.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
A representative appointed by the commanding officer of the Homestead Air Reserve Base, who may attend those meetings at which a Board considers a zoning action that, if approved, would affect the intensity, density, or use of the land adjacent to or in close proximity to the military installation.

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 20-43.1. Community Councils; recall</catch_line>
<text>
Any elected member of a Community Council or any member appointed by the Community Council pursuant to Section 20-43(A)(7) may be removed from office by the electors of the Council area. The procedure for removal by electors shall be as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
The person proposing the exercise of recall shall submit the recall petition to the Clerk of the Circuit Court for approval of the form of the petition. Recall petitions shall be submitted for approval during the months of January and June only.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The person or persons circulating the recall petition shall, within sixty (60) days after approval of the form of the petition, obtain the valid signatures of electors in the council area in numbers at least equal to ten (10) percent of the registered voters in the council area on the date on which the recall petition is approved, according to the official records of the County Supervisor of Elections. Each signer of a petition shall place thereon, after his or her name, the date and the signer's place of residence or precinct number. Each person circulating a copy of the petition shall attach to it a sworn affidavit stating the number of signers and the fact that each signature was made in the presence of the circulator of the petition.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The signed petition shall be filed with the Clerk of the Circuit Court which shall within thirty (30) days after filing order a canvass of the signatures thereon to determine the sufficiency of the signatures. If the number of signatures is insufficient or the petition is deficient as to form or compliance with this section, the Clerk shall notify the person filing the petition that the petition is insufficient and has failed. The Clerk shall certify the petition if the number of signatures is sufficient and the petition if sufficient as to form and compliance with this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The Board of County Commissioners must provide for a recall election not less than forty-five (45) days nor more than ninety (90) days after certification of the petition.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The question of recall shall be placed on the ballot in a manner that will give the elector a clear choice for or against the recall. The result shall be determined by a majority vote of the electors voting on the question.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
If the majority is against recall the Community Council member shall continue in office under the terms of the member's previous election or appointment. If the majority is for recall, the member shall, regardless of any defect in the recall petition, be deemed removed from office immediately.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
No recall petition against an elected Community Council member shall be certified within one (1) year after the member takes office nor within one (1) year after a recall petition against the member is defeated.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Any vacancy created by recall in a Community Council shall be filled for the remaining term by appointment in the manner prescribed for filling vacant positions.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 20-43.2. Community Councils; removal</catch_line>
<text>
Any elected or appointed member of a Community Council may be removed from office for cause by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners. The following events shall be deemed sufficient cause for removal: malfeasance, misfeasance, neglect of duty, drunkenness, incompetence, permanent inability to perform official duties, or indictment for crime. Any vacancy created by removal in a Community Council shall be filled for the remaining term by appointment in the manner prescribed for filling vacant positions.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 20-44. Community Councils; organization; new member orientation; Community Council workshop</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
The County Manager shall assign existing County staff positions to provide support for the Community councils, to the fullest extent feasible. Such staff may include: a Community Council Administrator, an Administrative Assistant, clerical staff and others as the County Manager deems needed. Team Metro shall develop strong linkages to each Community Council.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
The County Manager shall coordinate the activities and schedules of Community Councils with other County activities to ensure maximum effectiveness and efficiency. The County Manager may limit the total staff time available to each Community Council.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Within parameters recommended by the County Manager and approved by the County Commission, Community Councils shall be empowered to establish their own procedures for conducting their business and to select from the activities described in Section 20-41(B) those in which it wishes to engage. It is provided however that zoning procedures shall be adopted pursuant to Sections 33-308 of the Code. It is further provided that no zoning or non zoning meeting of a Community Council or Community Zoning Appeals Board shall extend beyond 11:00 p.m.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
Prior to serving on a Community Council, a Community Council member appointed or elected to a Council after the effective date of this ordinance shall attend a New Member Orientation Seminar conducted by the Department of Planning and Zoning, the Commission on Ethics, Team Metro and the County Attorney's Office. The seminar shall include, but shall not be limited to, review of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan and issues related thereto, review of zoning regulations, incorporation and annexation issues, workforce and affordable housing issues and applicable laws, rules and regulations pertaining to duties and responsibilities of Community Council members.
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
All Community Council members shall attend in every even-numbered year a Community Council Workshop organized and conducted by the Department of Sustainability, Planning and Economic Enhancement, the Department of Permitting, Environment and Regulatory Affairs, the Commission on Ethics, and the County Attorney's Office. The Workshop shall include, but shall not be limited to, review of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan and issues related thereto, review of zoning regulations, incorporation and annexation issues, workforce and affordable housing issues and applicable laws, rules and regulations pertaining to duties and responsibilities of Community Council members.
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
Notwithstanding Section 20-43.2, failure of any elected or appointed member of a Community Council to attend a Community Council Workshop shall be deemed sufficient cause for removal.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 96-126, § 1, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 99-67, § 1, 6-8-99; Ord. No. 05-171, § 1, 9-8-05; Ord. No. 12-40, § 1, 6-5-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 20-45. Community Councils; conflict of interest</catch_line>
<text>
In addition to the provisions of the Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance, each Community Council member is prohibited from voting on or participating in any way in any matter presented to the Community Council on which the member serves if the member has any of the following relationships with any of the persons or entities which would be or might be directly or indirectly affected by any action of the Community Council on which the member serves: (i) officer, director, partner, of counsel, consultant, employee, fiduciary or beneficiary; or (ii) stockholder, bondholder, debtor, or creditor, if in any instance the transaction or matter would affect the Community Council member in a manner distinct form the manner in which it would affect the public generally. Any Community Council member who has any of the above relationships or who would or might, directly or indirectly, profit or be enhanced by the action of the Community Council on which the member serves shall absent himself or herself from the Community Council meeting during the discussion of the subject item and shall not vote on or participate in any way in said matter.
</text>
</law>
