<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_CV._MIAMI-DADE_COUNTY_STS_OVERSI</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1561. Creation of Task Force</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created and established in Miami-Dade County an advisory task force to be known as the Miami-Dade County STS Oversight Task Force (STS Task Force).
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1562. Membership</catch_line>
<text>
The STS Task Force shall be composed of nine members as follows:
<section prefix = "a">
One (1) member of the Board of County Commissioners appointed by the Commission who shall serve as the Chairperson of the STS Task Force;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Four (4) STS users appointed by the Committee on Disability Issues; and
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Four (4) representatives from the providers of STS services appointed by the Commission.

Notwithstanding the foregoing, the STS Task Force shall, upon creation, be composed of those individuals appointed to serve on the STS Oversight Task Force pursuant to Resolution 133-02.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1563. Terms of Office</catch_line>
<text>
All members shall serve for two years and may be reappointed thereafter for successive two-year terms. Members may be removed in accordance with the provisions of Section 2-11.39 of the Code of Miami-Dade County. Vacancies on the Task Force shall be filled in the same manner by which Task Force members were appointed.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1564. Organization</catch_line>
<text>
The STS Task Force shall select a Vice-chairperson. A majority of the members shall constitute a quorum. The STS Task Force shall adopt a regular schedule of meetings. All meetings of the STS Task Force shall be public and written minutes shall be maintained.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1565. Duties and Functions</catch_line>
<text>
The STS Task Force shall be charged with:
<section prefix = "a">
Monitoring the effectiveness of paratransit software utilized for the provision of STS services;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Monitoring service provided by STS brokers and service providers;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Considering any other matters relating to the provision of STS services; and
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Providing semiannual reports to the Board of County Commissioners regarding the effectiveness of paratransit software, the service provided by STS brokers and service providers and any other matters relating to the provision of STS services.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-1566. Staff Support</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager shall provide adequate departmental staff support and access to necessary resources to enable the STS Task Force to carry out its duties and functions.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-1567—2-1570. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (114) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 03-46, §§ 1—6, adopted March 11, 2003, did not specifically amend the Code. Hence its inclusion herein as article CV, sections 2-1561—2-1566, was at the discretion of the editor. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
