<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 23 PENSIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_IV._DEATH_BENEFITS</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 23-61. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
County employee shall mean an officer or other employee occupying a position and who is paid a salary or wage for services rendered, and shall include members of the Board of County Commissioners of Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Average weekly wage is the total gross salary or wage paid divided by the number of weeks employed limited to no more than two hundred sixty (260) weeks immediately preceding the death of said County employee.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Dependent is any person more than one-half of whose total support, as defined by the United States Internal Revenue Service, was furnished by the decedent.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 65-46, § 3, 6-17-65)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 23-62. When payments made; amount paid; to whom paid</catch_line>
<text>
Upon proper proof of the death of any County employee indicating that such death was the natural and proximate result of an accident or overt act occurring at some definite time and place while said employee was in the actual performance of duty and not caused by wilful negligence on the part of the employee, there shall be paid one-half of the average weekly wage of said employee to the dependent widow or dependent surviving spouse until said dependent widow or dependent surviving spouse remarries or twenty thousand dollars ($20,000.00) is expended, whichever first occurs. If said employee leaves no dependent widow or dependent surviving spouse, or if said dependent widow or dependent surviving spouse dies or remarries before the youngest child of the deceased employee shall have attained the age of eighteen (18) years, then such payment shall be paid to said employee's child or children under such age until the youngest child attains the age of eighteen (18) years or the sum of twenty thousand dollars ($20,000.00) is expended, whichever first occurs; or if said employee is unmarried, then to any relative or relatives dependent upon said deceased employee until said relative attains the age of eighteen (18) years or marries or dies or ceases to be dependent, or twenty thousand dollars ($20,000.00) is expended, whichever first occurs.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 23-63. Amounts paid under workers' compensation</catch_line>
<text>
Any amounts paid or payable under these provisions shall be reduced by any amounts paid or payable under the provisions of the State worker's compensation law, except that the foregoing limitations shall not reduce the statutory obligations imposed on account of the State worker's compensation law during the period of such statutory obligation. Any amounts paid or payable as an obligation of the State worker's compensation law shall not reduce the amount of twenty thousand dollars ($20,000.00) provided for herein.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 23-64. Source of payment</catch_line>
<text>
The payments authorized herein other than those paid from the workers' compensation benefits fund shall be paid from the Dade County general fund for contingencies and administered by the Insurance and Safety Division in conjunction with worker's compensation benefits.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 23-65. Special panal to decide discretionary matters</catch_line>
<text>
All discretionary matters arising under the provisions of this article shall be approved by a panel of five (5) members, consisting of the worker's compensation claims supervisor and a safety officer who are obliged to investigate all job-connected deaths, and one (1) representative of the County Manager's Office, the Personnel Department, and the Department of the descendent.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 23-66. Modification of article</catch_line>
<text>
The benefits, or any of them, provided for in this article may be modified or terminated at any time by ordinance.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (3) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 65-46 added the provisions included in this article to the Code. The editors, in their discretion, have inserted these provisions at this place. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
