<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 26 PARK AND RECREATION DEPARTMENT RULES AND REGULATIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_II._PROGRAMMING_PARTNERS_PROGRAM</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 26-21. Findings</catch_line>
<text>
The Board finds that:
<section prefix = "A">
The purposes described in the Whereas clauses [of the ordinance from which this article derives] are incorporated into the body of this article by reference. This article shall hereafter be known as the "Programming Partners Ordinance" and referred to herein as this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
To fulfill the goal of the Recreation and Open Space Element of the CDMP Objective 4C, Section ii, the Department stipulates that it shall work with community-based organizations, non-profit youth service organizations, foundations, facility support societies and other special interest groups to expand opportunities for private, non-profit investment in park improvements and recreational programming.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
County procurement processes primarily govern the purchase of goods and services through specifications and competitive bidding, and are managed through the Department of Procurement Management. As Programming Partners selection criteria are based on elements other than price, the standard procurement process should not apply, and Programming Partners shall become a distinct and unique process.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
This Article creates a process to identify and select qualified Programming Partners to assist the Department in providing recreational and cultural programming services. Selection is based on an organization's ability to successfully fulfill specific, mutually agreed upon Recreational Outcomes that meet community needs.
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
Based upon these findings, the Board concurs that a fair and standard process for the recruitment, selection, agreement and evaluation of Not-For-Profit Program Service Providers be implemented.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 26-22. Scope</catch_line>
<text>
This section shall apply to all permit agreements, license agreements and lease agreements for programming as defined herein, by not-for-profit organizations at Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department Facilities with the park classification of Metropolitan Park, District Park, Community Park, Special Activity Areas, and Single-Purpose Park. This section shall supersede Section 2-8.1 and Administrative Order 3-38 and 8-5 for the issuance of such permit agreements, license agreements and lease agreements with these entities.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 26-23. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
As used in this article, the following terms shall mean:
<section prefix = "A">
Community-based Organization (CBO) shall refer to any not-for-profit agency, group, organization, society, association, partnership or individual whose primary purpose is to provide a community service to improve or enhance the well-being of the community of Miami-Dade County at large or to improve or enhance the well-being of certain individuals within this community who have special needs.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Community Park shall refer to the park classification, as established in accordance with the guidelines of Miami-Dade County's adopted CDMP, for staffed County Park and Recreation Facilities, usually of 30-100 acres in size with mixed passive and active recreational facilities.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Concession Rights shall refer to a Programming Partner's privilege to engage in the trade of certain goods, such as food and drink, in compliance with their IRS status in order to raise funds for the operations of its programs.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
County Park and Recreation Facility shall refer to any public park land and the recreational facilities, thereon, owned and/or operated by the Department. The following park classifications: Natural Area Preserves, Greenways, Neighborhood parks and mini-parks, by definition are considered passive use areas not usually suited for on-site program development and therefore they are exempt from this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
Department shall refer to the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
Development Rights shall refer to a Programming Partner's privilege to raise funds or provide services to plan, design and construct capital improvements on County Park and Recreation Facilities so long as any improvements are in accordance with the host Facility's approved general plan, and all capital improvements are authorized through the appropriate Department procedures.
</section>
<section prefix = "G">
District Park shall refer to the park classification, as established in accordance with the guidelines of Miami-Dade County's adopted CDMP, for staffed County Park and Recreation Facilities, usually of 200 to 500 acres in size with intensive active, user-based recreational facilities.
</section>
<section prefix = "H">
Exclusive Use shall refer to a Programming Partners' serving as the sole provider of recreational programming services at a County Park and Recreation Facility.
</section>
<section prefix = "I">
Metropolitan Park shall refer to the park classification, as established in accordance with the guidelines of Miami-Dade County's adopted CDMP, for staffed County Park and Recreation Facilities, usually of 200-plus acres in size that incorporate activities based upon the natural and cultural resources of the park.
</section>
<section prefix = "J">
Non-Exclusive Use shall refer to a Programming Partners' sharing time and facility usage with other recreational programming service providers at a County Park and Recreation Facility.
</section>
<section prefix = "K">
Not-For-Profit Program Service Provider(s) shall refer to any legally incorporated not-for-profit organization created under the laws of the State of Florida (the State) and designated as a tax-exempt entity by the United States Internal Revenue Service, which has among its purposes the provision of youth, athletic, senior, adult, cultural, environmental, conservation and/or recreational services.
</section>
<section prefix = "L">
Programming shall refer to recreational or cultural activities or services provided to County Park and Recreation Facilities through either a Programming Partner or the Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "M">
Programming Partners Agreement or Programming Partnership Agreement shall refer to the executed contract for services between the Programming Partner and the Department approved and authorized as outlined in the Administrative Order.
</section>
<section prefix = "N">
Programming Partner(s), Partner(s) or Partnering Organization(s) shall refer to any Not-For-Profit Program Service Provider that is selected by the Department under this article and accompanying Administrative Order to provide programs in County Park and Recreation Facilities.
</section>
<section prefix = "O">
Public Park Purpose shall refer to the use of County Park and Recreation Facilities for aesthetic, educational, recreational or cultural use, which promote personal, social, environmental and economic benefits to the County community.
</section>
<section prefix = "P">
Recreational Outcomes shall refer to the measurable recreational or educational programming goals and objectives the Programming Partner seeks to achieve as a condition of its agreement with the Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "Q">
Request For Programming Proposals (RFPP) means a formal written solicitation prepared and issued for the purpose of seeking sealed responses from prospective proposers by a date and time certain as established by the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "R">
Single Purpose Park shall refer to the park classification, as established in accordance with the guidelines of Miami-Dade County's adopted CDMP, for staffed County Park and Recreation Facilities, usually between five and fifteen acres in size, that are devoted to a single recreational function.
</section>
<section prefix = "S">
Special Activity Areas shall refer to the park classification, as established in accordance with the guidelines of Miami-Dade County's adopted CDMP, for staffed County Park and Recreation Facilities of no set size, that incorporate activities based upon the natural or cultural resources of the park.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 26-24. Purpose</catch_line>
<text>
The Programming Partners Program provides a vehicle for the Department to build collaborative relationships with Programming Partners through a fair and standard recruitment, selection, agreement and evaluation process that fosters quality, equity and diversity in recreational and cultural programming opportunities, while ensuring that both the County and its Partners are accountable for the stewardship of County Park and Recreation Facilities.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 26-25. Goals</catch_line>
<text>
To fulfill the purpose of Programming Partners, the Department seeks to:
<section prefix = "A">
Establish a fair and standard process to recruit, qualify and select Programming Partners.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Create a graduated system for agreement authorization.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Identify Recreational Outcomes required to fulfill community programming needs and deficiencies throughout all County Park and Recreation Facilities except as exempted by definition in Section 26-26 of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
Develop performance measures that gauge Programming quality and effectiveness, and provide a process for corrective actions and a graduated system of penalties for non-compliance.
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
Provide financial oversight to ensure that Programming proceeds are reinvested directly into program operations and the upkeep and maintenance of the County Park and Recreation Facility hosting the Programming Partner.
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
Create mandatory training programs to empower Partners and improve overall professionalism, quality and diversity of Programming.
</section>
<section prefix = "G">
Ensure responsible stewardship of County Park and Recreation Facilities and recreational open space by scheduling programs to allow for general public access, and adequate and appropriate maintenance of lands and facilities.
</section>
<section prefix = "H">
Offer Development Rights to Programming Partners to empower them to obtain funding for capital improvements to County Park and Recreation Facilities, and expedite construction projects in accordance with established department policies and procedures.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 26-26. Exemptions</catch_line>
<text>
County Park and Recreation Facilities classified as Natural Area Preserve, Greenways, Neighborhood Parks and mini-parks are exempt from this article. Facilities with these designations are passive use in nature and are not generally suited for on-site development of any duration. Active, organized use of these facilities will continue to be addressed through existing procedures outlined in Administrative Orders for Special Events and Permits to Conduct Business on County Property.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 26-27. Administration</catch_line>
<text>
By implementing order, procedures for the advertisement, selection, and award of all agreements with Programming Partners shall be established. The implementing order shall be consistent with this article. The Department shall administer the Programming Partners process, which shall include at a minimum:
<section prefix = "A">
Recruitment Procedures for new Partners;
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Measures for Existing Partners;
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Criteria for Selection;
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
Partnership Agreement Types and Authorizations;
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
Required Information and Reporting;
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
Criteria for Performance Monitoring;
</section>
<section prefix = "G">
Measures to Address non-Performing Partners;
</section>
<section prefix = "H">
Procedures for Partnership Renewal;
</section>
<section prefix = "I">
Requirements for Participation in Fee Reduction/Scholarship Program;
</section>
<section prefix = "J">
Requirements for Background Checks of Volunteers;
</section>
<section prefix = "K">
Approval of Programming Partners Fees and Charges Schedules;
</section>
<section prefix = "L">
Mandatory Training Programs;
</section>
<section prefix = "M">
Opportunities for Recognition;

All Requests for Proposals for Programming Partners (RFPP) shall be prepared and issued by the Department. The Department shall receive and open such proposals, evaluate each proposal for responsiveness and qualifications, rank all proposals and shall make recommendations to the entity authorized by the Administrative Order to make the selection of award for a Programming Partner, as set forth herein. The type of agreement executed and level of authority for approval will be based upon the program purpose, use, term and amount of operating revenue and/or capital investment provided by the Programming Partner.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 26-28. Partnership Agreements</catch_line>
<text>
The type of Partnership Agreement and the required delegated authority, (Department Director, County Mayor or County Mayor's designee, or Board of County Commissioners) to enter into such agreements shall be determined by the purpose, use, duration and level of capital investment incurred by the Programming Partner, and shall be detailed in the Implementing Order.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 26-29. Concession Rights</catch_line>
<text>
Concession Rights will be limited to Programming Partners operating in Community, District, Single-Purpose and Metropolitan Parks.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 26-30. Development Rights</catch_line>
<text>
Development Rights to construct recreational facilities on County-owned, -operated and -maintained parks will be granted at the Department's discretion and to the extent that they fulfill the host park's approved general plan.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 26-31. Partner Revenues, Fees and Charges</catch_line>
<text>
Revenues, fees and charges collected by Programming Partners shall be for fulfillment of the Programming Partner's mission and in keeping with the Programming Partner's not-for-profit status.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 26-32. Training</catch_line>
<text>
All selected Programming Partners must participate in a mandatory training program, that will include, but not be limited to: department rules and regulations; ethics in the public sector; officials education and conduct; coaching certification; parental codes of conduct; inclusiveness and sensitivity for persons with disabilities; record keeping and reporting; and, facility stewardship.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 26-33. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Section 1 of Ord. No. 08-07, adopted Jan. 10, 2008, deleted § 26-33, the Shannon Melendi Act, which had derived from Ord. No. 02-137, adopted July 23, 2002; and Ord. No. 05-122, adopted June 21, 2005. The user is directed to §§ 26-37—26-39 for similar provisions.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 26-34. Existing Partners</catch_line>
<text>
Community-Based Not-For-Profit organizations and Programming Partners currently providing or desiring to provide programming services at County Park and Recreation Facilities may be offered the opportunity to negotiate and/or renew a Programming Partnership Agreement with the Department based on the needs of the Department provided that no such term, extension or renewal shall extend beyond ten (10) years following the effective date of this ordinance. In the event that no agreement can be reached to the mutual satisfaction of the parties, and in any event following the expiration of any agreed upon term, extension or renewal an open competitive RFPP process will be initiated. The Board, upon written recommendation of the County Mayor or the County Mayor's designee, may by two-thirds vote of the members present waive competitive bidding when it finds this to be in the best interest of the County. Nothing in this section shall impair any validly existing contractual rights.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 26-35. CBO Grant Process</catch_line>
<text>
Any Programming Partner with an unsatisfactory Performance Evaluation shall not be eligible for grant funding in accordance with A.O. 3-15. After receiving an "unsatisfactory" Performance Evaluation, the Programming Partner will have a designated period of time to improve. Once the Performance Evaluation has been brought up to a satisfactory level, the Programming Partner will become eligible for grant funding.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 26-36. Audit</catch_line>
<text>
The Department will reserve the right to request or perform an audit to determine compliance with contract terms in addition to the reporting requirements in the Programming Partnership Agreement.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (3) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 02-137, §§ 1—16, adopted July 23, 2002, did not specifically amend the Code. Hence, its inclusion herein as article II, sections 26-21—26-36, was at the discretion of the editor. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
