<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_V._FAMILY_LEAVE</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 11A-29. Legislative findings and purpose</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
The County Commission finds that the number of families within the County in which both parents or a single parent is employed outside the home has increased significantly within recent years. Due to a lack of employment policies designed to accommodate working parents, many individuals are forced to choose between job security and parenting or providing care for ill family members. The Commission further finds that it is necessary to promote the economic security of families by guaranteeing jobs to wage earners who choose to take a period of leave upon the birth or placement for adoption of a child or serious health condition of a family member. The Commission also recognizes that unrestricted leave by an employee may interfere with an employer's legitimate business needs. The Commission, therefore, declares that it is the policy of the County to balance the demands of the workplace with the needs of families, to promote stability and economic security in families and to entitle employees to take reasonable leave for medical reasons, for the birth or adoption of a child, and for the care of a child, spouse or other close relative who has a serious health condition. The County further declares that employees should be entitled to take such leave without risk of termination of employment or retaliation by employers.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The County Commission finds that the enactment of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993, Public Law No. 103-3 (29 U.S.C. ยง 2611 et seq.) fulfills many of the purposes for which this chapter was originally intended. In order to avoid imposing possibly conflicting burdens on employers and unduly confusing employees about their family leave rights, the Commission believes it appropriate to make the County ordinance consistent with the federal act and intends that the ordinance be so interpreted. In enacting this revised chapter, the County Commission intends to provide employees in the County with an efficient alternative means of enforcing their rights to family medical leave through the Commission on Human Rights.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 97-17, ยง 1, 2-25-97; Ord. No. 09-53, ยง 17, 6-30-09)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 11A-30. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
As used in this article:
<section prefix = "1">
Commission shall mean the Miami-Dade County Commission on Human Rights.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Director shall mean the Director of the Miami-Dade County Commission on Human Rights or his or her designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Employer shall mean a person as defined in Section 11A-2(9) of this chapter which has in the regular course of business fifty (50) or more employees working in Miami-Dade County for each working day during each of twenty (20) or more calendar work weeks in the current or preceding calendar year.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Employee shall mean a person who has been employed in Miami-Dade County by the employer with whom leave is requested for at least twelve (12) months and for at least one thousand two hundred and fifty (1,250) hours of service with such employer during the previous twelve-month period.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Grandparent shall mean any grandparent of an employee for whom the employee has assumed primary financial responsibility.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
All other terms shall be defined as in the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993, Public Law No. 103-3 (29 U.S.C. ยง 2611 et seq.) and any amendments thereto.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 11A-31. Entitlement to leave</catch_line>
<text>
Employees, as defined in this article, shall be entitled to take leave on the same terms and conditions as are provided in Sections 102, 103, 104 and 108 of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993, Public Law No. 103-3, any amendments thereto, except:
<section prefix = "1">
An employee may also take leave under this chapter to care for a grandparent with a serious health condition on the same terms and conditions as leave is permitted under the Family and Medical Leave Act to care for a parent with a serious health condition.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to affect any employee benefit plan that the employer may otherwise provide.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 11A-32. Exemption for governmental employers that provide equivalent leave rights</catch_line>
<text>
This article shall not apply to any municipality, special district, or other local government entity that maintains a leave policy that:
<section prefix = "a">
Provides employees with at least the same rights to leave as are provided by this article; and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Includes an administrative procedure for its employees to enforce such rights.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 11A-33. Procedures for family leave complaint</catch_line>
<text>
The procedures for a family leave complaint shall be the same as the procedures outlined in Section 11A-28.
</text>
</law>
