<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 29 TAXATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XI._COUNTY_TRANSIT_SYSTEM_SALES_</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-90. Sales surtax levied</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby levied and imposed a one (1) percent County transit system surtax on all transactions occurring in Miami-Dade County which transactions are subject to the State tax imposed on sales, use, rentals, admissions and other transactions by Part I of Chapter 212 Florida Statutes.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-91. Surtax rate; limitations</catch_line>
<text>
The surtax rate shall be one (1) percent of the amount of taxable sales and taxable purchases representing such transactions. However:
<section prefix = "a">
The tax on any sales amount above five thousand dollars ($5,000.00) on any item of tangible personal property and on long distance telephone service shall not be subject to the surtax;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
In the case of utility, telecommunication, or wired television services billed on or after the effective date of the surtax, the entire amount of the tax for utility, telecommunication, or wired television services shall be subject to the surtax.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
In the case of written contracts which are signed prior to the effective date of any such surtax for the construction of improvements to real property or for remodeling of existing structures, the surtax shall be paid by the contractor responsible for the performance of the contract. However, the contractor may apply for one (1) refund of any such surtax paid on materials necessary for the completion of the contract. Any application for refund shall be made no later than fifteen (15) months following initial imposition of the surtax. The application for refund shall be in the manner prescribed by applicable rule of the Florida Department of Revenue.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-92. Transactions deemed to have occurred in Miami-Dade County</catch_line>
<text>
For the purpose of this article, a transaction shall be deemed to have occurred in Miami-Dade County when:
<section prefix = "a">
The dealer is located in Miami-Dade County, delivery is made to a location within Miami-Dade County or to a location within a County also imposing the surtax, and the sale includes tangible personal property, except as otherwise provided herein; provided, that the sale of any motor vehicle or mobile home of a class or type which is required to be registered in this State or in any other state shall be deemed to have occurred only in the County identified as the residence address of the purchaser on the registration or title document for such property;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The event for which an admission is charged is located in Miami-Dade County;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The consumer of utility or wired television services is located in Miami-Dade County, or the telecommunication services are provided to a location within Miami-Dade County;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The user of any aircraft or boat of a class or type which is required to be registered, licensed, titled, or documented in this State or by the United States Government imported into Miami-Dade County for use, consumption, distribution, or storage to be used or consumed in Miami-Dade County is located in Miami-Dade County, however, it shall be presumed that such items used outside Miami-Dade County for six (6) months or longer before being imported into the County were not purchased for use in Miami-Dade County. The provisions of this paragraph shall not apply to the use or consumption of such items upon which a like tax of equal or greater amount has been lawfully imposed and paid outside Miami-Dade County;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The purchaser of any motor vehicle or mobile home of a class or type which is required to be registered in this State is a resident of Miami-Dade County as determined by the address appearing on or to be reflected on the registration document for such property;
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Any motor vehicle or mobile home of a class or type which is required to be registered in this State is imported from another state into Miami-Dade County by a user residing therein for the purpose of use, consumption, distribution, or storage in Miami-Dade County, however, it shall be presumed that such items used outside Miami-Dade County for six (6) months or longer before being imported into the County were not purchased for use in Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
The real property which is leased or rented is located in Miami-Dade County;
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
The transient rental transaction occurs in Miami-Dade County;
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
The delivery of any aircraft or boat of a class or type which is required to be registered, licensed, titled, or documented in this State or by the United States Government is to a location in Miami-Dade County; however, the provisions of this paragraph shall not apply to the use or consumption of such items upon which a like tax of equal or greater amount has been lawfully imposed and paid outside the County;
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
The dealer owing a use tax on purchases or leases is located in Miami-Dade County;
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
The delivery of tangible personal property other than that described in paragraphs (d), (e), or (f) is made to a location outside Miami-Dade County, but the property is brought into Miami-Dade County within six (6) months after delivery, in which event, the owner must pay the surtax as a use tax; or
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
A Florida manufacturer or wholesaler sells tangible personal property to a dealer who is located outside Miami-Dade County, but delivers the property within Miami-Dade County to a customer of the dealer, in which event the dealer must collect and remit the surtax.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-93. Administration, collection and enforcement</catch_line>
<text>
The Florida Department of Revenue shall administer, collect and enforce the tax levied hereunder pursuant to the procedures specified in Section 212.054(4) Florida Statutes (1988 supp.), as the same may be amended or renumbered from time to time.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 29-94. Trust fund created; uses of surtax proceeds</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created within the County accounts a Miami-Dade County Rapid Transit Trust Fund which shall be the depository of the surtax proceeds collected by the State and distributed to Miami-Dade County hereunder. Such proceeds shall be used only for the purposes of development, construction, equipment, maintenance, operation, supportive services, including a Countywide bus system, and related costs of a fixed guideway rapid transit system. The Board of County Commissioners shall be the Trustee of the Trust Fund and may provide for expenditure of monies therein for the purposes enumerated in this section.
</text>
</law>
