<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XIIIA._NUISANCE_ABATEMENT</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-98.4. Legislative findings and intent</catch_line>
<text>
This article [Ordinance No. 92-42] is enacted pursuant to the provisions of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter and Florida Statute, Section 893.138, as it may be renumbered or amended from time to time, and shall be known and may be cited as the "Miami-Dade County Public Nuisance Abatement Ordinance."
The Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, hereby finds and declares that any places or premises which are used as the site of the unlawful sale or delivery of controlled substances, prostitution, youth and street gang activity, gambling, illegal sale or consumption of alcoholic beverages, or lewd or lascivious behavior, may be a public nuisance that adversely affects the public health, safety, morals, and welfare. This Board also finds that abating the public nuisance which results from said criminal activity is necessary to improve the quality of life of the residents of Miami-Dade County and that said abatement will safeguard the public health, safety, and welfare.
This article is hereby declared to be remedial and essential to the public interest and it is intended that this article be liberally construed to effect the purposes as stated above. The provisions of this article and the standards set forth herein shall be applicable only to the unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
The provisions of this article shall be cumulative and supplemental to and not in deregation of any provision of the Florida Statutes, the Code of Miami-Dade County, or any other applicable law.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-98.5. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
For the purpose of this article the following definitions shall apply:
Public nuisance: Any place or premise which has been used on more than two (2) occasions within a twelve-month period:
<section prefix = "1">
As the site of the unlawful sale or delivery of controlled substances, or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
By a youth and street gang for the purpose of conducting a pattern of youth and street gang activity, or
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
For prostitution, or solicitation of prostitution, or
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
For illegal gambling, or
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
For the illegal sale or consumption of alcoholic beverages, or
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
For lewd or lascivious behavior, or
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Any premise or place declared to be a nuisance by Florida Statute, Section 823.05 or Section 823.10 as they may be renumbered or amended from time to time.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-98.6. Operating procedure</catch_line>
<text>
Any employee, officer or resident of Miami-Dade County may file a complaint and request for prosecution with the Miami-Dade County Public Nuisance Abatement Board regarding the existence of a public nuisance located within Miami-Dade County. Said complaint shall be filed with the Director of the Miami-Dade Police Department, or his designee. Upon the filing of more than two (2) complaints on any particular place or premises, the Director or his designee shall mail written notice of such complaints by certified mail with return receipt to the owner of the place or premises complained of at the owner's address as shown in the Miami-Dade County property tax collector's file. Said notice shall provide for the owner of the place or premises to contact the Director or his designee within fourteen (14) days of receipt of the notice. This time period shall be allowed for the purpose of allowing the owner to take such good faith measures as are appropriate to abate the nuisance. The Director or his designee may extend the fourteen (14) days to allow the owner to institute or continue actions to abate the nuisance provided the actions are reasonable. In the event the owner fails to respond to Notice of Complaint or fails to take reasonable action to abate the nuisance, the Director or his designee shall schedule a hearing on the complaint before the Miami-Dade County Public Nuisance Abatement Board, and written notice of said hearing shall be by certified mail with return receipt to the owner of the premises and the complaintant at least ten (10) days prior to the scheduled hearing.
The aforesaid notice of hearing shall include:
<section prefix = "a">
A statement of the time, place and nature of the hearing;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A statement of the legal authority and jurisdiction under which the hearing is to be held;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
A reference to the particular sections of the statutes and ordinances involved;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
A short and plain statement summarizing the incidents complained of.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-98.7. Public Nuisance Abatement Board</catch_line>
<text>
The Miami-Dade County Public Nuisance Abatement Board is hereby created and established. The Board shall consist of nine (9) members with one member appointed by each County Commissioner.
<section prefix = "a">
Qualification of members. The composition and representative membership of the Board shall be as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
All members shall reside in the unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
One (1) member shall be a law enforcement officer as defined in Florida Statutes, Section 943.10 who is retired or inactive and who is not employed by Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
One (1) member shall be an attorney practicing law in Miami-Dade County and a members in good standing of the Florida Bar.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Eleven (11) members of the general public, who possess outstanding reputations for civic pride, integrity, responsibility and business or professional ability, with interest or experience in abating public nuisances.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Terms of office. The initial appointments to the Board shall be as follows: Seven (7) members shall be appointed for the term of one year, six (6) members shall be appointed for the term of two (2) years. Thereafter all appointments shall be made for the term of two (2) years. No members shall serve more than three (3) consecutive terms or seven (7) years. Appointments to fill any vacancy on the Board shall be for the remainder of the unexpired term of office. A member may be removed with or without cause by the affirmative vote of not less than a majority of the entire County Commission. Should any member of the Board fail to attend three (3) consecutive meetings without due cause, the chairperson shall certify the same to the County Commission. Upon such certification, the member shall be deemed to have been removed and the County Commission shall fill the vacancy by appointment.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Organization of the Board. The members of the Board shall elect a chairperson and such other officers as may be deemed necessary or desirable, who shall serve at the will of the Board. Members shall serve without compensation, but shall be entitled to be reimbursed for necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties, upon approval by the County Commission.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Meetings of the Board. Meetings of the Board shall be held monthly, or more frequently if necessary, to hear and dispose of the pending complaints. Notice of the time and place of meetings shall be given to all complaintants and owners of premises scheduled to be heard. Notice shall be given in writing at least ten (10) days prior to the hearing. Any aggrieved person may request a continuance of the hearing. The Board may grant a continuance of any hearing for good cause. The chairperson may call an emergency meeting of the Board, and meetings may also be called by written notice signed by three (3) members of the Board. The meetings of the Board shall be recorded and be transcribed at the expense of the party requesting the transcript. All meetings shall be in compliance with Florida's "Government in Sunshine Law" and Chapter 286.011, Florida Statute. No less than seven (7) members shall constitute a quorum. No less than six (6) members voting affirmatively shall be required to declare any place or premises a public nuisance under this provision. The County Manager shall provide adequate and competent clerical and administrative personnel, and such technical or scientific personnel as may be reasonably required by the Board for the proper performance of its duties. The County Manager shall provide a regular meeting place for the Board. All records shall be public records as defined by Chapter 119.011, Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Conduct of hearings.
<section prefix = "1">
The Director of the Miami-Dade Police Department or his designee shall present cases before the Board. All parties shall have an opportunity to present evidence and argument on all issues involved, to conduct cross-examination and submit rebuttal evidence, and to be represented by counsel. When appropriate, the general public may be given an opportunity to present oral or written communications. If the Board proposes to consider such material, then all parties shall be given an opportunity to cross-examine or challenge or rebut it. The Board may consider any evidence, including evidence of the general reputation of the place or premises. All testimony shall be under oath and shall be recorded. Formal rules of evidence shall not apply, but fundamental due process shall be observed and shall govern the proceedings. Orders of the Board shall be based on competent and substantial evidence and must be based on a preponderance of the evidence.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
After considering all evidence, the Board may declare the place or premises to be a public nuisance as defined in this chapter and may enter an order prohibiting:
<section prefix = "i">
The maintaining of the nuisance;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
The operating or maintaining of the place or premises; or
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
The conduct, operation, or maintenance of any business or activity on the premises which is conducive to such nuisance.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
An order entered under subsection (2) shall expire after one year or at such earlier time as stated in the order. The Board may retain jurisdiction to modify its orders prior to the expiration of said orders.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The Board may bring a complaint under Section 60.05 of the Florida Statutes, seeking a permanent injunction against any public nuisance.

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-98.8. Costs</catch_line>
<text>
In the event that the Board declares a place or premises to be a nuisance and issues an order pursuant to Section 2-98.7(e)(2) above, the Board shall assess against the owner of the place or premises the costs which the County has incurred in the preparation, investigation, and presentation of the case. These costs shall be due and payable ten (10) days after the written order of the Board has been filed. A certified copy of an order imposing costs may be recorded in the public records and thereafter shall constitute a lien against the land on which the violation exists or, if the violator does not own the land, upon any other real or personal property owned by the violator; and it may be enforced in the same manner as a court judgment by the sheriffs of this state including levy against the personal property, but shall not be deemed to be a court judgment except for enforcement purposes. After one year from the filing of any such lien which remains unpaid, Miami-Dade County may foreclose or otherwise execute on the lien. Interest shall accrue on the unpaid costs at the legal rate of interest set forth in Section 55.03, Florida Statute as that may be amended from time to time.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-98.9. Appeals</catch_line>
<text>
An aggrieved party may appeal a final order of the Miami-Dade County Public Nuisance Abatement Board to the Circuit Court of the Eleventh Judicial Circuit, Appeals Division. Such an appeal shall not be a hearing de novo, but shall be limited to appellate review of the record created before the Board. An appeal shall be filed within thirty (30) days of the date of the written order appealed from.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-98.10. Rights preserved</catch_line>
<text>
This article does not restrict the right of any person to proceed under Section 60.05 of the Florida Statutes, against any Public Nuisance.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (25) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 92-42, adopted May 19, 1992, amended the Code by the addition of provisions which have been included herein at the discretion of the editor as Art. XIIIA. These provisions were previously designated as Art. XIII, §§ 2-95—2-98.3 and subsequently redesignated as Art. XIIIA, §§ 2-98.4—2-98.10 hereof. See the editor's note to Article XIII of this chapter. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
