<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XLVIII._MIAMI-DADE_ECONOMIC_ADVO</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-501. Creation and purpose</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
There is hereby created and established a revocable trust, the terms of which may be modified by Miami-Dade County, which trust shall be named and known as the Miami-Dade Economic Advocacy Trust (hereinafter referred to as the "Trust"). The Trust shall be a public body corporate and politic which, through its governing body, may exercise all those powers either specifically granted herein or necessary in the exercise of those powers herein enumerated. The Trust shall be an agency and instrumentality of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The purpose of the Trust shall be to ensure the equitable participation of Blacks in Miami-Dade County's economic growth through advocacy and monitoring of economic conditions and economic development initiatives in Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
This Board recognizes the independence of the Trust and its obligation to provide the Board of County Commissioners and the County Mayor or the Mayor's designee with independent advice on matters of policy relating to the purposes and projects of the Trust.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Notwithstanding the independence of the Trust, this Board may by resolution take any action to effectuate the purposes of the Trust.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 92-12, § 1, 2-18-92; Ord. No. 01-01, § 1, 1-23-01; Ord. No. 09-70, § 2, 9-1-09)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-502. Governing body</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The governing body of the Trust shall be a Board of Trustees composed of fifteen (15) voting members. A quorum of the Trust shall be the lesser of seven (7) Trustees or a majority of those Trustees in office.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Board of Trustees shall hold regular meetings in accordance with the bylaws of the Trust and other such meetings as it deems necessary.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The establishment and activities of the Board of Trustees shall be governed by Section 2-11.36 et seq. of the Code of Miami-Dade County, as applicable.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 92-12, § 2, 2-18-92; Ord. No. 08-86, § 1, 7-1-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-503. Appointment and tenure</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Nominating council. Trustees shall be appointed by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners (hereinafter known as "Board") after having been selected by the Miami-Dade Economic Advocacy Trust Nominating Council (hereinafter known as "Nominating Council") established and described herein. The Nominating Council shall be comprised of five (5) voting members, two (2) of whom shall be the Chairperson of the Board of Trustees of the Trust and the Chair of the Board's committee with jurisdiction over economic development issues, who shall serve as the chair of the Nominating Council and three (3) of whom shall be appointed by the Chair of the Board of County Commissioners and ratified by the Board. No acting Trustee of the Trust, other than the Chairperson of the Board of Trustees, shall serve on the Nominating Council, nor shall any acting member of the Nominating Council, other than the Chairperson of the Board of Trustees, be eligible to serve on the Board of Trustees of the Trust. In serving on the Nominating Council, the Chairperson of the Board of Trustees of the Trust shall not vote on or participate in any way in any matter affecting the Chairperson's appointment to the Board of Trustees of the Trust. The members of the Nominating Council shall be appointed for staggered three-year terms and shall not serve more than two (2) consecutive and complete three (3) years each as set forth in Section 2-503(d) of this article. The sole function of the Nominating Council shall be to solicit, screen, interview and recommend for appointment the best qualified candidate for each vacancy of the Board of Trustees. The Nominating Council and the procedures under which it will operate shall be approved by the Board of County Commissioners. The Nominating Council shall submit to the Board of County Commissioners one (1) nominee for each vacancy on the Trust Board. The slate of nominees shall be submitted directly to the Board of County Commissioners no later than September 1 of each year. As applicable, Section 2-11.36 et seq. of the Code of Miami-Dade County shall govern the establishment and activities of the Nominating Council. In the event the Commission is unable to appoint a member to the Board of Trustees pursuant to said section(s), no action of the Trust shall be rendered void because of such inability on the part of the Commission. The County Mayor shall designate a liaison to coordinate the Nominating Council process.
In the event of a vacancy during the term of a Trustee, the Trust shall notify the Board of County Commissioners of the vacancy and shall request that it be filled in accordance with the applicable criteria set forth herein either as a part of the annual appointment process or by a special meeting of the Nominating Council.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Composition. Notwithstanding Section 2-11.1 of this Code with respect to eligibility of membership on the Board of Trustees, the voting membership shall include representatives from the following areas of professional expertise: (1) economic and business development; (2) criminal justice; (3) community based organizations; (4) educational organizations; (5) banking and finance; and (6) health organizations. In addition, the Board of Trustees shall have at least one (1) voting member from the Miami-Dade County School Board and one (1) voting member from State or local government. At least seven (7) members of the initial Board of Trustees shall be selected from members of the existing Trust Board of Directors. With respect to the appointment of the balance of Trustees, careful consideration shall be given to the expertise needed to accomplish the goals and objectives of the Trust. In addition, a majority of the membership of the Board of Directors shall be members of the African-American community.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Qualifications. Each member of the Board of Trustees shall be a United States citizen, a permanent resident and duly qualified elector of Miami-Dade County unless the Board of County Commissioners waives the residency requirement by a two-thirds vote of its membership. No person shall be qualified to sit as a Trustee if that person is an officer, representative, administrator or employee of any consultant, contractor or agency contracting with or receiving funding from the Trust except if that person is employed by or is serving on the Board of Trustees as a representative of State or local government. Trustees who are representatives of or who are employed by any State or local governmental agency may not vote on matters affecting the governmental agency by which they are employed or whom they represent.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Tenure of Trustees. The Trustees shall serve terms of three (3) years each; provided, however, that of the original Board of Trustees, the Board of County Commissioners shall select one-third (1/3) for a term of one (1) year and one-third (1/3) for a term of two (2) years. No Trustee shall be permitted to serve more than two (2) consecutive and complete terms of three (3) years each unless so authorized by a two-thirds (2/3) vote of the full membership of the Board of County Commissioners. All Trustees serving on the Board of Trustees on the effective date of this ordinance shall continue to serve on the Board of Trustees. Current Trustees shall be eligible to serve up to two (2) consecutive and complete three-year terms. Service on the Board of Trustees by current members prior to the effective date of this ordinance shall not count towards the maximum term of service provided for in this ordinance. The initial Board of Trustees, appointed after the effective date of this ordinance, excluding Trustees serving on the Board of Trustees on the effective date of this ordinance, shall serve staggered terms. One-third (1/3) of Trustees appointed after the effective date of this ordinance shall serve for a term of one (1) year, one-third (1/3) shall serve for a term of two (2) years, and one-third (1/3) shall serve for a term of three (3) years. Straws shall be drawn to determine the terms.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Compensation. Trustees shall serve without compensation but shall be entitled to reimbursement for necessary expenses.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 92-12, § 3, 2-18-92; Ord. No. 01-01, § 1, 1-23-01; Ord. No. 08-86, § 2, 7-1-08; Ord. No. 09-70, § 3, 9-1-09)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-504. Removal of Trustees</catch_line>
<text>
Any Trustee shall be removed for excessive absence in accordance with Section 2-11.39 of the Code of Miami-Dade County. In addition, before or after the transition period any Trustee may be removed for cause by two-thirds vote of the entire membership of the Board of County Commissioners or, at the conclusion of the transition period (hereinafter defined), by two-third vote of the entire membership of the Board of Trustees.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-505. Organization; staff support</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Organization. The Board of Trustees shall organize after the members have qualified to serve and shall elect one of its voting members as Chairperson, one of its voting members as Vice-Chairperson and such other officers as the Board of Trustees may determine to be necessary. In addition, the Board of Trustees shall make, adopt and amend bylaws, rules and regulations for its own governance.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Employees. The Executive Director and all employees of the Trust shall be Miami-Dade County employees. The Board of Trustees shall submit the names of nominee(s) for the position of Executive Director to the County Manager. The Manager shall make a recommendation from the nominee(s) proposed by the Trust to the Board of County Commissioners for its approval. The Trust shall have the power to remove the Executive Director.
The Board of Trustees shall submit the names of nominee(s) for the position of Executive Director to the County Manager. The Manager shall make a recommendation from the nominee(s) proposed by the Trust to the Board of County Commissioners for its approval. The Trust shall have the power to remove the Executive Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Staff support. The County Attorney shall serve as Attorney for the Trust, the County Manager shall provide audit, budget and financial assistance to the Trust, and the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners shall be the Clerk and Secretary of the Trust.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The Board of County Commissioners shall provide to the Trust fiscal review and oversight as well as programmatic focus and direction.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The Trust shall present quarterly financial reports, including a current statement of all accounts, to the Commission Auditor and the County Manager. Copies of said reports shall be provided to the Board of County Commissioners. Said reports shall also include information concerning an assessment of the performance of each agency funded by the Trust as well as those program activities carried out directly by the Trust. In addition to these quarterly reports, the Trust shall submit annual reports to the County Manager and the Commission Auditor summarizing and evaluating all programs and activities undertaken by the Trust during the previous fiscal year. The annual report shall include an audit in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles of all funds received and expended by the Trust. The Trust shall not be able, however, to establish any bank accounts without the express approval of either the Board of County Commissioners or the County Manager; provided, however, that the Trust can establish an account for Miami-Dade Community Foundation monies to receive and expend non-County monies which the Trust receives. No County monies nor income from County accounts shall be deposited into external accounts. The Trust shall be subject to periodic reviews as deemed necessary by the County Mayor, the Board of County Commissioners, the Department of Audit and Management Services and the Office of Strategic Business Management. In the event that these reviews reveal management problems, as determined by the reviewing entity, then the County Mayor, after the approval of the Board of County Commissioners, may place the Trust on Management Watch. If the Trust is placed on Management Watch, the Mayor shall present a plan to the Board of County Commissioners which provides timelines for removal of the Trust from Management Watch. The Board of County Commissioners shall have the authority to remove the Trust from Management Watch.
The Trust, in addition to providing quarterly financial reports, shall submit to the Board an annual Report Card on the State of the Black Community in Miami-Dade County. The report card shall include information on factors such as, but not limited to, the unemployment rate, the rates of business ownership, graduation rates, and homeownership rates within Miami-Dade County's Black community. The report card shall be presented to the Board and to the community.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Subject to the Miami-Dade County budgetary process and the availability of funds, the County will include in its annual budget funds for administrative costs and additional funds for programmatic activities. Requests for administrative and programmatic funds are to be made in accordance with the procedures described in Section 2-506(i). The County Manager is directed to include his recommendation for administrative and programmatic funding for the Trust in the annual proposed budget.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 92-12, § 5, 2-18-92; Ord. No. 01-01, § 1, 1-23-01; Ord. No. 08-86, § 3, 7-1-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-506. Powers and duties of the Trust</catch_line>
<text>
The Trust, acting through its governing body, shall be authorized to exercise such powers and shall be required to perform such duties as are hereinafter provided:
<section prefix = "a">
Every five (5) years, the Trust shall establish a five-year comprehensive plan (hereinafter "the plan"). The plan shall contain one-year goals and objectives, the completion of which shall be needed to accomplish the comprehensive plan. The first plan shall be submitted to the Board of County Commissioners for approval.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Trust shall be empowered to expend administrative and programmatic resources to achieve each of its one-year goals and objectives as well as to accomplish and complete each five-year plan.

</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Trust shall identify and develop a variety of alternative funding sources and shall seek and apply for State, federal and private grants, including but not limited from philanthropic and non-tax based sources.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The Trust shall serve as an advocate for and providing of the economic conditions and economic development initiatives in Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The Trust shall submit to the Board an annual scorecard that reflects the performance of those entities, (both public and private) charged with and funded to improve conditions in blighted communities.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The Trust shall conduct a disparity study that examines the present economic conditions of Blacks in Miami-Dade County. This study shall be conducted every ten (10) years and submitted to the Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
The Trust, as an agent and instrumentality of Miami-Dade County, shall be authorized to act for Miami-Dade County in the performance and enforcement of all contracts and, subsequent to the effective date of this chapter and subject to the limitations set forth below, shall additionally be empowered to negotiate and execute such contracts as are properly within the powers and duties of the Trust. However, the Trust shall not without the prior approval of the Board of County Commissioners, enter into or amend any contract which shall require the expenditure of funds in excess of the amounts appropriated to the trust by the Board of County Commissioners.
The Trust shall comply with the formal bid requirements of Section 4.03(D) of the Charter of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and for such purpose the term "board" as used in Section 4.03(D) shall be construed to be "board of trustees" and the term "manager" shall be construed to be executive director of the Trust.
For all construction contracts, the trust shall comply with the provisions of Section 10-38 of the County Code and the administrative procedures adopted pursuant to said section.
For all purchases of commodities and services, the trust shall comply with the provisions of Section 2-8.2 of the County Code and the administrative procedures adopted pursuant to said section.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
The Trust's budget requests shall be prepared and submitted in the same manner as the budget for a County department and will be considered as part of the Miami-Dade County budget process. The Trust's budget requests shall be prepared in a format prescribed by the County Manager.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-507. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 01-01, § 1, adopted Jan. 23, 2001, repealed section 2-507 in its entirety. Former section 2-507 pertained to an extension of the transition period and derived from Ord. No. 92-12, § 7, adopted Feb. 18, 1992.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-508. Applicability of Florida Open Government and Conflict of Interest Laws</catch_line>
<text>
The Trust shall at all times operate under the Florida Open Government Laws, including the "Sunshine Laws," Public Meeting Laws and Public Record Laws, and shall be governed by all State and County conflict of interest laws, as applicable, including the Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics ordinance, Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-509. Validity</catch_line>
<text>
If any section, subsection, sentence, clause or provision of this article is held invalid, the remainder of this article shall not be affected by such invalidity.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-510—2-520. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (72) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 92-12, adopted Feb. 18, 1992, amended the Code by the addition of provisions which have been included herein at the discretion of the editor as Art. XLVIII, §§ 2-501—2-509. (Back)
Section 1 of Ord. No. 09-70, adopted Sept. 1, 2009, renamed Art. XLVIII, Metro-Miami Action Plan Trust, to read as herein set out. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
