<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 30A URBAN RENEWAL</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_II._SOUTH_BEACH_REDEVELOPMENT_TR</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 30A-16. Incorporation of recitations as to purpose, authority, etc</catch_line>
<text>
The following recitations [from the preface to Ordinance No. 78-20] are hereby incorporated as a part of this article:
Whereas, the legislature of Florida enacted the Community Redevelopment Act of 1969 during the legislative session held during 1969; and
Whereas, all powers arising through the aforesaid enactment were conferred by that enactment upon counties with home rule charters, which counties in turn are authorized to delegate such powers to municipalities within their boundaries when such municipalities wish to undertake redevelopment projects within their respective municipal boundaries; and
Whereas, such authorization for counties to delegate such powers to municipalities is contained in Section 163.410, Florida Statutes, which states:

"163.410 Exercise of powers in counties with home rule charters
"In counties which have adopted home rule charters, the powers conferred by this part shall be exercised exclusively by the governing body of such County. However, the governing body of any such County which has adopted a home rule charter may, in its discretion, by resolution delegate the exercise of the powers conferred upon said County by this part within the boundaries of a municipality to the governing body of such a municipality. Such a delegation to a municipality shall confer only such powers upon a municipality as shall be specifically enumerated in the delegating resolution. Any power not specifically delegated shall be reserved exclusively to the governing body of the County.;" and
Whereas, the City of Miami Beach, acting through its own community redevelopment agency, indicated its wish to undertake a project which will involve the acquisition and redevelopment in accordance with a plan for redevelopment of that portion of Miami Beach known as South Beach and extending from Sixth Street on the north to Government Cut on the south and from the Atlantic Ocean on the east to Biscayne Bay on the west; and
Whereas, the redevelopment trust fund will provide payment for the construction, reconstruction or relocation of County facilities made necessary by the redevelopment project; and
Whereas, the City of Miami Beach on February 1, 1977, requested the County to adopt a resolution pursuant to the provisions of Section 163.410, Florida Statutes, delegating to the City of Miami Beach all powers then conferred by the statute upon Miami-Dade County, but only with regard to that portion of Miami Beach described in the preceding whereas clause, so that the said municipality could proceed to adopt its plan for redevelopment, and acquire and arrange for the redevelopment of the above described portion of the said City; and
Whereas, the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County passed on February 1, 1977, Resolution No. R-88-77, entitled:
"RESOLUTION DELEGATING ALL POWERS CONFERRED UPON Miami-Dade COUNTY UNDER THE COMMUNITY REDEVELOPMENT ACT OF 1969 UPON THE CITY OF MIAMI BEACH FOR THE ACQUISITION AND REDEVELOPMENT OF THE SOUTH BEACH AREA WITHIN MIAMI BEACH SUBJECT TO THE IMPLEMENTATION OF THE PLAN PRESENTED TO THE BOARD OF COUNTY COMMISSIONERS"; and

Whereas, the delegation of authority was expressly made subject to the implementation of the redevelopment plan presented that date to the Board of County Commissioners, with any substantial deviation being subject to the subsequent approval of the Board of County Commissioners; and
Whereas, a substantial modification of the plan was presented to the Board of County Commissioners on January 17, 1978, and approved by the Board through Resolution No. R-52-78; and
Whereas, the 1977 Florida legislature enacted Chapter 77-391, Laws of Florida, amending the Community Development Act of 1969, which is codified as Part III of Chapter 163, Florida Statutes, also known as Sections 163.330 through 163.450, Florida Statutes; and
Whereas, the City of Miami Beach approved Resolutions Nos. 77-15283, 77-15291 and 77-15413, adopted on March 2nd, March 30th and August 17th, 1977, respectively, approving modifications to the redevelopment plan of South Beach; and
Whereas, Chapter 77-391, Laws of Florida, created Section 163.387, Florida Statutes, permitting the establishment of redevelopment trust funds and the funding of the funds through the deposit in the funds of the increment in the income, proceeds, revenues, and funds of the County and municipality derived from or held in connection with its undertaking and carrying out of community redevelopment projects; and
Whereas, the additional redevelopment powers established by Chapter 77-391, Laws of Florida, including the authority to establish and fund a redevelopment trust fund were not delegated to the City of Miami Beach in Resolution No. R-88-77, passed on February 1st, 1977, or in Resolution No. R-52-78, passed on January 17th, 1978; and
Whereas, the establishment and funding of the redevelopment trust fund by such tax increment can only be effectuated through an ordinance of the Board of County Commissioners delegating the authority to establish a redevelopment trust fund to the City of Miami Beach; and
Whereas, the County is sympathetic to the project envisaged and proposed by the City of Miami Beach which will ultimately involve the expenditure of several hundreds of millions of dollars, which will be financed in part through revenue bonds to be issued by the City of Miami Beach and which is presently to be secured by such revenue sources as are provided by law, including the rents and revenues that individual projects and properties within the area of redevelopment will generate, the sale of properties by the City to individual entrepreneurs for redevelopment, the lease of a number of properties retained in ownership by the City, and revenues generated by increased assessed valuation of property resulting from the completed project; and
Whereas, the County desires to increase the viability of the project by delegating the authority to establish a redevelopment trust fund and funding it by the annual tax increment; and
Whereas, this Board desires to accomplish the purpose outlined in the memorandum from the County Manager, a copy of which is attached to this ordinance, for the reasons delineated therein; and
Whereas, the Board hereby finds that this delegation of power and ensuing appropriation of funds serves a public purpose;
now, therefore be it ordained by the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida, [as follows in this article].

</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30A-17. Delegation of authority to establish a redevelopment trust fund to the City of Miami Beach</catch_line>
<text>
The authority to create a redevelopment trust fund ("the fund"), as defined in Section 163.387, Florida Statutes, is hereby delegated to the City of Miami Beach pursuant to the provisions of Section 163.410, Florida Statutes, solely with respect to the area known as South Beach, which is generally bounded by Sixth Street on the north, Government Cut on the south, the Atlantic Ocean on the east, and Biscayne Bay on the west, and is legally described in the amended and restated redevelopment plan ("the community redevelopment project area"). This delegation is made subject to the provisions of Resolution No. R-88-77, adopted on February 1, 1977, Resolution No. R-52-78, adopted on January 17, 1978, and Resolution No. R-646-79, adopted on June 1, 1979, and so much therein as has been replaced by Resolution No. R-612-82, adopted on May 4, 1982, and by Resolution No. R-1056-84, adopted on September 4, 1984, and the implementation of the amended and restated redevelopment plan presented to the Board, the prior approval of which plan is hereby affirmed and ratified. This delegation is made so that the City may proceed with the implementation of a plan for redevelopment, and the acquisition of property and redevelopment of the aforesaid area through its municipally created community redevelopment agency.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30A-18. Appropriation of funds; calculation of increment</catch_line>
<text>
The County shall annually pay into the fund a sum equal to the increment in the income, proceeds, revenues and funds of the County derived from, or held in connection with, the community redevelopment project area, and the City's undertaking and carrying out of the community redevelopment project plan. The increment shall be determined annually and shall be that amount equal to ninety-five (95) percent of the difference between:
<section prefix = "a">
That amount of general Countywide operating ad valorem taxes levied each year by the County on taxable real property contained within the geographic boundaries of the community redevelopment project area; and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
That amount of general Countywide operating ad valorem taxes which would have been produced by the rate upon which the tax is levied each year by or for the County upon the total of the assessed value of the taxable real property in the community redevelopment project area, as shown upon the assessment rolls used in connection with the taxation of such property by the County, last equalized prior to the effective date of the city's Resolutions Nos. 77-15283, 77-15291 and 77-15413, adopted on March 2nd, March 30th and August 17th, 1977, respectively, approving the community redevelopment plan with modifications.

In calculating the increment, the amount of the ad valorem taxes levied based on the Countywide debt service on County bonds and other special purpose taxes shall be totally excluded from the calculation. All increment in this amount shall continue to be used for its voter-approve purpose and shall not be appropriated in any part to the fund.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30A-19. Obligation to appropriate; duration of obligation; accounting requirements for County increment</catch_line>
<text>
The County shall annually appropriate to the fund the tax increment due the fund by January first of each year. The County's obligation to annually appropriate to the fund shall commence immediately upon the effective date of this article [April 14, 1978] and continue until all loans, advances and indebtedness incurred as a result of the community redevelopment project and secured by a pledge of the tax increment funding granted by this article, as described in Section 163.385, Florida Statutes, have been paid in full or provision for their payment in full has been made. In no year shall the County's obligation to the fund exceed the amount of that year's tax increment as determined in Section 30A-18. In the final year in which existing indebtedness so supported is discharged, only so much of that year's tax increment as is needed to finally discharge that indebtedness shall be advanced by the County into the fund created pursuant to Section 30A-17. The County's increment contributions are to be accounted for as a separate revenue within the fund but may be combined with other revenues for the purpose of paying debt service.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30A-20. Review and approval of master bond indenture or other financing instrument or ordinance or resolution authorizing financing instruments; review of subsequent financing instruments to assure compliance with master indenture</catch_line>
<text>
The County Commission shall review and approve the initial master bond indenture or ordinance or resolution authorizing financing instruments and instruments of indebtedness such as bonds or tax anticipation notes as described in Section 163.385, Florida Statutes (1977), as to its provisions relating to refunding, prepayment and redemption, other provisions relating to the governance of financing instruments and instruments of indebtedness, the application of funds necessary to pay costs of necessary residential property acquisition, moving expenses and relocation benefits as provided under the revised redevelopment plan. Subsequent financing instruments or instruments of indebtedness prepared pursuant to the master indenture shall be reviewed by the County Manager and shall be approved unless he determines that the instruments do not conform with the terms of the approved initial master indenture and ordinance or resolution authorizing financing instruments.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30A-21. Relocation assistance trust fund</catch_line>
<text>
Out of the proceeds of each bond sale where such proceeds will be used for property acquisition which will result in displacement of individuals, families or businesses, there shall be withdrawn, placed in trust, and separately accounted for, such sums as are prescribed in the revised redevelopment plan to pay the costs of moving expenses and relocation benefits.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30A-22. Review of financial records; right of audit</catch_line>
<text>
The financial records for the fund shall be available for County inspection, and the County reserves the right of audit.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 30A-23. Liberal construction to effectuate public purpose</catch_line>
<text>
This article, being for a public purpose and for the welfare of the citizens of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall be liberally construed to effectuate the purposes thereof.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 30A-24—30A-50. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
</law>
