<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_VI._LICENSING_AND_REGULATION_OF_</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 31-601. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
For the purposes of this article, the following definitions shall apply:
<section prefix = "a">
The Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 or the ADA means the civil rights acts signed into law on July 26, 1990 as Public Law 101-336, 104 Stat. 327, as the same may be amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Applicant means an individual, partnership or corporation which applies for a for-hire license, permit, or chauffeur's registration, pursuant to the provisions of this article. "Applicant" shall also mean an individual, partnership or corporation which makes application, where applicable, to renew or transfer a for-hire license, permit or chauffeur's registration pursuant to the provisions of this article. In the case of partnerships and corporations, "applicant" shall also mean each individual with a partnership interest, each shareholder of the corporation as well as the corporate officers and directors.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Ancient limousine means a luxury motor vehicle as defined in section 320.086(1), Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Antique limousine means an antique luxury motor vehicle as defined in section 320.086(2), Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Chauffeur means a duly licensed driver registered with and authorized by the Consumer Services Department to operate a for-hire passenger motor vehicle.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Chauffeur registration means a registration card issued by the CSD.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Collectible limousine means a luxury motor vehicle of the age of twenty (20) or more years from the date of manufacture, equipped with an engine and parts of the age of twenty (20) years or more from the date of manufacture.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Commission means the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
County means Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
County Manager means the chief executive officer and head of the administrative branch of county government as provided in Article 3 of the Home Rule Charter of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
CSD means the Miami-Dade County Consumer Services Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Director means the CSD director or the director's designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
Fares or Rates means the charges established pursuant to this article to be paid by passengers for the transportation services provided by a for-hire passenger motor vehicle.
</section>
<section prefix = "n">
For compensation or compensation means for money, property, service, or anything of value, including tips and commissions.
</section>
<section prefix = "o">
For-hire means driving, operating, or managing a for-hire passenger motor vehicle, and includes all non-revenue producing operations of the passenger motor vehicle.
</section>
<section prefix = "p">
For-hire license means an annual, renewable license issued pursuant to this Article which authorizes the provision of for-hire transportation services and which may expire, be suspended or revoked.
</section>
<section prefix = "q">
For-hire passenger motor vehicle or limousine means any chauffeur-driven limousine as defined herein which engages in pre-arranged transportation of persons and their accompanying property for compensation over the public streets, but excluding ambulances and nonemergency medical transportation vehicles; vehicles used exclusively for the transportation of decedents and persons participating in funeral services; vehicles used solely to provide free transportation services for customers of the business establishment owning said vehicles; vehicles used solely to provide special transportation services for the Miami-Dade Transit Agency pursuant to a contract with Miami-Dade County; and rental or leased vehicles which rental or lease does not include a chauffeur; provided, however, that no vehicles excluded under this definition shall be used on a for-hire basis except as authorized by this article. Vehicles used to provide Miami-Dade Transit Agency special transportation services pursuant to a contract with Miami-Dade County are subject to the regulations contained in Article IV of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "r">
Good cause shall mean delay caused by circumstances beyond the control of the applicant.
</section>
<section prefix = "s">
In service means a for-hire vehicle which is displaying a valid, current operating permit or decal, as applicable, issued by the CSD.
</section>
<section prefix = "t">
Lease of a limousine vehicle means a written agreement for the transfer from a lessor to a lessee of the right to possess and use a motor vehicle, meeting the requirements of Chapter 521, Florida Statutes, for a scheduled term exceeding four (4) months.
</section>
<section prefix = "u">
Limousine means a "luxury limousine sedan," a "stretch limousine," a "super-stretch limousine," an "ancient limousine," an "antique limousine," or a "collectible limousine" and which provides service on a pre-arranged basis only, which is dispatched by its central business location.
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
Luxury limousine sedan or luxury sedan means a luxury, non-metered vehicle of a wheelbase size smaller than a stretch limousine, as defined by CSD.
</section>
<section prefix = "w">
Operate means to provide transportation services for compensation regulated by this article utilizing a for-hire passenger motor vehicle.
</section>
<section prefix = "x">
Operating permit means the valid and current vehicle decal issued to the license holder which authorizes a specific, registered vehicle to operate for-hire and which may expire, be suspended or revoked.
</section>
<section prefix = "y">
Operator means any person who has been issued a for-hire license.
</section>
<section prefix = "z">
Out of service means the removal of a for-hire vehicle from operation by removal of a valid, current operating permit and filing with the CSD a CSD form removing the vehicle from service.
<section prefix = "aa">
Own means a person who holds the legal title of a motor vehicle; or, in the event a motor vehicle is the subject of a security agreement or lease with an option to purchase with the debtor or lessee having the right to possession, then the debtor or lessee shall be deemed the owner.
</section>
<section prefix = "bb">
Pre-arranged or pre-arrange means a written or telephone reservation made at least one hour in advance by the person requesting service at the place of business of the for-hire license holder for the provision of limousine service for a specified period of time.
</section>
<section prefix = "cc">
Passenger means a person utilizing a for-hire limousine for the purpose of being transported to a destination, or a person who is awaiting the arrival of a prearranged for-hire limousine, and does not include the chauffeur.
</section>
<section prefix = "dd">
Person means any natural person(s), firm, partnership, association, corporation, or other business entity.
</section>
<section prefix = "ee">
Personnel authorized by the CSD means uniformed enforcement personnel and any other individual authorized by the director.
</section>
<section prefix = "ff">
Place of business means the specific Miami-Dade County, Broward County or Palm Beach County address where management of for-hire operations is provided and which is zoned for the appropriate business usage and matches the address on a current valid occupational license.
</section>
<section prefix = "gg">
Solicit means an appeal by bell, horn, whistle, words or gestures by a chauffeur or his or her agent directed at individuals or groups.
</section>
<section prefix = "hh">
Stage means to stop, park, or otherwise place a limousine vehicle in the loading or curbside area of a hotel, restaurant, shopping center, public sports facility, museum, theater, performing arts center or transportation facility when the limousine vehicle is not engaged in a prearranged, round trip or one way fare. A curbside or loading area shall not include a parking lot.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Street means any public street, avenue, road, boulevard, alley, lane, highway, sidewalk, public park, viaduct, or other public place accessible to the public, located in Miami-Dade County and used by motor vehicles.
</section>
<section prefix = "jj">
Stretch limousine means a sedan cut and stretched a minimum of forty-two (42) inches beyond its standard basis, manufactured to carry between six to eight (6—8) persons, excluding the driver.
</section>
<section prefix = "kk">
Super-stretch limousine means a luxury vehicle, as defined by CSD, stretched a minimum of one hundred twenty (120) inches beyond its standard basis and manufactured to carry nine (9) or more passengers, including the driver.
</section>
<section prefix = "ll">
Trade name or doing business as or (d/b/a) name means the county-approved name under which the for-hire license holder may provide for-hire passenger motor vehicle transportation services, and which name shall not duplicate the name of any other license holder.

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 31-602. For-hire limousine licenses</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Prohibition against unauthorized operations. It shall be unlawful for any person to use, drive, or operate or to advertise in any newspaper, airwaves transmission, telephone directory, or other medium accessible to the public that it offers for-hire limousine services or to cause or permit any other person to use, drive, or operate any for-hire limousine vehicle upon the streets of Miami-Dade County without first obtaining a Miami-Dade County for-hire license and maintaining it current and valid pursuant to the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Out-of County origin exception. Nothing in this article shall be construed to prohibit discharge within Miami-Dade County of any passenger lawfully picked up in another County and lawfully transported into Miami-Dade County. Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, (1) Any passenger lawfully picked up in another county, transported to, and discharged at any location within Miami-Dade County, may be picked up at the discharge location and returned to the county of origin as long as the transportation is part of a pre-arranged, round-trip fare pursuant to a written contract, the limousine has complied with all of the regulatory requirements of the other county and the county where the passenger is picked up has adopted a similar provision; and (2) A limousine from another county may pick up a passenger at either the Miami International Airport (MIA) or the Miami-Dade Seaport (Seaport) and transport said passenger directly to the limousine's county of origin as long as the transportation is part of a pre-arranged one-way continuous fare pursuant to a written contract, the passenger arrived at either the MIA or the Seaport, the limousine has complied with all of the regulatory requirements of the other county and the county where the passenger is picked up has adopted a similar provision. Pre-arranged means a written or telephone reservation made at least one hour in advance by the person requesting service at the place of business of the for-hire license holder for the provision of limousine service for a specified period of time. Any limousine that picks up or discharges passengers at either the MIA or the Seaport shall meet the MIA and the Seaport limousine requirements. A copy of the contract shall be in the possession of the chauffeur at all times and shall be made available to enforcement personnel upon request.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Application procedures. Every initial application for a for-hire license, renewal application, transfer, or amendment to a for-hire license shall be in writing, signed and sworn to by the applicant, and shall be filed with the CSD together with an investigative and processing fee which shall be nonrefundable. If the applicant is a corporation, the form shall be signed and sworn to by the president or vice-president, and the corporate secretary shall attest such signature and affix the corporate seal. If the applicant is a partnership, the form shall be signed and sworn to by a general partner. The application shall be on a form provided by the CSD and shall contain all information required thereon, including:
<section prefix = "1">
Sufficient information to identify the applicant, including but not limited to full legal name, and trade name, date of birth, telephone number, and residence address, of the applicant. If the applicant is a corporation, the foregoing information shall be provided for each officer, resident agent, director, and stockholder. If the applicant is a partnership, the foregoing information shall be provided for each partner. As part of such application, the applicant shall also disclose the foregoing information for any person who has any interest (legal, equitable, beneficial or otherwise) in the license. Post office box addresses will not be accepted hereunder. All corporate or partnership applicants shall be organized or qualified to do business under the laws of Florida and shall have a place of business in either Miami-Dade County, Broward County or Palm Beach County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The class or classes of transportation service which the applicant desires to furnish.
<section prefix = "i">
Limousine service:
<section prefix = "a">
Luxury limousine sedan;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Stretch limousine;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Super-stretch limousine;
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Ancient limousine;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Antique limousine;
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Collectible limousine.
<section prefix = "3">
A brief description of the kind(s) and type(s) of vehicles, seating capacity, seating arrangements, gross weight, mileage, and number of vehicles proposed to be used.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The names and addresses of at least three (3) residents of the County as references.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The trade name under which the applicant intends to operate and a description, where applicable, of a distinctive uniform and decorative color scheme including placement of numbers and other markings.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
A record and proof of all present and prior transportation business activities of the applicant during the past five (5) years.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
A record of all crimes to which the applicant has pled nolo contendere, pled guilty, or of which the applicant has been found guilty or been convicted, whether or not adjudication has been withheld within the five (5) years preceding the date of the application. The applicant shall have his or her fingerprints and photograph taken by the Miami-Dade Police Department. In the case of a corporate or partnership applicant, this information shall be obtained from all corporate officers and directors or partners, as the case may be. In the case of corporations, the above information shall be obtained from stockholders who own, hold or control five (5) percent or more of the corporation's issued and outstanding stock.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Two (2) credit references including at least one bank where the applicant has an active account. In lieu of the second credit reference, the applicant may submit alternative written evidence of financial trustworthiness.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Where applicable, the contract disclosing the terms and conditions of the proposed transfer, including amount of compensation which has been paid or is payable to the transferor and any other consideration given or to be given to the transferor in connection with the transfer of the for-hire license.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
A limousine management service plan which shall include:
<section prefix = "a">
Maintenance facilities and maintenance program for the upkeep of vehicles operating under the for-hire license.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A system for handling complaints, accidents and property left by a passenger in the for-hire motor vehicle.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
A central place of business, with a properly listed telephone for receiving all calls relating to for-hire vehicle service and where the operator will maintain the business records and daily manifests as set forth in this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
A driver training program which the applicant will utilize to ensure quality service.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
A proposal for submission of appropriate insurance coverage as required by section 31-608 of this article.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
A sworn statement signed by the applicant that all the information provided by the applicant is true and correct.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Any additional information as the Director shall require to enforce the provisions of this article.
<section prefix = "d">
Investigation of for-hire license applicants. The director shall investigate each application and accompanying required documents and reject any application that is not properly filed or that is incomplete or untrue in whole or in part. The director may approve or deny the issuance of for-hire licenses as specified in this chapter on such terms and conditions as the public interest may require. The director's decision to reject or to deny may be appealed in accordance with this chapter.
An applicant shall not be eligible for a for-hire license if he/she/it:
<section prefix = "1">
Has misrepresented or concealed a material fact on his, her, or its application;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Is an alien who is not duly authorized to work by the immigration laws or the Attorney General of the United States;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Is a user of alcohol or drugs whose current use would constitute a direct threat to property or the safety of others;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Has pled nolo contendere, pled guilty, been found guilty or been convicted of a felony within the last five (5) years, regardless of whether adjudication has been withheld, unless his or her civil or residency rights have been restored;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Has pled nolo contendere, pled guilty, been found guilty or been convicted of any crime wherein a for-hire vehicle was employed whether or not adjudication has been withheld;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Has pled nolo contendere, pled guilty, been found guilty, or been convicted of any felony, regardless of whether adjudication has been withheld, involving moral turpitude relating to sex, the use of a deadly weapon, homicide, violence against a law enforcement officer under § 775.0823, Florida Statutes, or is a habitual violent felony offender under § 775.084, Florida Statutes;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Has violated any condition, limitation, or restriction of a for-hire license imposed by the director or commission where the director deems the violation to be grounds for denial;
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Was enjoined by a court of competent jurisdiction from engaging in the for-hire business or was enjoined by a court of competent jurisdiction with respect to any of the requirements of this chapter;
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Has as a stockholder, officer, director, or partner of a corporation or partnership committed an act or omission which would be cause for denying a for-hire license to the officer, director, stockholder, or partner as an individual;
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Failed to comply with the terms of a cease and desist order, notice to correct a violation or any other lawful order of the director;
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Does not have a place of business located in either Miami-Dade County, Broward County or Palm Beach County, Florida;
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Has any unsatisfied civil penalty or judgment pertaining to for-hire operation;
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Has had a for-hire license issued by Miami-Dade County revoked;
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
Has within the last five (5) years plead nolo contendere, pled guilty, been found guilty, or been convicted of any misdemeanor, regardless of whether adjudication has been withheld, involving moral turpitude relating to sex; or
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
Has within the last ten (10) years pled nolo contendere, pled guilty, been found guilty, or been convicted, regardless of whether adjudication has been withheld, of any offense involving trafficking in narcotics. After said ten-year period, such a person shall only be eligible if and when his or her civil or residency rights have been restored.

<section prefix = "e">
Conditions for obtaining a for-hire license. No for-hire license shall be issued unless the applicant:
<section prefix = "1">
Has paid an initial or annual license fee;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Has provided an adequate management plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Has submitted proof of insurance required by this article;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Has ensured that the for-hire limousine to be operated under the applicant's for-hire license has passed all required vehicle inspections. Failure of the applicant to meet all of the foregoing requirements within forty-five (45) days after notification of conditional approval shall cause the license not to be issued. If the applicant believes he, she or it cannot meet the foregoing requirements within the forty-five-day period, the applicant may, prior to expiration of such forty-five-day period, request in writing a reasonable extension from the director. If the request states good cause for an extension, the director may grant such a reasonable extension as the director finds is in the public interest.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Vehicles authorized to operate under a for-hire license.
<section prefix = "1">
Except for luxury limousine sedans, limousines shall be solely owned or leased by the for-hire license holder. Under no circumstances shall a limousine license holder require a chauffeur to purchase or lease a limousine motor vehicle. This requirement shall become effective one (1) year after the adoption of this article when a new vehicle is placed into service as provided by Section 31-609(b).
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The number of vehicles authorized to operate under for-hire license are as follows:
<section prefix = "a">
Luxury limousine sedan for-hire license holders shall operate only one vehicle per for-hire license.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Stretch, super-stretch, ancient, antique, or collectible limousine license holders may operate more than one vehicle per license, after each such vehicle has obtained a valid and current operating permit.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Issuance and replacement of for-hire license.
<section prefix = "1">
Issuance. Each for-hire license shall be on a form developed by the CSD and shall be signed by the director. Each for-hire license shall, at a minimum, contain the name and the business address of the license holder, date of issuance, its expiration date and such additional terms, conditions, provisions, and limitations as were imposed during the approval process.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Replacement. The director may issue a replacement license to any license holder upon application, payment of a nonrefundable replacement fee and presentation of proof or a sworn affidavit that the license has been lost or stolen.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Expiration of and renewal process for for-hire license. For-hire licenses may be issued for such periods as specified in the Administrative Order establishing the fees. The CSD may establish staggered license terms to ease administration of the renewal process. Each renewal shall be submitted no less than thirty (30) days prior to expiration of the current initial or annual for-hire license together with payment of a license fee. As part of the renewal process, the original application shall be updated and verified by the applicant on forms supplied by the CSD. The director shall deny any renewal application that is not timely, is not properly filed, is incomplete, is untrue in whole or in part, or results in a determination by the director that the applicant has failed to satisfy the requirements of subsection 31-602(c), (d) or (e). Renewal applications shall additionally include disclosure of all interests in the for-hire license (legal, beneficial, equitable or otherwise) and a sworn statement as to the number of months which each permitted for-hire vehicle operated during the preceding license year. Appeal of the denial of a renewal application shall be in accordance with this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Grace period. License holders shall have a grace period of up to thirty (30) days after expiration of their license in which to renew same provided, however, that all operations shall cease on the date of license expiration and the license holder shall also pay a late fee over and above the annual license fee. All for-hire licenses which have not been renewed on or before thirty (30) days after their expiration shall automatically be deemed revoked.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Rules pertaining to change in control of the for-hire license. Except as provided in Section 31-602(n), no for-hire license shall be assigned, transferred, or sold (either outright or under a conditional sales contract). Except as provided in Section 31-602(n), any change in the ownership structure of a corporation or partnership where at least five (5) percent of the shares of said corporation or at least five (5) percent of the partnership interest is assigned, sold or transferred to another shall be deemed a sale and shall immediately terminate the license and a new for-hire license application shall be filed. The for-hire transportation service may continue to operate provided that such application has been filed with the CSD within thirty (30) days of the change in accordance with Section 31-602 and be accompanied by an investigatory and processing fee.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Rules of operation. For-hire license holders shall abide by all rules and regulations applicable to for-hire license holders and shall be subject to the enforcement provisions contained in this chapter and chapter 8CC of the Miami-Dade County Code. A for-hire license holder shall comply with the following regulations:
<section prefix = "1">
Every operator shall collect and file on a daily basis all manifests and trip sheets for each for-hire limousine. The operator shall furnish the forms for each manifest to the chauffeur, which forms shall be approved by the County. Operators shall not destroy, mutilate, alter, or otherwise deface any daily manifests without CSD approval. All manifests shall be available for inspection and copying by the CSD or any police agency during regular business hours and shall be retained for one (1) year;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Shall maintain a record of all requests for service for each passenger transport request received by telephone or made in writing or pursuant to a corporate charge account which shall minimally include the following information: name of passenger or corporation requesting service, assigned vehicle number, date and time of service request, service provision, including charge accounts, and origin and destination of each trip. All records must be made available for inspection and copying within one business day of such request by the CSD or any police agency during regular business hours and shall be retained for one (1) year;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
No for-hire license holder, chauffeur, or any other person shall directly or indirectly provide compensation in any form to any individual or entity or engage in any activity in connection with the payment of compensation, for the right to pick up passengers, or provide limousine service from any hotel, motel, apartment, restaurant, nightclub, bar, or any other business establishment, or public facility. The license or registration of any for-hire license holder, or chauffeur violating this provision shall be subject to suspension for up to six (6) months and/or revocation in accordance with the provisions of Section 31-612 or other appropriate enforcement action as provided in this chapter;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
It shall be a violation of this article for any individual or entity to accept compensation in any form, either directly or indirectly, from any passenger service company, for-hire license holder, chauffeur, or any other person for the right to pick up passengers or provide limousine service from any hotel, motel, apartment, restaurant, nightclub, bar, or any other business establishment or public facility;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Each operator shall maintain accurate records of all revenues, all associated expenses, capital expenditures, and other financial and operating information as may be required by the CSD. The revenue records shall include charge account contracts that reflect rates charged to all passengers. The CSD shall be granted access to these records for the purpose of inspection and copying same upon five (5) days prior notice. All such records and information shall be confidential except that they will become public records for the purpose of rate hearings, revocation or suspension hearings. Each operator shall annually furnish financial and operating information to the CSD on forms and in the manner prescribed by the CSD;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Shall maintain a log of all customer complaints;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Shall maintain quarterly vehicle accident records for all vehicles operated in the prior quarter;
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Shall hold any personal property deposited in the lost and found facility for a period of six (6) months, at the end of which time the personal property shall become the property of the finder. A record of personal property reported to or deposited at the lost and found facility shall be kept for at least one (1) year;
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Comply with applicable federal law, Florida law, and ordinances, rules and regulations of the County applicable to the operation of for-hire vehicles;
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Immediately report any change of address;
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Maintain all records pertaining to the for-hire operations of a vehicle at the place of business for one year and make same available for inspection during the regular business hours of the license holder. When requested by the CSD, the license holder shall provide copies of the records;
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Obtain the operating permit for each for-hire vehicle operated pursuant to authority of the for-hire license and pay all application and vehicle inspection fees;
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Not permit or authorize any chauffeur or other person to operate any for-hire vehicle without that vehicle's current valid operating permit being displayed therein;
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
Not allow any person to operate a for-hire vehicle who is not a Miami-Dade County registered chauffeur;
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
Not allow or permit any person to operate a for-hire vehicle without current, valid, and sufficient insurance coverage as required in this chapter;
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
Register and have inspected by CSD all vehicles to be placed into service and all vehicles taken out of service;
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
Not permit or authorize anyone to drive any for-hire vehicle unless the brakes, steering mechanism, tires, horn, windshield wipers, side and rearview mirrors, and all lighting devices are in good working order, and the vehicle meets all other applicable vehicle standards as set forth in this chapter;
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
Not allow or permit any person to operate a for-hire vehicle while his or her ability or alertness is so impaired or so likely to become impaired through fatigue, illness, or any other cause, as to make it unsafe for the chauffeur to begin or continue to drive the for-hire vehicle;
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
Not refuse or neglect to transport or to dispatch to or from any place in the county any orderly person requesting service. Every deaf or hard of hearing person, totally or partially blind person, or physically disabled person shall have the right to be accompanied by a service animal specially trained for the purpose, without being required to pay an extra charge for the service animal;
</section>
<section prefix = "20">
A limousine for-hire license holder shall be prohibited from leasing a for-hire license to another person or entity, or requiring that a chauffeur pay any amount of compensation for the right to operate the vehicle authorized by the for-hire license;
</section>
<section prefix = "21">
A limousine for-hire license holder shall, except as provided herein, be prohibited from entering into a written agreement with an existing for-hire limousine license holder or passenger service company as defined in Article II. Notwithstanding the foregoing, a luxury sedan limousine license holder who has been issued three (3) or less luxury sedan limousine licenses may enter into a written agreement with an existing for-hire limousine license holder or passenger service company for the provision of the following services as stated in Section 31-602(c)(10). Under no circumstances shall an existing for-hire limousine license holder or passenger service company require a sedan limousine license holder to purchase any services or goods others than those stated in Section 31-602(c)(10);
</section>
<section prefix = "22">
Not allow a driver to solicit or pick up passengers other than by prearrangement through a person located at the limousine license holder's place of business;
</section>
<section prefix = "23">
Disclose to the customer if a vehicle substitution is necessary and provide the customer with an opportunity to cancel a contract based thereon;
</section>
<section prefix = "24">
Not allow a driver to stage;
</section>
<section prefix = "25">
A holder of a luxury limousine sedan license, or stretch limousine license, or super stretch limousine license shall provide limousine services with not more than ten (10) percent of the limousine service provided being paid for in cash;
</section>
<section prefix = "26">
A holder of an ancient, antique or collectible limousine license shall provide limousine service with not more than fifty (50) percent of the limousine service provided being paid for in cash.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Responsibility for violations of chapter. The holder of a for-hire license shall be held responsible for any applicable violation of this article arising from the operation of the for-hire vehicle authorized under the holder's for-hire license and shall be subject to the penalties provided in this chapter for any such violation. In addition, his, her, or its license shall be subject to suspension or revocation for any such violation. Charges against or penalties imposed on a for-hire license holder or for-hire chauffeur for the same or related violations shall not relieve the for-hire license holder of responsibility under this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
As part of the annual renewal of a for-hire license, each operator shall certify on a form provided by the CSD the number of months during the preceding year that he, she, it operated and provided the service authorized by the for-hire license. Failure to operate for at least nine (9) months during the preceding year shall result in automatic revocation of such license. Operations within the thirty-day grace period provided in subsection (i) shall not be counted for purposes of determining compliance with the requirements of the two (2) preceding sentences.
</section>
<section prefix = "n">
No for-hire limousine luxury sedan license shall be assigned, sold, (either outright or under a conditional sales contract) or transferred without prior County approval. Any change in the ownership structure of a corporation or partnership where at least five (5) percent of the shares of said corporation or at least five (5) percent of the partnership interest is assigned, sold or transferred to another shall be deemed a sale for the purposes of this section. The Director is authorized to approve assignments, sales, or transfers when requested by submission of an application (which discloses the information specified in and is signed and sworn to in accordance with the requirements of subsections (c) and (d) of this section) and payment of a transfer investigative and processing fee and after an investigation and determination, based on the criteria set forth in this section. An assignee, buyer, or transferee shall not begin operating the limousine luxury sedan license during the pendency of the application approval process. If the County approves an application to assign, sell, or transfer a limousine luxury sedan license, the assignor's, seller's, or transferor's limousine luxury sedan license shall be suspended until the County reissues the limousine luxury sedan licenses to the assignee, buyer, or transferee. Provided, however, that the County shall reissue the limousine luxury sedan licenses to the assignee, buyer, or transferee at a cost not to exceed the annual, limousine luxury sedan license renewal fee. Any limousine luxury sedan license issued pursuant to Section 31-603(c)(ii)—(v) shall not be assigned, sold or transferred for a period of five (5) years from the date of issuance, except upon: (1) the sale of the luxury sedan license holder's business within the five-year period; (2) the sale of shares or the corporation or partnership as provided in this subsection; or (3) the transfer of all for-hire luxury sedan licenses by an individual to a person as defined in Section 31-601. No transfer shall be approved that results in a license holder holding or controlling more than thirty (30) percent of the total number of luxury limousine sedan licenses issued by the County. Appeals of the Director's decision shall be made pursuant to the requirements of this Chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "o">
It shall be unlawful to operate any vehicle as a for-hire motor vehicle without first having obtained a for-hire license and an operating permit specifically relating to said vehicle. The for-hire operating permit shall, at all times, be displayed within the vehicle and shall be available for inspection by any police officer or authorized agent of the CSD.
</section>
<section prefix = "p">
Conversion of super-stretch limousine certificates of transportation to a limousine for-hire license. Within ninety (90) days after the date of enactment of this article, super-stretch limousine certificate of transportation license holders shall obtain a stretch or super-stretch limousine for-hire license and corresponding operating permit for each vehicle operated thereunder. Such permits shall be obtained pursuant to the provisions of this Chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "q">
Rules for existing for-hire limousine licenses. Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, any person who converts an existing for-hire limousine license after the date of adoption of this article pursuant to Section 31-603(c)(i) and is providing luxury limousine service may lease the luxury limousine sedan license to a person who meets the requirements of Section 31-602(c) and (d), including payment of the application and investigatory fee, until such license is assigned, sold or transferred as provided in Section 31-602(n).
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 00-139, § 1, 11-14-00; Ord. No. 09-26, § 1, 4-7-09)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 31-603. Luxury limousine sedan for-hire limousine licenses</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Rules governing the distribution of luxury limousine sedan for-hire licenses.
<section prefix = "i">
Upon the effective date of this article, the director shall be authorized to issue the number of luxury limousine sedan for-hire licenses pursuant to subsections (c)(i), (ii), (iii) and (iv). In 2006, 2007 and 2008, the director shall be authorized to issue forty-two (42) luxury limousine sedan licenses each calendar year. The CSD director shall administratively issue such licenses pursuant to the provisions of this section.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Method for distribution of new luxury limousine sedan for-hire licenses. Issuance of luxury limousine sedan for-hire licenses shall be issued by the CSD director in accordance with the following procedures:
<section prefix = "i">
Random selection or lottery for new issues. A random selection or lottery process shall be conducted as determined by the director. The random selection or lottery process shall be conducted by an individual who shall not have responsibility for the enforcement of this chapter. All fees and applications must be received by the CSD no later than fifty (50) calendar days after the announcement of the lottery.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Separate lottery conducted by CSD. If, due to revocation, cancellation, or lapse, there are ten (10) or more luxury sedan licenses which may be issued, the CSD shall have authority to issue such licenses utilizing the procedures of this section. In such event, the applicable deadlines for submission of applications and for conduct of the lottery may be administratively determined by the director.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Conditions for participating in random selection or lottery process. All applicants shall pay a non-refundable fee to participate in each random selection or lottery process. Each application to participate in the random selection or lottery process shall be filed in accordance with Section 31-602 of this Chapter, including payment of the investigative and processing fee provided therein. In addition to the eligibility requirements found elsewhere in this Chapter, an applicant shall not be eligible to participate in the random selection or lottery process if he/she/it has, during the three (3) years prior to application, pled nolo contendere, pled guilty or been found guilty of a total of four (4) or more violations of any one or combination of the following sections of this Chapter: Section 31-602 (a); Section 31-603 (b); and/or Section 31-607(a). The CSD shall disqualify applicants who do not meet the requirements of this Chapter from participation in the lottery. The director's decision shall be final.
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
No luxury limousine sedan for-hire license shall be issued until the applicant has met the provisions of Section 31-602 within forty-five (45) days after the applicant has been notified of his or her selection. If the applicant believes he or she cannot meet the requirements within the 45-day period, the applicant may, prior to expiration of such 45-day period, request in writing, a reasonable extension from the CSD director. The CSD director may grant such a reasonable extension that the director finds is in the public interest.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Conditions for initial issuance of luxury limousine sedan licenses:
<section prefix = "i">
Each holder of a current and valid for-hire license to operate a limousine shall, upon application, receive one luxury limousine sedan license for each such license held. Such application shall be filed no later than forty-five (45) days after the effective date of this article. Failure to file such application within the prescribed period shall result in forfeiture of such option.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Each lessee of a current and valid for-hire limousine license as of January 1, 1999, shall, upon application and the submission of documentation requested by CSD, receive one (1) luxury limousine sedan license for each for-hire limousine license leased prior to January 1, 1999. Such application shall be filed no later than forty-five (45) days after the effective date of this article. Failure to file such application within the prescribed period shall result in forfeiture of such option.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Each person in whose name continuous intra Miami-Dade County luxury limousine service was offered prior to January 1, 1999 shall be issued one (1) luxury limousine sedan license for each for-hire luxury limousine sedan operated if the applicant: (1) submits an application which is approved by the CSD; (2) pays the applicable application investigative and processing fees: (3) provides proof of continuous, intra Miami-Dade County luxury limousine sedan service, as required herein; and (4) enters into a settlement agreement with the County, which shall, among other things, include a promise that the applicant's future limousine operations will comply with the requirements of the Code and requires the payment of a five hundred dollar ($500.00) per vehicle penalty for each year that a vehicle has been operated illegally. The settlement agreement may provide for payment of such penalty over a period of years. In order to demonstrate continuous, intra Miami-Dade County luxury limousine sedan service before January 1, 1999, the applicant shall submit, in addition to any other information required by the County, the following documents: (1) annual federal tax records relating to luxury limousine services showing the payment of taxes consistent with the provision of luxury limousine services as stated in the application; (2) a list and description of all vehicles operated, vehicle identification numbers and the years of operation; (3) annual revenues per vehicle; (4) evidence of automobile liability insurance as required by Florida Statutes for each vehicle operated; (5) the number of hours operated per year, per vehicle; (6) proof that each vehicle provided at least 240 intra Miami-Dade County trips for the 12-month calendar period prior to January 1, 1999; (7) occupational licenses for each year the applicant provided for-hire limousine service from a municipality in Miami-Dade County, Miami-Dade County, or in the absence of an occupational license from the preceding governmental entities, an occupational license from a municipality in Broward or Palm Beach Counties, or from Broward or Palm Beach Counties; (8) manifests for each trip provided by each vehicle; (9) Articles of Incorporation, if required by law; (10) fictitious name registrations, if required by law; (11) annual renewals of Articles of Incorporation and fictitious name registrations, if required by law; (12) the name, address and telephone number for all chauffeurs who drove each luxury limousine and the dates of employment; and (13) a notarized affidavit, signed under oath, that the submitted application and documents are true and genuine. The CSD shall disqualify applicants who do not meet the requirements of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
After totaling the number of for-hire luxury limousine sedan licenses issued pursuant to (c)(i), (ii) and (iii), twenty (20) percent of the total number of issued luxury limousine sedan licenses to be issued or 100 luxury limousine sedan licenses, whichever number is greater, shall be distributed through a random selection or lottery process to taxicab chauffeurs who as of January 1, 1999, were providing taxicab service in compliance with the requirements of Chapter 31 of the Code. The applicant shall be required to furnish such documentation as shall be required by the CSD.
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
If, in the future, additional luxury limousine sedan for-hire licenses are to be issued, all applicants must meet the requirements of Section 31-602 and Section 603 and, shall be distributed as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
Two-thirds (2/3) to holders of a current and valid limousine for-hire license; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
One-third (1/3) to applicants who are not holders of current and valid limousine for-hire license.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "vi">
No lottery applicant may apply for more than ten (10) luxury limousine sedan licenses.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Renewals. Additional rule for renewal of luxury limousine sedan for-hire licenses. Failure to use a for-hire license during any nine (9) month period shall be deemed abandonment and shall result in automatic revocation of the for-hire license.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Leasing the for-hire license. A luxury limousine sedan license shall not be leased to another party.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 00-139, § 1, 11-14-00; Ord. No. 06-110, § 1, 7-6-06)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 31-604. Establishing limousine rates</catch_line>
<text>
Except as otherwise provided herein, the Commission shall establish minimum rates for luxury limousine sedan, stretch limousine, super-stretch limousines, antique limousines, ancient limousines and collectible limousines operating in Miami-Dade County. Such rates shall be established, altered, amended, revised, increased, or decreased in accordance with the following procedures:
<section prefix = "1">
The CSD, at two-year intervals or upon request of the Commission or the County Manager, shall investigate and prepare a report concerning the existing rates for luxury sedans, ancient limousines, antique limousines, collectible limousines, stretch, and super stretch limousines. Said investigation shall specify the relative changes in the consumer price index over the preceding two-year period and shall quantify what the rates would be if the currently approved minimum limousine rates were adjusted for such change. Such investigation may also consider the financial records of the industry to determine revenues or expenses when requested by the Commission or County Manager.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The CSD's report shall be forwarded to the County Manager who shall prepare a recommendation to the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
A public hearing concerning rates shall be scheduled at which time all interested parties shall have an opportunity to be heard. The Commission shall consider the CSD's report, the County Manager's recommendation, and all evidence produced at the hearing and, by resolution, shall determine and set the appropriate rates as may be in the public interest; provided, however, limousine minimum rates shall be no less than three and one-third (31/3) times the hourly rate of taxicabs.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 31-605. Chauffeur's registration</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful for any person to drive a limousine over any street in Miami-Dade County without first having obtained a chauffeur's registration from the CSD pursuant to Chapter 31 of this Code. No later than January 1, 2002, initial limousine chauffeurs shall be required to complete an apprentice program as prescribed by the CSD.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 31-606. Duties of Consumer Services Department</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
In addition to the duties and responsibilities specified in this article, the CSD shall be charged with the following duties and responsibilities:
<section prefix = "1">
Process, investigate, and prepare all reports required by this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Investigate and prepare reports on alleged violations of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Enforce the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Attempt to resolve complaints received from any source concerning the industry.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Issue, deny, suspend, and revoke all for-hire licenses and chauffeurs' registrations pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, and maintain appropriate files regarding same.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Prepare and conduct or cause to be conducted a training and orientation program for chauffeurs and a training and orientation for for-hire license holders.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Develop and implement, in cooperation with the industry, service expansion and improvements.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Provide technical assistance to the industry.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Create and render technical assistance to a for-hire vehicle advisory group comprised of representatives from consumers, the industry, transportation-related interests, municipalities, and public interest organizations.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Develop a standardized reporting technique for operators after consultation with a for-hire vehicle advisory group.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Assign an exclusive number to be displayed on each for-hire vehicle operating in Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Provide a system to handle complaints of municipal officials relating to for-hire service within such municipalities and expedite the solution of same.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Perform any other functions assigned by the County Manager.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
Coordinate cooperative enforcement activities with municipalities, including implementing procedures for the disposition of fine revenues collected.
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
Prepare and implement, in coordination and after consultation with the industry, changes, amendments, or modifications to administrative orders establishing fees pursuant to this article and provide the industry with at least ten (10) days notice prior to consideration of such changes, amendments or modifications by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
Upon court order have closed and sealed unlicensed service provider establishments in accordance with this article.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Director may propose and the County Manager may promulgate further rules and regulations to carry out the provisions of this article, which rules and regulations, when approved by the Board of County Commissioners, shall have the force and effect of the law.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Except for the fees established by the County Manager and approved by the Commission for for-hire vehicles providing transportation of persons and their baggage from Miami International Airport and from the Port of Miami, whenever in this article a fee is charged or is required to be paid, the amount of such fee shall be established by administrative order of the County Manager and approved by the Commission. Such fees shall be deposited in a separate Miami-Dade County fund and shall be used exclusively to accomplish the regulatory purposes of this article. The amount of each fee established hereunder shall be reasonably related to the cost of the services and regulation provided therefor.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 00-139, § 1, 11-14-00)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 31-607. Operating permits</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It shall be unlawful for any for-hire vehicle to be operated in Miami-Dade County without first obtaining a Miami-Dade County operating permit and maintaining such permit current and valid in accordance with this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Before any for-hire vehicle shall be operated, the license holder shall make separate application to CSD for a permit for each motor vehicle to be operated under such for-hire license. Each application shall be accompanied by a permit fee, which shall be non-refundable. Each permit application shall be in writing on a form provided by the CSD. The application shall state the name and license number of the for-hire license holder and shall state the make, model year of manufacture, VIN number, and state license plate number of the vehicle to be operated. Such application shall be accompanied by proof that the for-hire license holder owns the vehicle. No permit shall be issued until the applicant has presented proof of the insurance coverage required by this article and the for-hire vehicle has passed all required vehicle inspections.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Permits shall be separately numbered and shall identify the vehicle to which they apply. It shall be unlawful to operate a for-hire vehicle without a current, valid operating permit displayed within such vehicle.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Each operating permit may be issued for up to a one (1) year period. The term of the permit shall be concurrent with the term of the for-hire license and may be renewed upon compliance with this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Operating permits shall not be transferred, assigned, or leased.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
In the event any motor vehicle for which a permit has been issued shall become unsafe to operate or its body or seating facilities become so damaged, deteriorated, or unclean as to render said vehicle unfit for public use, CSD may suspend the permit until such time as the condition is remedied; provided, that no such suspension shall be effective until the permit holder or vehicle driver has received notice of the particular conditions to be remedied.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 00-139, § 1, 11-14-00)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 31-608. Insurance requirements</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
No for-hire motor vehicle shall be permitted to operate without the license holder having first obtained and filed with the CSD a certificate of insurance on forms provided by the CSD for each for-hire motor vehicle showing the federal vehicle identification number, a vehicle description, and the for-hire license number, and shall list the for-hire license holder, each chauffeur the license holder allows to operate the vehicle, and the owner of the vehicle as insureds under an automobile liability insurance policy with limits of liability no less than one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00) per person, and three hundred thousand dollars ($300,000.00) per occurrence for bodily injury, and fifty thousand dollars ($50,000.00) per occurrence for property damage. Additionally, the certificate of insurance shall specify coverage for complete 24-hour vehicle operations for all drivers who have a Miami-Dade County chauffeur's registration, regardless of where operated or whether engaged in for-hire operations, and shall state the limits of automobile liability and property damage coverage. Failure to provide current certificates of insurance or to maintain appropriate insurance coverage for each for-hire vehicle shall be grounds for revocation of the for-hire license.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Scope of Insurance. The insurance required in this section shall be issued by an insurer that is a member of the Florida Insurance Guaranty Association. Insurance coverage shall be for a policy term of at least six (6) months. Nothing in this insurance policy or declaration shall permit binders, deductibles, self insurance, or any provision requiring the insured to reimburse the insurance company for claims.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Each automobile liability insurance policy shall be endorsed to provide for thirty (30) days' notice by registered mail to the CSD or any material change, cancellation, or expiration. No policy will be accepted for a shorter period than six (6) months.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Unless an operator furnishes the CSD with satisfactory evidence of the required insurance coverage prior to the expiration of the thirty (30) days' notice specified in subsection (c) of this section, or upon a third notice of cancellation within twelve (12) months, the for-hire license shall be suspended forthwith by the Director and surrendered to the CSD pending a hearing to determine whether said for-hire license should be revoked. This automatic suspension requirement will not pertain to a for-hire motor vehicle when its insurer withdraws from Florida and cancels its policies, or when the policy is canceled through no fault of the operator.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Examination of Insurance Policy. The CSD reserves the right to require submission of a certified copy of or to examine the original policies of insurance including but not limited to endorsements, amendments, exclusions, riders, any additional contracts between the insured and the insurer and applications to confirm the existence of the required insured coverage.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 00-139, § 1, 11-14-00)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 31-609. Vehicle standards</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
In addition to the applicable Federal Motor Vehicle Safety requirements in 49 Code of Federal Regulations, part 571, and Florida Statutes, the following vehicle standards shall apply to all for-hire motor vehicles operated under the provisions of this article. It is the operator's responsibility to insure that each vehicle meets the following standards and minimum inspection requirements:
<section prefix = "1">
Brakes within allowable parameters as provided by test equipment readings for stopping effectiveness. There shall be no leaks in lines, hoses, fittings, or parts; hoses shall not be cracked or frayed; there shall be no audible air leaks in air brake system.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
License, permit or inspection decals, as applicable, shall be correctly displayed and be clearly visible from the outside of the vehicle;
<section prefix = "a">
Chauffeur registration, operating permit number, rate card, passenger advisory, and any additional information as may be required shall be displayed within the vehicle in accordance with the instructions of the CSD.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Exterior vehicle signage and markings shall be as required by the CSD.
<section prefix = "3">
Inside rear-view mirror and a mirror on each side of vehicle.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
A functioning speedometer and odometer indicating speed in miles per hour and a functioning odometer indicating distance in miles.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Functioning windows, door handles, and latches. The primary and secondary hood/trunk/rear access door latches shall be fully operable.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
A functioning interior light within the passenger compartment. If the light becomes defective, the operator must correct the defect on the very next day or remove the vehicle from service at that time.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
An operating air-conditioning system that provides cooled and heated air. If the air-conditioning system becomes inoperable, the vehicle must be removed from service until such system is repaired. Maximum output temperature will be based on a sliding scale chart which takes outside air temperature and relative humidity into account. Output temperature will be taken at center duct with controls set for maximum cooling.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
The vehicle exterior must be free of grime, oil, or other substances and free from cracks, breaks, dents and damaged paint that detracts from the overall appearance of the vehicle and that could harm, injure, soil, or impair the passenger or his or her personal belongings.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Equipped with hubcaps or wheel covers, on all four (4) wheels. If not on the vehicle, the operator must put them on the vehicle the next day.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Bumpers/mouldings/guards shall be installed/replaced as originally manufactured except for moldings on side panel doors.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
The interior of the trunk, or rear portion of for-hire vehicles, shall be free from dirt, grime, oil, trash, or other material which could soil items placed therein and free of protruding metal or other objects that could damage items placed therein.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
The passenger compartment must be clean, free from torn upholstery or floor coverings, damaged or broken seats, and protruding sharp edges. All equipment in the interior of the vehicle shall be safely and adequately secured. There shall be no holes opening to the passenger compartment from the underbody.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
A horn which shall be audible.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
The driver's vision must be unobstructed on all four (4) sides.
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
Safe tires no recaps shall be used. Maximum allowable treadwear shall be where tread is level with wear bar, or 2/32 inches when measured at three random places in tire tread. The tires shall be inflated to manufacturer's specifications and free of cuts, cracks, bulges or exposed belts.
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
Front-end and rear-end alignment shall be within allowable parameters as provided by test equipment readings for alignment.
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
Wiper blades must be able to clean glass when wet and the rubber element shall not be torn, ripped, or loose.
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
All lights shall be operable including four-way flasher, turn and signal, clearance, warning, marker, brakes, taillight, license plate, backup, and parking light. All lights must be of correct color and properly positioned as required by Florida Statutes and regulations. All dome lights must be operable with lens in place.
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
Reflectors and lenses shall not be cracked or missing and must be of correct color and properly positioned.
</section>
<section prefix = "20">
Both low and high beam headlights shall be operable, and within test equipment allowable readings.
</section>
<section prefix = "21">
Glass shall not be broken or cracked and chips must be capable of being ground out, leaving a smooth, clear finish.
</section>
<section prefix = "22">
Doors shall be operable with all weather stripping and rubber seals.
</section>
<section prefix = "23">
Vehicle steering and suspension shall be functional.
</section>
<section prefix = "24">
Seat belts for all persons transported shall be in place and functional, unless otherwise exempted by regulation.
</section>
<section prefix = "25">
Limousines shall not display the word(s) "taxicab," "taxi," or "cab" on the vehicle exterior or interior and shall not be equipped with a taximeter.
<section prefix = "b">
Vehicle age limits and inspection schedules. Vehicle age limits and frequency of for-hire vehicle inspections are as follows; provided however, that the CSD may inspect a for-hire vehicle at any time:
<section prefix = "1">
Luxury limousine sedans. No luxury limousine sedan initially placed into service shall be older than two (2) model years of age. No luxury limousine sedan that exceeds five (5) model years of age shall be inspected or operated.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Stretch limousines. No stretch limousine initially placed into service shall be older than two (2) model years of age. No stretch limousine that exceeds five (5) model years of age shall be inspected or operated; provided, however, that a luxury sedan vehicle that is either a fifteen (15) or greater model year Rolls Royce, Packard or Mercedes-Benz that has been stretched a minimum of forty-two (42) inches may be operated beyond five (5) model years as long as the vehicle meets the inspection requirements of the Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Super-stretch limousines. No super-stretch limousine initially placed into service shall be older than two (2) model years of age. No super-stretch limousine that exceeds seven (7) model years of age shall be inspected or operated; provided, however, that a luxury sedan vehicle that is either a fifteen (15) or greater model year Rolls Royce, Packard or Mercedes-Benz that has been stretched a minimum of one hundred twenty (120) inches may be operated beyond seven (7) model years as long as the vehicle meets the inspection requirements of the Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The limousine vehicle age requirements will be effective one year after adoption of this article. Notwithstanding the vehicle age limits required by Section 31-609(b)(1), (2) and (3) of the Code, no luxury limousine sedan, stretch limousine or super-stretch limousine initially placed into service during 2011 or 2012 shall be older than three (3) model years of age.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Ancient, antique, or collectible limousines are exempt from the vehicle age requirements of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Limousines shall minimally meet the following inspection schedule:
<section prefix = "i">
Limousines one (1) through two (2) model years of age shall be inspected annually;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Limousines three (3) through four (4) model years of age shall be inspected semi-annually;
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Limousines five (5) model years of age or more shall be inspected quarterly; provided, however, that ancient or antique limousines shall be inspected semi-annually.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Inspection fees. The CSD shall charge non-refundable fees for inspection and re-inspection of any for-hire vehicle for compliance with the vehicle standards and requirements of this subsection. Inspection results shall be recorded and a copy provided. Any vehicle failing to meet any required vehicle safety standard shall not be operated until it passes a re-inspection.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Display of information identifying vehicle number and company. The operating permit number, fares, or rates, for-hire license holder's name, and business telephone number shall be permanently displayed in the interior of the vehicle in accordance with instructions issued by the CSD.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Telecommunication devices. Limousines shall be equipped with a two-way radio or cellular telephone.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Vehicles operated pursuant to a luxury limousine sedan license shall be either entirely silver, black, navy or white.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 00-139, § 1, 11-14-00; Ord. No. 11-77, § 2, 10-4-11; Ord. No. 12-66, § 1, 9-6-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 31-610. Enforcement of article</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
This article shall be enforced by authorized personnel of the CSD, the police forces of the various municipalities in Miami-Dade County, and by the Miami-Dade Police Department. When specifically authorized by the Director, this article may be enforced by personnel of the Seaport and Aviation Department when violations occur within their respective boundaries. The CSD shall prepare and distribute to all authorized enforcement personnel an enforcement manual outlining procedures for the detection, reporting, and issuance of citations or deficiency reports for violations of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The CSD may employ a deficiency or warning system through which operators are given written notice of minor violations and a specified period of time to correct same. Unless otherwise provided, all other violations shall be processed under Chapter 8CC of the Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Deficiency reports and citations shall be issued to the party responsible for the violation as set forth in this article. Any person issued a deficiency report or a citation shall sign and accept said report or citation. Notice given to a chauffeur for a violation involving the vehicle under his control shall be deemed notice to the operator.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Whenever a corporation, partnership, or association violates any of the provisions of this article, such violation shall be deemed also to be that of the individual officers, directors, partners, or agents of such corporation who have personally authorized, personally ordered, or personally done any of the actions constituting in whole or in part such violation, and any such officer, director, partner, or agent may be fined in the same manner and to the same extent as herein provided for an individual.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, the Director may secure enforcement of the provisions of this article by any legal action necessary, such as application to any court for injunctive relief or other appropriate relief.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 00-139, § 1, 11-14-00)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 31-611. Suspension and revocation proceedings</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Grounds for suspension or revocation. In addition to the grounds for automatic suspension or revocation provided elsewhere in this chapter, for-hire licenses, operating permits, and chauffeur registrations shall be subject to suspension or revocation by the Director as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
Upon the Director's determination that:
<section prefix = "i">
The license, registration, or permit holder has pled nolo contendere, pled guilty, been found guilty, or been convicted (regardless of whether adjudication has been withheld) of any criminal offense which would preclude the issuance of the license, registration, or permit as provided in this chapter;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
The license, registration, or permit was obtained by an application in which any material fact was omitted or falsely stated;
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
The license, registration, or permit holder has failed to comply with or has violated any of the provisions of this chapter;
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
The public interest will best be served by revocation, or suspension of the license, registration, or permit; provided, however, that good cause be shown;
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
The chauffeur has failed any drug test required by the Code or state or federal law; or
</section>
<section prefix = "vi">
Any for-hire limousine has been operated in violation of any of the provisions of this chapter.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Notice of suspension or revocation action. Except where this chapter provides for automatic suspension or revocation, the CSD shall provide notice of suspension or revocation to the violator by certified mail, ten (10) days before the violator must comply with the director's decision.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Appeals from decisions of Director and administrative hearings.
<section prefix = "1">
Right to appeal. Any for-hire license holder and for-hire chauffeur shall have the right to appeal application denials, suspensions, and revocations by the Director. The named party shall elect to either:
<section prefix = "a">
Comply with the Director's decision in the manner indicated on the Notice of Director's decision; or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Request an administrative hearing before a hearing officer to appeal the decision of the Director.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Filing the appeal. Appeal by administrative hearing shall be accomplished by filing within ten (10) days after the date of the decision complained of a written notice of appeal to the Clerk of the Courts, Code Enforcement Section. The notice of appeal shall set forth concisely the nature of the decision appealed and the reasons or grounds for appeal.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Failure to appeal. Failure to appeal the decision of the Director within the prescribed time period shall constitute a waiver of the person's right to an administrative hearing before the hearing officer. Where the Director's decision involves a suspension or revocation, a waiver of the right to an administrative hearing shall be treated as an admission of the violation and the Director's decision shall be deemed final and enforceable. No further remedies shall be granted and the decision shall stand.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Hearing officers. Hearing Officers shall be appointed by the Clerk of the Courts, Code Enforcement Section.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Scheduling and conduct of hearing.
<section prefix = "a">
Upon receipt of a timely request for an administrative hearing, the hearing officer shall set the matter down for hearing on the next regularly scheduled hearing date or as soon as possible thereafter or as mandated in the specified section of the Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The hearing officer shall send a notice of hearing by first class mail to the named party at his, her or its last known address. The notice of hearing shall include but not be limited to the following: place, date, and time of the hearing; right of the named party to be represented by a lawyer; right of the named party to present witnesses and evidence; in the case of a director's decision involving suspension or revocation, notice that failure of the named party to attend the hearing shall be deemed a waiver of the right to hearing and an admission of the acts specified in the notice; and notice that requests for continuances will not be considered if not received by the hearing officer at least ten (10) calendar days prior to the date set for hearing.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The hearing officers shall call hearings on a monthly basis or upon the request of the CSD. No hearing shall be set sooner than fifteen (15) calendar days from the date of notice of the Director's decision, unless otherwise prescribed by this chapter.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
A hearing date shall not be postponed or continued unless a request for continuance, showing good cause for such continuance, is received in writing by the hearing officer at least ten (10) calendar days prior to the date set for the hearing. No additional continuances shall be granted without concurrence of the CSD.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
All hearings conducted by a hearing officer shall be open to the public. All testimony shall be under oath. If the named party has been properly notified, a hearing may proceed in the absence of the named party and the failure to attend a hearing shall be deemed a waiver of the right to a hearing and an admission of the acts specified in the notice.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The proceedings at the hearing shall be recorded and may be transcribed at the expense of the party requesting the transcript.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
The Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners shall provide clerical and administrative personnel as may be reasonably required by each hearing officer for the proper performance of his or her duties.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Each case before a hearing officer shall be presented by the director or his or her designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
The hearing need not be conducted in accordance with the formal rules relating to evidence and witnesses.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Each party shall have the following rights: to call and examine witnesses; to introduce exhibits; to cross-examine opposing witnesses on any relevant matter; to impeach any witness regardless of which party first called him or her to testify; and to rebut the evidence against him or her. All relevant evidence shall be admitted.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
The hearing officer shall make findings of fact based on the evidence of record. In order to make a finding upholding the Director's decision the hearing officer must find that a preponderance of the evidence supports the Director's decision and, where applicable, indicate that the named party was responsible for the violation of the relevant section of the Code as charged.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
If the Director's decision is affirmed the named party may be held liable for the reasonable costs of the administrative hearing.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
The fact-finding determination of the hearing officer shall be limited to whether the alleged violation occurred or whether competent, substantial evidence supports the Director's decisions. Based upon this fact-finding determination, the hearing officer shall either affirm or reverse the decision of the Director. If the hearing officer affirms the decision of the Director, the named party shall have fifteen (15) days from the date of the hearing officer's decision to comply with the decision of the Director. If the hearing officer reverses the decision of the Director and finds (1) the named party not responsible for the violation alleged; or (2) insufficient basis for the denial of application, a written decision shall be prepared setting forth the basis for such determination. If the hearing officer reverses the decision of the Director, the named party shall not be required to comply with the decision of the Director, absent reversal of the hearing officer's findings pursuant to Section 31-611(c)(6). If the decision of the hearing officer is to affirm, then the following shall be included in the decision:
<section prefix = "a">
Decision of the Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Administrative costs of the hearing.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Date for compliance, if applicable.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "n">
The hearing officer shall have the power to:
<section prefix = "a">
Adopt procedures for the conduct of hearings;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Subpoena alleged violators and witnesses for hearings; subpoenas may be served by the Miami-Dade County Police Department or by the hearing officer's staff;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Subpoena evidence; and
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Take testimony under oath.
<section prefix = "6">
Appeals.
<section prefix = "a">
The named party or the county may appeal a final order of the hearing officer by filing a notice of appeal in the Circuit Court in and for Miami-Dade County, Florida, in accordance with the procedures and within the time provided by the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure for the review of administrative action.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Unless the findings of the hearing officer are overturned in a proceeding held pursuant to Section 31-611(c)(6), all findings of the hearing officer shall be admissible in any further proceeding to compel compliance with the director's decision.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Nothing contained in this chapter shall prohibit Miami-Dade County from enforcing the Code by any other means authorized by law. The enforcement procedures outlined herein are cumulative to all others and shall not be deemed to be prerequisites to filing suit for the enforcement of any section of this Code. The words "action" and "decision" as used herein shall not include the filing of any action by the director in any court. The Director may reconsider at any time any action or decision taken by the Director and therefore may modify such an action or decision.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 00-139, § 1, 11-14-00)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 31-612. Violations; penalties</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
In addition to any other penalties provided by law, including, but not limited, to those provided in this article, a violation of any applicable provision of this article by a for-hire license holder or registered chauffeur shall constitute a civil offense punishable by the applicable civil penalty as provided in the schedule of civil penalties in Section 8CC-10 of this Code. Failure of a person to pay a civil penalty within sixty (60) days of the due date for paying such fine as specified on the civil violation notice or within sixty (60) days of the date of the final outcome of any timely filed appeal of such violation notice, whichever is later, shall result in automatic suspension of such person's for-hire license, operating permit, and chauffeur registration, and all for-hire operations shall cease until such fine is paid in full. If a person commits five (5) violations of the same section of this chapter during any twelve (12) month period, such person's for-hire license, operating permit, or chauffeur's registration shall be automatically revoked. If a person commits five (5) violations of this chapter during any twelve (12) month period, such person's for-hire license, operating permit, or chauffeur's registration may be suspended for a period of up to six (6) months or revoked.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Failure to correct items recorded on a deficiency report by the time of deadline shall cause a citation to be issued for each such item. Citations shall be issued under Chapter 8CC of the Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Any person who is found guilty on at least two (2) prior occasions within a three (3) year period of advertising or providing for-hire transportation, driving, or operating a for-hire vehicle without having a valid, current for-hire license, operating permit, or chauffeur's registration as required by this chapter, shall be punishable by fines of greater than five thousand dollars ($5,000.00) but less than ten thousand dollars ($10,000) and/or imprisonment not to exceed forty-five (45) days.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Except for civil violations, the hearings specified in subsection (c) hereof shall be within the jurisdiction of the County Court, and the Clerk of the Court is hereby empowered to dispose of the case and fines assessed through the normal procedure.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Anyone who engages a for-hire vehicle with intent to defraud the chauffeur or operator shall be in violation of this article and subject to a fine of five hundred dollars ($500,00) and/or imprisonment not to exceed ten (10) days.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Any person who is found guilty of signing an application for issuance, renewal, modification, assignment, sale, or transfer of a for-hire license, chauffeur registration, or operating permit which falsely states any material fact shall be punished by a fine of one thousand dollars ($1,000.00) and/or imprisonment in the County Jail for thirty (30) days.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 00-139, § 1, 11-14-00)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 31-613. Special provisions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The provisions of this article shall be the exclusive regulations applicable to the provision of and operation of for-hire motor vehicle transportation services in Miami-Dade County. Notwithstanding the provisions of any municipal ordinance, resolution, or agreement to the contrary, from and after the effective date of this article, no municipality shall authorize, establish, change, alter, amend, or otherwise regulate for-hire transportation in Miami-Dade County. Regulations established by this article shall be uniform throughout Miami-Dade County both in the incorporated and unincorporated areas without regard to municipal boundaries. All municipal ordinances or resolutions to the contrary are hereby superseded and rescinded.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in this article, a stretch limousine license holder that has, as of October 1, 2003, been issued a current and valid permit to operate a vehicle that has been categorized by the automobile industry as a sports utility vehicle may continue to operate a sports utility vehicle pursuant to the for-hire license until October 1, 2006 provided that: 1) the stretch limousine license is maintained current and valid; 2) all permits issued pursuant to the for-hire license to operate a sports utility vehicle are continuously operated and maintained current and valid; 3) all sports utility vehicles operated pursuant to the for-hire license meet and comply with all other requirements for a luxury sedan, including, but not limited to, the vehicle standards, vehicle age requirements, inspection frequency and minimum rates for a luxury sedan; and 4) the permit is operated in compliance with the preceding provisions and all requirements of Chapter 31 of the Code. Any change in ownership of the license holder or failure to comply with applicable requirements shall result in automatic revocation of the permit and removal of the sports utility vehicle from service under the stretch for-hire limousine license. A for-hire license holder operating a sports utility vehicle pursuant to this subsection (b) shall not at any time operate any more sports utility vehicles than the number authorized as of October 1, 2003.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Temporary limousine licenses. Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the County Manager may prescribe rules and regulations for the approval and issuance of temporary limousine licenses for Super Bowls, summits, political conventions and other major special events of national or international significance, such as nationally televised awards shows, where the event's organizers can demonstrate that the existing supply of limousines is not adequate to meet the needs of the event.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Notwithstanding the vehicle age limits required by Section 31-609(b) of the Code, any properly permitted and inspected luxury limousine sedan, stretch limousine, or super-stretch limousine scheduled for retirement on December 31, 2012, shall be allowed to be operated for an additional one-year period.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 00-139, § 1, 11-14-00; Ord. No. 03-266, § 1, 12-8-03; Ord. No. 06-112, § 1, 7-6-06; Ord. No. 09-58, § 1, 6-30-09; Ord. No. 11-11, § 1, 3-1-11; Ord. No. 11-102, § 1, 12-19-11; Ord. No. 12-66, § 1, 9-6-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 31-614. Seizure, impoundment and forfeiture</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Seizure. Police officers or such other employees as may be designated by the County Manager are authorized to seize and impound any for-hire motor vehicle which such officer or employee has probable cause to believe is being operated in violation of Section 31-602(a) or 31-607(a) of Article VI of Chapter 31 of the Miami-Dade County Code. A vehicle seized in accordance with this subsection shall be removed to a designated secured facility.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Notice of Seizure.
<section prefix = "1">
Within twenty-four (24) hours of a seizure, as described in Section 31-614(a), a police officer or other designated county employee shall make a diligent search and inquiry as to the owner's name and address and make a good faith effort to give a notice of seizure in writing to said vehicle owner of the fact of such seizure, the grounds for seizure, identification of the seized vehicle and information concerning these regulations and the designated secured facility to which the vehicle was or will be taken. A copy of said notice of seizure shall also be given to the proprietor of such secured facility.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Whenever an officer or designated employee seizes a vehicle under this section, and does not know, and is not able to ascertain the name of the owner, or for any other reason is unable to give the notice to the owner as hereinabove provided, then and in that event the officer or designated employee shall immediately send or cause to be sent a written report of such removal by mail to the Motor Vehicle Commissioner of the Miami-Dade Police Department.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Vehicle impoundment hearing. Whenever the owner of record of a vehicle seized pursuant to this section makes a request of the CSD in person and in writing for a vehicle impoundment hearing within ten (10) days of seizure exclusive of Saturdays, Sundays and legal holidays, a magistrate, as provided in Section 318.32, Florida Statutes, a county court judge or a hearing examiner, who shall not have responsibility for the enforcement of this article and who shall be designated by the CSD Director, shall conduct the hearing within twenty-four (24) hours or as soon as practicable, excluding Saturdays, Sundays and legal holidays.
All interested persons shall be given reasonable opportunity to be heard at the vehicle impoundment hearing. The formal rules of evidence shall not apply. If, after the hearing, the magistrate, county court judge or hearing examiner determines that there is no probable cause to believe that the vehicle is subject to seizure and impoundment under subsection (a), the magistrate, county court judge or hearing examiner shall order the immediate return of the vehicle. If, after the hearing, the magistrate, county court judge or hearing examiner determines that there is probable cause to believe that the vehicle is subject to seizure and impoundment under subsection (a), the magistrate, county court judge or hearing examiner shall order the continued impoundment of the vehicle as provided in this section unless the owner of the vehicle (1) posts with the court or CSD a cash bond in the amount of the maximum fine(s), plus any applicable towing and storage fees, or (2) pleads guilty or nolo contendere and pays in full any towing and storage fees plus the fine(s). Notwithstanding the foregoing, if, after the hearing, it is determined that there is probable cause to believe that the vehicle is subject to forfeiture proceedings pursuant to Section 31-614(g), said vehicle shall not be released.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Hearing regarding Code violation charged in field enforcement report and/or complaint/arrest affidavit. Within ten (10) days after a vehicle is seized and impounded pursuant to this section or as soon as practicable, the CSD and/or the Clerk's Office shall notify by certified mail, return receipt requested, the owner of record of the date, time and location of a hearing that will be conducted regarding the Code violations charged in the field enforcement report, the complaint/arrest affidavit or other charging instrument. The hearing shall be conducted within thirty (30) days after the vehicle was seized or as soon as practicable. The hearing shall be conducted by a magistrate, county court judge or hearing examiner. All interested persons shall be given a reasonable opportunity to be heard at the hearing.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Decisions at hearing.
<section prefix = "1">
If the magistrate, county court judge or hearing examiner dismisses the Code violation(s) charged in the field enforcement report, complaint/arrest affidavit or other charging document and/or finds the person charged not guilty, the magistrate, county court judge or hearing examiner shall issue an order for release of the seized vehicle without removal and storage fees.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
If the magistrate, county court judge or hearing examiner finds a violation of the Code, the magistrate, county court judge or hearing examiner shall assess a fine and/or jail sentence as provided in Section 31-612 of the Code, and removal and storage fees. The fine(s), if any, and removal and storage fees must be paid in order to obtain an order for release of the seized vehicle. A magistrate, county court judge or hearing examiner shall not issue an order releasing the vehicle where said vehicle is subject to forfeiture proceedings pursuant to Section 31-614(g).
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
If the owner does not obtain the vehicle by the date specified in the order of release, the owner shall be responsible for any further storage fees, and payment of such fees shall be made before the release of the vehicle.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
A vehicle shall not be released from storage prior to the scheduled hearing specified in this subsection if the vehicle is subject to forfeiture pursuant to Section 31-614(g) of the Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Default hearing. If the owner of the seized vehicle fails to appear for the hearing specified in Section 31-614(d), a default hearing will be held. A magistrate, county court judge or hearing examiner shall make a determination pursuant to paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection (e). The CSD will inform the respondent of the default determination by certified mail, return receipt requested. The information mailed to the owner shall include the provision of Section 31-614 herein concerning abandoned vehicles. The respondent may comply with the default determination within seven calendar days of such mailing or move to vacate such default determination. In the event that such default determination is vacated, the respondent shall be entitled to a hearing de novo on the original complaint/arrest affidavit, field enforcement report or other charging document. Such hearing shall be scheduled within ten (10) working days of the order vacating the default determination or as soon as practicable.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Appeals. If a violation of Section 31-602(a) or 31-607(a) of the Code is found, the assessed fine(s) together with removal and storage must be paid in order to appeal. However, if the vehicle is the subject of a forfeiture proceeding pursuant to Section 31-614(g) of the Code, only the fine, if any, must be paid in order to appeal. If upon appeal the decision is reversed in whole or part, the appellant shall receive a refund of the relevant fine(s) and fees.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Forfeiture.
<section prefix = "1">
Forfeiture. In addition to the penalties set forth in Sections 31-611 and 31-612 of the Code, any for-hire motor vehicle used to commit three (3) or more violations of Section 31-602(a) or 31-607(a) of the Code on at least three (3) separate occasions within a thirty-six (36) month period, where all of such violations were committed on or after the effective date of this article shall be subject to forfeiture upon notice and judicial determination.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Determination by the CSD Director. The Director of the CSD shall determine whether to pursue the remedy of forfeiture. Miami-Dade County shall not use the seized vehicle for any purpose until the rights to, interest in, and title to the seized property are perfected in accordance with this section. This section does not prohibit use or operation necessary for reasonable maintenance of seized vehicles. Reasonable efforts shall be made to maintain seized vehicles in such a manner as to minimize loss of value.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Vehicles subject to forfeiture may be seized provided that the owner is notified at the time of the seizure or by certified mail, return receipt requested, that there is a right to an adversarial preliminary hearing after the seizure to determine whether probable cause exists to believe that such vehicle has been used to commit three (3) or more violations of Section 31-602(a) or 31-607(a) of the Code on at least three (3) separate occasions within a thirty-six (36) month period, where all of such violations were committed on or after the effective date of this article. The CSD or other authorized law enforcement agencies shall make a diligent effort to notify the owner of the seizure. Notice provided by certified mail must be mailed within five (5) working days of the seizure and shall state that the owner may request an adversarial preliminary hearing within fifteen (15) days of receiving such notice. When a post-seizure adversarial preliminary hearing as provided herein is requested, it shall be held within ten (10) days after the request or as soon as practicable. If the court determines that the required probable cause exists, the court shall order the property restrained by the least restrictive means to protect against disposal waste, or continued illegal use pending disposition of the forfeiture proceeding. If the court orders the release of the vehicle, all fines, if any, and towing and storage fees shall be paid prior to release.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Neither replevin nor any other action to recover any interest in such property shall be maintained in any court, except as provided in this section; however, such action may be maintained if forfeiture proceedings are not initiated within forty-five (45) days after the date of seizure. However, if good cause is shown, the court may extend the aforementioned period to sixty (60) days.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The court shall order the forfeiture of any other property of a claimant of a vehicle, excluding lienholders, up to the value of the vehicle subject to forfeiture under this section if the vehicle:
<section prefix = "a">
Cannot be located;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Has been transferred to, sold to, or deposited with a third party;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Has been placed beyond the jurisdiction of the court;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Has been substantially diminished in value by any act or omission of the person in possession of the property; or
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Has been commingled with any property which cannot be divided without difficulty.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Exceptions.
<section prefix = "a">
No vehicle shall be forfeited under the provisions of this section if the owner of such vehicle establishes by a preponderance of the evidence that she or he neither knew, nor should have known after a reasonable inquiry, that such vehicle was being used or was likely to be used in violation of Section 31-602(a) or 31-607(a) of the Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
No bona fide lienholder's interest shall be forfeited under the provisions of this section if such lienholder establishes by a preponderance of the evidence that she or he neither knew, nor should have known after a reasonable inquiry, that such property was being used or was likely to be used in violation of Section 31-602(a) or 31-607(a) of the Code, that such use was without his or her expressed or implied consent, and that the lien had been perfected in the manner prescribed by law prior to such seizure.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
No vehicle which is rented or leased from a company engaged in the business of renting or leasing vehicles shall be forfeited under the provision of this section if the company establishes by a preponderance of the evidence that it neither knew, nor should have known, that the vehicle was being used or was likely to be used in violation of Section 31-602(a) or 31-607(a) of the Code. When a vehicle which is rented or leased from a company engaged in the business of renting or leasing vehicles is seized under this section, upon learning the address or phone number of said company, the CSD shall, as soon as practicable, inform said company that the vehicle has been seized.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Any interest in, title to, or right to a vehicle titled or registered jointly by the use of the conjunctives "and," "and/or," or "or" held by a co-owner shall not be forfeited if the co-owner establishes by a preponderance of the evidence that such co-owner neither knew, nor had reason to know, after reasonable inquiry, that such property was used or was likely to be used in violation of Section 31-602(a) or 31-607(a) of the Code. When the interests of each culpable co-owner are forfeited, any remaining co-owners shall be afforded the opportunity to purchase the forfeited interest in, title to, or right to the property from Miami-Dade County. If any remaining co-owner does not purchase such interest, Miami-Dade County may hold the property in co-ownership, sell its interest in the property, liquidate its interest in the property, or dispose of its interest in the property in any other reasonable manner.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Forfeiture proceedings.
<section prefix = "a">
It is the policy of Miami-Dade County that the provisions of this section are adopted to deter and prevent the continued use of for-hire motor vehicles to violate Section 31-602(a) or 31-607(a) of the Code while protecting proprietary interests of innocent owners and lienholders and to authorize the use of the proceeds collected under this section as supplemental funding for enforcement purposes.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Florida Rules of Civil Procedure shall govern forfeiture proceedings under this section unless otherwise specified herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Any trial on the ultimate issue of forfeiture shall be decided by a jury, unless such right is waived by the claimant of the vehicle through a written waiver or on the record before the court conducting the forfeiture proceeding.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Miami-Dade County shall promptly proceed against the vehicle by filing a complaint in the circuit court.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
<section prefix = "i">
The complaint shall be styled, "in RE FORFEITURE OF." (followed by the name or description of the vehicle). The complaint shall contain a brief jurisdictional statement, a description of the subject matter of the proceeding, and a statement of the facts sufficient to state a cause of action that would support a final judgment of forfeiture. The complaint must be accompanied by a verified supporting affidavit.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
If no person entitled to notice requests an adversarial preliminary hearing, as provided in Section 31-614(g)(3), the court, upon receipt of the complaint, shall review the complaint and the verified supporting affidavit to determine whether there was probable cause for the seizure. Upon a finding of probable cause, the court shall enter a probable cause order.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
The court shall require any claimant of a vehicle who desires to contest the forfeiture to file and serve upon the attorney representing Miami-Dade County any responsive pleadings and affirmative defenses within twenty (20) days after receipt of the complaint and probable cause finding.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
<section prefix = "i">
Miami-Dade County shall serve notice of the forfeiture complaint by certified mail, return receipt requested, to each person having a security interest in the vehicle. Miami-Dade County shall also publish notice of the forfeiture complaint twice each week for two (2) consecutive weeks in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
The notice shall, in addition to stating that which is required by Section 31-614(g)(3) describe the property, state the county, place, and date of seizure; state the governmental entity holding the seized property, and state the name of the court in which the complaint will be filed.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Miami-Dade County shall be obligated to make a diligent search and inquiry as to the owner of the vehicle, and if, after such diligent search and inquiry, Miami-Dade County is unable to ascertain any person entitled to notice, the actual notice requirements by mail shall not be applicable.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
When the claimant of the vehicle and Miami-Dade County agree to settle the forfeiture action prior to the conclusion of the forfeiture proceeding, the settlement agreement shall be reviewed, unless such review is waived by the claimant of the vehicle in writing, by the court or a mediator or arbitrator agreed upon by the claimant and Miami-Dade County.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Upon clear and convincing evidence that the seized vehicle was used to commit a third or subsequent violation of Section 31-602(a) or 31-607(a) of the Code on at least three (3) separate occasions within a thirty-six (36) month period, where all of such violations were committed on or after the effective date of this article, the court shall order the seized property forfeited to Miami-Dade County. As used in this subsection, a "violation" occurs when a person or entity pleads guilty or nolo contendere or is convicted or found guilty (regardless of whether adjudication is withheld) of violating Section 31-602(a) or 31-607(a) of the Code using the vehicle subject to forfeiture. The final order of forfeiture by the court shall perfect in Miami-Dade County right, title, and interest in and to such property, subject only to the rights and interests of bona fide lienholders, and shall relate back to the date of seizure.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
<section prefix = "i">
The seized property shall be released immediately to the person entitled to possession of the property as determined by the court when the claimant prevails at the conclusion of the forfeiture proceeding, and Miami-Dade County decides not to appeal.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
When the claimant of the vehicle prevails at the conclusion of the forfeiture proceeding, any decision to appeal must be made by the CSD Director. If the claimant prevails on appeal, Miami-Dade County shall immediately release the seized property to the person entitled to possession of the property as determined by the court.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Disposition of forfeited property where no lien. When Miami-Dade County obtains a final judgment granting forfeiture of a vehicle, it may elect to:
<section prefix = "i">
Retain the property for the County's use;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Sell the property at public auction or by sealed bid to the highest bidder; or
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Salvage, trade, or transfer the vehicle to any public or nonprofit organization.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Disposition of forfeited property where lien. If the forfeited vehicle is subject to a lien preserved by the court as provided in Section 31-614(g)(6)(b) Miami-Dade County shall:
<section prefix = "i">
Sell the property with the proceeds being used towards satisfaction of any liens; or
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Have the lien satisfied prior to taking any action authorized by Section 31-614(g)(7)(j).
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Priority of disbursement. The proceeds from the sale of a forfeited vehicle shall be disbursed in the following priority:
<section prefix = "i">
Payment of the balance due on any lien preserved by the court in the forfeiture proceedings.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Payment of the costs incurred by Miami-Dade County in connection with the storage, maintenance, security, and forfeiture of such property.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Payment of court costs incurred in the forfeiture proceeding.
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
The remaining proceeds shall be deposited in an Enforcement Trust Fund hereby established by the Board of County Commissioners. Such proceeds and interest earned therefrom shall be used for enforcement of the provisions of Chapter 31 of the Code.
<section prefix = "h">
Abandoned vehicles.
<section prefix = "1">
If an owner does not assert an interest in a seized vehicle by removing it from storage within the time periods specified in paragraph (2) of this subsection (h), the vehicle shall be deemed abandoned. A declaration of such abandonment may be made by a circuit court judge after a duly noticed hearing without further hearing.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
A vehicle shall be deemed abandoned, pursuant to paragraph (1) herein, if an owner:
<section prefix = "a">
Has not removed the vehicle from storage within ten (10) days of obtaining an order of release pursuant to Section 31-614(c), (e) or (g)(7)(j) herein;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Has not paid the fines, if any, and towing and storage fees within ten (10) days of a hearing determination of violation pursuant to Section 31-614(e)(2) herein, or within ten (10) days after notice of a default determination of violation was mailed to the owner pursuant to Section 31-614(e)(5) herein;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Has not paid the fines, if any, and towing and storage fees within ten (10) days of denial or a motion to vacate a default determination pursuant to Section 31-614(e)(5);
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Has not paid the fines, if any, and towing and storage fees within ten (10) days after a notice was mailed by the CSD to the owner that the County will not pursue the remedy of forfeiture pursuant to Section 31-614 herein.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
In the event that a vehicle has been deemed abandoned pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection (h), the CSD shall mail to the owner a notice that the vehicle has been recovered by CSD as an abandoned vehicle and that, if unclaimed, its ownership shall vest in Miami-Dade County and it will be sold at public auction or by bid after ten days from the date such notice was mailed. Such notice shall also be mailed to any lienholder or mortgagee shown in the records of the jurisdiction which issued the number of license plates on the vehicle.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
An owner, lienholder or mortgagee may claim the vehicle within ten (10) days from the date that the notice described in paragraph (3) of this subsection (h) was mailed, by paying the towing and storage fees due and any fine(s).
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
In the event that an abandoned vehicle is not claimed within ten (10) working days after the notice described in paragraph (3) of this subsection (h) was mailed, ownership of the abandoned vehicle shall vest in CSD after a duly noticed hearing and declaration of abandonment by a circuit court judge. The CSD may sell an abandoned vehicle at public auction or by bid. Proceeds shall be paid into the Enforcement Trust Fund.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 00-139, § 1, 11-14-00)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 31-615. Advertisement of for-hire services</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
No person may knowingly place or publish an advertisement in any publication which is primarily circulated, displayed, distributed, or marketed within Miami-Dade County, Florida, which advertisement identifies for-hire transportation regulated by this article, unless the advertisement includes the for-hire license number of the limousine company.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
For the purposes of this section, an advertisement shall be defined to include any announcement, listing, display, entry, or other statement of whatever nature or kind, and specifically to include a name and address or telephone number placed under a heading where the heading describes or encompasses any for-hire transportation regulated under this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
No person shall advertise a rate or fare other than the rate or fare approved pursuant to Section 31-604
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
No person shall advertise limousine service in a manner that is false, deceptive or misleading including, but not limited to, representing the limousine service as taxicab service or as demand response service.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 00-139, § 1, 11-14-00)</history>
</law>
