<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXXIIIA._SOUTH_FLORIDA_CULTURAL_</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-300. Consortium created</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby authorized to be created and established, pursuant to Section 163.01, Florida Statutes, an agency of Miami-Dade County to be known as The South Florida Cultural Consortium (hereinafter "Consortium").
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-300.1. Purpose</catch_line>
<text>
The purpose of the Consortium shall be to create a formal process for intercounty cooperation for enhancement, encouragement and public expenditures in support of culture and the arts within Broward, Miami-Dade, Monroe, and Palm Beach Counties and with such other government entities with which these counties may in the future contract.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-300.2. Membership</catch_line>
<text>
The membership of the Consortium shall be composed of the Chair of each county's cultural council responsible for matters relating to culture and the arts and the executive Director of each county cultural council, or such other Council staff member as the county manager or county administrator for each respective county may designate.
Members shall serve without compensation but may be reimbursed from consortium funds for actual authorized expenses incurred in the discharge of their duties as provided below.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-300.3. Meetings</catch_line>
<text>
The Consortium will meet no less frequently than two (2) times per year and otherwise as may be called by the Chair of the Consortium. The Consortium shall annually elect a Chair from among the members who are executive directors or designated staff people. In the event the Chair resigns, a new election shall be held as soon as practicable. Each member shall have one (1) vote and a member must be present to exercise that vote. A quorum shall consist of a majority plus one (1) of all Consortium members. All Consortium action, except as noted below, shall require a majority vote at a duly constituted meeting. A matter may be reconsidered at the same meeting at which it was initially decided or at the next meeting of the Consortium, provided that the motion to reconsider must be offered by a member who voted with the majority at the initial determination. The fiscal year shall be October 1 through September 30.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-300.4. Powers</catch_line>
<text>
The Consortium shall have the following powers which may be exercised without further approval of the governing body of any participating County:
<section prefix = "a">
To seek and accept in the name of the participating counties, federal, State, local or private gifts, grants, assistance, funds and bequests in the furtherance of its purposes;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
To enter into contracts for commodities, goods and services, and into leases not exceeding one (1) year in duration and these contracts and leases shall bind the participating counties to the same extent as if entered into by those counties directly;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
To expend or carry over budgeted sums to the succeeding fiscal year, provided that all expenditures and leases shall be in accordance with federal regulations, State law and the Miami-Dade County Charter, ordinances and procedures, and further provided that where Miami-Dade County ordinances and procedures require action by the Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners, then action by the Consortium shall be required in lieu thereof, and where Miami-Dade County ordinances and procedures require action by the County Manager, then action by the Chair shall be required in lieu thereof;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
To grant moneys in accordance with a formal program or programs which it shall develop; and
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
To acquire, operate, maintain, lease or sell any personal property subject to federal grant restrictions. At no time may the Consortium expend or commit more money in any fiscal year than it has received. The Consortium may sue and be sued in its own name; provided that each participating county shall bear an equal share of all liabilities incurred as a result of formal Consortium acts.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-300.5. Membership contributions</catch_line>
<text>
Unless a County withdraws from the Consortium by giving notice prior to October 31 of its intention not to participate effective January 1 of the following year, each County shall contribute an equal amount of dollars to fund the Consortium for each calendar year of the Consortium and that amount shall not be less than sixty-six thousand six hundred and seventy dollars ($66,670.00). Each County shall include this amount in its annual budget and shall hold its contribution in a segregated fund/project until committed for expenditure by formal action of the Consortium.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-300.6. Fiscal and administrative agent</catch_line>
<text>
Miami-Dade County shall be designated as the fiscal and administrative agent for the Consortium. All sums due to the Consortium from any source except the contributions of the other counties shall be paid to Miami-Dade County. No expenditure shall be made without formal authorization from the Consortium in accordance with procedures which it shall adopt. Documentation of all expenditures associated with contributions of the other counties shall be maintained and provided to Miami-Dade County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-300.7. Contract approval</catch_line>
<text>
All contracts, leases and expenditures shall be formally approved by the Consortium and signed by the Executive Director of the Miami-Dade Cultural Affairs Council, acting in his capacity as administrative and fiscal agent for the Consortium.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-300.8. Prohibition on borrowing</catch_line>
<text>
Without the express authorization of each of the participating counties, the Consortium may not borrow funds nor issue debt instruments; provided that nothing in the article shall prevent the Consortium from leasing equipment or paying for equipment under a lease-purchase or installment sale agreement, the term of which shall not exceed the remaining term of the interlocal agreement authorized hereby.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-300.9. Cooperation</catch_line>
<text>
Employees of the participating counties shall reasonably cooperate with the Consortium and shall provide such in-house service as may be available. The Consortium may engage such consultants and other service providers as it deems necessary.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-300.10. Legal advisor</catch_line>
<text>
The Miami-Dade County Attorney shall furnish legal advice and representation to the Consortium. All contracts and leases to be considered by the Consortium must have been approved by the Miami-Dade County Attorney's Office for form and legal sufficiency before Consortium action.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-300.11. Establishment of uniform rates for services and materials offered</catch_line>
<text>
The Consortium shall establish uniform rates for the temporary use of any equipment it may lease, service it may provide, or literature it may sell to the general public. The Consortium shall establish such rules and regulations as may be necessary in the conduct of its business. These rates, rules and regulations shall be enforced in each participating County as if they had been promulgated by each County Commission by resolution.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-300.12. Distribution of assets</catch_line>
<text>
At the termination of the Consortium all property then held by the Consortium in which the federal government holds no equity shall be evaluated and distributed among the participating counties or sold at public auction and the proceeds distributed to those counties. Property purchased with federal grant funds shall be disposed of in accordance with applicable regulations.
At the termination of the Consortium each participating County is entitled to an equal proportionate share of all property (or the proceeds thereof) acquired in part with the contribution of that County. Any County terminating its participation prior to the termination date fixed by the Consortium, as it may be extended from time to time, shall not be entitled to any share of any property or the proceeds thereof.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-300.13. Insurance</catch_line>
<text>
The Consortium will participate with the Miami-Dade County self-insurance program and may purchase insurance.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-300.14. Reports</catch_line>
<text>
The Consortium shall, in February of each year during the term of this article, report to the County Commission of each of the participating counties as to the past and proposed activities of the Consortium. In addition, copies of all agendas and of minutes of each Consortium and Executive Committee meeting shall be furnished to the County administrator or Manager and the County Attorney or general counsel of each party.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-300.15. Delegation of powers</catch_line>
<text>
The Consortium may delegate to its Executive Committee any and all of the business of the Consortium. The Executive Committee shall be composed of the executive director members of the Consortium. The Executive Committee shall meet no less frequently than ten (10) times during each calendar year. A quorum of the Executive Committee shall be three (3) members, and the Consortium Chair shall Chair the Executive Committee. All meetings of the Executive Committee shall comply with the requirements of the Florida Government in the Sunshine Law.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-300.16. Interlocal agreement</catch_line>
<text>
To implement the foregoing article, Broward County, Miami-Dade County, Monroe County, and Palm Beach County shall, at the earliest practicable time, enter into an interlocal agreement pursuant to the provisions of Section 163.01, Florida Statutes.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (55) ---
Editor's note— For purposes of classification and for ease of reference, the editor has grouped §§ 2-300—2-300.16, as enacted by Ord. No. 85-26, under an article title, Art. XXXIIIA, and has renumbered the former article XXXIIIA as XXXIIIB. Language naming specific persons in § 2-300.2 has been deleted to preserve the general and permanent format of the Code. Consult the text of the original ordinance, on file in the Office of the County Clerk, to determine the names of the individuals. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
