<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_VIII._DOMESTIC_LEAVE</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 11A-60. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
As used in this article:
<section prefix = "1">
Commission shall mean the Miami-Dade County Commission on Human Rights.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Director shall mean the Director of Miami-Dade County Commission on Human Rights.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Domestic violence shall mean a pattern of coercive behavior used by one (1) person to control another such as but not limited to: physical, sexual, emotional and psychological violence and abuse; threats; intimidation; verbal abuse; economic control; and stalking; and as defined in Sections 741.28, 784.046 and 784.048 of Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Employee shall mean a person who has been employed by the employer in Miami-Dade County for at least ninety (90) days and for at least three hundred and eight (308) hours of service with such employer during the previous ninety (90) days.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Employer shall mean a person defined in 11A-29 of this Chapter which has in the regular course of business fifty (50) or more employees working in Miami-Dade County for each working day during each of twenty (20) or more calendar work weeks in the current or preceding calendar year.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Perpetrator shall mean a person who engages in domestic or repeat violence against another person(s).
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Victim of domestic or repeat violence shall mean a person who is subjected to domestic or repeat violence by a perpetrator.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 11A-61. Entitlement to domestic leave</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Employees, as defined in this article, shall be entitled to a total of thirty (30) work days of unpaid domestic leave during any twelve (12) month period for one (1) or more of the following:
<section prefix = "a">
To obtain and receive medical and/or dental assistance for a medical and/or dental problem resulting from domestic or repeat violence, including obtaining such services for the employee's dependent children;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
To obtain and receive legal assistance relating to domestic or repeat violence, including but not limited to criminal prosecution, a protective order, divorce, custody of children, and child support;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
To attend court appearances relating to domestic or repeat violence, including but not limited to criminal prosecution, protective order, divorce, custody of children and child support;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
To attend counseling or support services, including counseling or support services for dependent children;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Any other arrangements necessary to provide for the safety and well-being of an employee subject to domestic or repeat violence.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Domestic leave under this section may be taken by an employee intermittently or on a reduced leave schedule. However, if an employee requests intermittent leave or reduced leave that is foreseeable based on a planned schedule, the employer may require such employee to transfer temporarily to an available alternative position for which the employee is qualified and that has equivalent pay and benefits, and better accommodates recurring periods of leave.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Domestic leave may be taken in addition to the family leave allowed under Article V of this Chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Prior to requesting domestic leave, an employee must exhaust all paid vacation leave and/or personal leave.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-05, §1, 1-21-99)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 11A-62. Certification and confidentiality</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
An employer may require that a request for leave under Section 11A-61 be supported by certification issued by an authorized person from a health care provider, attorney of record, counselor, law enforcement agency, clergy, domestic violence advocacy agency, domestic violence center, or domestic violence shelter. The certification shall be sufficient if it indicates that the employee is being subjected to domestic or repeat violence and needs time off to attend to one (1) of the matters described in 11A-61(a) through (e).
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
To the extent allowed by law, employers shall maintain the confidentiality of any employee requesting domestic leave under this article.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-05, §1, 1-21-99)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 11A-63. Employment and benefits protection</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Any eligible employee who takes domestic leave, shall on return from leave, be entitled to:
<section prefix = "a">
Restoration by the employer to the position of employment held by the employee when leave commenced; or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Restoration to an equivalent position with equivalent employment benefits, pay and other terms and conditions of employment.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The taking of leave shall not result in the loss of any employment benefits accrued prior to the date on which the leave commenced.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Nothing in this article shall be construed to entitle any restored employee to:
<section prefix = "a">
The accrual of any seniority or employment benefits during any period of leave; or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Any right, benefit, or position of employment other than any right, benefit or position to which the employee would have been entitled had the employee not taken the leave.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit any employer from requiring any employee on leave to report periodically to the employer on the status and intention of the employee to return to work.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
During any period when the eligible employee takes leave, the employer shall maintain coverage under any group health plan for the duration of such leave at the level and under the conditions coverage that would have been provided if the employee had continued in employment continuously for the duration of such leave. However, the employer may recover the premium that the employer paid for maintaining coverage for the employee under such group health plan during any period of unpaid leave if:
<section prefix = "a">
The employee fails to return from leave after the period of leave to which the employee is entitled has expired; and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The employees fails to return to work for a reason other than continuance or recurrence of domestic or repeat violence or other circumstances beyond the control of the employee.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-05, §1, 1-21-99)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 11A-64. Prohibited acts</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
It shall be unlawful for any employer to interfere with, restrain, or deny the exercise of any right provided under this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
It shall be unlawful for any employer to discharge or in any other manner discriminate against any individual for opposing any practice made unlawful under this section.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-05, §1, 1-21-99)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 11A-65. Procedures for domestic leave complaint</catch_line>
<text>
The procedures for a domestic leave complaint shall be the same as the procedures outlined in Section 11A-28.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 11A-66. Domestic leave for County and Public Health Trust employees</catch_line>
<text>
The Miami-Dade County employee leave manual and the Public Health Trust employee leave manual shall include provisions consistent with the requirements of this article for domestic leave.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 11A-67. Clerk of the Court to report perpetrators</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Upon a final conviction for a domestic violence related crime, the Clerk of the Court shall forward a copy of such final conviction to the employer of record of the perpetrator.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
For purposes of this section, "employer" shall mean any person, entity, corporation, partnership that employees any employee regardless of length of time or whether full or part-time.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-05, §1, 1-21-99)</history>
<catch_line>Secs. 11A-68, 11A-69. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
</law>
