<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXXIX._CHILD_CARE_TASK_FORCE</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-362. Task force created</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby authorized to be created and established the Miami-Dade County Child Care Task Force.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-362.1. Purpose</catch_line>
<text>
The purpose of the Task Fore is to advise the Board of County Commissioners on issues relating to child care within the incorporated and the unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, including, without limitation, consideration of the assessment of impact fees, joint public-private ventures, as well as other potential revenue sources and funding.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-362.2. Membership</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Task Force all be comprised of nine (9) members, and shall include a member to represent each of the following entities: The Greater Miami Chamber of Commerce, the South Florida Builder's Association, the Miami-Dade County Community Action Agency and the James E. Scott Community Association. Members shall serve without compensation but may be reimbursed for actual authorized expenses incurred in the discharge of their duties.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Members shall be appointed to three-year terms which shall end concurrent with the last day of the County's fiscal year; provided, however, that initially three (3) members shall be appointed to serve a one-year term, three (3) members shall be appointed to serve a two-year term and three (3) members shall be appointed to serve a three-year term.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Failure to maintain the qualifications for membership set out in Section 2-11.38, failure to maintain the attendance requirements of Section 2-11.39, or a violation of the Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance, Section 2-11.1, Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall be grounds for removal from the Task Force.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 88-60, § 1, 7-5-88)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-362.3. Procedure</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Chairperson. The Task Force shall have a Chairperson appointed by the Board of County Commissioners, who shall keep that position until the expiration of his or her term, or until replaced by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Meetings. The Task Force shall meet at the call of the Chairperson, but in no event shall meet less often than once every three (3) months. A quorum shall consist of five (5) members. The Task Force may appoint committees of at least two (2) Task Force members, and may include as committee members individuals who are not Task Force members. All actions by Task Force committees are advisory, and are not binding upon the Task Force. All meetings of the Task Force and its committees shall comply with all requirements of the Florida "Government in the Sunshine" Law, Chapter 119, Florida Statutes, as it may be amended from time to time.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 88-60, § 1, 7-5-88)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-362.4. Powers</catch_line>
<text>
The Task Force shall have the power to invite individuals to address it, to hold public hearings, workshops and seminars. The Task Force shall have all the powers necessary to carry out its purposes. The Task Force cannot commit itself or the County to any expenditure of funds without the specific approval of the Board of County Commissioners, or by the County Manager, under circumstances when he has been authorized to do so by the Board of County Commissioners.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-362.5. Staff</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager shall provide the Task Force with adequate staff and support services to enable it to carry out its purposes.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-362.6. Reports</catch_line>
<text>
No less frequently than once per year, the Task Force shall submit a written report to the Board of County Commissioners detailing its activities during the past year and outlining its contemplated activities for the ensuing year.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-363—2-370. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
</law>
