<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXVA._GREATER_MIAMI_YOUTH_PLANNI</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-237. Created and established; composition, qualifications term, compensation of Board of Directors; officers; rules of procedure; quorum</catch_line>
<text>
The Greater Miami Youth Planning Council is hereby created and established.
<section prefix = "a">
The Board of Directors of the Youth Planning Council shall consist of eleven (11) members, four (4) of whom are youths between twelve (12) and twenty-one (21) years of age, four (4) of whom are lay community leaders and have evidenced a continuing interest in the well-being of young people and three (3) of whom are professionals providing services to youth.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The members of the Board of Directors at the Youth Planning Council shall be nominated and appointed in the following manner:
<section prefix = "1">
The four (4) members who are between twelve (12) and twenty-one (21) years of age shall be appointed by the Board of County Commissioners from a panel of twelve (12) names presented by the Coalition of Service Agencies' representatives designated for that purpose by the following: South Florida Young Adult Program (Neighborhood Youth Corps), Young Women's Christian Association, Girl Scout Council of Tropical Florida, Florida State Division of Youth Services, Regional Drug Program of the State Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services, Miami-Dade Police Department, American Red Cross, Switchboard of Miami, Workmen's Circle, Catholic Welfare Bureau, James E. Scott Community Association, Youth Industries, Miami-Dade County School Board, Young Women's and Young Men's Hebrew Association, South Florida Boy Scout Council, Miami-Dade County Park and Recreation Department, Florida International University, Miami-Dade Community College, United Way of Miami-Dade County, Young Men's Christian Association, Miami-Dade County Department of Youth Services, the Urban League of Greater Miami, the Miami-Dade County Community Relations Board, Youth Advisory Board, Organized Migrants in Community Action, North Miami-Dade Youth for Progress, Miami-Dade County Community Action Agency, Model Cities, Centro Mater, Redlands Christian Migrant Association, Belafonte-Tacolcy, La Casa Abierta, and the Federation of Cuban Professionals Exile.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Of the four (4) members who are lay community leaders, three (3) shall be appointed by the Board of County Commissioners from a panel of nine (9) nominated by the Board of Directors of the United Way of Miami-Dade County, and one shall be appointed from a panel of three (3) nominated by the Miami-Dade County Youth Advisory Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The three (3) members who are professionals providing services to youth shall be appointed from a list of nine (9) nominated by the above listed agencies (subsections (b)(1)).
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Three (3) members of the Board of Directors shall serve for a term of one year, four (4) members shall serve terms of two (2) and three (3) years, respectively, as designated by the Board of County Commissioners at the time of appointment.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Each member shall be eligible for reappointment and shall hold office until his or her successor is duly appointed and qualified. Any member appointed to serve in lieu of any member on account of death, resignation or disability of such member shall serve only for the unexpired term of such member.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
After the initial appointment, each term of office shall be for a period three (3) years.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The Board of Directors shall, by majority vote of the entire membership, select or change its officers, and adopt or change its rules of procedure. Six (6) members shall constitute a quorum but the Board shall not take a position on any issue without meeting and deciding what that position shall be by two-thirds of the entire membership. Members shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for necessary expenses incurred in the per- formance of their official duties, upon approval of the County Commission. All meetings shall be open to the public.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-238. Duties and powers of the Board of Directors</catch_line>
<text>
The Board shall have the following duties, functions, powers and responsibilities:
<section prefix = "a">
To serve in an advisory capacity to the Miami-Dade County Commission or any other institution or agency in any matters affecting the rights of young people and to provide the County Commission and other groups with an authoritative source of consolidated information and representative opinion regarding youth and youth concerns.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
To assure that youth have direct input into planning and decision-making in all areas affecting them by the establishment of a youth congress to be comprised of a representative group of young people.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
To assure that youth serving agencies, through their professional staff, are provided a forum for interchange of ideas and problems thereby leading to the development of new and innovative services to youth, the coordination of existing services, and the reduction of duplication and gaps in services to youth.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-239. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 85-80, § 1, adopted Oct. 1, 1985, repealed § 2-239, "Miami-Dade County Youth Focus on Government Board," as derived from Ord. No. 75-108, § 1, adopted Nov. 18, 1985, and Ord. No. 75-61, § 2, adopted July 3, 1979.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-240. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (44) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 74-35, §§ 1, 2, adopted May 21, 1974, repealed former Art. XXVA, §§ 2-237, 2-238, pertaining to a Youth Relations Board, and enacted in lieu thereof a new Art. XXVA, §§ 2-237, 2-238, as herein set out. Former Art. XXVA was derived from Ord. No. 70-92, §§ 1, 2, adopted Dec. 8, 1970, and Ord. No. 71-84, § 1, adopted April 13, 1971. (Back)
Cross reference— Children's services council, § 2-231 et seq.; young people's council, § 2-240.1 et seq. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
