<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_V._WATER_AND_SANITARY_SEWER_CONN</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-76. Short title and application</catch_line>
<text>
This article is to be known as the Miami-Dade County Water and Sanitary Sewer Connection Ordinance and shall apply to all areas of Miami-Dade County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-77. Declaration of legislative intent</catch_line>
<text>
This Board (Board of County Commissioners) finds that many residences and nonresidential buildings in Miami-Dade County abut streets and easements in which water and/or sewer mains have been laid but obtain their water supply from wells and not from said mains. The sewage disposal for the said residences is provided by septic tanks. The growing population of Miami-Dade County, the increasing contamination of ground water, the easy passage of water through the porous rock and sub-soil underlying much of Miami-Dade County, particularly in times of heavy rains and high ground water level, combined with the continued use of individual wells, and septic tanks, constitutes a danger to the public health of Miami-Dade County and requires the extension of public water supply and public sewage disposal wherever it is physically feasible.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-78. Connection to public water supply and public sewer disposal in abutting streets and easements required</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
All premises used or intended for human habitation or occupancy including, but not limited to, establishments to be used for household, domestic, food processing, food handling, restaurant, dairy or bottling processors, public buildings and places of assembly or other establishments where a water supply is or may be used for human consumption or where human wastes may be disposed of, and which abuts a water main owned by a water utility, or a sewage main owned by a sewage utility, shall be connected to the said water and/or sewer main in such manner as to meet the requirements of the South Florida Building Code and the Miami-Dade County Public Works Manual. A water or sewer main shall be deemed to abut a building or premises if it is located in a street or easement adjoining the land on which the building is located and if it traverses one (1) full dimension of the building.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Where a premises is abutted by two water mains, either one of which the premises can validly be connected to in compliance with the South Florida Building Code and the Miami-Dade County Public Works Manual, and the premises is currently connected to the water main located in the rear of the premises, the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department may require such premises to connect to a water main owned by the Department which abuts the front of the property and to which such premises may validly be connected, at no cost to the property owner. The Department shall be responsible for all costs of disconnection of the water main abutting the rear of the premises and connection to the water main abutting the front of the premises. An owner of a premises who has previously paid a water connection fee to the Department shall not be required to pay an additional water connection fee if the premises was connected to a different water main pursuant to this Section.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Should the owner of a premises currently connected to a water main refuse to allow the Department to disconnect the premises from the water main abutting the rear of the premises and to connect the premises to the water main abutting the front of the premises in accordance with Section 32-78(b), the Department shall have the right to terminate water service to such premises, and shall incur no liability therefore.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The department shall use certified plumbing contractors to disconnect the premises from the rear water main and to connect the premises to the front water main as provided in Section 32-78(b).
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 71-47, § 1, 6-1-71; Ord. No. 08-140, § 1, 12-2-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-79. Notice to connect; procedure</catch_line>
<text>
If the County Manager finds and determines that buildings subject to the terms of this article have not been connected to water mains of water utilities, or sewer mains of sewer utilities, he shall so notify the record owner of the said buildings in writing and demand that such owner cause the connections to be made by duly licensed contractors or the property owner in accordance with the South Florida Building Code within ninety (90) days of the date of service of the notice as hereinafter provided. The notice shall be served by registered mail, addressed to the owner or owners of the property described as they are known to the Manager or as their names and addresses are shown upon the records of the County Tax Assessor, or other Public Records of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and shall be deemed complete and sufficient when so addressed and deposited in the United States mail with proper postage prepaid. In the event that such notice is returned by postal authorities the Manager shall cause a copy of the notice to be served by a law enforcement officer upon the occupant of the land or upon any agent of the owner thereof. In the event that personal service upon the occupant of the land or upon any agent of the owner thereof cannot be performed after reasonable search by a law enforcement officer the notice shall be served by physical posting on the said property, and by publication in a newspaper of general circulation at least twice, seven (7) days between publications, and ninety (90) days before the date of connection is required. The notice shall be in substantially the following form:
"NOTICE REQUIRING CONNECTION TO WATER AND/OR SEWER MAIN
Name of owner _____  
Address of owner _____  
Our records indicate that you are the owner(s) of the following land in Miami-Dade County, Florida: (describe property)
An inspection of this land discloses, and I have found and determined, that a building is located thereon which is not connected to a water main of the (name of utility) and/or to a sewer main of the (name of utility) located in (name of street or description of easement) abutting the said property.
You are hereby notified that unless the said building is connected to the said main(s) within ninety (90) days of personal service upon you, or of the second publication hereof, Miami-Dade County will proceed to effect said connection and the cost of the work, including advertising costs, connection charges and other expenses necessary to make complete connection to building, will be imposed as a lien on the land if not otherwise paid within ninety (90) days after said connection has been made and the cost thereof ascertained by Miami-Dade County.
<section prefix="1" type="table">
<table class="table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
  <col width="66.66666666666667%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FL</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">By: _____<br />County Manager&quot;</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 

</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-80. Connection effected by County; lien; recording; redemption</catch_line>
<text>
If within ninety (90) days after service of the said notice or by physical posting of the notice on the property, or by publication in a newspaper, all as set forth in the preceding section, the connection required thereby has not been effected, the County Manager shall cause the connection to be effected by Miami-Dade County at the expense of the property owner. The cost of the said connection shall constitute a lien upon the real estate served thereby as is hereinafter set out. Upon ordering a connection to be made by the County, the County Manager shall cause to be recorded in the public records a Notice of Water and/or Sewer Connection Lien Pending, which shall include a description of the property and a statement that a connection has been ordered, the cost of which shall under this article constitute a lien. The said notice of water or sewer connection lien shall, eight (8) months after the date thereof, be null and void and constitute no record notice of a pending lien. After causing the connection to be effected the County Manager shall certify to the Director of Finance the expenses, including such connection charges as may have been approved by the appropriate Miami-Dade County agency, incurred in effecting the connection and shall include a copy of the notice above described, whereupon such expense shall become payable within ninety (90) days, after which a special assessment lien and charge will be made upon the property, which shall be payable in ten (10) equal annual installments together with costs of recordation of all documents required to be recorded hereby and with interest at the rate of six (6) percent per annum on the unpaid balance from the date of such certification until paid; provided, however, that the said lien may be satisfied at any time by the payment of the entire sum due plus accrued interest, recordation costs, and such expenses and penalties as may result from the advertisement and sale of certificates for delinquent liens as hereinafter set out. The Director of Finance shall file for record a notice of such lien in the Office of the Clerk of the Circuit Court, and shall keep complete records relating to the amount payable thereon. One-tenth of the amount of liens accruing during any year ending on June first, shall be billed and mailed in the fall of the same year to the owners of land subject to such liens at the same time as tax statements for ad valorem taxes are mailed, and if the said amount shall not be paid on or before April first of the following year, the entire lien and all annual installments thereof shall be delinquent, overdue, and in default, and the entire amount of the lien shall be collected in the same manner as delinquent taxes by advertisement and sale of certificates. Upon full payments of liens provided hereby or tax sale certificates resulting therefrom, the Director of Finance shall, by appropriate means, evidence the satisfaction and cancellation of such lien upon the public records. The cost of recordation of the notice of water and sewer connection lien pending, the notice of lien, and the satisfaction of lien shall be secured by the lien hereby provided.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-81. Exceptions</catch_line>
<text>
Any owner of property who receives a notice to connect and who would be required to pay a connection charge to a utility, in accordance with the tariffs established by the Metro-County Water and Sewer Board, may petition the said Board for an exception from the connection requirements of this article. Any owner of property who receives a notice to connect and who would be required to pay a connection charge to Miami-Dade County, in the case of a County owned utility system, in accordance with the tariffs established by the Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Water and Sewer Authority, may petition the said Authority for an exception from the connection requirements of this article, If the said Board or Authority shall find that the said connection charge is not just and reasonable, it shall grant an exception from the said connection requirements, provided, however, that the exception shall not conflict with any findings or orders of the Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services, the Florida Department of Environmental Regulation, and/or the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management. Service lines from meters to buildings are the responsibility of property owners and the costs thereof shall not be considered by the said Board or Authority in granting the said exceptions.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-82. Delinquent connection charges</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
All water and sewer agreements between Miami-Dade County and developers and property owners offered and executed after the effective date herein shall require that any connection charges unpaid after thirty (30) days from the due date specified in the agreement shall accrue interest at the rate of twelve (12) percent per annum until fully paid.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The interest rate authorized herein may be modified from time to time by the County Manager consistent with the legal rate of interest authorized by Section 687.01, Florida Statutes.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 85-71, §§ 1, 2, 9-18-85)</history>
<EditorsNote>
Codification of §§ 1 and 2 of Ord. No. 85-71, adopted Sept. 18, 1985, as § 32-82 has been at the discretion of the editor.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-83. Peak Flows</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Submission of peak flow data. Every publicly owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system shall submit its peak flow data to the County for use in the County-wide rainfall dependent peak flow management study no later than February 8, 2007. Peak flow data is defined as the hourly flow rates that the system is expected to discharge into the County system during and resulting from a two year storm event. In the event a publicly owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system fails to provide its peak flow data by said date, the County shall determine and establish the peak flow limit for such publicly owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system and such system shall be bound by such determination and the publicly owned or operated sanitary sewer system shall be subject to the provisions in subsection (B).
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Enforcement; procedure; remedies. If actual peak flows exceed the data provided by a publicly owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system or the Peak Flow limit as set by the County pursuant to subsection (A), the owner or operator of such system shall be required to pay additional fees in accordance with the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department's schedule of rates, fees and charges, as amended, and may be subject to a building moratorium in accordance with section 24-13.2 of this code. In addition to any other judicial or administrative remedies provided by this chapter, the Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee, is authorized to institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to seek temporary or permanent, prohibitory or mandatory injunctive relief to enforce compliance with or prohibit the violation of; any provisions of this chapter; any lawful order of the Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department; or any consent agreement.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 01-104, § 1, 6-5-01; Ord. No. 02-107, § 1, 6-18-02; Ord. No. 06-87, § 1, 6-6-06)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-83.1. Water Conservation Plans</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Submission of Water Conservation Plan. Every publicly owned or operated water distribution system supplied potable water, in whole or in part, by Miami-Dade County, shall submit a water conservation plan to the County. All water conservation plans submitted must comply with the South Florida Water Management District Basis of Review for Consumptive Use Permit Application and the Florida Department of Environmental Protection Conserve Florida Guide, as well as the Environmental Protection Agency WaterSense Program. Said Plan shall be updated for the County's approval every five years following submittal and Conserve Florida Guide generated reports shall be filed annually at the close of the fiscal year. All water conservation plans submitted shall consider a twenty year horizon. In the event a publicly owned or operated water distribution system fails to provide its water conservation plan by the close of the fiscal year, the County shall determine and establish the conservation measures to be implemented by said system and the amount of water supplied to such system by the County which could be conserved via implementation of such measures, and such system shall be bound by such determination and the publicly owned or operated water distribution system shall be subject to the provisions in subsection (B).
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Enforcement; procedure; remedies. Where the County has, pursuant to subsection (A), established the conservation measures and the amount of water supplied to a water distribution system which could be conserved through the implementation of such measures, the owner or operator of such system shall be required to pay additional fees, in accordance with the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department's schedule of rates, fees and charges, as amended, for continued use of the water which could be conserved through implementation of the specified conservation measures. The Miami Dade Water and Sewer Department shall develop a water conservation plan for the water distribution system documenting the proposed measures, best management practices and projected water savings.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 06-177, § 1, 12-5-06)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-84. Water use efficiency standards manual</catch_line>
<text>
The Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department ("MDWASD"), in consultation with the Planning Department and such other applicable county departments and agencies, shall publish a water use efficiency standards manual to achieve maximum water savings in new residential and commercial developments in the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County. The manual shall be initially published on January 1, 2009, and may be updated annually on January 1 following approval by the County Commission. Each applicant for water service to a new residential or commercial development in incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County shall include in its application every water use efficiency standard that will be incorporated into the new development. The County or applicable municipality shall review the application for compliance with the manual. In evaluating the application for compliance, the County or applicable municipality will consider the availability of products required to implement the water use efficiency standards. The developer's agreement for water service shall include the water use efficiency standards approved by the County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-85. Alternative water supply for developments of regional impact</catch_line>
<text>
Applications for new Developments of Regional Impact ("DRI") with a projected water demand of one million gallons per day or greater shall be evaluated by MDWASD to determine the feasibility of an alternative water supply project. Such projects may include the installation of a reverse osmosis plant, wastewater reclamation facility and reuse distribution system.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-86. Water use efficiency and conservation education and outreach</catch_line>
<text>
The Miami-Dade County Water Use Efficiency Manager shall provide public information, education and outreach on all water use efficiency standards and water conservation programs.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 32-87—32-90. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (7) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 71-47, § 1, enacted June 1, 1971, amended Article V, §§ 32-76—32-81, to read as set out. Formerly said article and sections, derived from Ord. No. 65-44, §§ 1—6, enacted June 4, 1965, pertained to water connections. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
