<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="2">Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="3">ARTICLE_XXV._CHILDREN'S_SERVICES_COUNCIL</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-231. Purpose</catch_line>
<text>
In recognition of the special and urgent needs for advocacy and planning on behalf of children, there is hereby established the Miami-Dade County Children's Services Council for the purpose of advising the Board of County Commissioners on matters pertaining to the provision of services and care to all children within the County. The Council shall also assist in the coordination of efforts made by the public and private sectors to plan for and enhance the availability and quality of services and programs affecting children within the County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-232. Limited applicability of ordinance creating standards for creation and review of boards</catch_line>
<text>
Unless otherwise specified herein, Sections 2-11.36 through 2-11.39 of the Code of Miami-Dade County shall govern the Council.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-233. Composition and terms of membership</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Council shall be composed of twenty-seven (27) members as follows: The Miami-Dade State Attorney; the Superintendent of Schools; the District Administrator of the State of Florida Department of Children and Families District XI; the Senior Juvenile Justice Manager of the State Department of Juvenile Justice, District XI; the Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Health; the County Manager, seven (7) members, one (1) from each of the following organizations or agencies: A member of the Board of County Commissioners; a member of the Miami-Dade County School Board; a Judge assigned to the Juvenile Court Division of Florida's Eleventh Judicial Circuit; a member of the Miami-Dade Legislative Delegation; a representative of United Way; a representative from the Miami-Dade County PTA/PTSA; a representative from the Greater Miami Chamber of Commerce; one (1) youth representative between the ages of fifteen (15) and twenty-two (22) years; and thirteen (13) members appointed by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
No member appointed by the Board of County Commissioners or by a designated organization or agency shall serve more than three (3) consecutive and complete two-year terms. Of the initial Commission-appointed members, five (5) shall be appointed for two (2) years and four (4) shall be appointed for one (1) year. After the initial appointments, all terms shall be for two (2) years.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 90-50, § 1, 6-5-90; Ord. No. 90-108, § 1, 9-25-90; Ord. No. 95-83, § 1, 5-2-95; Ord. No. 97-54, § 1, 5-20-97; Ord. No. 99-40, § 1, 4-27-99)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-234. Appointment and removal of Commission-appointed Council members</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
With respect to the appointment of Council members by the Commission, the Commission shall give careful consideration to the advocacy needs of children and to the expertise needed to accomplish the goals of the Council, including, but not limited to, medical expertise.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
In the event of a vacancy during the term of a Commissioner-appointed member, the Council shall notify the Commission of the vacancy.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Any Commission-appointed Council member may be removed for cause by two-thirds vote of the entire membership of the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 90-50, § 1, 6-5-90)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-235. Organization of Council and staff support</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Council shall select one of its members as Chairperson, shall select any other officers as the Council deems necessary or desirable and shall adopt a schedule of regular meetings. A majority of the members of the Council shall constitute a quorum. No recommendations shall be forwarded nor action taken by the Council unless first approved by a majority of a quorum attending a regularly scheduled or specially called meting of the Council. Special meetings of the Council may be called by the Chairperson or upon the written request of five (5) Council members. All meetings of the Council shall be public and written minutes shall be maintained.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The County Manager, County Attorney and Department of Youth and Family Development shall provide appropriate staff support to the Council. The Council may engage the services of additional staff and personnel and contract for other services, subject to County Commission approval.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 90-50, § 1, 6-5-90)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-236. Council functions, responsibilities and restrictions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Council shall have the following functions within the scope of its powers and shall exercise same subject to the direction of the Board of County Commissioners.
<section prefix = "1">
To serve in an advisory capacity to County government with respect to all issues within the Council's jurisdiction.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To encourage and facilitate coordination and cooperation with respect to programs and funding among those public and private agencies providing children's services within Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
To formulate legislative, programmatic and funding agendas needed to address present and future needs of children in the community, including the identification and development of funding sources.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
To provide legislative analysis and development at the local, State and federal levels.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
To provide technical assistance as needed in the areas of concept development and grant writing.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
To conduct research, compile information and maintain a comprehensive data base relating to children's programs, services and needs.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
To monitor and evaluate existing children's services and give appropriate input with respect thereto.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
To provide a forum for the discussion of issues relating to children.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
To engage in advocacy activities on behalf of children.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
To advise public and private sector organizations and agencies on issues relating to children, including recommending public policies relevant to children and families.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
To network with other local governments to identify, increase and promote governmental and other funding for children's services programs.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
To perform any other advisory functions assigned to the Council by the Commission.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Chairperson, or his or her designee, shall present to the Board of County Commissioners on an annual basis a written report describing the Council's activities. The Chairperson, or his or her designee, may also appear as needed before the Board to present any matters pertinent to the Council's concerns.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Council is advisory only and shall not have the power or authority to commit Miami-Dade County or any of its agencies to any policies, to incur any financial obligation or to create any liability, contractual or otherwise, on the part of the County or any of its agencies.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Council members shall serve without compensation. The Board of County Commissioners may provide funds for appropriate and necessary expenses incurred by the Council or any of its members.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The Council shall have the authority to accept gifts of money, services, or personal property. Subject to the prior approval of the Board of County Commissioners, the Council may accept gifts of real property, the title of which shall be in Miami-Dade County. All gifts shall be held in a designated trust fund and used in the exercise of the Council's functions and responsibilities as outlined in this section. The trust fund shall be administered by the Department of Human Services, Office of Youth and Family Development and all expenditures of trust funds shall be approved by the Children's Services Council. Formal bid procedures and the requirements of Administrative Order 3-2 for the expenditure of trust funds for the purchase of goods and services associated with the programs and projects of the Children's Services Council are waived.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 90-50, § 1, 6-5-90; Ord. No. 92-36, § 1, 5-5-92; Ord. No. 96-75, § 1, 5-7-96)</history>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (43) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 90-50, § 1, adopted June 5, 1990, repealed former Art. XXV, §§ 2-231—2-236, relative to the Youth Advisory Board, and enacted a new Art. XXV, the substantive provisions of which have been designated at the discretion of the editor as §§ 2-231—2-236. The provisions of former Art. XXV derived from the following ordinances: Ord. No. 65-39, §§ 1—6, 5-18-65; Ord. No. 67-15, § 5, 3-7-67; Ord. No. 68-74, § 1, 12-3-68; Ord. No. 76-110, § 1, 12-7-76; Ord. No. 79-61, § 1, 7-3-79; Ord. No. 85-55, § 1, 7-16-85; Ord. No. 85-79, § 1, 10-1-85. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
