<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="2">Chapter_19A_MOBILE_HOMES</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 19A-1. Florida Statutes and State regulations</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Florida Statutes. Pursuant to Chapter 320, as amended, the following mandatory regulations set forth the minimum standards applicable to mobile homes and motor vehicles, as defined herein, used as housing:
<section prefix = "1">
All construction in mobile homes manufactured more than six (6) months after July 11, 1967, and sold or offered for sale in the State of Florida, shall meet the provisions of the American National Standards Institute Standard ANSI A-119-1; including body and frame construction and the installation of plumbing, heating and electrical systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Such vehicles shall be inspected where they are manufactured by the Florida Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles and shall bear a seal assuring compliance with the Standard ANSI A-119-1, as well as with such rules and regulations said Department deems necessary for effective administration and enforcement.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Such vehicles shall also bear the certification by the manufacturer that the vehicle to which the seal is attached meets or exceeds the provisions of the Standard ANSI A-119-1, except, where a used mobile home originally sold out of the State of Florida is resold in Florida, the dealer shall provide the certification.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Where a used mobile home, manufactured prior to July 11, 1967, is sold in the State of Florida, the seller shall provide certification that the vehicle meets the standards in effect at the time the vehicle was manufactured.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
(a) The owner of a mobile home shall secure it to the ground by the use of anchors and tie downs so as to resist wind overturning and sliding.
<section prefix = "b">
A mobile home manufactured in accordance with the Standard ANSI A-119-1 and labeled "hurricane and windstorm resistive" shall be anchored according to the instructions furnished by the manufacturer and shipped within each unit.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
A mobile home not meeting the ANSI Standard provisions shall be anchored as set forth in Section 19A-5 herein.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
The owner of a mobile home, or a motor vehicle used as housing, unless excepted by Section 19A-3, who resides in or is intending to reside in a trailer or mobile home park, or other authorized location in Florida, shall obtain a certificate of completion approving such use from the appropriate jurisdiction.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
After on-site inspection and compliance with federal, State and local codes and regulations, the final certificate of completion shall be issued.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
County ordinance. In the unincorporated areas, this chapter shall be enforced by the County Building Official.
<section prefix = "1">
In the incorporated areas, this chapter shall be enforced by the municipalities.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Where this chapter is not enforced within a municipality the County shall enforce the same through the County Building Official.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
No variance shall be granted from the provisions hereof.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 77-1, § 1, 1-4-77)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 19A-2. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
In construing the provisions of this chapter and each and every word, term, phrase, or part hereof where the context will permit the definitions provided in Section 320.01, Florida Statutes, and as otherwise provided herein shall apply:
<section prefix = "a">
Recreational vehicle: Classed under "motor vehicle," a recreational vehicle-type unit primarily designed as temporary living quarters for recreational, camping or travel use, which either has its own motive power or is mounted on or is drawn by another vehicle.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Travel trailer: Classed under "motor vehicle," a vehicular portable unit, mounted on wheels, of such a size or weight as not to require special highway movement permits when drawn by a motorized vehicle. It is primarily designed and constructed to provide temporary living quarters for recreational, camping or travel use. It is of a body width of no more than eight (8) feet and a body length of no more than thirty-two (32) feet when factory-equipped for the road.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Camping trailer: Classed under "motor vehicle," a vehicular portable unit mounted on wheels and constructed with collapsible partial sidewalls which fold for towing by another vehicle and unfold at the campsite to provide temporary living quarters for recreational, camping, or travel use.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Truck camper: Classed under "motor vehicle," a portable unit, designed to be loaded onto, or affixed to, the bed or chassis of a truck, constructed to provide temporary living quarters for recreational, camping, or travel use.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Motor home: Classed under "motor vehicle," a vehicular unit built on a self-propelled motor vehicle chassis, primarily designed to provide temporary living quarters for recreational, camping or travel use.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Mobile home: Not classed as a "motor vehicle," includes any type of trailer or vehicle body, regardless of any appurtenances, additions or other modifications thereto, without independent motive power, manufactured upon an integral chassis or undercarriage and designed either for travel over the highways or for housing accommodations or both.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Owner: Includes any person, firm, corporation, or association controlling any vehicle by right of purchase, gift, lease or otherwise.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Final certificate of completion: An instrument issued by the Building Official certifying that all final inspections required for mobile homes, and motor vehicles used as housing, have been completed in accordance with State and local codes and regulations and that occupancy is approved.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Mobile home or motor vehicle used as housing: A mobile home or motor vehicle used as a dwelling place and located on the same site for fourteen (14) or more continuous days.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Coastal General Flood Hazard District: Shall mean that a portion of Dade County comprised of those areas designated "A" upon the official flood hazard boundary map issued and approved by the Federal Insurance Administrator dated August 14, 1970, and No. 12-025-0000-01 through 56 and as the same may, from time to time, be amended by the Federal Insurance Administrator.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 19A-3. Exceptions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Existing mobile homes or motor vehicles used as housing which remain on the same site and which are in compliance with the requirements of Chapter 19A on January 4, 1977, shall be exempt from the additional requirements imposed by the amendment to this chapter having an effective date of January 5, 1977. Mobile homes or motor vehicles which are moved to a site after January 4, 1977 or which were used as housing, not in compliance with this chapter on January 4, 1977, must meet all requirements of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Travel trailers used as housing only during the time frame period of November 30th to May 1st shall be exempt from the provisions of this chapter.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 77-1, § 1, 1-4-77)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 19A-4. Penalty for violations</catch_line>
<text>
Any person found guilty of violating any provisions of these regulations shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00), or by imprisonment in the County Jail for a period not to exceed sixty (60) days, or both such fine and imprisonment, in the discretion of the Metropolitan Court; and each day's violation shall be considered a separate offense.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 19A-5. Foundations, piers and anchors</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
All mobile homes and motor vehicles used as housing shall be anchored and secured in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
The following mandatory provisions are substantially the minimum standards set forth by the Dpartment of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles, Division of Motor Vehicles, for blocking, anchoring and securing mobile homes and motor vehicles used as housing:
<section prefix = "1">
Foundations and piers.
<section prefix = "a">
Pier foundations shall be provided upon each main supporting beam running lengthwise in the frame of mobile homes and motor vehicles. Such foundations shall not exceed ten (10) feet center-to-center and shall be so located that the supporting beams extend no more than two (2) feet beyond the center line of the foundations, front or rear.
Double-wide structures will require twice the number of foundations and piers as is required for single-wide structures.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
All grass and other organic material shall be removed and the pier foundations shall be placed on stable soil, level rock or gravel, or embedded at least four (4) inches in sand or loam soil. Pier foundations shall be sixteen (16) inches by sixteen (16) inches by four (4) inches thick solid concrete, precast, poured-in-place, or the equivalent.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Corner piers shall be double blocked and all other piers shall be constructed of approved eight-inch by eight-inch by sixteen-inch concrete block, solid or cored with open cells vertical, centered on each pier foundation. A two-inch by eight-inch by sixteen-inch long wood plate, treated in accordance with paragraph 2913.2(a) of the South Florida Building Code, shall be placed on top of each pier with shim shingles fitted and driven tight between the wood plate and the main frame where necessary to provide uniform bearing.
<section prefix = "1">
Single block piers shall be installed perpendicular to the main supporting beams.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Piers over forty (40) inches in height shall be of double-block tiers, each tier turned ninety (90) degrees from the tier below and capped with four (4) inches of concrete, poured or the equivalent, and cushioned with pressure-treated wood shims or wood plate.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Corner piers over three (3) blocks high shall be double-blocked tiers, each tier turned ninety (90) degrees from the tier below, and capped with four (4) inches of concrete, poured or the equivalent, and cushioned with pressure-treated wood shims or wood plate.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Other equivalent types of foundations and piers may be provided where approved by the Building Official.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Tie downs.
<section prefix = "a">
Each structure shall be provided with minimum anchorage according to Table 19A and all anchorage products and their installation shall be approved by the Building Official.
     TABLE 19A
<section prefix="1" type="table">
<table class="table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="84px" /> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" colspan="3" valign="top" class=""> <i>Structure Length Excluding Hitch</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Component</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Up to</i> <br /><i>40 feet</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Over 40</i> <br />feet to<br /><i>60 feet</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Over</i> <br /><i>60 feet</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> *Ground anchors and frame ties per side</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 3</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 5</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 7</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">**Over-roof ties</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 3</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 3</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 3</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 
 * Required around the perimeter only (outside main frame members only of both single-wide and double-wide structures).
** Perimeter frame-tie ground anchors may be located so as to provide common anchorage with over-roof ties. Over-roof ties are not required for double-wide units.

     TABLE 19A-A*
<section prefix="2" type="table">
<table class="thead2 table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " colspan="2" valign="top" class=""> <i>Structure Length Excluding Hitch</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class=""> <i>Component</i> </td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class=""> <i>Less than</i> <br /><i>50 feet</i> </td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class=""> <i>50 feet</i> <br /><i>and longer</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Ground anchors and frame ties per side</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 6</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 7</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Over-roof ties</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 3</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> 4</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 
 * This table only applies to those newly installed mobile homes or motor vehicles used as housing, located within the Coastal General Flood Hazard District designated "A" upon the official flood hazard boundary map issued and approved by the Federal Insurance Administrator and required by the established rules and regulations issued by the federal Department of Housing and Urban Development on October 26, 1976 in accordance with the National Flood Insurance Program.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Frame ties shall be attached to the main framing members (chassis) in a manner not allowing release under vibratory loading. Frame ties shall include approved one-half-inch drop-forged steel turn-buckles with welded eyes connected to approved ground anchors with wire rope having a breaking strength of not less than four thousand seven hundred fifty (4,750) pounds, or the equivalent. End ties shall attach not more than twenty-four (24) inches from each end of the frame.
<section prefix = "1">
Intermediate ties shall be spaced at equal intervals according to the requirements tabulated in Table 19A
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Over-roof ties shall not contact with the structure except at adequately reinforced areas where the additional load will not damage such structure.
<section prefix = "1">
Over-roof ties shall be approved straps capable of resisting an up-lift force of not less than thirty (30) pounds per square foot. The intermediate strap shall be located midway between the end straps.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
End over-roof ties shall be installed not more than twenty-four (24) inches from the end of the structure, or at the first stud-and-truss, and attach to the same ground anchor as the frame ties. Where frames do not extend to the rear wall of structure, frame ties shall attach not less than six (6) inches from the rear end of the frame. Intermediate over-roof ties shall then be located as midway between end ties as is feasible.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Other equivalent types of ground anchors, frame ties and over the roof ties may be provided where the design and installation procedure are approved by the Building Official.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Ground anchors. Ground anchors shall be of approved design and shall be one of the following:
<section prefix = "a">
A steel screw auger not less than six (6) inches in diameter at one end of a minimum five-eighths-inch diameter steel rod and a welded eye at the other end.
<section prefix = "1">
Where installed, such augers shall penetrate the ground not less than three and one-half (3½) feet.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A five-eighths-inch diameter steel rod providing a six-inch hook at one end and a welded eye at the other, or a bent U-shaped five-eighths-inch rod with two (2) three-inch hooks, cast into a reinforced concrete slab not less than four (4) inches thick and one hundred (100) square feet in area.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
An eyebolt or U-shaped anchor rod as described in subparagraph (b) above, cast at least six (6) inches into a poured-in-place concrete deadman at least six (6) inches in diameter and embedded not less than two (2) feet deep in rock.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Exceptions.
<section prefix = "a">
Single-wide mobile structures of a model year prior to 1971 shall be considered as complying with the provisions of this section where at least one (1) over-roof tie is provided at each end of such structure. Frame ties shall, however, be provided as tabulated in Table 19A herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
End frame-ties only may be provided where mobile structures are located adjacent to a concrete slab, as set forth in subparagraph (3)(b) herein, providing the underside of the structure floor is twelve (12) inches or less above the surface of such slab and sixteen (16) inches or less above the ground surface beneath the structure, measured vertically.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Where a minimum of two-thirds the length of the frame of a mobile unit is supported by and attached to a structure which meets the requirements for uplift and overturning for permanent construction, as set forth in subsection 2306.4 of the South Florida Building Code, the tie down provisions of this chapter shall be considered as having been met.

</section>
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 77-1, § 1, 1-4-77)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 19A-6. Notification and enforcement of State regulations and chapter</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Trailer and mobile home park owners or operators shall notify all current and prospective park occupants of their legal responsibility to obtain a certificate of completion, unless excepted herein, and shall post the provisions of State regulations, as amended, and of this chapter, as amended, in conspicuous locations within such parks.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A temporary certificate of completion may be obtained by the park owner, owner or operator or State licensed mobile home or motor vehicle dealer for any mobile home or motor vehicle used as housing, and required to meet the provisions of this chapter for a maximum of thirty (30) consecutive days prior to obtaining the required final certificate of completion.
Such temporary certificate of completion must be obtained before occupancy and before its expiration in thirty (30) days, a final certificate of completion obtained or said mobile home or motor vehicle used for housing shall cease to be occupied.
A final certificate of completion shall be issued upon application after inspection verifies that the provisions of this chapter have been met and after payment of a reasonable fee.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 77-1, § 1, 1-4-77)</history>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (1) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 77-1, § 1, amended Ch. 19A to read as set out in §§ 19A-1—19A-6. Former Ch. 19A, pertaining to mobile homes and travel trailers, was derived from Ord. No. 67-40, §§ 1—5, adopted June 6, 1967. (Back)
Cross reference— Building code, Ch. 8; housing, Ch. 17; zoning requirements for mobile homes in mobile parks, § 33-166 et seq. (Back)
State Law reference— Mobile homes, F.S. § 320.822 et seq. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
