<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="2">Chapter_28_SUBDIVISIONS</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 28-1. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
For the purposes of this chapter, the following terms shall have the following meanings. When not inconsistent with the context, words used in the present tense include the future, words in the plural number include the singular, and words in the singular number include the plural. The word "shall" is always mandatory and not merely directory.
<section prefix = "a">
"Final plat" is the final tracing, map or drawing or chart on which the subdivider's plan of subdivision is presented to the governing body for approval, and which, if approved, will be submitted to the Clerk of the Circuit Court for recording.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
"Flood criteria" is the minimum finished elevation required for all lands as established and shown on the flood criteria map recorded in Plat Book 53, pages 68, 69, and 70 of the public records of this County as the same may be modified from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
"Lot" is a portion of a subdivision or other parcel of land, however designated, intended as a single building site or unit for transfer of ownership or for development.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
"The manual of public works construction of the Department of Public Works" is the comprehensive set of specifications prepared by the County's Department of Public Works covering the minimum requirements for the design and construction of engineering works such as, but not limited to: Streets, roads and highways, sidewalks, filling and grading, excavating, harbors and docks, drainage installation and structures, water control work and water supply, paving installations, curbs and gutters, bridges and overpasses and underpasses, underground sewage collections and disposal systems, underground utility line construction, levees, pumping stations and similar works.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
"Master plan" is the comprehensive plan prepared by the County's Department of Planning and Zoning which indicates the general locations recommended for the various functional classes of public works, places and structures and for the general physical development of the County and includes any unit or part of such plan separately adopted and any amendment to such plan or parts thereof.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
"Official map" is the map established by the County showing the streets, highways and parks laid out, adopted and established by the County or additions thereto resulting from the approval of subdivision plats by the governing bodies and the subsequent filing of such approved plats.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Streets, alleys, easements and rights-of-way.
<section prefix = "1">
"Alley" is a minor way which is used primarily for vehicular service access to the back or the side of properties otherwise abutting on a street.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
"Arterial street" is a heavily traveled street of considerable continuity used primarily as a main traffic artery.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
"Collector street" is a street which carries traffic from minor streets to arterial streets, including the principal entrance streets of a residential development and streets for circulation within such development.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
"Cul-de-sac" or "dead-end street" is a minor street with only one (1) outlet terminating at one (1) end with a turnaround.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
"Easement" or "servitude" is a strip reserved by the subdivider for public utilities, drainage and other public purposes, the title to which shall remain in the property owner, subject to the right of use designated in the reservation of the servitude.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
"Limited access highway" or "freeway" is a highway which permits no access except at authorized and controlled points, the acquisition of rights-of-way for such highway usually including the acquisition of access rights thereto. Access may also be limited through methods other than acquisition of access right.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
"Marginal access street" is a minor street which is parallel and adjacent to arterial streets and which provides access to abutting properties and protection from through traffic.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
"Minor street" is a street used primarily for access to the abutting properties.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
"Parkway" is a route intended to be used primarily by passenger vehicles which may have a varying width of right-of-way and which right-of-way is or is intended to be developed with a park-like character.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
"Width of street" is the shortest distance between the lines delineating the right-of-way of a street.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
"Right-of-way" is a strip of ground dedicated by the subdivider, deeded by the owner, for public use.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
"Mapped street" is any approved street shown on an official map, or the projection of an existing street through an unsubdivided parcel of land, whether the street is dedicated, or in existence or not. For the purpose of this definition all normal five-acre fractional lines shall be deemed the center line of mapped street, unless waived by the plat division of the appropriate authority.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
"Limited access line" is a designated line across which there shall be no vehicular access.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
"Subdivider" is any individual, firm, association, syndicate, copartnership, corporation, trust or any other legal entity commencing proceedings under this chapter to effect a subdivision of land hereunder for himself or for another.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
"Subdivision" is:
<section prefix = "1">
The division of land for any use so as to create one (1) or more lots, sites, tracts or parcels otherwise designated of any size for the purpose of transfer of ownership, leasing, or building development. The division of land, zoned for single-family residential use, shall not be deemed a subdivision if the land is being divided into parcels, each of which is more than one and one-quarter (1¼) acres in size exclusive of any official right-of-way.
The division of land, zoned for agricultural, general or interim use or which is unzoned, shall not be deemed a subdivision if the land is being divided into parcels each of which is five (5) acres or more in size, including any official right-of-way.
Separate parcels created pursuant to Section 33-257(2) or pursuant to Section 33-31 of the Code shall not be deemed a subdivision of real property.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The dedication of a road, highway, street, alley, easement through or on a tract of land regardless of area.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The resubdivision of land heretofore divided or platted into lots, sites or parcels.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
"Tentative plat" is a preliminary map, drawing or chart indicating the proposed layout of the subdivision submitted for approval. Said preliminary map, drawing or chart shall not be considered a boundary survey as defined in Chapter 21HH-6 of the Florida Administrative Code, as same may be amended from time to time. It shall be considered a specific purpose survey as defined in said Chapter 21HH-6; said specific purpose being for subdivision design, therefore conceptual in nature, and subject to change prior to the boundary survey being made for which a plat of record is being filed.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
"Decorative masonry wall" is a wall of masonry composition, at least five (5) feet in height, with a struck natural, painted, stuccoed, or painted struck block finish on both sides with a continuous concrete cap. For the purpose of this definition, a combination of fence and landscaping that creates a satisfactory buffer shall be considered acceptable substitutes for a decorative masonry wall.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
"Plat division of the appropriate authority" is the competent staff, including a professional land surveyor, of the governing body created to review plats or an independent land surveying firm under contract by the governing body to review plats. By definition, the independent land surveying firm shall not be the same as the land surveyor recording the plat, so as to prevent any conflict of interest. Municipalities without a plat division may request the County's plat division to review both tentative and final plats, in which case the subdivider shall pay the same fees to the County as a subdivider within the unincorporated areas of the County would pay.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
"County's plat division" by definition shall be a committee consisting of one (1) member from each of the following Miami-Dade County Departments: Public Works; Planning and Zoning; Environmental Resources Management; Parks and Recreation; and the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 28-2. Purpose of chapter</catch_line>
<text>
The public health, safety, comfort, and welfare requires the harmonious, orderly, and progressive development of land within the County. In furtherance of this purpose, this chapter regulates the subdivision of land in both the incorporated and unincorporated areas of the County. It is the further intent of this chapter to secure:
<section prefix = "a">
The establishment of standards of subdivision design which will encourage the development of sound and economically stable communities, and the creation of healthy living environments.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The efficient adequate and economic supply of utilities and services to land developments.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The prevention of traffic hazards and the provisions of safe and convenient vehicular and pedestrian traffic circulation in land developments.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The provision of public open spaces in land developments for recreational and educational purposes.

This chapter is intended to aid in the coordination of land development in the community in accordance with orderly physical patterns and to implement the master plan, or parts, thereof, and such zoning regulations and other measures in furtherance of such master plan as may have been or may hereafter be adopted.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 28-3. Application of chapter</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
This chapter shall apply to and be enforced in both the incorporated and unincorporated areas of the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
No person, firm, corporation or any other association, shall create a subdivision of a tract of land anywhere in the County except in conformity with this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
No tentative or final plat containing any restriction of any nature based on race, ethnicity, national origin, religion, sexual orientation or gender shall be submitted by a subdivider or presented to the plat division of the appropriate authority or the governing body for approval.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 77-6, § 1, 2-1-77; Ord. No. 05-87, § 1, 5-3-05)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 28-4. Plats and platting—Recording; exceptions</catch_line>
<text>
Whenever land is subdivided a plat must be recorded, except that the recording of a plat will not be required if:
<section prefix = "1">
The subdivision involved consists only of the dedication of a road, highway, street, alley or easement and due to unusual conditions and circumstances the plat division of the appropriate authority finds that it is not necessary that a plat be recorded. In lieu of the recording of a plat, the dedication may be required by deed, and may be subject to compliance with such conditions as may be deemed appropriate under the particular circumstances, such as improvements of sidewalks, streets, or drainage facilities and the acceptance of the dedication by the governing body. Posting of bond may be required.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The land to be subdivided is to be divided into no more than six (6) parcels and because of (a) unusual conditions created by ownership or development of adjacent lands, or (b) the isolation or remoteness of the land concerned in relation to other platted or improved lands, or (c) improvements and dedications existing on the land substantially in accordance with the requirements of this chapter, it is determined by the plat division of the appropriate authority that waiving of the requirement for platting would not conflict with the purpose and intent of this chapter. In lieu of platting the plat division of the appropriate authority may require any dedications, reservations, or improvements required in connection with platting under this chapter, including the posting of a performance and maintenance bond, as may be necessary to carry out the intent and purpose of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The resubdivision of land heretofore platted is of such unusual size or shape, or is surrounded by such development or unusual conditions as may be determined by the plat division of the appropriate authority to justify the waiving of the requirement for recording a plat. In lieu of the recording of a plat, such conditions may be imposed as may be deemed necessary and appropriate to preserve the public interest.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
A parcel of land conveyed by a recorded warranty deed that is dated prior to January 1, 1958, the effective date of this code; provided, however, that the parcel may be diminished in size as a result of a public dedication of any portion of that parcel.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 28-4.1. Same—Procedure for waiver of plat</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
To determine if the waiving of the requirement for platting would not conflict with the purpose and intent of this chapter, and the exceptions contained in Section 28-4 are applicable, a waiver of plat survey shall be submitted by the property owner.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A waiver of plat application shall be submitted, signed by the owner and notarized on the form prescribed by the plat division of the appropriate authority.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The waiver of plat survey shall be prepared by a land surveyor registered in the State of Florida and shall bear the embossed seal of the land surveyor.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The waiver of plat survey shall include the following items, unless waived by the plat division of the appropriate authority:
<section prefix = "1">
Legal description of the parent tract.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Legal description of each parcel to be created.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Location of property lines, existing easements, buildings, watercourses and other essential features.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The location of any existing sewers and water mains, or any underground or overhead utilities, culverts and drains on the property to be subdivided.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Location, names and present widths of existing and proposed streets, highways, easements, building lines, alleys, parks and other open public spaces and similar facts regarding property immediately adjacent.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Date of field survey, north point and graphic scale.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
The width and location of all streets or other public ways proposed by the developer.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
The proposed lot lines with dimensions.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Existing ground elevations of the property and extending not less than twenty-five (25) feet beyond the boundaries of property.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Existing easements or restrictions shown on underlying plat shall be shown.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
The location of all buildings, swimming pools, slabs, fences and other permanent structures on the adjacent properties that would be nonconforming with the creation of this division of land.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The property owner shall pay such fees as may be prescribed for checking the waiver of plat and investigating such matters concerning it as may be required.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The property owner shall submit a current opinion of title from any attorney authorized to practice law in this State with the submittal of the waiver of plat application.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Prior to the approval of the waiver of plat the property owner shall submit appropriate documentation showing the consent of any mortgage holders to the adoption of the waiver of plat.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Certification from the County that all taxes and assessments have been paid on the land within the proposed waiver of plat or receipted tax bills prior to the approval of the waiver of plat.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
The property owner shall pay clerk's fees for the recordation of the governing body's resolution that approved the waiver of plat.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
The property owner shall comply with all the County's Plat Committee requirements within 60 days of the recommendation for approval by the County's Plat Committee. If the property owner fails to comply with said requirements within the time prescribed, the Chief of Public Works and Waste Management's Land Development Division, or designee, shall notify the property owner that the recommendation for approval of the waiver of plat is rescinded.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 79-18, § 1, 3-6-79; Ord. No. 82-71, § 2, 7-20-82; Ord. No. 12-41, § 1, 6-5-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 28-4.2. Same—Administrative prohibition of action on or approval of tentative plats and waivers of plats in unincorporated Miami-Dade County and vested rights procedure</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Administrative prohibition of action on or approval of tentative plats and waiver of plats.
<section prefix = "1">
Whenever any zoning hearing for a district boundary change within the unincorporated area is initiated by the Director of the Department of Planning and Zoning, the County Manager may order that no tentative plat or waiver of plat, pertaining to any or all property involved in the application shall be acted upon or approved until the hearing upon said application has been finally concluded in accordance with the provisions of this Code. No such order shall issue unless the County Manager first determines that the processing and approval of tentative plats and waiver of plats would create a risk of land use contrary to the zoning which is most appropriate for the area. Said order shall not prevent processing and approval of a tentative plat or waiver of plat which would be permissible if the Director's application were granted.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Should the County Manager issue an order pursuant to this section, administrative personnel shall schedule the zoning application for the first public hearing date after appropriate legal notice. The Manager's order shall expire upon final action upon the zoning application. If the application for zoning change is not decided at the hearing for which it is first scheduled, the Board of County Commissioners shall at said time decide whether the Manager's order shall remain in effect and the Board shall review the continued effectiveness of the order at any subsequent hearing to which the application is deferred and not decided.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Vested rights.
<section prefix = "1">
Any property owner claiming a vested right to obtain action upon or approval of a tentative plat or waiver of plat contrary to this section may submit an application for a determination of vested rights to the Miami-Dade County Plat Division.
The application shall have attached an affidavit setting forth the facts upon which the applicant bases his claim for vested rights. The applicant shall also attach copies of any contracts, letters and other documents upon which a claim of vested rights is based. The mere existence of zoning shall not vest rights.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Miami-Dade County Plat Division shall review the application and determine whether the applicant has demonstrated:
<section prefix = "a">
An act of development approval by an agency of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County,
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Upon which the applicant has in good faith relied to his detriment,
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Such that it would be highly inequitable to deny the landowner the right to obtain action on or approval of a tentative plat.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Any appeal of the Miami-Dade County Plat Division's determination shall be made following the procedures outlined in Section 28-7(f) Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The provisions of this subsection (b) shall not prohibit the Board of County Commissioners from considering the issue of vested rights during other hearings where such rights are in issue, provided that a decision upon a claim of such rights shall be a final determination thereof and further administrative hearings thereon shall be neither required nor permitted.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 84-94, § 1, 12-4-84; Ord. No. 91-121, § 1, 9-16-91; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 1, 9-3-98)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 28-5. Same—Approval before recording</catch_line>
<text>
No plat of any subdivision shall be entitled to record in the office of the Clerk of the Circuit Court until it shall have been approved in the manner prescribed herein. In the event any such unapproved plat is recorded it shall be stricken from the record upon application of the governing body of the municipality in which the plat lies; or the governing body of the County for any nonconforming plat in the incorporated area or in the unincorporated area of the County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 28-6. Same—Revising plat after approval</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Any changes, erasures, modifications or revisions to an approved plat prior to recordation may only be made by the Plat Division to correct scriveners errors, reflect accurate legal descriptions and locate right-of-way dedications, drainage ways and easements.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
No changes, erasures, modifications or revisions to an approved plat prior to recordation shall be made unless resubmitted for new approval provided, however, that the governing body may, after public hearing and based only upon a recommendation of its Plat Division, change, modify or revise dedicated road rights-of-way or drainage easements.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 77-6, § 1, 2-1-77; Ord. No. 03-94, § 1, 4-22-03)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 28-7. Same—Procedure for platting</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Preliminary conference. The subdivider or his engineer, or land surveyor, prior to the preparation of the tentative plat, may informally seek the advice of the plat division of the appropriate authority in order that he may become familiar with the subdivision requirements and with the provisions of the master plan affecting the territory in which the proposed subdivision is located.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Tentative plat. The tentative plat shall show on a map all of the facts and data required by the various departments to determine whether the proposed layout of the land in the subdivision is satisfactory from the standpoint of public interest.
<section prefix = "1">
The following information shall be part of the tentative plat unless waived by the plat division of the appropriate authority.
<section prefix = "a">
Proposed subdivision name and identifying title and the name of the city, if any, in which the subdivision is located, and the section, township and range.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Location of property lines, existing easements, buildings, watercourses, elevations, permits and other essential features.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The names of all subdivisions immediately adjacent.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The location of any existing sewers and water mains, or any underground or overhead utilities, culverts and drains on the property to be subdivided.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Location, names and present widths of existing and proposed streets, highways, alleys, parks and other open public spaces and similar facts regarding property immediately adjacent.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The width and location of any street or other public ways or places shown upon the official map or the master plan, within the area to be subdivided, and the width and locations of all streets or other public ways proposed by the developer.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Date of field survey, north point and graphic scale.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Legal description and plan of proposed layout made and certified by a Florida-licensed land surveyor.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
The proposed lot lines with approximate dimensions and in the case of odd or irregularly shaped lots, suggested location of building setback lines.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Where the tentative plat submitted covers only a part of the subdivider's entire holding, a master tentative plat of the prospective future street system of the unsubdivided part will be required, and the street system of the unsubmitted part will be considered in the light of adjustments and connection with the street system of the plat submitted.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
A plat application signed by the owner and notarized on the form prescribed by the plat division of the appropriate authority.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
The numbering of all lots, blocks and the lettering of all tracts shall be shown on the tentative plat. All lots or tracts shall be numbered or lettered progressively. All blocks shall be progressively numbered except that blocks in numbered additions bearing the same name shall be numbered consecutively throughout the several additions.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
A location map at the scale of one (1) inch equals three hundred (300) feet showing existing and proposed rights-of-way.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The following information shall be submitted in addition to the tentative plat if requested by the plat division of the appropriate authority.
<section prefix = "a">
The names of owners of record of immediately adjacent property.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Any changes in the use, height, area and density districts or other regulations under Chapter 33, Zoning, applicable to the area to be subdivided, and any boundaries of such districts, affecting the tracts; all parcels of land proposed to be dedicated to public use and the conditions of such dedications.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Typical cross-section of the proposed grading and roadways or sidewalks and topographic conditions.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Location of closest available subdivision or public water supply system.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Location of closest available subdivision or public sewage disposal system.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Provisions for collecting and discharging surface drainage.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Preliminary designs of any bridges or culverts which may be required.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
A boundary survey.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
If required by these regulations or if proposed by the subdivider, the proposed location of any type of sidewalks, street lighting standards and species of street trees, the location of curbs, gutters, water mains, sanitary sewers and storm drains and the sizes and types thereof, the character, width and depth of pavement and sub-base, and the location of manholes and basins and underground conduits.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
The boundaries of proposed permanent utility easements over or under private property. Such easements shall provide satisfactory access to an existing public highway or other public open space shown upon the layout. Permanent drainage easements shall also be shown.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
All dimensions affecting public rights-of-way and proposed dedication of the public rights-of-way shall be established by a registered surveyor and shown on the grading and drainage plan accompanying approved and valid tentative plats when said plan is submitted for approval, with the same degree of accuracy as, and identical to, the corresponding dimensions shown on the final plat.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
A copy of owners' deed or a current opinion of title from any attorney authorized to practice law in the State.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Filing copies of tentative plat and plat application. The subdivider shall file such copies as may be required of the tentative plat with the plat division of the appropriate authority, together with the plat application. All tentative plats filed shall be reviewed for approval weekly, or at the regular meeting of the plat division, and the tentative plats should be filed at least ten (10) days in advance of the meeting at which approval is sought.
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
Checking and investigating. The subdivider shall pay such fees as may be prescribed by ordinance for checking the tentative plat and investigating such matters concerning it as may be required by law and this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
Approval of tentative plat. On plats that lie within the unincorporated areas of the County, copies of the tentative plat shall be distributed by the Department of Public Works to the Department of Planning and Zoning and the Department of Florida Health and to such other departments as may be necessary. Tentative approval shall confer upon the subdivider the right for a nine months period from the date of approval that the terms and conditions under which the tentative approval was granted will not be changed if the final plat is in accordance with the tentative approval.
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
Appeal of the County's plat division decision. Decisions of the County's plat division may be appealed within 14 (fourteen) days to the Executive Council of the Developmental Impact Committee as defined in Section 33-303.1(B) of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida; and appeals of the Executive Council's decision shall be by application for variance from Chapter 28 (Section 28-19) or, if applicable, by appeal of administrative decision pursuant to Section 33-314(C)(1) Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. The fourteen-day appeal period provided herein shall commence on the day after notification that the plat division has taken action on the particular matter, such notification to be given by the division through the posting of a short, concise statement of the action taken on a conspicuous bulletin board that may be seen by the public at reasonable times and hours in the office of the Public Works Department. Where the fourteenth day falls on a weekend or legal holiday the appeal period shall be deemed to extend through the next business day.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 77-6, § 1, 2-1-77; Ord. No. 78-12, § 2, 3-21-78; Ord. No. 82-71, § 3, 7-20-82; Ord. No. 89-10, § 8, 2-21-89; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 18, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 99-123, § 2, 9-21-99; Ord. No. 99-147, § 1, 10-19-99; Ord. No. 02-259, § 1, 12-3-02)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 28-8. Same—Final plat</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Conformity to tentative plat. The final plat shall have incorporated all changes or modifications as required to make the tentative plat conform to the requirements of this chapter. Otherwise it shall conform to the tentative plat, and it may constitute only that portion of the approved tentative plat which the subdivider proposed to record and develop at the time, provided that such portion conforms with all requirements of this chapter and meets with the approval of the various departments concerned.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Preparation. The final plat shall be prepared by a land surveyor registered in the state. The final plat shall be clearly and legibly drawn, to a sheet size of thirty (30) inches by thirty-six (36) inches and to a scale of sufficient size to be legible, with letters and numbers to be no smaller than one-eighth (1/8) of an inch in height. The final plat, insofar as preparation is concerned, shall comply with all applicable regulations and State laws dealing with the preparation of plats.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Contents.
<section prefix = "1">
Name of the subdivision. The plat shall have a title or name. If the plat be a town, city or village, the full name of such town, city or village must appear as the title or name of the plat subdivision. If the land platted be an addition to or a subdivision of a town, city or village already platted, then the title of the plat shall include, with the name of such addition or subdivision, the name of the town, city or village, as the case may be, and section, township and range of which such platted land is a subdivision, or to which it is an addition. The terms "Town," "City," "Village" or any other term suggesting a municipal corporation, shall not appear in the title or name of any plat which includes any property in the unincorporated area. The plat division of the appropriate authority shall disapprove any name or title which he may find to be sufficiently similar to the name of any existing town, city, village or municipal corporation, or the name similar to any previously approved plat in the incorporated or unincorporated areas of the County which may cause confusion as to the status or the location of any platted property.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Deed description. Description written on map or plat. There shall be written or printed upon the plat a full and detailed description of the land embraced in the map or plat showing the township and range in which such lands are situated and the section and part of sections platted and a location sketch showing the plat's location in reference to the closest centers of each section embraced within the plat. The description must be so complete that from it, without reference to the plat, the starting point can be determined and the outlines run. If a subdivision of a part of a previously recorded plat is made, the previous lots and blocks to be resubdivided shall be given. If the plat be a resubdivision of the whole of a previously recorded plat, the fact shall be so stated. Vacation of previously platted lands must be accomplished in the manner provided by law.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Names of adjacent subdivisions.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Names or numbers and width of streets immediately adjoining plat.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
All plat boundaries.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Bearings and distances to the nearest established street lines, section corners or other recognized permanent monuments which shall be accurately described on the plat.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Municipal, township, County or section lines accurately tied to the lines of the subdivision by distance and bearing.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Accurate location of all monuments.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Length of all arcs, radii, internal angles, points of curvature and tangent bearings.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Where lots are located on a curve or when side lot lines are at angles less than eighty-seven (87) degrees or more than ninety-three (93) degrees, the width of the lot at the front building setback line shall be shown.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
The name or numbering and right-of-way width of each street or other right-of-way shown on plat.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
The numbering of all lots and blocks shown on the plat. All lots shall be numbered either by progressive numbers, or in blocks progressively numbered, except that blocks in numbered additions bearing the same name shall be numbered consecutively throughout the several additions. Excepted parcels must be marked "not part of this plat."
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Plat restrictions to restrict type and use of water supply; type and use of sanitary facilities; use and benefits of water areas and other open spaces and odd-shaped and substandard parcels; resubdivision of parcels as "platted," and restrictions of similar nature.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
All areas reserved or dedicated for public purposes. No strip or parcel of land shall be reserved by the owner, unless the same is sufficient in size and area to be of some practical use or service.
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
The dimensions of all lots and angles or bearings.
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
Minimum building setback lines where required by ordinance.
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
Location, dimension and purpose of any easements.
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
Certification by a registered surveyor to the effect that the plat represents a survey made by him, and that all monuments shown thereon actually exist, and that their location is correctly shown.
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
An acknowledgment by the owner of his adoption of the plat, and of the dedication of streets and other public areas and the consent of any mortgage holders to such adoption and dedication. If existing right-of-way is to be closed, purpose of closing must be stated on the plat.
</section>
<section prefix = "20">
The signature and seal of the governing body. On plats within the unincorporated areas of the County, the signature of the Director of Public Works, the Director of the Department of Planning and Zoning and the Clerk and Mayor and, in his absence, the Chairman of the County Commission. Provided, however, that where property is being replatted the signatures of the governing body shall be affixed or denied pursuant to the procedures established in Section 177.101, Florida Statutes (1971), unless the vacation of prior plats has previously been validly accomplished.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Other data required with plat.
<section prefix = "1">
Restrictive covenants desired by the developer so long as they do not violate existing ordinances. Restrictive covenants shall be required covering the same restrictions included in subsection (c)(13) of this section; restrictions controlling building lines, establishment and maintenance of buffer strips and walls, and restrictions of similar nature.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The surveyor shall show on the face of the plat (or shall certify on a separate sheet, not to be recorded in the public records) the Florida State Plane Coordinates (current readjustment) of at least two (2) of the permanent reference monuments shown on the plat. This requirement may be waived by the plat division of the appropriate authority if (A) any portion of the land encompassed by the plat is more than one (1) mile from the nearest station shown on the list on file in the Miami-Dade County Public Works Department's Survey Office, as updated; or (B) all stations within one (1) mile of the plat have been lost. A copy of the certified corner record (as defined in Section 177.503 Florida Statutes (1993)), for the corners used shall be provided with the final plat.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Current opinion of title from any attorney authorized to practice law in this State.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Certification from the city and County that all taxes and assessments have been paid on the land within the proposed subdivision or receipted tax bills.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
If a zoning change is involved, certification from the appropriate agency shall be furnished indicating that the change requested has been approved and is in effect, and that the size of lots and other features shown on the plat conform to all zoning requirements. Signing of the final plat by the director of that agency shall constitute such certification.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Clerk's fees for recording the plat.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
On plats within municipalities certification from the appropriate agency shall be submitted to the County's plat division certifying that all required improvements within the public right-of-way have been completed or that the municipality is holding sufficient bond for the completion of the improvements. The certification shall also state that the plat appears to conform to all of the requirements of this chapter. The County's plat division shall review certification from the appropriate agency within forty-five (45) days of the acknowledged receipt of the plats. Failure of the County to act on said plats within forty-five (45) days of the acknowledged receipt of the plat shall be deemed an approval of the plat.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
No plat shall be entitled for recording in the Clerk's office until the plat is signed by the Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Public Works, certifying that the plat appears to conform to all of the requirements of this chapter. A certification of the Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Public Works need not appear if the plat division of the appropriate authority submits an affidavit to the Clerk stating that the County has not acted on said plat within forty-five (45) days of the acknowledged receipt of the subject plat.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 77-6, § 1, 2-1-77; Ord. No. 94-51, § 1, 3-17-94; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 18, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 99-123, § 2, 9-21-99)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 28-9. Same—Final approval; rejection, for plats within the unincorporated areas of the County</catch_line>
<text>
Approval of plats by the Director of the Department of Public Works shall be final, insofar as that Department is concerned. Approvals shall not be denied if the plat complies with this chapter.
After approval has been given as provided in this chapter, the Director of the Department of Public Works shall inform the subdivider, or his surveyor, as the case may be, that the plat has been given final approval and is ready for recording. In the event the plat has been rejected, the Director of the Department of Public Works will so notify the subdivider or his surveyor in writing with all reasons for such rejection.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 28-9.1. Same—Fees for plats within the unincorporated areas of the County</catch_line>
<text>
The Miami-Dade County Department of Public Works shall charge and collect fees for subdivision platting at the rates established by administrative order, which shall not become effective until approved by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners.
</text>
The Miami-Dade County Department of Public Works shall charge and collect fees for subdivision platting at the rates established by administrative order, which shall not become effective until approved by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners.
Annotation—AO 4-47
<catch_line>Sec. 28-10. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 94-51, § 2, adopted March 17, 1994, repealed former § 28-10, relative to bonds, which derived from Ord. No. 77-6, § 1, adopted Feb. 1, 1977.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 28-11. Building permits, issuance</catch_line>
<text>
No building permit shall be issued for construction of any improvements on a parcel that was not legally created in compliance with these regulations except permits for a construction trailer or sale office trailer, permanent buildings to be used as single family home and townhouse models, entrance features, perimeter walls, lift stations and multi-family residential, commercial and industrial buildings, may be issued if the developer complies with the following requirements.
<section prefix = "a">
For construction trailer or trailer used as sales office: No permits will be approved until at least a tentative plat has been approved and the Public Works Department has reviewed and permitted paving and drainage plans. In addition, no permit shall be issued unless the trailer complies with the Department of Environmental Resources Management's requirements for providing potable water and sanitary facilities.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
For permanent buildings to be used as single family or townhouse models:
Permits for models not to exceed 25 percent of the total number of lots will be approved when:
<section prefix = "1">
The tentative plat has been approved by the Plat Committee and is current.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Paving and drainage plans have been approved.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
All the Department of Environmental Resources Management's requirements, including the approval of Water and Sewer extension plans are complied with.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
A letter signed by the property owner has been submitted to the Supervisor, Platting Section, requesting the construction of models prior to final plat recording. The letter shall include the number of models being requested (only one (1) of each single family model will be allowed, or only one (1) of each model townhouse building) together with the lot and block numbers for each such model. The letter shall state that the owner understands and agrees that the model home, or homes, shall not be occupied until the plat is recorded in the public records and that the penalty for violation of this occupancy prohibition shall be the demolition of the model. The letter shall also state that the owner agrees and shall release and hold Miami-Dade County, its employees and agents, harmless from any and all liability and causes of action of whatsoever nature and kind for and as a result of the issuance of building permits and any construction prior to final plat approval and recordation. The Supervisor, should he/she approve the models, will send a copy of the owner's letter to the Zoning Processing Section to be placed in the plat file.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
No certificate of completion shall be issued for any model until after the final plat is recorded except that a Temporary Certificate of Completion may be issued by the Planning and Zoning Department.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Entrance features, perimeter wall and lift station permits may be issued after tentative plat approval by the Plat Committee and receipt of a letter to the Supervisor, Platting Section, signed by the property owner requesting the permit prior to final plat recording and releasing and holding Miami-Dade County, its employees and agents, harmless from any and all liability and causes of action of whatsoever nature or kind for and as a result of the issuance of building permits and any construction prior to final plat approval and recordation. The Supervisor should he/she approve the request, will send a copy of the owner's letter to the Zoning Processing Section to be placed in the plat file.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
For multi-family residential, commercial, and industrial buildings; tentative plat.
<section prefix = "1">
The tentative plat has been approved by the Plat Committee and is current.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Building permits may be issued, on only one site, lot or tract, until the proposed final plat for the subdivision in which the structure, or structures, is to be located has been listed on an agenda for approval by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Paving and drainage plans (if required) shall have been approved by the Public Works Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
A letter, signed by the property owner, has been submitted to the Supervisor, Platting Section, requesting the permit prior to final plat recording. The letter shall state the proposed lot and block or tract for such permit, and the owner's acknowledgment and agreement that no certificate of occupancy or use will be sought or issued for the structure, or structures, until after the final plat is recorded. The letter shall also state that the owner agrees and shall release and hold Miami-Dade County, its employees and agents, harmless from any and all liability and causes of action of whatsoever nature or kind for and as a result of the issuance of building permits and any construction prior to final plat approval and recordation. The Supervisor, should he/she approve the request, will send a copy of the owner's letter to the Zoning Processing Section to be placed in the plat file.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
No certificate of occupancy or use for the subject structure, or structures, will be issued until the plat is recorded.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
The issuance of the building permit shall not modify or affect the concurrency capacity of the underlying tentative plat in any way.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
For multi-family residential commercial, and industrial buildings; waiver of plat.
<section prefix = "1">
The waiver of plat has been recommended for approval by the Plat Committee.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Building permits may be issued, on only one parcel, until the proposed waiver of plat for the subdivision in which the structure, or structures, is to be located has been listed on an agenda for approval by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Paving and drainage plans and a bond in lieu of the immediate construction of any improvements (if required) shall have been approved by the Public Works and Waste Management Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
A letter, signed by the property owner, has been submitted to the Supervisor, Platting Section, requesting the permit, or permits, prior to the waiver of plat approval by the Board of County Commissioners. The letter shall state the proposed parcel for such permit, or permits, and the owner's acknowledgment and agreement that no certificate of occupancy or use will be sought or issued until after the waiver of plat is approved by the Board of County Commissioners and the resolution is recorded in the public records. The letter shall also state that the owner agrees and shall release and hold Miami-Dade County, its employees and agents, harmless from any and all liability and causes of action of whatsoever nature or kind for and as a result of the issuance of building permits and any construction prior to waiver of plat approval. Should the Supervisor approve the request, a copy of the owner's letter to the Zoning Processing Section shall be placed in the plat file.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
No certificate of occupancy or use for the subject structure, or structures, will be issued until the waiver of plat is approved by the Board of County Commissioners and the resolution is recorded in the public records.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
The issuance of the building permit, or permits, shall not modify or affect the concurrency capacity of the waiver of plat in any way.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
For Permanent Buildings to be used as Single Family or Townhouse Production Homes:
Permits for single family or townhouse production homes will be approved when:
<section prefix = "1">
The tentative plat has been approved or the waiver of plat has been recommended for approval by the Plat Committee and is current.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Paving and Drainage plans have been approved. A bond in lieu of the immediate construction of any improvements (if required) shall have been approved by the Public Works and Waste Management Department for any waiver of plat.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
All DERM requirements, including the approval of Water and Sewer Extension plans are complied with.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The proposed final or waiver of plat for the subdivision in which the production homes are to be located has been listed on an agenda for approval by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
A letter, signed by the property owner, has been submitted to the supervisor, Platting Section, requesting approval of production homes prior to final plat recording, or waiver of plat approval by the Board of County Commissioners. The letter shall state that the owner understands and agrees that the production home shall not be occupied until the plat is recorded in the public records, or the waiver of plat has been approved by the Board of County Commissioners and the resolution is recorded in the public records, and that the penalty for violation of this occupancy prohibition shall be the demolition of the production home. The letter shall also state that the owner agrees and shall hold Miami-Dade County, its employees and agents, harmless from any and all liability and causes of action of whatsoever nature and kind for and as a result of the issuance of building permits and any construction prior to final plat approval and recordation. or the waiver of plat has been approved by the Board of County Commissioners and the resolution is recorded in the public records. The Supervisor, should he/she approve the models, will send a copy of the owner's letter to the Zoning Processing Section to be placed in the plat file.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
No certificate of completion shall be issued for any production home until after the final plat is recorded except that a Temporary of Certificate of Completion may be issued by the Planning and Zoning Department.

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 28-12. Public improvements and maintenance, withholding from subdivisions not approved or accepted</catch_line>
<text>
All cities and the County shall withhold all public improvement of whatsoever nature, including the maintenance of streets and the furnishing of sewage facilities and water service from all subdivisions which have not been approved, and from all areas dedicated to the public which have not been accepted, in the manner prescribed herein.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 28-13. Drainage</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Master plan and manual of public works construction. The developer shall plan all drainage for his subdivision in accordance with the master plan entitled, "County Water-Control Plan," recorded in Plat Book 64, page 114 and in accordance with the flood criteria map, recorded in Plat Book 53, pages 68, 69, and 70, or as such plan and map may be changed or modified. The drainage plans shall be subject to approval of the Public Works Department for compliance with such plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Permit to construct or alter drainage ways. No individual, partnership, or corporation shall construct, deepen, widen, fill, reroute, or alter any existing drainage way, ditch, drain, or canal without first obtaining a written permit from the County's Department of Public Works and/or the County's Department of Environmental Resources Management. Plans for all such work shall comply with the manual of public works construction of the County's Public Works Department, and all such work shall be done under the supervision and subject to the approval of the County's Department of Public Works and/or the County's Department of Environmental Resources Management. Rights-of-way for all such drainage works and maintenance thereof as prescribed by the manual of public works and construction and the County water control plan, must be dedicated to the use of the public, such dedication to be made prior to any such construction or alteration if so required by the County's Public Works Department and/or the County's Department of Environmental Resources Management.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Rights-of-way and easements. Whenever any drainage way, stream, or surface drainage course is located or planned in any area that is being subdivided, the subdivider shall dedicate such stream or drainage course and an adequate right-of-way necessary for maintenance, future expansion and other purposes along each side of such stream or drainage course as is determined by uniform standards prescribed by the manual of public works construction.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Storm water. Adequate provision shall be made for the disposal of storm water subject to standards prescribed in the manual of public works construction.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Contour map and drainage of adjacent areas. A contour map shall be prepared for the area comprising the subdivision and such additional areas as may be required by the County's Department of Public Works and/or the County's Department of Environmental Resources Management, necessary to include all watersheds which drain into or through the property to be developed, provided that this map of the adjacent areas may be prepared from existing maps or other data available to and acceptable by the County's Department of Public Works and/or the County's Department of Environmental Resources Management. The design for drainage of the subdivision must be adequate to provide for drainage of adjacent water shed areas, and design of drainage structures must provide for drainage of adjacent water sheds after complete development of the total area. Where ditches and canals are required, rights-of-way shall be provided for future needs in accordance with uniform standards proscribed in the County's manual of public works construction. Provided, however, that the developers may be permitted by the County's Department of Public Works and/or the County's Department of Environmental Resources Management to excavate or open, or construct necessary drainage ways and structures only of sufficient capacity to provide for existing drainage needs whenever the developed or undeveloped status of adjacent water sheds may so warrant as determined by the County's Department of Public Works, and/or the County's Department of Environmental Resources Management.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Off-site drainage. Off-site drainage shall be mutually coordinated by and between the subdivider, and the plat division of the appropriate authority.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 77-6, § 1, 2-1-77)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 28-14. Design standards</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Conformity with master plan. If a master plan has been adopted for such area, the proposed subdivision shall conform in principle with such master plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Streets.
<section prefix = "1">
Conformance. The arrangement, extent, width, grade and location of all streets shall conform to the master plan, if one (1) has been adopted for the area, and shall be considered in their relation to existing and planned streets, topographical conditions, to public conveniences, safety, and in their appropriate relation to the proposed uses of the land to be served by such streets. Where not shown on the master plan, the arrangement and the other design standards of streets shall conform to the provisions found herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Relation to adjoining street system. The arrangement of streets in new subdivisions shall make provisions for the continuation of existing streets in adjoining areas.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Projection of street. Where adjoining areas are not subdivided, the arrangement of streets in new subdivisions shall make provisions for the proper projection of streets.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Streets to be carried to property lines. When a new subdivision adjoins unsubdivided land then the new streets shall be carried to the boundaries of the tract proposed to be subdivided where required to promote reasonable development of the adjacent lands or provide continuity of road systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Street jogs prohibited. Street jobs with center line offsets of less than one hundred twenty-five (125) feet shall be prohibited unless because of unusual conditions the plat division determines that a lesser center line offset is justified.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Dead-end streets or cul-de-sacs. Dead-end streets or cul-de-sacs designated to be so permanently, shall not be longer than six hundred (600) feet, and at the closed end, a turnaround having an outside roadway diameter of at least eighty-four (84) feet, and a street property line diameter of at least one hundred (100) feet, may be required. If a dead-end street is of a temporary nature a similar turnaround may be required, and provision made for future extension of street into adjoining property, as may be required by the plat division.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Marginal access streets. Where a subdivision butts on or contains an existing limited access highway, freeway, parkway or arterial street, marginal access streets or other such treatment as may be necessary for adequate protection of residential property and to afford separation of through and local traffic may be required.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Minor streets. Minor streets shall be so laid out that their use by through traffic shall be discouraged.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Railroad on or abutting subdivision. Where a subdivision borders on or contains a railroad right-of-way or limited access highway right-of-way, a street approximately parallel to and on each side of such right-of-way may be required, at a distance suitable for the appropriate use of the intervening land for park purposes in residential districts or for commercial or for industrial purposes in appropriate districts. Such distances shall be determined with due regard for the requirements of approach grade and future grade separation in accordance with uniform standards prescribed by the manual of public works construction.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
A tangent of at least one hundred (100) feet long shall be introduced between reversed curves on arterial and collector streets.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
When connecting street lines deflect from each other at any one (1) point by more than ten (10) degrees, they shall be connected by a curve with a radius adequate to insure a sight distance and safe turning movement in accordance with uniform standards prescribed by the County's manual of public works construction.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Streets shall be laid out so as to intersect as nearly as possible at right angles.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Property lines at street intersections shall be rounded with a radius of twenty-five (25) feet. A greater radius may be prescribed by the plat division in special cases in accordance with uniform standards prescribed by the County's manual of public works construction. The plat division may permit comparable cutoffs or chords in place of rounded corners.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
Street right-of-way widths shall be as shown on the master plan or in Chapter 33 of this Code and where not so shown shall be not less than as follows:
<section prefix = "a">
Arterial—One hundred (100) feet right-of-way;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Collector—Seventy (70) feet right-of-way;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Minor, for apartments and residences—Fifty (50) to sixty (60) feet right-of-way as may be determined in uniform standards prescribed by the County's manual of public works construction;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Marginal access—Forty-five (45) feet where required in residential areas—Fifty (50) feet where access is limited, by a limited access highway, a railroad or canal—Seventy (70) feet in industrial subdivision;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Minor for industrial areas—Seventy (70) feet right-of-way;
unless because of unusual conditions the plat division determines that a lesser right-of-way width is justified.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
Half streets shall be prohibited, except where essential to the reasonable development of the subdivision in conformity with other requirements of these regulations, and where the plat division of the appropriate authority finds it will be practical to require the dedication of the other half when adjoining property is subdivided. Whenever a half street is adjacent to a tract to be subdivided, the other half of the street shall be platted within such tracts.
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
No street names or numbers shall be used which will be confused with or duplicate the names of existing streets. Street names shall be subject to the approval of the plat division of the appropriate authority.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Alleys.
<section prefix = "1">
Alleys may be dedicated in commercial and industrial districts, except that the plat division of the appropriate authority may waive this requirement where other definite and assured provision is made for service access, such as off-street loading, unloading, and parking consistent and adequate for the uses proposed.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The width of any alley shall not be less than twenty (20) feet.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
Easements.
<section prefix = "1">
Easements across lots (not including drainage) and, where possible, centered on rear or side lot lines shall be provided for utilities where necessary.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Where a subdivision is traversed by a watercourse, drainageway, or canal, there shall be provided a storm water easement or drainage right-of-way conforming substantially with the lines of such watercourse, and such further width or construction, or both, as will be adequate for the purpose. Parallel streets or parkways may be required in connection therewith in accordance with uniform standards prescribed by the manual of public works construction.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "E">
Blocks.
<section prefix = "1">
The length, width and shape of blocks shall be determined with due regard to:
<section prefix = "a">
Provision of adequate building sites suitable to the special need of the type of use contemplated.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Zoning requirements as to lot size and dimensions.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Need for convenient access, circulation, control and safety of street traffic.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Limitations and opportunities of topography.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Block length shall not exceed one thousand five hundred (1,500) feet, or be less than four hundred (400) feet, unless a lesser or greater length is requested by the subdivider and is deemed advisable because of unusual conditions by the plat division of the appropriate authority.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
In blocks nine hundred (900) feet in length or over, pedestrian crosswalks not less than ten (10) feet wide may be required to provide circulation or access to school, playground, shopping center, transportation, and other community facilities.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "F">
Lots.
<section prefix = "1">
The lot depth, shape and orientation, and the minimum building setback lines shall be appropriate for the location of the subdivision and on the type of development and use contemplated.
<section prefix = "a">
Lot dimensions shall conform to the requirements of the appropriate authority.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Each lot shall be provided, by means of a public street, with satisfactory access to an existing public street or in the case of units within a townhouse site, or cluster development, each lot shall be provided perpetual right of access by private street or roadway to an existing public street in accordance with the provisions of Section 33-202.3, Metropolitan Code, or where applicable, municipal townhouse or cluster regulations.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Double frontage or through lots shall be avoided except where essential to provide separation of residential development from traffic arteries or to overcome specific disadvantages of topography or orientation. A decorative masonry wall, or in the sole discretion of the plat division of the appropriate authority a combination of fence and landscaping that provides a satisfactory buffer may be required along the rear property line, across which there shall be no right of vehicular access. This portion of the block line shall be shown as a limited access line on the final plat.
Visual screening for decorative walls. In an effort to prevent graffiti vandalism, the following options shall be utilized for walls abutting zoned or dedicated rights-of-way:
<section prefix = "a">
Wall with landscaping. The wall shall be setback two and one-half (2½) feet from the right-of-way line and the resulting setback area shall contain a continuous extensively landscaped buffer which must be maintained in a good healthy condition by the property owner, or where applicable, by the condominium, homeowners or similar association. The landscape buffer shall contain one or more of the following planting materials:
<section prefix = "1">
Shrubs. Shrubs shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Hedges. Hedges shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Vines. Climbing vines shall be a minimum of thirty-six (36) inches in height immediately after planting.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Metal picket fence. Where a metal picket fence abutting a zoned or dedicated right-of-way is constructed in lieu of a decorative wall, landscaping shall not be required.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Side lot lines shall, where possible, be substantially at right angles or radial to street lines.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "G">
Acceptance of dedication. The dedication of public spaces shall not constitute an acceptance of the dedication by the County. The acceptance of the dedication shall be indicated by a resolution of the governing body and by an indication on the plat.
</section>
<section prefix = "H">
Waiver of standards. Those design standards enumerated within (B) "Streets", (C) "Alleys," and (F) "Lots" above may be waived by the plat division of the appropriate authority, except that the plat division of the appropriate authority may not waive (F)(1)(a) "Lot dimensions."
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 77-6, § 1, 2-1-77; Ord. No. 78-14, § 1, 3-21-78; Ord. No. 95-19, § 22, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 99-38, § 1, 4-27-99)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 28-15. Required improvements</catch_line>
<text>
Prior to the granting of the final approval, the subdivider shall have installed or shall have furnished adequate bond of one hundred ten (110) percent of the cost of improvements for the ultimate installation of the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Permanent reference monuments. Monuments shall be constructed and placed in accordance with Chapter 177 of Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Streets.
<section prefix = "1">
Construction; inspection; approval. All streets shall be constructed and surfaced in accordance with applicable standards specifications of the County entitled "Specifications for Second Road Construction and Residential Streets," or in accordance with requirements indicated in the County's manual of public works construction of the Department of Public Works. Such construction shall be subject to the inspection by the governing body or their designated representatives, and subjected to issuance of permits. Where street construction complies in specifications such installation shall be approved. No other permits of any kind for construction of streets shall be required.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Curbs, gutters and drainage. Curbs, gutters, drainage and drainage structures which are required by ordinance shall be provided in accordance with standard specifications or in accordance with the manual of public works construction of the Department of Public Works. Such construction shall be subject to the inspection of the governing body or their designated representatives, and subjected to issuance of permits therefor.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Sidewalks. Sidewalks shall be required in all residential, multiple-family and business areas and along all arterial highways, except, that in areas zoned in the agricultural zone classification, or other zone classifications requiring lots of similar frontage and area, no sidewalks shall be required; and except in those areas zoned in the EU-1, EU-M or EU-S classifications or other zone classification requiring lots of similar frontage and areas, sidewalks shall be required only along section and quarter section lines or roads that may be substituted therefor. On plats within municipalities, sidewalk requirements may be waived by the municipalities, on roads that are not County maintained.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Street signs. Street name signs shall be placed at all street intersections within or abutting the subdivision. Such signs shall be of a type approved by the County and shall be placed in accordance with the standards of the County and the manual of public works construction. The type of street signs and their locations shall meet with the approval and inspection of the County's Director of Traffic and Transportation.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Waiver of improvements. Those required street improvements enumerated within (1) "Construction; inspection; approval" through (4) "Street signs" above may be waived by the County's Plat Division.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Guardrails. On any street adjacent to or abutting a canal, a lake or other body of water a guardrail or other form of traffic barrier must be installed to protect any vehicle from entering the canal, lake or other body of water.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Water supply system.
<section prefix = "1">
Water supply system. Where a water supply system is required by the Public Health Director, each lot within the subdivision area shall be provided with a connection thereto. All systems and extensions shall be subject to the approval of the Directors of the Department of Public Health and the Public Works Department and the Department of Environmental Resources Management and shall be in accordance with all State and County regulations and standards governing their installation.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Individual wells. Where a water supply system is not required, individual wells may be permitted by the Public Health Director and/or the Director of Environmental Resources Management if all County and State regulations and standards governing their installations and uses are adequately met.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Fire hydrants. Where required by the Fire Department Chief, fire hydrants or fire wells shall be installed in all subdivisions in accordance with the uniform standards established by the public works manual.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Sewage disposal system.
<section prefix = "1">
Sewer systems. Where a sewer system is required by the Director of Environmental Resources, each lot in the subdivision shall be provided with a connection thereto. All systems, extensions, and connections shall be subject to the approval of the Director of Environmental Resources Management and shall be in accordance with all County and State regulations and standards governing their installation.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Septic tanks. Septic tanks may be permitted upon approval by the Director of Environmental Resources Management in accordance with the provisions of Chapter 24 of the Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Code. Septic tanks shall be installed in compliance with all of the requirements, specifications and standards of the County and State governing their use.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Underground electric and communication lines. Except as expressly provided hereinafter, all utility lines including but not limited to those required for electrical power distribution, telephone and telegraph communication, street lighting and television signal service shall be installed underground. This section shall apply to all cables, conduits or wires forming part of an electrical distribution system including service lines to individual properties and main distribution feeder electric lines delivering power to local distribution systems; provided that it shall not apply to wires, conductors or associated apparatus and supporting structures whose exclusive function is in transmission of electrical energy between generating stations, substations and transmission lines of other utility systems. Appurtenances such as transformer boxes, pedestal-mounted terminal boxes, and meter cabinets may be placed aboveground but shall be located in conformance with the requirements of the manual of public works construction. In areas zoned for industrial use, all electrical and communication distribution systems may be installed overhead, but the service conductors from the utility pole to the building (structure) shall be an underground service lateral.
Easements shall be provided for the installation of utilities or relocating existing facilities in conformance with the respective utility company's rules and regulations. In subdivisions of less than twenty-one (21) lots, the plat division of the appropriate authority may waive the requirements for underground installations if the service to the adjacent area is overhead and it does not appear that further development will occur.
Any new service which is allowed by the provisions herein to be supplied by overhead utilities shall be connected to a service panel that is convertible for underground utility service at a future date.
The subdivider or developer shall make the necessary costs and other arrangements for such underground installation with each of the persons, firms or corporations furnishing utility services involved.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Decorative masonry walls. Decorative masonry walls, not to exceed seven (7) feet in height, or an acceptable combination of fence and landscaping shall be installed adjacent to the rear lot line of double frontage lots as required by the plat division of the appropriate authority. For purposes of this section only, an "acceptable combination of fence and landscaping" shall be based upon the following factors:
<section prefix = "1">
Conformity with existing architecture and landscaping of the subdivision; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Conformity with the objectives of maintaining privacy for the residents of the subdivision.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Street and alley lighting. On plats within the unincorporated areas of the County street and alley lighting will be provided for through the establishment of a special taxing district. In subdivisions of less than twenty-one (21) lots, the Directors of the Public Works, and the Planning and Zoning Departments may waive the requirements for street lights if the benefits derived are not consistent with the costs thereof.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 28-16. Construction plan</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Preparation. The subdivider, or his engineer, shall confer with the appropriate agencies to determine the standards and specifications which will govern the proposed improvements. The subdivider shall submit complete construction plans prepared by an engineer and/or surveyor, as the case may be, registered in the State of Florida for the entire development of the area for which application to plat has been submitted, together with the complete and accurate contour map using U.S.C. and G.S. datum, to the appropriate agencies for their review and approval. The construction plans shall include the complete design of required sanitary sewer system, water supply system, storm drainage system and the street system for the entire area to be subdivided. Due consideration shall be given to the problems that may be created by the subdivision of adjacent lands, especially as pertains to drainage in order that conformance with the overall drainage plan will be obtained. The subdivider shall do no construction work until his completed construction plans have been approved by the appropriate agencies. Reasonable time must be allotted for the proper study of the plans submitted.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Reserved.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Construction of improvements; employing engineer. After approved construction plans have been filed and approved, the subdivider may construct the required improvements, subject to obtaining the required permits from the appropriate agencies.
On plats within the unincorporated areas of the County the Director of the Department of Public Works, and if sewerage and water systems are involved, the Director of the Department of Public Health shall be notified in advance of the date that such construction shall be commenced. Construction shall be performed under the supervision of the appropriate agencies and shall at all times be subject to inspection by these agencies. However, this in no way shall relieve the subdivider and his engineer of close field supervision and final compliance with the approved plans and specifications.
Where deemed necessary, in accordance with the County's manual of public works construction, the appropriate agencies may require the subdivider to employ a registered engineer for complete supervision of the construction or installation of the improvements involved, and may require progress reports and final certificate of the construction or installation from such engineer. The appropriate agencies shall establish detailed regulations governing the inspections to be furnished by the developer or his engineer and may refuse to accept work which has been done without proper inspection. No construction work shall be undertaken prior to obtaining the required permits.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Acceptance of improvements. When construction is complete in accordance with the approved plan and specifications and complies with the provisions of these regulations, the subdivider shall obtain written final approval and acceptance from the appropriate agencies.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Bond in lieu of immediate construction. In lieu of immediate construction of improvements, the subdivider may file with the governing body a cash bond or letter of credit in an amount approved by the plat division and a company approved by the governing body or the department authorized by them, to insure the County the actual satisfactory completion of construction of proposed improvements within a period of not more than one (1) year from the date of such bond. The bond for the installation of sidewalks may be a separate bond. Provisions shall be made for extension of all such bonds, such extension to be commensurate with the progress of the development. Provisions shall also be made for reduction of such bonds, such reduction to be commensurate with the percentage of improvements constructed in the subdivision concerned. This bond shall also include a maintenance provision for two (2) years covering drainage and for one (1) year covering all other improvements by the subdivider. The amount to be included for maintenance shall be outlined in the manual of public works construction. Bonds shall be subject to cancellation, reduction or renewal only by the governing body upon written certification of the plat division of the appropriate agency.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 77-6, § 1, 2-1-77; Ord. No. 94-51, § 3, 3-17-94)</history>
Annotation—CAO 77-31.
<catch_line>Sec. 28-17. Subdivision of portion of tract</catch_line>
<text>
The owner or developer of a tract may prepare a master plan for that entire tract and then may submit a tentative and final plat for only a portion of the tract. No construction of subdivision improvements shall be started until construction plans for the entire area covered by the final plat have been approved. Except as provided in Section 28-16(c), improvements must be installed for all of that area for which a final plat is submitted before building permits will be issued. In such cases of partial subdivision of a tract, the street system, drainage systems, trunk sewers and sewage treatment plants and water plants shall be designed and built to serve the entire area, or designed and built in such a manner as to be easily expanded or extended to service the entire area.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 28-18. Encroachment on or in streets</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
No building or any other type of structure shall be permitted on or in, a mapped street, except required and approved underground installations, and further excepting that pump houses for drip irrigation may be permitted to encroach into public rights-of-way providing prior written approval is obtained from the Director of Public Works Department, and further providing that a building permit is secured for such pump house placement. The Public Works Director shall determine whether the request will be contrary to the public interest based upon the following criteria: (a) safe and sufficient passing distance for motorists and pedestrians, (b) location of existing pavement, if any, (c) safe sight distance for motorists, (d) the effect on adjacent land uses, (e) access to land in the area. Upon the Director's determination that the pump house encroachment will not be contrary to the public interest the property owner shall execute and deliver a written covenant running with the land in favor of Miami-Dade County committing that within sixty (60) days after notice from the Public Works Director that the pump house has become contrary to the public interest based on the above-mentioned criteria, the property owner shall remove the pump house at the owner's expense and terminate the encroachment. Said covenant shall be in a form approved by the County Attorney's Office, and shall be executed so as to be entitled to recording in the public records of Miami-Dade County. The property owner shall establish that there is no lien or encumbrance prior in right to such covenant except for non-delinquent ad valorem property taxes, failing which a removal bond satisfactory to the Public Works Director shall additionally be posted. Upon the owner's compliance with the provisions of this section, the Public Works Director shall issue written approval.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
For the purpose of this section, "drip irrigation" shall mean low volume irrigation as defined in Section 32-8.2(c), Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, Florida, which is intended and designed to deliver water and nutrients to the root area of a plant in quantities matching evapotranspiration requirements as closely as possible, and at a rate close to what the soil will absorb.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
(1) Wire fences without barbed wire may be permitted to be constructed within the rights-of-way set forth in Section 33-133, Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, Florida, providing written approval is obtained from the Director of the Public Works Department, and further providing that a building permit is secured for such fence placement. An applicant for the Public Works Director's approval of a wire fence shall submit the written consents of all the owners of all parcels abutting the subject property, and of all the owners of all parcels immediately across the street from the subject site. In the event the applicant is unable to submit such consents, an application for non-use variance may be filed pursuant to the provisions of Sections 28-18(c)(2) and 33-311 of the Code. Prior to consideration by the Public Works Director, notice shall be mailed to all property owners within one thousand (1,000) feet of the property on which the fence is to be located if the property is situated wholly within the Urban Development Boundary (as shown on the Comprehensive Development Master Plan), and to all property owners within one thousand five hundred (1,500) feet of such property, if any portion of such property is outside the Urban Development Boundary. The notice shall state that any interested party may respond in writing within thirty (30) days and that no permit will be granted until after the thirty-day period has expired. After considering the application and all statements of interested parties, the Public Works Director shall determine whether the requested fence will be contrary to the public interest based upon the following criteria: (a) location of existing pavement, if any; (b) safe sight distance for motorists; (c) effect on adjacent land uses; (d) access to land in the area; and (e) safe recovery zone for vehicles. Under no circumstances shall any fence or wall be placed within the public right-of-way less than ten (10) feet from the edge of any existing roadway pavement. Upon the Director's determination that the fence will not be contrary to the public interest, the property owner shall execute and deliver a written covenant running with the land in favor of Miami-Dade County committing that within sixty (60) days after notice from the Public Works Director that the fence has become inconsistent with the public interest based on the above-mentioned criteria the property owner shall remove the fence at the owner's expense. Said covenant shall be in a form approved by the county attorney's office, and shall be executed so as to be entitled to recording in the public records of Miami-Dade County. The property owner shall establish that there is no lien or encumbrance prior in right to such covenant except for non-delinquent ad valorem property taxes, failing which a removal bond satisfactory to the Public Works Director shall additionally be posted.
<section prefix = "2">
The director shall publish notice of his determination regarding fence placement or removal in a newspaper of general circulation and shall provide mail notice to the same property owners who were entitled to be mailed notice in advance of the director's determination, as provided in this subsection. Appeal of the director's determination or decision shall be filed within thirty (30) days of such publication or of the mailing of such notice, whichever date is later, and shall proceed as provided in subsection (d) of this section. The public interest criteria contained in this subsection shall apply to any appeal regarding the placement in or removal from the right-of-way of any wire fence. No masonry wall or wood fence shall be permitted to be constructed on or in a right-of-way unless approved as a non-use variance pursuant to the provisions of Section 33-311 of the Code. In addition to the criteria set forth in Section 33-311(e)(2), the public interest criteria contained in this subsection shall apply to any public hearing or appeal regarding the placement in or removal from the right-of-way of any masonry wall or wood fence.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Appeals of the director's decision regarding pump house or fence placement or removal may be taken to the Community Zoning Appeals Board pursuant to Section 33-311(c), Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and, thereafter, to the Board of County Commissioners pursuant to Sections 33-313 through 33-316 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 77-6, § 1, 2-1-77; Ord. No. 92-94, § 2, 9-15-92; Ord. No. 94-24, § 1, 2-1-94; Ord. No. 94-50, § 1, 3-17-94; Ord. No. 98-125, § 18, 9-3-98)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 28-19. Variances</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Authority of Community Zoning Appeals Board. The County's Community Zoning Appeals Board may authorize a variance from these regulations. The Community Zoning Appeals Board may vary the regulations so that substantial justice may be done, provided that such variance will not have the effect of nullifying the intent and purpose of the overall community plan. In granting any variance, the County's Community Zoning Appeals Board shall prescribe any conditions that are deemed necessary to or desirable for the public interest. In making its findings, the Community Zoning Appeals Board shall take into account among other things the nature of the proposed use of the land and the exiting use of the land in the vicinity, the number of persons to reside or work in the proposed subdivision and the probable effect of the proposed subdivision upon traffic conditions in the vicinity. No variance shall be granted unless the County's Community Zoning Appeals Board finds, among other things, that all three (3) of the following conditions exist in regard to the land concerned:
<section prefix = "1">
That there are special circumstances or conditions affecting the property and that the strict application of the provisions of this chapter would deprive the applicant of the reasonable use of the land.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
That the variance is necessary for the preservation and enjoyment of a substantial property right of the applicant.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
That the granting of the variance will not be detrimental to the public welfare or injurious to the other property in the territory in which the property is situated.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Large scale developer. The standards and requirements of these regulations may be modified by the Community Zoning Appeals Board in the case of a plan and program for a new town or a complete community which in the judgment of the Community Zoning Appeals Board provides adequate public spaces and improvements for the circulation, recreation, light, air, and service needs of the tract when fully developed and populated, and which also provides such covenants or other legal provisions as will assure conformity to and achievement of the plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Hearing and notice. All such variances shall be granted only after hearing and notice as prescribed in Section 33-310. The Community Zoning Appeals Board shall not act without considering the recommendations of the Planning Director and the Zoning Official.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Variance to specified sections. Where the use of a fire well or septic tank or both well and septic tank have been approved for use as provided in Sections 28-15(c)(2), 28-15(c)(3) and 28-15(d)(2), a variance to these sections need not be authorized by the Community Zoning Appeals Board.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 77-6, § 1, 2-1-77; Ord. No. 78-12, § 3, 3-21-78; Ord. No. 94-51, § 4, 3-17-94; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-127, § 3, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 98-125, § 18, 9-3-98)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 28-20. Municipal regulations; effect</catch_line>
<text>
Any municipality which has, or which desires to provide higher standards of subdivision regulations than those provided by this chapter shall certify such regulations, as have been adopted in accordance with law, to the County Department of Public Works. Any such regulations which provide for higher standards in any municipality shall be enforced as a supplement to this chapter by the County departments concerned.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (1) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 77-6, § 1, enacted Feb. 1, 1977, repealed former Ch. 28, relative to subdivisions, and enacted in lieu thereof a new Ch. 28 as herein set out. Former Ch. 28 was derived from Ord. No. 57-30, adopted Dec. 21, 1957; Ord. No. 61-16, adopted April 18, 1961; Ord. No. 64-29, adopted July 21, 1964; Ord. No. 65-24, adopted April 6, 1965; Ord. No. 65-26, adopted April 20, 1965; Ord. No. 66-21, adopted May 17, 1966; Ord. No. 68-31, adopted May 21, 1968; Ord. No. 68-69, adopted Nov. 19, 1968; Ord. No. 69-12, adopted Feb. 18, 1969; Ord. No. 69-53, adopted Sept. 3, 1969; Ord. No. 70-42, adopted May 27, 1970; Ord. No. 71-18, adopted Feb. 16, 1971; Ord. No. 72-42, adopted July 27, 1972; and Ord. No. 74-39, adopted June 4, 1974. (Back)
Annotations—AO 4-47; CAO's 77-22, 77-31. (Back)
Cross reference— Planning Department, § 2-104 et seq.; Building and Zoning Department, §§ 2-117, 2-118; building code, Ch. 8; development within coastal flood hazard districts, Ch. 11C; fire prevention, Ch. 14; housing standards, Ch. 17; landscaping, Ch. 18A; mobile homes, Ch. 19A; planning generally, Ch. 23A; standards for acceptance of conveyances of park and recreational lands, § 25B-11 et seq.; water and sewer regulations, Ch. 32; zoning, Ch. 33; developments in incorporated areas creating County impact, Ch. 33A; road impact fees, Ch. 33E; service concurrency management program, Ch. 33G; park impact fee, Ch. 33H; police services impact fee, Ch. 33I; fire and emergency services impact fee, Ch. 33J. (Back)
State Law reference— Platting, F.S. § 177.011 et seq. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
