<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="2">Chapter_16_GENERAL_OBLIGATION_BONDS</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 16-1. Public hearings required before specific capital projects may be authorized or commenced</catch_line>
<text>
Whenever the issuance of bonds secured by the County's ad valorem taxing power has been authorized by the voters of the County in a referendum election, and the bonds are authorized for a generally stated purpose or objective or for a number of projects that will accomplish such purpose rather than for a specifically designated capital project, then before any specific capital project may be authorized or commenced the Board of County Commissioners shall hold one (1) or more public hearings in one (1) or several geographical areas of the County in order to provide the residents of the County with an opportunity to appear, and to criticize or comment upon the specific capital project proposed.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 16-2. Public hearing required annually to establish priorities among capital projects</catch_line>
<text>
Whenever bonds are described in the preceding section are authorized but unissued, the Board of County Commissioners will meet at least once annually to conduct a public hearing in order to provide the residents of the County with an opportunity to appear and state their individual views on the establishment of relative priorities among the various capital projects of a specific nature that are being considered or could be considered for implementation by the Board of County Commissioners under such general obligation bond issues.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 16-3. Public hearings</catch_line>
<text>
Whenever bonds as described in the preceding sections are authorized but remain uncommitted to specific projects, no action shall be taken by the Board of County Commissioners with regard to the authorization or commencement of specific capital projects or with regard to modifying capital project priorities except after public hearings at which citizens may express their viewpoints and opinions and after such studies as may be deemed necessary resulting from the views expressed in such public hearing.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (1) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 72-80, § 1, adopted Nov. 7, 1972, amended this Code by adding provisions designated Ch. 6, §§ 6-1—6-3, which provisions were redesignated Ch. 16, §§ 16-1—16-3, by the editors in order to maintain the alphabetical sequence of chapters within the Code. (Back)
Cross reference— Consideration of bond matters and debt instruments after sale, § 2-1.1; construction and financing of public facilities, Ch. 8D; safe neighborhood parks ordinance, § 25B-20 et seq. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
