<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="2">Chapter_8C_BUILDING_SECURITY_MEASURES</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 8C-1. Provisions for parking lots illumination, air conditioning condenser unit security, and public swimming pools, spas and hot tub barriers and installation of guardrails and other traffic barriers for parking lots to be set forth in this chapter and the Florida Building Code</catch_line>
<text>
This chapter prescribes requirements for illumination for open parking lots, alleys and access thereto and parking under or within buildings for all buildings and structures, air conditioning condenser unit security and barriers for new construction of public swimming pools, spas and hot tubs and installation of guardrails and other traffic barriers for parking lots abutting bodies of water.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8C-2. Application, enforcement, and exemptions</catch_line>
<text>
The provisions of this chapter, except where otherwise provided, shall apply to the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County. It is provided, however, that the municipalities may enact more restrictive regulations than set forth in this chapter. The enforcement of this chapter shall be the responsibility of the local building official. Except for certain exemptions for government facilities as expressly provided, Section 8C-3 below shall apply to existing occupancies as well as those constructed subsequent to the effective date of this chapter.
Every new and existing building for the purpose of this Chapter shall be classified in accordance with Chapter 3, "Occupancy Classification" of the Florida Building Code. Whenever there is any uncertainty as to the classification of a building, the Building Official for purposes of this chapter shall have the authority to make the determination of the classification within which it falls.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8C-3. Illumination for open parking lots, alleys and access thereto and parking and nonenclosed areas under or within buildings</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Generally:
<section prefix = "1">
This section applies to new construction and all existing buildings.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Open parking lots, alleys, and access thereto shall be illuminated as set forth below. For purposes of this paragraph, alley is defined as a narrow vehicular thoroughfare up to twenty-five (25) feet in width upon which service entrances or buildings abut and not generally used as a thoroughfare for general traffic; provided, however, alleys shall not include public rights-of-way.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Groups A (Assembly), D (Day Care) and E (Educational) occupancies:
<section prefix = "1">
Open parking lots and access thereto shall be provided with a maintained minimum of 1 foot-candle on the parking surface from dusk until dawn; provided, however, the lighting level may be reduced by fifty (50) percent on non-business days and commencing thirty (30) minutes after the termination of business on each operating day. The uniformity ratio shall not exceed a twelve to one ratio (12:1) maximum to minimum foot-candles. This provision shall not apply to governmental facilities not generally open to the public, and shall apply to those governmental facilities that are generally open to the public only during the dusk-to-dawn hours such facilities are open.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Parking and nonenclosed areas under or within buildings at grade shall be provided with a maintained minimum of 1 foot-candle of light on the parking and walking surfaces from dusk until dawn and the ratio of maximum to minimum illumination in foot-candles shall not exceed twelve to one (12:1); provided, however, the lighting level may be reduced by fifty (50) percent on non-business days and thirty (30) minutes after the termination of business one each operating day. This provision shall not apply to governmental facilities not generally open to the public, and shall apply to those governmental facilities that are generally open to the public only during the dusk-to-dawn hours such facilities are open.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Alleys shall be provided with a maintained minimum of 1/3 foot-candle on the alley surface from dusk to dawn. The uniformity ratio shall not exceed a twelve to one (12:1) maximum to minimum foot-candles. This provision shall not apply to governmental facilities not generally open to the public, and shall apply to those governmental facilities that are generally open to the public only during the dusk-to-dawn hours such facilities are open.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Groups F (Factory Industrial), H (Hazardous), I (Institutional), S (Storage) and R4 (Residential care/assisted living facilities) occupancies:
<section prefix = "1">
Open parking lots and access thereto shall be provided with a maintained minimum of 0.5 foot-candle on the parking surface from dusk until dawn; provided, however, the lighting level may be reduced by fifty (50) percent on non-business days and commencing thirty (30) minutes after the termination of business on each operating day. The uniformity ratio shall not exceed a twelve to one ratio (12:1) maximum to minimum foot-candles.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Alleys shall be provided with a maintained minimum of 1/3 foot-candle on the alley surface from dusk to dawn. The uniformity ratio shall not exceed a twelve to one (12:1) maximum to minimum foot-candles. This provision shall not apply to governmental facilities not generally open to the public, and shall apply to those governmental facilities that are generally open to the public only during the dusk-to-dawn hours such facilities are open.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Parking and nonenclosed areas under or within buildings at grade shall be provided with a maintained minimum of 1 foot-candle of light on the parking and walking surfaces from dusk until dawn and the ratio of maximum to minimum illumination in foot-candles shall not exceed twelve to one (12:1) provided, however, the lighting level may be reduced by fifty (50) percent on non-business days and commencing thirty (30) minutes after the termination of business on each operating day. This provision shall not apply to governmental facilities not generally open to the public, and shall apply to those governmental facilities that are generally open to the public only during the dusk-to-dawn hours such facilities are open.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The area immediately outside of exterior doors shall have security illumination and shall be activated during the dark period of every day.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Group B (Business) and M (Mercantile) occupancies:
<section prefix = "1">
Open parking lots and access thereto shall be provided with a maintained minimum of 1.0 foot-candle on the parking surface from dusk until dawn; provided, however, the lighting level may be reduced by fifty (50) percent on non-business days and commencing thirty (30) minutes after the termination of business on each operating day. The uniformity ratio shall not exceed a twelve to one ratio (12:1) maximum to minimum foot-candles.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Alleys shall be provided with a maintained minimum of 1/3 foot-candle on the alley surface from dusk to dawn. The uniformity ratio shall not exceed a twelve to one (12:1) maximum to minimum foot-candles. This provision shall not apply to governmental facilities not generally open to the public, and shall apply to those governmental facilities that are generally open to the public only during the dusk-to-dawn hours such facilities are open.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Parking and nonenclosed areas under, or within buildings shall be provided with a maintained minimum of 1 foot-candle of light on the walking and parking surfaces from dusk until dawn, and the ratio of maximum to minimum illumination in foot-candles shall not exceed twelve to one (12:1); provided, however, the lighting level may be reduced by fifty (50) percent on non-business days and commencing thirty (30) minutes after the termination of business on each operating day. It is provided, however, that this provision shall not apply to governmental facilities not generally open to the public, and shall apply to those governmental facilities that are generally open to the public only during the dusk-to-dawn hours such facilities are open.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The area immediately outside of exterior doors shall have security illumination and shall be activated during the dark period of every day.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Group R1 (Residential transient) and R2 (Residential multiple dwelling) occupancies:
<section prefix = "1">
Open parking lots and access thereto shall be provided with a maintained minimum of 1.0 foot-candle on the parking surface from dusk until dawn. The uniformity ratio shall not exceed a twelve to one ratio (12:1) maximum to minimum foot-candles. Alleys shall be provided with a maintained minimum of one-third (1/3) foot-candle on the alley surface from dusk to dawn.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Parking and nonenclosed areas under, or within buildings shall be provided with a maintained minimum of 1.0 foot-candle of light on the walking and parking surfaces from dusk until dawn, and the ratio of maximum to minimum illumination in foot-candles shall not exceed twelve to one (12:1).
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 01-196, § 1, 11-20-01)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8C-4. Public swimming pool, spa and hot tub barriers</catch_line>
<text>
All new construction of public swimming pools, spas and hot tubs shall be provided with a permanent barrier complying with the following:
<section prefix = "1">
The top of the barrier shall be at least forty-eight (48) inches above grade measured on the side of the barrier which faces away from the swimming pool. The maximum vertical clearance between grade and the bottom of the barrier shall be two (2) inches measured on the side of the barrier which faces away from the swimming pool. Where the top of the pool structure. Where the barrier is mounted on top of the pool structure, the maximum vertical clearance between the top of the pool structure and the bottom of the barrier shall be four (4) inches.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Opening in the barrier shall not allow passage of 4-inch diameter sphere.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Solid barriers which do not have openings shall not contain indentations or protrusions except for normal construction tolerances and tooled masonry joints.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Where the barrier is composed of horizontal and vertical members and the distance between the tops of the horizontal members is less than forty-five (45) inches, the horizontal members shall located on the swimming pool side of the fence. Spacing between vertical members shall not exceed 1¾ inches in width.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Where the barrier is composed of horizontal and vertical members and the distance between the tops of the horizontal member is forty-five (45) inches or more, spacing between vertical members shall not exceed four (4) inches. Where there are decorative cutouts within vertical members, spacing within the cutouts shall not exceed 1¾ inches in width.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Maximum mesh size for chain link fences shall be a 2¼ inches square unless the fence is provided with slats fastened at the top or the bottom which reduce the openings to no more than 1¾ inches.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Where the barrier is composed of diagonal members, the maximum opening formed by the diagonal members shall be no more than 1¾ inches.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Pedestrian access gates with direct access to the pool, spa or hot tub, shall be equipped with self-closing and self-latching devices. The release mechanism on all such devices shall be located a minimum of fifty-four (54) inches above the pool deck floor or exterior grade level.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Where the release mechanism of the self-latching device is located less than fifty-four (54) inches from the bottom of the gate, the release mechanism shall be located on the pool side of the gate at least three (3) inches below the top of the gate and barrier shall have no opening greater than ½ inch within eighteen (18) inches of the release mechanism.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8C-5. Air Conditioning Condenser Units Securing Methods</catch_line>
<text>
All installations of exterior air conditioning condenser units in single-family and fee simple townhomes in unincorporated Miami-Dade County shall comply with the following:
<section prefix = "1">
An anchor bolt with a minimum of 500 pounds pull-out resistance shall secure the air conditioning condenser unit from within the unit through to the concrete slab on which the unit rests.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8C-6. Guardrails for parking lots adjacent to or abutting bodies of water</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
On all parking lots adjacent to or abutting a canal, a lake or other body of water, a guardrail or other form of traffic barrier tested and approved for crashworthiness by the Federal Highway Administration shall be installed, after obtaining a building permit, to protect any vehicle from entering the canal, lake, or other body of water.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
This section applies to new construction and to all existing parking lots adjacent to or abutting bodies of water. All existing parking lots, as of the adoption of this ordinance, that are not in compliance with this section, shall have a period of eighteen months from the adoption of this ordinance in which to comply.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The provisions of this section shall only apply to the unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 12-84, § 3, 10-2-12)</history>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (1) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 03-214, § 1, adopted Oct. 7, 2003, amended chapter 8C by changing its title from "Parking Lots Illumination and Public Swimming Pools, Spas, and Hot Tub Barriers" to "Building Security Measures." (Back)
Editor's note— Ord. No. 01-196, § 1, adopted Nov. 20, 2001, added a new chapter 8C, sections 8C-1—8C-4. Former chapter 8C, pertaining to intrusion and burglary security was repealed by Ord. No. 96-171, § 4, adopted Nov. 19, 1996 and derived from Ord. No. 76-18, § 1, adopted Feb. 3, 1976; and Ord. No. 79-114, § 1, adopted Dec. 4, 1979. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
