<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="2">Chapter_1_GENERAL_PROVISIONS</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 1-1. How Code designated and cited</catch_line>
<text>
The ordinances embraced in the following chapters and sections shall constitute and be designated "Code of Metropolitan Dade County, Florida" and may be so cited.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 1-2. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
In construing the provisions of this Code, where the context will permit and no definition is provided herein, the definitions provided in Section 1.01, Florida Statutes shall apply.
<section prefix = "a">
The word "County" shall mean the County of Dade in the State of Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The words "County Commission" or "Board of County Commissioners" shall mean the Board of County Commissioners of Dade County, Florida, as constituted under and pursuant to the Home Rule Charter.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The words "Manager" or "County Manager" shall mean the County Manager of Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
State. The words "the State" or "this State" shall be construed to mean the State of Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Titles. Wherever reference is made to officials, boards, departments and similar official bodies of the county by title only, i.e. Director of Public Works, Tax Collector, etc., such title shall be construed as if the words "of Dade County, Florida" followed it.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Tense. Words used in the past or present tense include the future as well as the past and present.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Preceding, following. The words "preceding" and "following" mean next before and next after, respectively.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Shall. The word "shall" is always mandatory and not merely directory.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Interpretation. In the interpretation and application of any provisions of this Code, it shall be held to be the minimum requirements adopted for the promotion of the public health, safety, comfort, convenience and general welfare. Where any provision of the Code imposes greater restrictions upon the subject matter than the general provisions imposed by the Code, the provision imposing the greater restriction or regulation shall be deemed to be controlling.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 1-3. Catchlines of sections</catch_line>
<text>
The catchlines of the several sections of this Code printed in boldface type are intended as mere catchwords to indicate the contents of the section and shall not be deemed or taken to be titles of such sections, nor as any part of the section, nor, unless expressly so provided, shall they be so deemed when any of such sections, including the catchlines, are amended or reenacted.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 1-4. Amendments to Code; effect of new ordinances; amendatory language</catch_line>
<text>
All ordinances passed subsequent to this Code of Ordinances which amend, repeal or in any way affect this Code of Ordinances, may be numbered in accordance with the numbering system of this Code and printed for inclusion therein. When subsequent ordinances repeal any chapter, section or subsection or any portion thereof, such repealed portions may be excluded from said Code by omission from reprinted pages.
Amendments to any of the provisions of this Code should be made by amending such provisions by specific reference to the section number of this Code in substantially the following language: "That section ____________ of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, Florida is hereby amended to read as follows: ____________ (Set out new provisions in full) ____________."
When the County Commission desires to enact an ordinance of a general and permanent nature on a subject not heretofore existing in the Code, which the Commission desires to incorporate into the Code, a section in substantially the following language shall be made a part of the ordinance:
"Section ____________. It is the intention of the County Commission, and it is hereby ordained that the provisions of this ordinance shall become and be made a part of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, Florida, and the sections of this ordinance may be re-numbered to accomplish such intention."
All sections, articles, chapters or provisions of this Code desired to be repealed should be specifically repealed by section or chapter number, as the case may be.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 1-4.1. Administrative amendments to Code; power of the County Attorney</catch_line>
<text>
The Board of County Commissioners hereby authorizes the County Attorney to administratively amend, from time to time, the Code of Miami-Dade County solely for the purpose of conforming said ordinances to any change in numbering references to the State Constitution, State statutes, State rules and regulations and to the Miami-Dade County Code.
Additionally, the Board of County Commissioners hereby authorizes the County Attorney to update the Code and County administrative regulations or rules to delete any provisions which, as a matter of law, have been preempted, and declared null and void by Section 790.33, Florida Statutes, as amended, entitled "Field of Regulation of Firearms and Ammunition Preempted." The County Attorney also is authorized to direct the codifier of the Code to notate any provision that, as a matter of law, has been preempted and declared null and void by Section 790.33, Florida Statutes, as amended.
Except as provided in this section the County Attorney shall have no authority to administratively conform the Code wherein said amendments to the State Constitution, State statutes, State rules and regulations, and the Miami-Dade County Code substantively alter the provisions of the said Constitution, statutes, rules or regulations and/or Miami-Dade County Code provisions.
Notwithstanding the foregoing, where conflicts in language by error or omission are found between provisions of the Code as originally enacted and as recodified, the original Code provisions shall govern and the county attorney is authorized to administratively amend such conflicts, omissions or errors to conform the new recodified Code with the original Code.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 1-4.2. County name change</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
"Miami-Dade County" is hereby recognized as the official name of Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
All references to Dade County, Metropolitan Dade County or Metro-Dade County in the Florida Constitution, Florida Statutes, Code of Metropolitan Dade County, federal law, case law, court orders, regulations, public records, official county seal and logo, tax and special assessment rolls, and any and all other documents, papers, letters, maps, plats, books, tapes, photographs, films, sound recordings, data processing software, or other material, regardless of the physical form, characteristics, or means of transmission, shall deemed to be references to Miami-Dade County. This ordinance, and this section, shall apply to all such references without regard to whether they precede, are contemporary with, or occur subsequent to the effective date of this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The county remains the same political subdivision of the State of Florida as previously for all purposes and retains all rights, privileges, immunities, obligations and claims thereof unaffected by the change of name.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 97-212, §§ 1—3, 12-2-97)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 1-4.3. Reorganization of County Administrative Departments</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The powers, functions and responsibilities of the Enterprise Technology Services Department provided in all enactments of this Board including, but not limited to, ordinances, resolutions, implementing orders, regulations, rules, and provisions in the Code of Miami-Dade County ("Legislative Enactments") are hereby transferred to the Information Technology Department. All references in Legislative Enactments relating to the Enterprise Technology Services Department shall be deemed to be references to the Information Technology Department. All delegations of Commission authority, power and responsibility to the Director of the Enterprise Technology Services Department shall be deemed to be a delegation to the Director of the Information Technology Department or, at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The powers, functions and responsibilities of the Government Information Center provided in Legislative Enactments are hereby transferred to the Department of Community Information and Outreach. All references in Legislative Enactments relating to the Government Information Center shall be deemed to be references to the Department of Community Information and Outreach. All delegations of Commission authority, power and responsibility to the Director of the Government Information Center shall be deemed to be a delegation to the Director of the Department of Community Information and Outreach or, at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The powers, functions and responsibilities of the Departments of Building and Neighborhood Compliance, Planning and Zoning (except those powers, functions and responsibilities that set forth, define or otherwise affect the Office of Countywide Healthcare and Planning), Environmental Resources Management, Economic Development and International Trade, Small Business Development, Film and Entertainment, Sustainability, Consumer Services, Sustainability, Planning and Economic Enhancement and Permitting, Environment and Regulatory Affairs, provided in Legislative Enactments are hereby transferred to the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources. Commencing October 1, 2012, the powers, functions and responsibilities that set forth, define or otherwise affect the stormwater utility functions, including, but not limited to, the administration of the County's Floodplain Management Program, are hereby transferred from the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources to the Department of Public Works and Waste Management. All references in Legislative Enactments relating to the Departments of Building and Neighborhood Compliance, Planning and Zoning (except those powers, functions and responsibilities that set forth, define or otherwise affect the Office of Countywide Healthcare and Planning), Environmental Resources Management, Economic Development and International Trade, Small Business Development, Film and Entertainment, Sustainability, Consumer Services, Sustainability, Planning and Economic Enhancement and Permitting, Environment and Regulatory Affairs, shall be deemed to be references to the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources. Commencing October 1, 2012, the references to the Departments of Building and Neighborhood Compliance, Planning and Zoning (except those powers, functions and responsibilities that set forth, define or otherwise affect the Office of Countywide Healthcare and Planning), Environmental Resources Management, Economic Development and International Trade, Small Business Development, Film and Entertainment, Sustainability, Consumer Services, Sustainability, Planning and Economic Enhancement, Permitting, Environment and Regulatory Affairs, and Regulatory and Economic Resources that set forth, define or otherwise affect the stormwater utility functions, including, but not limited to, the administration of the County's Floodplain Management Program, shall be deemed to be references to the Department of Public Works and Waste Management. All delegations of Commission authority, power and responsibility to the Directors of the Departments of Building and Neighborhood Compliance, Planning and Zoning (except those delegations that set forth, define or otherwise affect the Office of Countywide Healthcare and Planning), Environmental Resources Management, Economic Development and International Trade, Small Business Development, Film and Entertainment, Sustainability, Consumer Services, Sustainability, Planning and Economic Enhancement and Permitting, Environment and Regulatory Affairs, shall be deemed to be a delegation to the Director of the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources or, at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee, except, commencing October 1, 2012, for those delegations that set forth, define or otherwise affect the stormwater utility functions, including, but not limited to, the administration of the County's Floodplain Management Program, which shall be deemed a delegation to the Director of the Department of Public Works and Waste Management, or, at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The powers, functions and responsibilities of the Community Action Agency and the Department of Human Services provided in Legislative Enactments are hereby transferred to the Department of Community Action and Human Services. All references in Legislative Enactments relating to the Community Action Agency and the Department of Human Services shall be deemed to be references to the Department of Community Action and Human Services. All delegations of Commission authority, power and responsibility to the Directors of the Community Action Agency and Department of Human Services shall be deemed to be a delegation to the Director of the Department of Community Action and Human Services or, at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The powers, functions and responsibilities of the Department of Emergency Management provided in Legislative Enactments are hereby transferred to the Department of Fire Rescue. All references in Legislative Enactments relating to the Department of Emergency Management shall be deemed to be references to the Department of Fire Rescue. All delegations of Commission authority, power and responsibility to the Director of the Department of Emergency Management shall be deemed to be a delegation to the Director of the Department of Fire Rescue or, at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The powers, functions and responsibilities of the Office of Americans with Disabilities Act Coordination and the Departments of General Services Administration (except for those powers, functions and responsibilities that set forth, define or otherwise affect infill housing), Procurement Management, Capital Improvement (except for those powers, functions and responsibilities that set forth, define or otherwise affect bond programs), and Human Resources provided in Legislative Enactments are hereby transferred to the Department of Internal Services. All references in Legislative Enactments relating to the Office of Americans with Disabilities Act Coordination and the Departments of General Services Administration (except for those references that set forth, define or otherwise affect infill housing), Procurement Management, Capital Improvement (except for those references which set forth, define or otherwise affect bond programs), and Human Resources shall be deemed to be references to the Department of Internal Services. All delegations of Commission authority, power and responsibility to the Directors of the Office of Americans with Disabilities Act Coordination and the Departments of General Services Administration (except for those delegations which set forth, define or otherwise affect infill housing), Procurement Management, Capital Improvement (except for those delegations which set forth, define or otherwise relate to bond programs), and Human Resources shall be deemed to be a delegation to the Director of the Department of Internal Services or, at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the Director of the Department of Internal Services shall hold the powers and responsibilities of the personnel director as set forth in Section 5.05 of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
The powers, functions and responsibilities of the Departments of Strategic Budget Management, Grants Coordination, Planning and Zoning (only those powers, functions and responsibilities that set forth, define or otherwise affect Office of Countywide Healthcare Planning functions), and Capital Improvements (only insofar those powers, functions and responsibilities set forth, define or otherwise affect bond programs) provided in Legislative Enactments are hereby transferred to the Department of Management and Budget. All references in Legislative Enactments relating to the Departments of Strategic Budget Management, Grants Coordination, Planning and Zoning (only those references that set forth, define or otherwise affect Office of Countywide Healthcare Planning functions) and Capital Improvements (only those references that set forth, define or otherwise affect bond programs) shall be deemed to be references to the Department of Management and Budget. All delegations of Commission authority, power and responsibility to the Director of the Departments of Strategic Budget Management, Grants Coordination, Planning and Zoning (only those delegations that set forth, define or otherwise affect Office of Countywide Healthcare Planning functions) and Capital Improvements (only those delegations that set forth, define or otherwise affect bond programs) shall be deemed to be a delegation to the Director of the Department of Management and Budget, or at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
The powers, functions and responsibilities of the Miami-Dade Public Housing Agency, General Services Administration (only those powers, functions and responsibilities that set forth, define or otherwise affect infill housing) and Department of Housing and Community development provided in Legislative Enactments are hereby transferred to the Department of Miami-Dade Public Housing and Community Development. Commencing October 1, 2012, the powers, functions and responsibilities that set forth, define or otherwise affect the Enterprise Zone Program, are hereby transferred from the Department of Public Housing and Community Development to the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources. All references in Legislative Enactments relating to the Miami-Dade Public Housing Agency, General Services Administration (only those references that set forth, define or otherwise affect infill housing) and Department of Housing and Community Development shall be deemed to be references to the Department of Miami-Dade Public Housing and Community Development. Commencing October 1, 2012, the references relating to the Miami-Dade Public Housing Agency, General Services Administration (only those references that set forth, define or otherwise affect infill housing), the Department of Housing and Community Development and the Department of Miami-Dade Public Housing and Community Development that set forth, define or otherwise affect the Enterprise Zone Program, shall be deemed to be a reference to the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources. All delegations of Commission authority, power and responsibility to the Directors of the Miami-Dade Public Housing Agency, General Services Administration (only those delegations that set forth, define or otherwise affect infill housing) and Department of Housing and Community Development shall be deemed to be a delegation to the Director of the Department of Miami-Dade Public Housing and Community Development, or, at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee, except, commencing October 1, 2012, for those delegations which set forth, define or otherwise affect the Enterprise Zone Program, which shall be deemed to be a delegation to the Director of the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources, or, at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
The powers, functions and responsibilities of the Departments of Park and Recreation and Public Works (only those powers, functions and responsibilities that set forth, define or otherwise affect Right-of-Way Aesthetic and Assets Management functions) provided in Legislative Enactments are hereby transferred to the Department of Park, Recreation and Open Spaces. All references in Legislative Enactments relating to the Departments of Park and Recreation and Public Works (only those references that set forth, define or otherwise affect Right-of-Way Aesthetic and Assets Management functions) shall be deemed to be references to the Department of Park, Recreation and Open Spaces. All delegations of Commission authority, power and responsibility to the Directors of the Departments of Park and Recreation and Public Works (only those delegations that set forth, define or otherwise affect Right-of-Way Aesthetic and Assets Management functions) shall be deemed to be a delegation to the Director of the Department of Park, Recreation and Open Spaces or, at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
The powers, functions and responsibilities of the Departments of Public Works and Solid Waste Management provided in Legislative Enactments are hereby transferred to the Department of Public Works and Waste Management. Commencing October 1, 2012, the powers, functions and responsibilities that set forth, define or otherwise affect platting, roadway concurrency management, land development and permitting functions, are hereby transferred from the Department of Public Works and Waste Management to the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources. All references in Legislative Enactments relating to the Departments of Public Works and Solid Waste Management shall be deemed to be references to the Department of Public Works and Waste Management. Commencing October 1, 2012, those references to the Departments of Public Works, Solid Waste Management and Public Works and Waste Management that set forth, define or otherwise affect platting, roadway concurrency management, land development and permitting functions, shall be deemed to be references to the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources. All delegations of Commission authority, power and responsibility to the Directors of the Departments of Public Works and Solid Waste Management shall be deemed to be a delegation to the Director of the Department of Public Works and Waste Management, or, at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee, except, commencing October 1, 2012, for those delegations that set forth, define or otherwise affect platting, roadway concurrency management, land development and permitting functions, which shall be deemed to be a delegation to the Director of the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources or, at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Any delegation made by the County Mayor pursuant to this section shall be made in writing and shall become effective upon the filing of the delegation, or any amendment or modification thereto, with the Clerk of the Board, with a copy to the County Attorney and each Commissioner. The Clerk of the Board shall list such delegations on the agenda of the next available Commission meeting and such delegations shall be subject to disapproval by majority vote of those Commissioners present upon a motion made at such meeting.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Notwithstanding any provision of a Legislative Enactment to the contrary, the qualification and requirements of any Department Director set forth in any Legislative Enactment may be satisfied by a designee of the County Mayor who shall (a) report directly to the Department Director and (b) have primary responsibility for overseeing the functions of the Department related to such qualifications. The County Mayor shall report to the Board of County Commissioners in writing which qualifications of a Department Director, if any, will be satisfied by a designee of the Mayor at the time the Mayor presents the appointment of the Department Director to the Board pursuant to Section 2.02(D) of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter and Part 8.1 of the Rules of Procedure of the County Commission.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 11-70, § 12, 9-23-11; Ord. No. 11-72, § 11, 11-23-11; Ord. No. 11-74, § 6, 11-23-11; Ord. No. 12-38, § 4, 5-15-12; Ord. No. 12-70, § 11, 9-20-12; Ord. No. 12-72, § 11, 9-20-12; Ord. No. 12-74, § 6, 9-20-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 1-4.4. Transfer of Delegated Authority from the County Manager to the County Mayor</catch_line>
<text>
Commencing with the elimination of the County Manager as a Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter County officer on November 20, 2012, all delegations of Board authority, power and responsibility to the County Manager provided in enactments of this Board including, but not limited to, ordinances, resolutions, implementing orders, regulations, rules, and provisions of the Code of Miami-Dade County are hereby delegated to the County Mayor or the County Mayor's designee. All references in enactments of this Board including, but not limited to, ordinances, resolutions, implementing orders, regulations, rules, and provisions of the Code of Miami-Dade County relating to the County Manager shall be deemed to be references to the County Mayor or the County Mayor's designee.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 1-5. General penalty; compliance; civil liability; criminal liability; penalties</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Unless otherwise specifically provided herein, any person violating any of the provisions of this Code shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment in the county jail for a period not to exceed sixty (60) days, or by both such fine and imprisonment, in the discretion of the court having jurisdiction over the cause. Any person who violates or fails to comply with this Code shall also be subject to fines in accordance with Chapter 8CC of the Code of Miami-Dade County. Each day of violation or noncompliance shall constitute a separate offense.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Compliance with this Code is the responsibility of tenants, property owners and other responsible parties as herein established.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Any person who violates a provision of this Code or any lawful rule, regulation or written order promulgated under this Code is subject to injunction or other equitable relief to enforce compliance with or prohibit the violation of the Code. Further, such person is liable for any damage to Miami-Dade County caused by such violation, and for the reasonable costs and expenses incurred by Miami-Dade County in enforcing the provisions of this Code, including but not limited to the costs of enforcement inspections, preparation of enforcement reports, photographs, title searches, postage and other demonstrable administrative costs for enforcement and collection. All such sums shall become immediately due and payable upon expenditure by the County and shall become delinquent if not paid within thirty (30) days after receipt by the violator of a department's bill itemizing the enforcement costs incurred in enforcing the provisions of this Code (the "due date"). All such delinquent sums shall bear interest at the rate of twelve (12) percent per annum.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Unless otherwise specifically provided herein, any person who violates a provision of this Code or any lawful rule, regulation or written order promulgated under this Code is subject to the judicial imposition of a civil penalty for each offense of an amount not to exceed ten thousand dollars ($10,000.00) per offense. In assessing the penalty, the court may receive evidence in mitigation. Each day during any portion of which a violation occurs constitutes a separate offense.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Upon the rendition of a judgment or decree by any of the courts of this State against any person and in favor of a department or the County in any action to enforce compliance with or prohibit the violation of the provisions of this Code, the court shall adjudge or decree against that person and in favor of the department or the County a reasonable sum as fees or compensation for the attorney acting on behalf of the department or the County in the suit in which recovery is had. Such fees or compensation shall be included in the judgment or decree rendered in the case. This provision shall apply to all civil actions filed after the effective date of this ordinance. Cessation of the violation of any of the provisions of the Code prior to rendition of a judgment or prior to execution of a negotiated settlement, but after an action has been filed by the department or the County to enforce the provision of this Code, shall be deemed for the purposes of this section the functional equivalent of a confession of judgment or verdict in favor of the department or the County, for which attorney's fees shall be awarded as set forth in this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit or require the County to bring an action on behalf of any private person.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
All the judicial and administrative remedies in this section are independent and cumulative.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 79-26, § 1, 4-3-79; Ord. No. 99-54, § 1, 5-25-99)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 1-6. [Laws of Florida, chapter 2000-312, section 10 nullified within the county.</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
This Board [of County Commissioners] finds that Section 10 of Chapter 2000-312 of the Laws of Florida is a special law applying to Miami-Dade County (or a general law applying only in Miami-Dade County) that is inconsistent with the common interest of the people of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
This Board in the exercise of the home rule powers vested in Miami-Dade County by Article VIII, Section 6 of the Florida Constitution of 1968 and the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter hereby supersedes and nullifies Section 10 of Chapter 2000-312 of the Laws of Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
This Board finds that the "governing board, agency, or authority that is wholly independent from the public health trust" created or required to be created by Section 10 of Chapter 2000-312 of the Laws of Florida is a board whose jurisdiction lies wholly within Miami-Dade County that is inconsistent with the common interest of the people of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
This Board in the exercise of the home rule powers vested in Miami-Dade County by Article VIII, Section 6 of the Florida Constitution of 1968 and the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter hereby abolishes the board, offices, and functions of the "governing board, agency, or authority" created or required to be created by Section 10 of Chapter 2000-312.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The County Attorney is authorized to prosecute or defend any lawsuits to ensure that the purpose and intent of this ordinance are fulfilled.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 00-111, §§ 2—6, 9-19-00)</history>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 00-111 did not specifically amend the Code, and its inclusion as section 1-6 was at the discretion of the editor.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 1-7. [Certain provisions not applicable to DEFGH program.</catch_line>
<text>
Notwithstanding and prevailing over any other provision in the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida to the contrary. Administrative Order 3-2, Code Section 2-8.5 relating to local preference and Code Section 10-34 relating to listing of first-tier subcontractors shall not apply to contracts for construction of the DEFGH Program and such contracts shall be exempt from the requirements thereof.
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 00-172 did not specifically amend the Code, and its inclusion as section 1-7 was at the discretion of the editor.

</EditorsNote>
</law>
