<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="2">Chapter_8E_CRANES_AND_HOISTING_EQUIPMENT</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 8E-1. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
As used in this chapter, the following words and terms shall have the following meaning:
<section prefix = "a">
Accredited Certifying Entity. A certifying entity is any organization whose certification program is accredited by the National Commission for Certifying Agencies (NCCA) or other nationally accepted and adopted accredited agency.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Crane. A machine for lifting or hovering a load and moving it horizontally, in which the consisting mechanism is an integral part of the machine. It may be driven manually or by power and may be a fixed or mobile machine and includes tower crane and mobile tower crane. The term does not include stackers, lift trucks, power shovels, backhoes, excavators, concrete pouring equipment, or straddle type mobile boat hoists.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Hoisting Equipment. Includes mast climbing work platforms, tower cranes, mobile cranes and personnel and material hoists.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Mast. A vertical structure that supports and guides the elevating assembly.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Mast Climbing Work Platform. A powered device consisting of an elevating assembly, base or chassis and mast that when erected is capable of supporting personnel, material, equipment, tools, and is capable of traveling vertically in infinitely adjustable increments to reach the desired work level.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Tower Crane. A hammerhead, luffing, or other type of tower crane that is regularly assembled and disassembled for use at various sites. It is usually characterized by provisions to facilitate erection and dismantling and may include features to permit climbing or telescoping.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Mobile Cranes. A mobile or locomotive crane covered within the scope defined in Section I, American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME) B30.5 and includes crawler cranes, locomotive cranes, wheel mounted cranes, and any variation hereof that retains the same fundamental characteristics.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Personnel and Material Hoist. A mechanism and its hoistway for use in connection with the construction, alteration, on-going maintenance or demolition of a building, structure or other work. It is used for hoisting and lowering workers or material or both, and is equipped with a car that moves vertically on guide members.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8E-2. Purpose, scope, exceptions</catch_line>
<text>
This chapter shall provide a uniform standard for the construction, installation, operation and use of Hoisting Equipment, for the inspection and certification of Hoisting Equipment, and for the education and certification of Hoisting Equipment operators. This chapter shall be of uniform applicability throughout incorporated and unincorporated Miami-Dade County. The following Hoisting Equipment is specifically exempted from the application of this chapter:
<section prefix = "a">
Mobile cranes having a boom length of less than 25 feet or a maximum rated load capacity of less than 15,000 pounds.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Operators of electric line trucks.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Marine terminal operations.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Aerial work platforms or boom-supported platforms covered by the ANSI/SIA A92 series of standards.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8E-3. Referenced codes and standards</catch_line>
<text>
The codes and standards referenced in this chapter shall be considered part of the requirements of this Code to the prescribed extent of each such reference. Where differences occur between provisions of this Chapter and referenced codes and standards, the provisions of this chapter shall apply. Where differences occur between different provisions of referenced codes and standards, the conflict shall be resolved in favor of the provision that provides the greatest measure of protection to the public safety. Where standards are not otherwise specified, the applicable standards shall be those set forth by the manufacturer's published literature including all updates with respect to the equipment at issue.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8E-4. Tower crane manufacture, installation and use</catch_line>
<text>
The following standards shall be applicable to tower cranes proposed to be installed and used within the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County:
<section prefix = "a">
The equipment manufacturers' (O.E.M.) specifications;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The mandatory rules contained within the applicable ASME B30 standard of the American Society of Mechanical Engineers made applicable to construction Tower Cranes (ASME B30.3);
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The most current standards of the U.S. Department of Labor, Occupational Safety and Health Administration ("OSHA") applicable to cranes including 29 CFR 1926.550;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The wind load standards contained within SEI/ASCE-7 for High Velocity Hurricane Zones as applied to the crane base foundation, the tie-ins to the building, the freestanding height and the height above the top tie-in. In applying the provisions of SEI/ASCE-7 for temporary installations, the design velocity reduction factors contained in SEI/ASCE 37-02 may be considered in factoring the wind speed at the discretion of the Building Official. The decision shall be made by the Building Official on a site-by-site basis. Factors to be considered include, but are not limited to, proximity to other structures, density, swing radius of the crane, hoist location and other safety requirements.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8E-5. Standards for mobile crane manufacture, installation and use</catch_line>
<text>
The following standards shall be applicable to mobile cranes proposed to be installed and used within the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County:
<section prefix = "a">
The equipment manufacturers' (O.E.M.) specifications;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The mandatory rules contained within the applicable standard of the American Society of Mechanical Engineers made applicable to construction Mobile Cranes (ASME B30.5);
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The most current standards of the U.S. Department of Labor, Occupational Safety and Health Administration ("OSHA") applicable to cranes including 29 CFR 1926.550 and 29 CFR 1910.80.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8E-6. Standards for personnel/material hoist manufacture, installation and use</catch_line>
<text>
The following standards shall be applicable to personnel/material hoists proposed to be installed and used within the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County:
<section prefix = "a">
The equipment manufacturers' (O.E.M.) specifications;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The mandatory rules contained within the applicable ANSI standard (ANSI A10.4). Bridging devices may be used provided they meet manufacturers' specifications;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The most current standards of the U.S. Department of Labor, Occupational Safety and Health Administration ("OSHA") applicable to cranes including 29 CFR 1926.552;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The wind load standards contained within SEI/ASCE-7 for High Velocity Hurricane Zones as applied to the hoist tie-ins and the floor shoe connections. In applying the provisions of SEI/ASCE-7 for temporary installations, the design velocity reduction factors contained in SEI/ASCE 37-02 may be considered in factoring the wind speed at the discretion of the Building Official. The decision shall be made by the Building Official on a site-by-site basis. Factors to be considered include, but are not limited to, proximity to other structures, density, hoist location and other safety requirements.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8E-7. Crane siting</catch_line>
<text>
Together with the permit documents, the permit applicant shall submit to the Building Official all required applications and/or approvals related to the operation of the crane on site, including, but not limited to, any required by the Federal Aviation Administration pursuant to 14 CFR Part 77 and FAA Advisory Circular AC70/7460-2K and the Miami-Dade County Transit Adjacent Construction Manual.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8E-8. Building permits and inspections</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Permits. In addition to the requirements of the Florida Building Code, and of Section 8-10 of this Code, the following shall apply to any construction involving the placement or erection of Hoisting Equipment regulated by this chapter. The structural building plan for any threshold building shall contain sufficient information for the Building Official to determine whether the Hoisting Equipment to be used in the construction complies with the standards set forth in this section. In the event that the complete fabrication, including the connection to the foundation, base structural support and attachment to the building structure, requires the preparation and approval of shop drawings, the Building Official may issue the building permit subject to permit holds. The permit holds shall be released upon completion and approval of all required information.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Inspections. In the event that any construction involves the use of Hoisting Equipment regulated by this chapter, the Building Official shall require the use of a Special Hoisting Equipment Inspector. The Special Crane Inspector shall perform the inspections set forth in the approved inspection plan and report to the Building Official the results of the inspections in forms designed for that purpose. The Building Official shall be authorized to suspend or revoke the building permit relating to any construction for gross negligence, gross incompetence, failures to correct any identified failures to comply with the applicable standards, or willful or repeated disregard of any occupational safety standard or order involving the crane. Decisions of the Building Official may be appealed to the Board of Rules and Appeals in the manner set forth in this Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Schedule. The inspection plan shall provide for crane inspection which shall occur at a minimum as follows:
Tower Cranes
-
After initial erection of crane
-
After each time top-climbing is completed on the crane and/or after each period of 6 months the crane has been erected on a construction project
-
After the passage of a hurricane or catastrophic wind event in the area of installation of the crane
-
After a major incident/accident involving the tower crane
Mobile Cranes
-
Annual inspection with a rated load test within the configuration of the crane and the manufacturer's recommended load chart
-
After a major incident/accident involving the mobile crane
-
After the passage of a hurricane or catastrophic wind event in the area of an assembled and erected mobile crane
Personnel/Material Hoists
-
After initial erection of personnel/material hoist, including a full rated load drop test
-
Every 90 days, including a full load drop test
-
After a hurricane
-
After a major incident/accident involving the personnel/material hoist
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Hoisting equipment inspection companies. To perform inspections of Hoisting Equipment, companies and/or individuals shall comply at a minimum with the following requirements:
-
Incorporated or registered in the State of Florida conducting third party inspections on cranes and/or personnel/material hoists.
-
Cannot be wholly or partly owned by an Equipment Owner or Equipment Manufacturer in the crane and hoisting industry.
-
Cannot be receiving financial support from an equipment Owner or Equipment Manufacturer in the crane and hoisting industry.
-
Must carry a minimal of $1,000,000 professional liability insurance.
-
Must carry a minimal of $1,000,000 general liability insurance.
-
Must have in its full time employment an individual who is qualified to perform inspections as set forth in subpart (e) below.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Qualification of individuals performing crane inspections. To perform the requisite crane inspections, individuals must possess the following qualifications:
-
Minimal five (5) years of work experience in the crane industry specifically erecting, operating, maintaining, inspecting and supervising equipment. Two (2) of the five (5) years of documented work experience must be in the capacity of conducting inspections of cranes.
-
Must provide proof, reasonably satisfactory to the Certifying Entity, of completion of at least one (1) factory-sponsored or approved technical course to inspect the subject equipment.
-
Cannot be an employee of an Equipment Owner or Equipment Manufacturer in the crane and hoisting industry.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Qualifications of personnel/material hoist employee inspector. To perform the requisite inspections, an individual must possess the following qualifications:
-
Minimal five (5) years of work experience in the personnel/material hoisting industry, specifically erecting, operating, maintaining, inspecting and supervising of equipment. Two (2) years of the five (5) years of documented work experience must be in the capacity of conducting inspections of personnel/material hoists and following all applicable codes and standards.
-
Must provide proof, reasonably satisfactory to the Certifying Entity, of completion of at least one (1) factory-sponsored or approved technical course to inspect the subject equipment.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
[Certifying, decertifying and implementation.] The Office of Building Code Compliance of Miami-Dade County shall be the Certifying Entity responsible for certifying and decertifying Special Hoisting Equipment Inspectors in accordance with the provisions of this Chapter. To implement the provisions of this Chapter, the County Manager shall issue an implementing order to be approved by this Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
[Appeals.] Decisions of the Building Official based on the application of this Chapter shall be appealed to the Board of Rules and Appeals in the manner set forth in this Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
[Interpretation of provisions.] The Board of Rules and Appeals may interpret provisions of this Chapter in order to cover a special case if it appears the provisions do not definitely cover the point raised or if the intent of the provision is not clear, or that ambiguity exists in the wording, but shall have no authority to grant variances where this Chapter is clear and specific.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 08-34, § 1, 3-18-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8E-9. Tower crane and mobile crane operator qualifications and certifications</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Tower cranes and mobile cranes shall only be operated by individuals certified in accordance with this Section. Certificates shall be issued by the Accredited Certifying Entity and shall be valid for five years. Certificates shall be issued to operators who:
<section prefix = "1">
Pass a physical examination conducted by a physician which at a minimum shall include the examination criteria specified in the American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME) B30.5-2000 standard, Chapter 5-3.1.2(a)(1—5, 7, 8) or the U.S. Department of Transportation (US DOT) physical examination requirements contained in 49 CFR Sections 391.41 through 391.49.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Pass a substance abuse test. The level of testing shall be consistent with the standard practice for the industry where the crane is in use and this test shall be conducted by a recognized laboratory service.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Pass a written examination developed, validated, and administered in accordance with the Standards for Educational and Psychological Testing (Copyright 1999) published jointly by the Joint Committee of the American Educational Research Association, the American Psychological Association, and the National Council on Measurement in Education. The exam shall test knowledge and skills identified as necessary for safe crane operations and shall, at a minimum, include the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Operational characteristics and controls, including characteristic and performance questions appropriate to the crane type for which qualification is sought;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Emergency control skills, such as a response to fire, power line contact, loss of stability, or control malfunction;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
A demonstration of basic arithmetic skills necessary for crane operation and the ability to read and comprehend the crane manufacturer's operation and maintenance instruction materials, including load capacity information (load charts) for the crane for which certification is sought;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Knowledge of the requirements of this chapter, chapters 5-0 through 5-3 of The American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME) B30.5-2000 and B30.5a-2002 Addenda to the standard for mobile and locomotive cranes or chapters 4-0 through 4-3 of the ASME B30.4-1996 standard for portal, tower, and pedestal cranes or Chapter 3-3 of the ASME B30.3-1993 standard for Construction Tower Cranes, depending on the type of crane(s) the operator intends to operate.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Pass a "hands-on" examination to demonstrate proficiency in operating the specific type of crane, which at a minimum shall include pre-start and post-start inspection, maneuvering skills, shutdown, and securing procedures.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Recertification. Crane operators shall recertify every five (5) years and shall be required to meet all of the qualifications set forth in subsection (a). Operators with at least one thousand (1,000) hours of documented experience operating the specific type of crane for which recertification is sought as covered by this section during the immediately preceding certification period and who meet the physical examination, substance abuse, and written examination requirements set forth in subsections (a)(1), (a)(2) and (a)(3) of this section shall not be required to take the "hands-on" examination specified in subsection (a)(4) to recertify.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Trainees may be authorized to operate mobile or tower cranes provided they are under the direct supervision of an operator possessing a valid certificate of competency for the type of crane operated by the trainee. The term "direct supervision" means the supervising operator is in the immediate area of the trainee and within visual sighting distance and able to effectively communicate with the trainee. When performing direct supervision, the supervising operator shall have no other duties other than to observe the operation of the crane by the trainee.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Existing Operators. For the period commencing on the effective date and ending one year thereafter, the certification requirements of this Section shall be deemed satisfied by any individual who satisfies the waiver requirements of this subsection. To be certified by waiver an individual must: (a) make written application for waiver from the Accredited Certifying Entity; (b) demonstrate to the Accredited Certifying Entity three years' experience in the operation of tower cranes and mobile cranes and (c) pass a hands-on examination to demonstrate proficiency in operating the specific type of crane. Only active performance of the tasks and skills required to operate the equipment for which the applicant is seeking certification throughout the applicant's career shall be counted toward the experience requirements. A certification obtained by waiver shall be valid only for five years and shall be subject to recertification in the same manner provided for in subsection (b) above.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 08-34, § 1, 3-18-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8E-10. Communications</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Crane to crane. When more than one crane is used within the same swing radius an independent and clear channel of radio communication and operable equipment to transmit same between the cranes shall be provided.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Signal persons. Prior to signaling crane operators, all signal persons shall be tested and demonstrate their qualifications in the following areas:
<section prefix = "1">
Basic understanding of crane operation and limitations.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Standard hand and voice signals as provided in the applicable American National Standard (ANSI).
Certification of the signal person shall be in accordance with any recognized federal, state or local testing program.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 08-34, § 1, 3-18-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8E-11. Hurricane preparedness</catch_line>
<text>
General. Hoisting Equipment shall abide by the following hurricane precautions:
<section prefix = "1">
Hoisting Equipment shall abide by all manufacturers' recommendations relating to hurricane preparedness including any relating to the placement and removal of advertisement banners, the use and removal of rigging.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Tower crane turntable must be lubricated prior to the event.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Mobile cranes with fixed booms must be laid down whenever feasible.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Hydraulic cranes must have booms retracted and stored.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Any counterweighted hoist must have the counterweight locked below the top tie-in.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Tower crane must be set in the weathervane position.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
All rigging must be removed from the hoist block.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
All power at base of tower shall be disconnected by a general contractor.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
A hurricane preparedness plan which conforms with the requirements of this section shall be available at the site for inspection.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8E-12. Additional enforcement</catch_line>
<text>
In addition to other methods for enforcement provided in this Chapter, the Miami-Dade County Building Code Compliance Office shall be authorized to enforce the provisions of this Section through the issuance of civil violations fines in the manner more specifically provided in Chapter 8CC of this Code. Violation of this Chapter involving any damages to the public health and safety may also be addressed by the County through an action in court for injunctive or other available relief.
</text>
</law>
