<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="2">Chapter_23A_PLANNING_GENERALLY</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 23A-1. Comprehensive Development Master Plan</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Board of County Commissioners of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, Florida, hereby adopts and enacts as Part I of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan the following capitalized section headings contained in the document entitled "Recommended Metropolitan Development Policies as Proposed by Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Planning Advisory Board and Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Planning Department":
 I. GROWTH MANAGEMENT
Miami-Dade County must plan for and manage its population growth in a manner compatible with preserving the natural environment, insuring the provision of services, and protecting natural and man-made amenities.

 II. PROVISION OF SERVICES
Insure that appropriate services, including energy, are coordinated with development and redevelopment, and are available to all.

 III. ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION
Achieve a harmonious relationship between man and his environment and assure for all citizens and tourists a healthy and aesthetically pleasing surrounding, and educate Miami-Dade County's residents as to their role within and relationship to the total environment.

 IV. DEVELOPMENT PATTERN
Provide the best possible distribution of land uses, by type and density, to meet the physical, social, cultural and economic needs of the present and future resident and tourist population in a manner which would maintain or improve the quality of the natural and man-made environment.
Plans for the development or redevelopment of municipalities should be consistent with the policies of the County's Comprehensive Development Master Plan. To provide adequate housing for all segments of the community, including for low and moderate income persons.


 V. TRANSPORTATION
Provide access to employment and the facilities and services of the entire metropolitan area; plan for mobility, opportunity, variety, energy conservation and minimum travel times and costs, safety, comfort and convenience while traveling; and provide for efficiency, economy and a well-balanced, integrated transportation system within Miami-Dade County without detracting from the quality of life of the community.
Public or mass transportation should be given top priority as a positive tool to support and improve the viability of the County and the region.
Provide a system of transportation facilities which will anticipate the need for the movement of people and storage of goods and vehicles.
Coordinate and integrate the County transportation facilities with surrounding activities so that these facilities contribute to the enrichment of the physical environment of Miami-Dade County.
Transportation facilities should be planned and designed to conserve energy and other natural resources and existing man-made facilities and to reduce the total need for new public investment.
Development within a reasonable radius of rapid transit terminals should be considered as having Countywide impact and managed consistent with overall Countywide goals.


 VI. ECONOMIC AND SOCIAL NEEDS
Foster that type of economic growth and institute those social programs that will improve the quality of life of all Miami-Dade County's residents.
To support and promote the cultural arts and spiritual values of our citizens.


 VII. GOVERNMENTAL REGULATION AND ADMINISTRATION
Improve the process of evaluating development and redevelopment projects to achieve creative developments which are coordinated with services and to insure the harmonious relationship between man and his environment.
Plans made at various levels of government should be coordinated with each other and should involve citizen participation and input during the entire process.
Provide more efficient tools and systems of implementing the Comprehensive Development Master Plan.


</section>
<section prefix = "b">
It is hereby determined that the remaining statements of policies, goals and objectives contained on pages 1 through 27 of the document entitled "Recommended Metropolitan Development Policies as Proposed by Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Planning Advisory Board and Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Planning Department" are accepted as a guideline for further implementation by the Board of County Commissioners and all agencies of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County in the further preparation and implementation of Parts II and III of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan for Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
It is hereby determined that all agencies of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall be guided by the development policies contained in subsection (a) of this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Planning Advisory Board and Department of Planning and Zoning are hereby instructed to further prepare and implement Parts II and III of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan for Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, Florida, in a manner consistent with the development policies contained in subsection (a) of this section. Further, in carrying out this said duty, the Planning Advisory Board and Department of Planning and Zoning shall be guided by those goals, policies and objectives referred to in subsection (b) hereof.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 74-100, §§ 1—4, 12-4-74; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 15, 9-3-98)</history>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 74-100, § 5, provided that said ordinance be included in this Code, but did not specify the manner of inclusion, hence, codification of §§ 1—4 as § 23A-1 was at the discretion of the editors.

</EditorsNote>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (1) ---
Annotations—AO 4-81; CAO 76-14. (Back)
Cross reference— Planning Department, § 2-104 et seq.; Building and Zoning Department, § 2-117 et seq.; building code, Ch. 8; construction of roads, bridges, causeways, etc., Ch. 9; dumps and landfill sites, Ch. 11B; development within coastal flood hazard district, Ch. 11C; fire prevention, Ch. 14; housing, Ch. 17; landscaping, Ch. 18A; environmental protection, Ch. 24; subdivisions, Ch. 28; urban renewal, Ch. 30A; water and sewers, Ch. 32; zoning, Ch. 33; development in incorporated areas creating County impact, Ch. 33A; areas of critical environmental concern, Ch. 33B; road impact fees, Ch. 33E; Key Biscayne Beach preservation, Ch. 33F; service concurrency management program, Ch. 33G; park impact fee, Ch. 33H; police services impact fee, Ch. 33I; fire and emergency services impact fee, Ch. 33J. (Back)
State Law reference— Planning generally, F.S. § 163.3161 et seq. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
