<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="">ARTICLE IV. NATURAL AND BIOLOGICAL ENVIRONMENTAL RESOURCES PERMITTING AND PROTECTION; REGULATION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS AND STORMWATER MANAGEMENT</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="">DIVISION_1._WORK_IN_CANAL_RIGHTS-OF_WAY_</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48. Permit required; expedited administrative authorizations; exceptions; work standards; compliance with work standards, suspension of permit</catch_line>
<text>
Sec. 24-48. Permit required; expedited administrative authorizations; exceptions; work standards; compliance with work standards, suspension of permit.
<section prefix = "1">
It shall be unlawful for any person to perform work or authorize, allow, suffer or permit work to be performed in County canal rights-of-way, reservations or easements anywhere in Miami-Dade County, or to trim, cut or alter a mangrove tree anywhere in Miami-Dade County, or to authorize, allow, suffer or permit the trimming, cutting or alteration of a mangrove tree anywhere in Miami-Dade County, or to fill, dredge or authorize, allow, suffer or permit filling or dredging or perform or authorize, allow, suffer or permit any type of work in, on, over, or upon tidal waters, submerged bay bottom lands, or wetlands anywhere in Miami-Dade County, or to perform or authorize, allow, suffer or permit any work which results in harmful obstruction or alteration of the natural flow of surface waters or substantial reduction in recharge of water to the Biscayne Aquifer, or authorize cause, permit, allow, let or suffer the dewatering of groundwater into any groundwater, surface water or drainage structure anywhere in Miami-Dade County, or the construction of a drainage system for any project anywhere in Miami-Dade County, without first having obtained a permit or approval from the Department. All said work shall conform to minimum standards set forth in the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and the "Permit Information Manual IV" of the South Florida Water Management District, dated September 11, 2008, as same may be amended from time to time. This section shall not apply to work in treatment facilities or their ancillary facilities such as, but not limited to, cooling canals or polishing ponds or to the following projects:
<section prefix = "a">
Repair and/or replacement of the decking or handrails, on an existing dock or pier, limited to their original dimensions.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Sealing of cracks and spall repair on a bridge, seawall or bulkhead cap or face.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Repair or sealing of the pilasters of an existing seawall or bulkhead.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Backfilling landward of existing seawalls or bulkheads.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Placement of riprap, gunite-filled tube, or other approved material beneath an undercut seawall or bulkhead provided that material does not extend more than two (2) feet waterward of the seawall or bulkhead.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Placement of sand-cement riprap bags at the toes of a seawall or bulkhead provided the bags do not extend more than two (2) feet or the width of two (2) standard sand-cement bags waterward of the seawall or bulkhead.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
The removal of old or unused or rotting piles or the removal of dilapidated docks, boatlifts, davits, or piers.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
The trimming of a mangrove tree(s) performed in accordance with the permit exemption provisions of Section 403.9326, Florida Statutes, provided that notification is given to the Department as required pursuant to Section 24-48.17(1) of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Roadway maintenance activities which are performed or authorized by the Miami-Dade County Public Works Department to correct safety deficiencies or are undertaken to maintain the continuity of existing use for an established road or road right-of-way. This provision shall not apply to any work involving expansion in the width or length of roads or work involving the filling of roads to higher elevations when said roads occur at elevations which are less than the elevations set forth by Miami-Dade County flood criteria.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Maintenance of private roads approved by the Department or maintenance of roads and fill pads approved by the Department located upon a public or private utility right-of-way. This provision shall not apply to any work involving expansion in the width or length of roads or work involving the filling of roads to higher elevations when said roads occur at elevations which are less than the elevations set forth by Miami-Dade County flood criteria.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Installation, repair, or replacement of marine hardware on docks and piers necessary to secure vessels including, but not limited to, cleats, mooring whips, chocks and mooring bits.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Construction, installation, repair, or replacement of permanent uncovered benches and/or tables on docks and piers.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
Construction, installation, repair, or replacement of fenders, except fender piles, on docks and piers necessary for the protection of vessels.
</section>
<section prefix = "n">
Construction, installation, repair, or replacement of storage boxes, not exceeding thirty-six (36) inches in height, on docks and piers.
</section>
<section prefix = "o">
Construction, installation, repair, replacement of ladders on docks and piers to provide access to and from vessels and/or the water.
</section>
<section prefix = "p">
The placement of concrete jackets or other forms of protection on existing dock, pier or mooring piles.
</section>
<section prefix = "q">
The replacement of fender piles or mooring piles at the same exact location as they presently exist and provided that the following criteria are adhered to:
<section prefix = "i">
The fender piles or mooring piles to be replaced do not protrude into the water more than twenty-five (25) percent of the width of the waterway.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
The work will be done by a contractor holding an applicable certificate of competency.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
The contractor shall contact the Director or the Director's designee a minimum of twenty-four (24) hours prior to performing the fender pile or mooring pile replacement work with information on the location and the number of fender or mooring piles to be replaced.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "r">
The installation of a drainage system for any project which does not use, generate, handle, dispose of, discharge or store hazardous materials and not otherwise requiring a class II permit. This exemption, however, shall not apply to an airport facility, a resource recovery and management facility, a sewage treatment facility, or any property that has known soil or groundwater contamination.
</section>
<section prefix = "s">
Repair or replacement of uniform waterway markers or uniform waterway regulatory markers, which markers conform with Sections 327.40 and 327.41, Florida Statutes, respectively, as may be amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "t">
Work in wetlands associated with the resumption of a lawfully permitted agricultural operation, during an agricultural fallowing period as defined in Section 24-5, as the site generally existed immediately prior to the agricultural fallowing period.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The following activities shall not require a permit and shall be eligible to receive a written expedited administrative authorization, provided the Department determines that the work meets one of the criteria set forth herein below in subsections (a)—(g) and will not result in adverse environmental impacts. The following items shall be required for departmental review: Site location and sketch of proposed work, full description of the work to be performed, all relevant information necessary to determine potential environmental impacts, as well as an administrative review fee. The Department will respond to the request with an approval, approval with conditions or denial within ten (10) business days from receipt of the required information. If the project is found to be ineligible for the expedited administrative authorization, the applicant may revise the request based on comments from the Department or the applicant may apply for a permit pursuant to Section 24-48.1. Expedited administrative authorizations are valid for a period of two (2) years unless otherwise specified.
<section prefix = "a">
Scientific, water quality, or geotechnical sampling or testing in tidal waters or wetlands.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Work in tidal waters and wetlands, not to exceed thirty (30) days, associated with motion picture, television, photographic or other media production.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Treatment or removal of vegetation which is listed as a prohibited species as set forth in Section 24-49.9 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, for restoration and enhancement activities.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Work in wetlands performed to restrict access to property for the purpose of maintaining the property in its natural state and protecting the property from trespass, illegal dumping, or damage to wetlands.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The placement of natural limerock boulder riprap waterward of an existing seawall, bulkhead or unconsolidated shoreline provided that the riprap is placed on a two (2) horizontal to one (1) vertical slope and the riprap does not extend more than ten (10) feet waterward of the mean high water line; provided, however, the Department conducts an inspection prior to the placement of the riprap and determines that said placement will not result in an adverse environmental impact to benthic communities.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Repair and/or replacement of the tieback systems on an existing seawall or bulkhead, provided that the contractor submits structurally approved plans from the applicable building authority.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Repair and/or replacement of the cap of an existing seawall or bulkhead, provided that the contractor submits structurally approved plans from the applicable building authority.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
All work to be performed under any County permits shall conform with the applicable portions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
If the Director, or the Director's designee, determines that the permittee and/or contractor is not performing the construction in accordance with the conditions of the permit or the approved plans upon which the permit was issued, the Director, or the Director's designee, may order suspension of the permit or the stopping of work until such time as the permittee and/or the contractor has complied with the permit, plans or standards. In such case, the permittee or the contractor or both shall take all necessary precautions to leave the work area in a safe and secure condition. In the event of any future widening, repairs, installation, construction, or reconstruction, by or for Miami-Dade County, of any road, bridge, canal, culvert, traffic signal, streetlight, water distribution system, sewage collection system, storm drainage system, or any other County facility within the public right-of-way in which the permittee or the contractor or both have constructed any utility which has not been conveyed to a francbised public utility, said permittee or contractor or both shall move or remove such utility as may be required for the public convenience as and whenever specified by the Director of the Public Works Department and at the expense of the permittee or the contractor or both.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
It shall be unlawful for any person to violate or fail to comply with any of the conditions or special conditions of a written expedited administrative authorization a class I, class II, class III, class IV, class V, or class VI permit issued by the Director, or the Director's designee.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48.1. Permit classifications; interpretation as to permit requirement, fee; determination of wetlands</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
There are six (6) permit classifications: class I, class II, class III, class IV, class V and class VI.
<section prefix = "a">
Class I: Class I permits are required to trim or cut a mangrove tree, unless specifically exempt pursuant to the provisions of Section 403.9326, Florida Statutes, as may be amended from time to time, or to alter or remove a mangrove tree anywhere in Miami-Dade County or for any type of work as defined herein to take place in, on, over or upon any tidal waters, bay bottom lands anywhere in Miami-Dade County or in wetlands supporting halophytic vegetation anywhere in Miami-Dade County, including, but not limited to, dredging or filling; provided, however, that class I permits shall not apply to the construction, installation or alterations of outfalls or overflow systems as described under the definition of class II permits (Section 24-48.l(l)(b)).
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Class II: Class II permits are required for the construction, installation and/or alteration of any outfall or overflow system in, on, under or upon any water body of Miami-Dade County, including, but not limited to, canals, rivers, lakes, lagoons and/or all tidal water bodies.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Class III: Class III permits are required for work in, on, upon or contiguous to nontidal lakes, canals, rivers and other water areas and waterfronts under the direct control of Miami-Dade County by virtue of ownership, dedication by plat, right-of-way easement, reservation, or right-of-way and access agreement or instrument, including canal right-of-way as herein defined; provided, however, that class III permits shall not apply to Sections 33-13(e) and 33-16(a) of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, nor shall they apply to the construction, installation, and/or alteration of outfalls or overflow systems as described under the definition of class II permits (Section 24-48.1(1)(b)).
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Class IV: Class IV permits are required for any work in, on, or upon wetlands anywhere in Miami-Dade County, except for work in wetland areas requiring a class I permit under this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Class V: Class V permits are required for any dewatering of groundwater, surface water or water which has entered into an underground facility, excavation or trench.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Class VI: Class VI permits are required for the installation of a drainage system for any project that has known soil or groundwater contamination, or that uses, generates, handles, disposes of, discharges, or stores hazardous materials.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
If any person is in doubt as to whether or not the proposed work requires a permit as hereunder provided, said person may request a written determination from the Director. Within thirty (30) days after receipt of such request, the Director shall issue a letter of interpretation with respect to whether or not a permit is required for the proposed work. The Director may require any or all of the information which is required in a short form permit application as a condition precedent to the issuance of such a letter. Such letter shall have no precedential value to any person other than the person who requested said written determination, or his grantees, heirs, successors or assigns. A fee, to be set by administrative order approved by the Board of County Commissioners, shall be collected from any person requesting a letter of interpretation by the Director. The fee shall be applied towards the permit application fee if the Director determines that a permit is required.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Determinations as to the landward extent of wetlands shall be based on the unified statewide methodology adopted pursuant to Section 373.421(1), Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time. A determination that any portion of a tract of land is not a wetland does not preclude the requirement for a permit on any other portion of the tract that is determined to be a wetland. The unified statewide methodology adopted pursuant to Section 373.421(1), Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time, is hereby adopted by reference, as same may be amended from time to time.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08; Ord. No. 12-58, § 5, 7-3-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48.2. Permit application forms; procedures</catch_line>
<text>
There are two (2) types of application forms; short form and standard form. The general criteria for determining the type of application form required are based on the magnitude of the project, and its potential environmental impact. Unless waived by the municipality, the applicant's plans shall require municipal approval.
<section prefix = "I">
Short Form Permit Application:
<section prefix = "A">
When permissible: A short form permit application may be accepted by the Department of Environmental Resources Management for the following types of work:
<section prefix = "1">
The construction, repair, or replacement of seawalls or bulkheads, including the minimum filling or dredging necessary for installation, at the mean high water line or no more than 12 inches waterward of their existing location.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Construction or the placement of a single-family residence fixed or floating dock, davit, boat lift, mooring or fender pile, all of which are associated with a single family residence provided that none of the foregoing protrude into the water more than twenty-five (25) percent of the width of the waterway.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Repair, replacement or restoration of docks, piers, davits, boat lifts, mooring or fender piles, provided none of the foregoing protrude into the water more than twenty-five (25) percent of the width of the waterway.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Installation, repair or replacement of mooring buoys, when it is determined that the proposed work will not present a hazard to navigation.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
All work requiring a class II, III, or VI permit.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Maintenance dredging projects where the dredged material is to be deposited on a self-contained upland site.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
The placement of riprap in front of an existing seawall, bulkhead or shoreline, that does not otherwise qualify under Section 24-48(2).
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Davit installation on a dock, seawall or bulkhead.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Repair or replacement of wave baffles at their original location and dimensions.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Construction or the placement of fixed or floating docks, piers, davits, boat lifts, mooring piles and fender piles in order to create fifty (50) or less boat slips at a new or existing boat docking facility other than a single-family residence, provided that the following criteria are adhered to:
<section prefix = "a">
None of the foregoing protrude into the water more than twenty-five (25) percent of the width of the waterway.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
No dredging or filling is associated or required for the project.
A boat docking facility expansion may only be accepted as a short form application if the facility has not been physically expanded during the past two (2) years.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Installation of a subaqueous cable or pipeline crossing requiring the dredging and backfilling of ten thousand (10,000) cubic yards or less of material.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Any non-exempt installation of aids to navigation.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Repair of bridge fender systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
Repair or replacement of an existing bridge.
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
Construction of artificial reefs.
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
Any non-exempt trimming or cutting or any other alteration of a mangrove tree(s) which is not a part of a coastal band community.
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
Clearing, farming, filling, dredging, plowing or any other work within wetlands requiring a class IV permit and not lying within the Bird Drive Everglades Wetland Basin or the North Trail Wetland Basin where the usage is consistent with existing zoning regulations and where the cumulative area upon which work will be performed does not exceed:
<section prefix = "a">
One (1) acre of wetlands in areas designated as "Environmental Protection" on the current Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan Map, or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Forty (40) acres of wetlands in areas designated as "Open Land" or "Agriculture" on the current Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan Map.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
Rockmining in the Transitional Northeast Everglades, the East Turnpike Wetland Basin and the C-9 Wetland Basin, when said rockmining has been previously approved as an unusual use by Miami-Dade County. However, a short form application for said rockmining shall be permitted only when the design and development criteria for the proposed rockmining project do not conflict with the prior unusual use approval by Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
Elevated boardwalks landward of the mean high water line.
</section>
<section prefix = "20">
Boat lift installation on a new or existing dock, seawall or bulkhead.
</section>
<section prefix = "21">
The clearing, farming, placement of clean fill, dredging, plowing or any other agricultural site alteration within the North Trail Wetland Basin or the Bird Road Drive Everglades Wetland Basin.
</section>
<section prefix = "22">
Clearing, placement of clean fill or dredging in wetlands associated with a modification of the Central and South Florida Flood Control Project, intended to restore historical patterns of hydrologic flow to Everglades National Park, Florida Bay or Biscayne Bay and performed by the State of Florida or the United States Government. Modifications intended to provide additional drainage of wetland areas shall be subject to the provisions of Section 24-48.2(II)(A).
</section>
<section prefix = "23">
All work requiring a class V permit.
</section>
<section prefix = "24">
Clearing, placement of clean fill, dredging or other work in wetlands or surface waters associated with the repair, replacement or maintenance of the Central and South Florida Flood Control Project, performed by the State of Florida or the United States Government.
</section>
<section prefix = "25">
Dredging and filling in wetlands or tidal waters for the sole purpose of environmental restoration or environmental enhancement.
</section>
<section prefix = "26">
The filling of privately owned boat notches, boat ramps or other manmade excavations into uplands in association with the installation of a seawall or bulkhead.
</section>
<section prefix = "27">
The construction of monitoring wells or stations in wetlands or tidal waters for the purpose of environmental monitoring or research unless otherwise exempt.
</section>
<section prefix = "28">
Work in wetlands or tidal waters associated with scientific studies conducted by public agencies, research, or academic institutions that does not otherwise qualify for approval under Section 24-48(1) or 24-48(2).
</section>
<section prefix = "29">
Filling at publicly-owned beaches for beach renourishment, beach restoration, or remediation of beach erosion.
</section>
<section prefix = "30">
The minimum dredging or filling in wetlands or tidal waters necessary for the repair or replacement of utility poles and lines.
</section>
<section prefix = "31">
All other work not specifically described in the list of projects requiring a standard form permit application or qualifying for approval under Section 24-48(1) or 24-48(2).
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Application procedure (class I, class II, class III, class IV, class V, and class VI permits):
<section prefix = "1">
The applicant or the applicant's agent shall submit to the Department an application in such form as prescribed by the Department. Written consent of the upland property owner who possesses riparian rights to the area of the proposed work shall be submitted with the application for a class I permit. For removal and disposal of contaminated sediments from the Miami River and its tidal tributaries conducted by the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers and the local project sponsor in conjunction with maintenance dredging of the Miami River federal navigation channel, the written consent of the upland property owner who possesses riparian rights to the area of the proposed work or the written consent of the lessee who possesses riparian rights to the area of the proposed work shall be the equivalent of the aforesaid verification of the application. In such case, the local project sponsor shall be deemed and shall be the applicant for the purposes of this article. Written consent shall be in a form prescribed by the Director or the Director's designee. The written consent of the upland property owner who possesses riparian rights to the area of the proposed work or by the lessee of said upland property shall not be required for a class I permit application submitted by a federal, state, county, municipal, or other governmental entity for dredging projects to improve drainage in tidal waters of canals and rivers, provided, that the proposed work shall be performed only on submerged lands owned by the governmental entity submitting the class I permit application. Written consent of the owner of the property upon which the work is proposed shall be submitted with the application for a class IV permit on a form approved by the Departments. A public hearing by the Board of County Commissioners shall be held for a short form application if a written request therefore is filed with the Department of Environmental Resources Management prior to the Department's issuance of the permit. The written request for public hearing before the Board of County Commissioners shall include in the written request the specific Department of Environmental Resources Management pending permit application number. If no such written request is filed, the Department shall approve and issue, deny or approve and issue subject to conditions, limitations or restrictions, the work proposed under the permit application based upon the applicable evaluation factors set forth in Section 24-48.3 of this Code. If a timely request is filed, the Board of County Commissioners shall approve, approve with conditions, limitations or restrictions, or deny a permit for the proposed work after conducting said public hearing in accordance with the procedures set forth in Section 24-48.2(II)(C)(1), (2) and (3). A short form permit application shall include but not be limited to the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Two (2) or more complete sets of construction plans and calculations for the proposed work prepared by an engineer licensed in the State of Florida. Said plans and calculations shall be subject to review and approval by the Department. Said plans and calculations may be prepared by an architect licensed in the State of Florida for work described in Section 24-48.2(I)(A)(4), (6), (7), (8), (9), (12), (16), (17), (21), (25), (26), (27), and (28). Said plans and calculations may be prepared by a land surveyor licensed in the State of Florida for the work described in Section 24-48.2(I)(A)(17), (18), (21), (23), (25), (27), (28) and (30). Applicants for permits to perform rockplowing or other agricultural site alterations as described in Section 24-48.2(I)(A)(17) and (21) are exempt from submitting plans prepared by an architect or engineer only if said rockplowing or agricultural site alteration does not involve the construction of any roads built at elevations higher than natural surface elevations, fill pads, culverts, or structures of any type; excavation of any borrow pits, ditches or canals; or the construction of any other drainage facilities or drainage structures. Short form applications for rockplowing or other agricultural site alteration which meet the requirements of this provision may substitute sketches or plans of the proposed work. Said sketches or plans shall be in sufficient detail to identify the type of the proposed work, location of the proposed work and whether or not the proposed work complies with all applicable development criteria and management practices. Work limited exclusively to the trimming or cutting of a mangrove tree(s) is exempt from this requirement.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A check in the amount of the required application fee payable to Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Evidence of ownership or a lease of the upland and submerged land, or evidence of ownership or a lease of the wetland upon which work is proposed. Said evidence of ownership may include, in the discretion of the Department, an affidavit of ownership executed by the owner of the property. For proposed work on submerged lands owned by a federal, state, county, municipal, or other governmental entity, evidence of ownership or a lease of the upland and a.) the written consent of the federal, state, county, municipal, or other government entity owning the submerged lands upon which the work is proposed or, b.) lease from the federal, state, county, municipal, or other governmental entity owning the submerged lands upon which the work is proposed, shall be required. Written consent shall be in a form prescribed by the Director or the Director's designee. For removal and disposal of contaminated sediments from the Miami River and its tidal tributaries conducted by the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers and the local project sponsor in conjunction with maintenance dredging of the Miami River federal navigation channel, the written consent of the owner or lessee of the submerged lands and the written consent of the owner or lessee of the upland who possesses riparian rights to the area of the proposed work shall be deemed to satisfy the requirements of this paragraph. The written consent shall be in a form prescribed by the Director or the Director's designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
If the proposed work is within an incorporated area, a substantiating letter or plan approval shall be submitted, as part of the permit application, from the zoning authority of the incorporated area. If the proposed work is within an unincorporated area, a substantiating letter or plan approval from Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning shall be submitted as part of the permit application. Said substantiating letter shall state that the proposed usage of the property upon which the proposed work would occur does not violate any zoning law applicable to the area of the proposed work. Applications by the Federal Government, the Florida Department of Transportation, Department of Environmental Protection or the South Florida Water Management District or a municipality or the County within its own jurisdiction, shall not be required to submit the above described substantiating letter or plan approval from the local zoning authority. For Class V projects and work limited exclusively to the trimming, cutting or alteration of mangrove tree(s), a substantiating letter or plan approval shall not be required.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
If the work is limited exclusively to the trimming, or alteration of a mangrove tree(s), a sketch shall be prepared by a licensed landscape architect which delineates the property lines of the upland owner, the location and size of all existing mangrove tree(s) on the site and the nature, degree, and methodology of the proposed trimming or cutting. If the proposed work involves trimming or cutting of less than five (5) mangrove tree(s) or involves the trimming of mangrove tree(s) for a property line survey, the sketch may be prepared by a person other than a licensed landscape architect.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
For all proposed work involving the placement of clean fill within the Bird Drive Everglades Wetland Basin or the North Trail Basin, a maintenance plan shall be submitted which shall include:
<section prefix = "i">
A description of how the stormwater management system shall be maintained in a functional condition,
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Treatment and control techniques as well as a management schedule to ensure that all of the stormwater management areas will be maintained free from exotic plant species, and
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
A description of how the stormwater management system shall be kept free of solid waste.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
For all proposed work which involves the placement of more than four (4) inches of fill above the seasonal high water table in the area(s) of the subject property designated as the stormwater management area(s), a report prepared by an engineer licensed in the State of Florida shall be submitted. Said report shall demonstrate the consistency of the site plan with the goals and requirements of either the North Trail Basin Fill Enforcement and Water Management Criteria (for properties located within the North Trail Basin), or with the Bird Drive Everglades Basin Fill Encroachment and Water Management Criteria (for properties located within the Bird Drive Everglades Wetland Basin).
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
In lieu of constructing an on-site stormwater management system to satisfy the North Trail Basin Fill Encroachment and Water Management Criteria, the Bird Drive Everglades Basin Fill Encroachment and Water Management Criteria or the Basin B Fill Encroachment and Water Management Criteria, persons who own parcels which parcels have been continuously four and one half (4.5) acres or less in size in any of the aforesaid basins since September 30, 1997 are eligible to contribute a to the Miami-Dade County Stormwater Compensation Trust Fund. The amount of the contribution shall be in accordance with an administrative order of the County Manager as approved by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Evidence that a public notice of filing of a class I permit application in a form approved by the Director or the Director's designee which describes the nature and location of the proposed work has been published in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County is required for class I permit applications submitted by federal, state, county, municipal, or other governmental entity for dredging projects to improve drainage in tidal waters of canals and rivers, when the work proposed will be performed only on submerged lands owned by the governmental entity submitting the class I permit application, and when the written consent of the upland property owner who possesses riparian rights to the area of the proposed work has not been obtained.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
In addition, the following supplemental information may, at the discretion of the Department, be required to be submitted with a short form permit application:
<section prefix = "a">
A written statement signed and sealed by an engineer licensed in the State of Florida, who is qualified by education and experience in the area of engineering design and inspection, that:
<section prefix = "i">
To the best of the engineer's knowledge and belief, the proposed work does not violate any laws, rules, or regulations of the State of Florida or any provisions of the Code of Miami-Dade County which may be applicable; that diligence and recognized standard practices of the engineering profession have been exercised in the engineer's design of the proposed work; and in the opinion of the engineer, based upon his knowledge and belief, the following will not occur:
<section prefix = "1">
Harmful obstruction or undesirable alteration of the natural flow of the water within the area of the proposed work.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Harmful or increased erosion, shoaling of channels or stagnant areas of water. (Not applicable to class IV permits.)
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Material injury to adjacent property.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Harmful effect upon the water quality within the receiving water body of the emergency overflow from a stormwater retention system. (Applicable to class II permits only.)
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Adverse environmental impacts from changes in water quality or quantity. (Applicable to class IV permits only.)
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
The engineer has been retained by the applicant to provide inspections throughout the construction period and to prepare a set of reproducible record prints of drawings showing changes made during the construction process based upon the marked-up prints, certified surveys drawings and other data furnished by the contractor to the engineer.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A covenant running with the land in favor of Miami-Dade County executed by the owner(s) of the property. The covenant shall be in a form approved by the Director. All covenants submitted pursuant to this provision shall be executed by the owner(s) of the property, accepted by the Director or Director's designee, and recorded in the Official Records of Miami-Dade County at the expense of the owner(s) of the property. Said covenant shall not be released or modified without the written consent of the Director. Said covenant shall restrict development or alteration of the property to a designated portion of the property and may include conditions for the environmental protection and environmental management of designated portions of the property.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
A comprehensive environmental impact statement, if required pursuant to Section 24-7(25).
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
If, in the opinion of the Director, inadequate information has been provided to evaluate the proposed work, or adverse environmental impact may occur as a result of the proposed work, the Director, before making a recommendation as to the application, shall require the applicant to conduct a coastal engineering study or water quality study or biological study or groundwater study. Said studies shall be a part of the permit application.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
For all proposed work within the North Trail Basin or the Bird Drive Everglades Wetland Basin, a covenant running with the land in favor of Miami-Dade County, in a form approved by the Board of County Commissioners, shall be executed. Said covenant may only be released or modified by action of the Board of County Commissioners and shall provide for the protection and maintenance of the stormwater management area of the subject property.

</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "II">
Standard Form Permit Application:
<section prefix = "A">
A standard form permit application shall be required for the following types of work. A standard form permit application shall also be required for all short form permit applications for which a public hearing has been requested pursuant to Section 24-48.2(I)(B)(1).
<section prefix = "1">
Any non-maintenance dredging of submerged lands exceeding 100 square feet in area not specifically described under Section 24-48(1) or 24-48.2(I).
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Construction or the placement of a fixed or floating dock, davit, boat lift, mooring or fender pile protruding more than twenty-five (25) percent into the width of the waterway.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Filling within tidal waters or wetlands supporting halophytic vegetation not specifically described under Sections 24-28(1) or 24-48.2(I).
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Construction or the placement of fixed or floating docks, piers, davits, boat lifts, mooring piles and fender piles in order to create fifty (50) or more boat slips at a new or existing boat docking facility.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Any non-exempt trimming or cutting or any alteration of a mangrove tree(s) which is a part of a coastal band community.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Clearing, farming, filling, dredging, plowing or any other work within wetlands requiring a class IV permit where cumulative area upon which work will be performed exceeds:
<section prefix = "a">
One (1) acre of wetlands in areas designated as "Environmental Protection" on the current Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan Map, or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Forty (40) acres of wetlands in areas designated as "Open Land" or "Agriculture" on the current Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan Map unless otherwise noted herein.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
The installation of new bridges over tidal waters.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Applications for variances of prohibited floating structures and prohibited fixed structures as required by Section 24-48.25
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
The applicant or the applicant's agent shall submit to the Department an application in such form as prescribed by the Department. Written consent of the upland property owner who possesses riparian rights to the area of the proposed work shall be submitted with the standard form application for a class I permit. For removal and disposal of contaminated sediments from the Miami River and its tidal tributaries conducted by the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers and the local project sponsor in conjunction with maintenance dredging of the Miami River federal navigation channel, the written consent of the upland property owner who possesses riparian rights to the area of the proposed work or the written consent of the lessee who possesses riparian rights to the area of the proposed work shall be required. In such case, the local project sponsor shall be deemed and shall be the applicant for the purposes of this article. Written consent shall be in a form prescribed by the Director or the Director's designee. Written consent of the upland property owner who possesses riparian rights to the area of the proposed work or by the lessee of said upland property shall not be required for a class I permit application submitted by a federal, state, county, municipal, or other governmental entity for dredging projects to improve drainage in tidal waters of canals and rivers, provided, that the proposed work shall be performed only on submerged lands owned by the governmental entity submitting the class I permit application. Written consent of the owner of the property upon which the work is proposed shall be submitted with the standard form application for a class IV permit. All permit applications shall be submitted to the Department in such form as prescribed by the Department. A standard form permit application shall include, but not be limited to, the following:
<section prefix = "1">
Evidence of ownership or a lease of the upland and submerged land, or evidence of ownership or a lease of the wetland upon which work is proposed. Said evidence of ownership may include, in the discretion of the Department, an affidavit of ownership executed by the owner of the property. For proposed work on submerged lands owned by a federal, state, county, municipal, or other governmental entity, evidence of ownership or a lease of the upland and a.) the written consent of the federal, state, county, municipal, or other government entity owning the submerged lands upon which the work is proposed or, b.) lease from the federal, state, county, municipal, or other governmental entity owning the submerged lands upon which the work is proposed, shall be required. Written consent shall be in a form prescribed by the Director or the Director's designee. For removal and disposal of contaminated sediments from the Miami River and its tidal tributaries conducted by the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers and the local project sponsor in conjunction with maintenance dredging of the Miami River federal navigation channel, the written consent of the owner or lessee of the submerged lands and the written consent of the owner or lessee of the upland who possesses riparian rights to the area of the proposed work shall be deemed to satisfy the requirements of this paragraph. The written consent shall be in a form prescribed by the Director or the Director's designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Three (3) copies of a plan or sketch of the proposed structure or work. For class I permits this shall include the locations of the mean high water line, mean low water line, the property lines of the upland owner, and soundings made in the surrounding water areas, corrected to mean low water datum. For work which involves the trimming or cutting of a mangrove tree(s), the sketch or plan shall delineate the location and size of all existing mangrove tree(s) on the site and the nature, degree and methodology of the proposed trimming or cutting.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
A written statement signed by the permit applicant or the applicant's authorized agent stating that, if approval is granted for the proposed work by the Board of County Commissioners, complete and detailed plans and calculations of the proposed work shall be prepared by an engineer licensed in the State of Florida in accordance with the minimum requirements of this chapter. Said plans and calculations shall be subject to the review and approval of the Department. Said written statement shall state that the applicant will secure the services of a licensed engineer to conduct inspections throughout the construction period, and that said engineer shall prepare all required drawings of record. This statement shall also provide that for work which involves cutting or trimming of a mangrove tree(s), a detailed plan of the proposed cutting or trimming shall be prepared by a licensed landscape architect and submitted to the Department for review and approval, and that the applicant will secure the services of a licensed landscape architect to supervise the trimming or cutting.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
A written statement signed and sealed by an engineer licensed in the State of Florida, who is qualified by education and experience in the area of engineering design and inspection, that:
<section prefix = "a">
To the best of the engineer's knowledge and belief, the proposed work does not violate any laws, rules or regulations of the State of Florida or any provisions of the Code of Miami-Dade County which may be applicable; that diligence and recognized standard practices of the engineering profession have been exercised in the engineer's design of the proposed work; and in the opinion of the engineer, based upon his knowledge and belief, the following will not occur:
<section prefix = "i">
Harmful obstruction or undesirable alteration of the natural flow of the water within the area of the proposed work.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Harmful or increased erosion, shoaling of channels or stagnant areas of water. (Not applicable to class IV permits.)
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Material injury to adjacent property.
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
Adverse environmental impacts from changes in water quality or quantity. (Applicable to class IV permits only.)
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The engineer has been retained by the applicant to provide inspections throughout the construction period and to prepare a set of reproducible record prints of drawings showing changes made during the construction process based upon the marked-up prints, certified surveys, drawings, and other data furnished by the contractor to the engineer. Work limited exclusively to the cutting or trimming of a mangrove tree(s) is exempt from the requirements of Section 24- 48.2(II)(B)(4)(a) and (b).
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Names and addresses from the most current County tax rolls of owners of all riparian or wetland property within three hundred (300) feet of the proposed work.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
A check in the amount of the required application fee payable to Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
If the proposed work is within an incorporated area, a substantiating letter or plan approval shall be submitted, as part of the permit application, from the applicable zoning authority of the incorporated area. If the proposed work is within an unincorporated area, a substantiating letter or plan approval from Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning shall be submitted as part of the permit application. Said substantiating letter shall state that the proposed usage of the property upon which the proposed work would occur does not violate any zoning law applicable to the area of the proposed work. Applicants for class I permits shall have the option of submitting the above described substantiating letter or plan approval from the applicable zoning authority after obtaining approval from the Board of County Commissioners but prior to permit issuance. Applications for class I or class IV permits by the State of Florida Department of Transportation and the Federal Government, the State of Florida Department of Environmental Protection or the South Florida Water Management District or a municipality or the County within its own jurisdiction shall not be required to submit the above described substantiating letter from the local zoning authority.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
For all proposed work involving the placement of clean fill within the Bird Drive Everglades Wetland Basin or the North Trail Basin, a maintenance plan shall be submitted which shall include:
<section prefix = "a">
A description of how the stormwater management system shall be maintained in a functional condition,
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Treatment and control techniques as well as a management schedule to ensure that all of the stormwater management areas will be maintained free from exotic plant species, and
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
A description of how the stormwater management system shall be kept free of solid waste.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
For all proposed work which involves the placement of more than four (4) inches of fill above the seasonal high water table in the area(s) of the subject property designated as the stormwater management area(s), a report prepared by an engineer licensed in the State of Florida shall be submitted. Said report shall demonstrate the consistency of the site plan with the goals and requirements of either the North Trail Basin Fill Encroachment and Water Management Criteria (for properties located within the North Trail Basin), or with the Bird Drive Everglades Basin Fill Encroachment and Water Management Criteria (for properties located within the Bird Drive Everglades Wetland Basin).
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
In addition, the following supplemental information may, at the discretion of the Department, be required to be submitted with a standard form permit application:
<section prefix = "a">
If, in the opinion of the Director, inadequate information has been provided to evaluate the proposed work, or adverse environmental impact may occur as a result of the proposed work, the Director, before making a recommendation as to the application, shall require the applicant to conduct a coastal engineering study or water quality study or biological study. Said studies shall be a part of the permit application.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
If requested by the Director, a coastal resources management line shall be determined for the property upon which work requiring a class I permit is proposed. Said line shall be determined according to scientifically recognized ecological techniques and said line shall be subject to approval by the Department. Said line shall identify those areas where detrital cycles contribute to the ecological productivity of coastal waters.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
A covenant running with the land in favor of Miami-Dade County executed by the owner(s) of the property. Said covenant shall be subject to the approval of the Board of County Commissioners and shall not be released or modified without the consent of the Board of County Commissioners. Said covenant shall restrict development or alteration of the property to a designated portion of the property and may include conditions for the environmental protection and environmental management of designated portions of the property.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
A comprehensive environmental impact statement, if required pursuant to Section 24-7(25).
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
The applicant, in his or her discretion, may provide evidence of public interest or public economic values relating to the proposed work.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
For all proposed work within the North Trail Basin or the Bird Drive Everglades Wetland Basin, a covenant running with the land in favor of Miami-Dade County, in a form approved by the Board of County Commissioners, shall be executed. Said covenant may only be released or modified by action of the Board of County Commissioners and shall provide for the protection and maintenance of the stormwater management area of the property.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Obtaining approval from the Board of County Commissioners:
<section prefix = "1">
The Director shall review the permit application for the proposed work and shall make a recommendation to the Board of County Commissioners of approval, denial, or approval subject to conditions, limitations or restrictions for the proposed work. The Director's recommendation shall be based upon the applicable evaluation factors set forth in Section 24-48.3 of this Code. The Board of County Commissioners or Community Zoning Appeals Board pursuant to Section 33-13 shall hold a public hearing concerning the proposed work. A notice of the time and place of said public hearing shall be published in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County a minimum of seven (7) days prior to the public hearing. Said notice shall include a brief description of the proposed work and the location of the proposed work. A courtesy notice containing substantially the same information set forth in said published notice shall be mailed to those parties whose names appear on the application as the owners of all riparian or wetland property within three hundred (300) feet of the proposed work. Failure to mail or receive said courtesy notice shall not affect any action or proceeding taken thereunder. The Board of County Commissioners or Community Zoning Appeals Board pursuant to Section 33-13 shall, after holding the public hearing, approve, deny, or approve subject to conditions, limitations or restrictions, the work proposed under the permit application based upon the applicable evaluation factors set forth in Section 24-48.3 of this Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
If the Board of County Commissioners or Community Zoning Appeals Board pursuant to Section 33-13 approves a permit application, the Department of Environmental Resources Management shall issue the permit subject to the conditions, limitations or restrictions required by the Community Zoning Appeals Boards or Board of County Commissioners. The Department of Environmental Resources Management, in its discretion, may require additional conditions, limitations and restrictions as part of the permit only if said additional conditions, limitations or restrictions are consistent with the action of the Board of County Commissioners or Community Zoning Appeals Board with respect to the permit.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
At the request of a permit applicant, a conclusive list of permit conditions, limitations, and restrictions, which may not be amended or modified by the Department of Environmental Resources Management except as provided in Section 24-48.2(II)(C)(3)(b), below, shall be prepared prior to the public hearing and shall be submitted to the Board of County Commissioners or Community Zoning Appeals Board pursuant to Section 33-13 as part of the Director's recommendation of approval, provided that the permit application includes the following:
<section prefix = "a">
All requirements set forth in Section 24-48.5(2)(a) and (b).
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A verified statement by the permit applicant that the proposed work shall commence within three (3) months of approval of said permit by the Board of County Commissioners or Community Zoning Appeals Board pursuant to Section 33-13 and that if the work does not commence within three (3) months of the date of approval of said permit by the Board of County Commissioners or Community Zoning Appeals Board, then the Department of Environmental Resources Management may, in its discretion, require additional conditions, restrictions, and limitations as to the permit other than those described in the aforesaid list. All such additional conditions, restrictions, and limitations shall be consistent with the action of the Board of County Commissioners or Community Zoning Appeals Board with respect to the permit.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48.3. Factors for evaluation of permit applications; incomplete permit applications</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
The Department shall base its recommendation for approval, denial or approval subject to conditions, limitations, or restrictions, and the Board of County Commissioners shall make its decision for approval, denial, or approval subject to conditions, limitations or restrictions, for any of the permits provided for under this article, upon the following evaluation factors, when applicable:
<section prefix = "a">
The potential adverse environmental impact and cumulative adverse environmental impact of the proposed work, including but not limited to the effect upon hydrology, water quality, water supply, wellfields, aquifer recharge, aesthetics, navigation, public health, historic values, air quality, marine and wildlife habitats, archeological values, wetland soils suitable for habitat, floral and faunal values, rare, threatened and endangered species, natural flood damage protection, wetland values, land use classification, recreation, and any other environmental values, affecting the public interest.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Conformance with standard construction procedures and practices and design and performance standards, including but not limited to, all applicable portions of the Miami-Dade County Public Works Manual, Chapter 33B of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and Miami-Dade County Ordinance No. 81-19 [codified as Sections 33D-1 through 33D-4], as all of same may be amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The information provided by the comprehensive environmental impact statement, if required.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Conformance with all applicable federal, state and local laws and regulations. Conformance with the Rules of the South Florida Water Management District set forth in Chapter 40E-40, Florida Administrative Code (F.A.C.), as same may be amended from time to time, pertaining to general surface water management permits within Miami-Dade County, and with the provisions contained in the "Basis of Review for Surface Water Management Permit Applications Within the South Florida Water Management District," dated September 11, 2008, as same may be amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Conformance with the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan, Chapter 33B of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, Miami-Dade County Ordinance No. 81-19 [codified as Sections 33D-1 through 33D-4], and the Miami-Dade County Manatee Protection Plan (a copy of which shall be made permanently available at the Department for reference by the public), as all of same may be amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Consistency with criteria for lake excavations in Miami-Dade County established by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
The recommendation to the Board of County Commissioners as to approval or denial from the municipality within which the proposed work is located.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
The relationship of the proposed work to a coastal resources management line established pursuant to the provisions of Section 24-48.2(II)(B)(10)(b).
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Preservation and protection of all existing wetland communities seaward of said management line.
<section prefix = "ii">
Protection of all existing wetland biological and hydrological functions landward of said management line.
<section prefix = "i">
Maximum protection of a wetland's hydrological and biological functions through adherence to the following fill limitations:
<section prefix = "i">
Placement of the minimum fill necessary on a site to provide for the land usage alternative which results in the least adverse environmental impact and the least cumulative adverse environmental impact.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Placement of temporary fill pads and fill roads for the purpose of conducting rockmining.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
For Class I permit applications proposing to exceed the boundaries described in Section D-5(03)(2)(a) of the Miami-Dade County Public Works Manual, the following additional factors shall be considered:
<section prefix = "i">
Whether the proposed exceedance is the minimum necessary, as determined by the Director or the Director's designee, to avoid seagrass or other valuable environmental resources,
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Whether the proposed exceedance is the minimum necessary, as determined by the Director or the Director's designee, to achieve adequate water depth for mooring of a vessel,
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Whether the applicant has provided to the Department notarized letter(s) of consent from adjoining riparian property owners in a form prescribed by the Director or the Director's designee, and
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
Whether the Department has received any letter of objection from adjoining riparian property owners.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
In addition to the applicable evaluation factors found in Section 24-48.3(1)(a) through (i) above, dredging or filling work proposed in class I permit applications shall comply with at least one (1) of the following criteria:
<section prefix = "a">
Minimum dredging and spoiling for public navigation or public necessity.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
An alteration of physical conditions as may be necessary to enhance the quality or utility of adjacent waters.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Minimum dredging and filling for the creation and maintenance of marinas, piers, docks and attendant navigational channels.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Minimum dredging and filling as is necessary for the elimination of conditions hazardous to the public health or for the elimination of stagnant waters.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Minimum dredging and filling as is necessary to enhance the biological, chemical or physical characteristics of adjacent waters.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
A physical modification necessary to protect public or private property.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
In addition to the applicable evaluation factors found in Section 24-48.3(1)(a) through (i) above, boat slips created by the construction or placement of fixed or floating docks, piers, piles and other structures requiring a permit under this article and located in tidal waters within the geographical boundaries of Miami-Dade County, Florida shall have a minimum water depth of four feet N.O.A.A. mean low water datum. It shall be unlawful to moor or store vessels at fixed and floating docks, piers, piles and any structure requiring a permit under this article in tidal waters within the geographical boundaries of Miami-Dade County in areas with less than four feet of depth N.O.A.A. mean low water datum except for those existing structures which were constructed or placed in accordance with all of the requirements of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida prior to October 11, 1985. The foregoing requirements in this subsection (3) shall not apply to:
<section prefix = "a">
Fixed or floating docks or piers in tidal waters which are utilized exclusively for fishing, viewing Biscayne Bay, or swimming and which do not have one or more slips or mooring or fender piles present or proposed at or adjacent to the dock or pier, or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Fixed or floating docks or piers in tidal waters which are utilized exclusively for launching canoes or kayaks, or
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Construction or placement of davits in tidal waters, provided that the davits are attached to seawalls or bulkheads, or
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Fixed or floating docks, piers or boat slips in tidal waters created by work requiring a permit under this Article if located in artificially created canals, provided the canal is bulkheaded and bordered by uplands on both sides of the canal, or
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Floating vessel platforms and floating boat lifts in tidal waters which qualify for the exemption contained within Section 403.813(2)(s), Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Installation of boat lifts, davits and mooring piles, in slips at existing permitted docks and piers.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Repair or reconstruction of existing legal docks provided there is a minimum water depth of three feet N.O.A.A. mean low water datum.
Additionally, no permit shall be issued for a proposed slip or for any other proposed work requiring a permit under this Article which is to be used for the mooring or securing of a vessel, unless adequate water depth exists, including when the vessel is fully loaded.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
In addition to the applicable evaluation factors found in Section 24-48.3(1)(a) through (i) above, any filling in the wetlands of Miami-Dade County shall comply with the following criteria: All fill shall consist only of clean fill.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
In addition to the applicable evaluation factors set forth in Section 24-48.3(1)(a) through (i) above and the fill quality requirements set forth in Section 24-48.3(4) above, the following requirements shall apply to any work within the North Trail Basin or within the Bird Drive Everglades Wetland Basin:
<section prefix = "a">
Except as provided in (e) below, the work shall be consistent with the North Trail Basin Plan (if it is located within the North Trail Basin), or shall be consistent with the Bird Drive Everglades Wetland Basin Plan (if it is located within the Bird Drive Everglades Basin). These plans are included in Sections 24-48.19 and 24-48.20 respectively.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
All tree islands shall be preserved.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All proposed work which involves filling (a) stormwater management area(s) shall be constructed as specified in the North Trail Basin Fill Encroachment and Water Management Criteria for properties located within the North Trail Basin, or as specified in the Bird Drive Everglades Basin Fill Encroachment and Water Management Criteria, for properties located within the Bird Drive Everglades Wetland Basin.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Stormwater management areas which are less than five (5) acres in size and are located within the Urban Development Boundary as it appears on the Comprehensive Development Master Plan's Land Use Map (as same is amended from time to time) shall not be left at natural grade (unfilled).
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The side slopes of the stormwater management area(s) shall be no steeper than four (4) horizontal to one (1) vertical (4:1).
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
In addition to the applicable evaluation factors set forth in Section 24-48.3(1)(a) through (i) above and the fill quality requirement set forth in Section 24-48.3(4) above, for projects located within Basin B, the total volume of fill material placed on a property between existing land elevation and elevation 7.58 NGVD shall not exceed the following formula: Area of site in square feet × 1.8. As an alternative to the foregoing formula other engineering approaches consistent with the requirements of full on-site retention without exceeding established stages for the 100-year, three-day storm shall be approved by the Director of the Department of Environmental Resources Management or the Director's designee.
<section prefix = "a">
The side slope of stormwater management area(s) shall be no steeper than four (4) horizontal to one (1) vertical (4:1).
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
In addition to the applicable evaluation factors contained within Section 24-48.3(1)(a) through (i) above, the following requirements shall apply to all work requiring a Class II Permit:
<section prefix = "a">
Wet retention shall not be utilized without prior pretreatment by means of dry detention or retention of the first inch of runoff from the proposed project's drainage area.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
An on-site retention system of applicable design shall be utilized as the first priority for the disposal of stormwater runoff at any location in Miami-Dade County with the exception of projects located in the North Trail Basin, Bird Drive Basin, East Turnpike Basin, Western C-9 Basin or any other area subject to Miami-Dade County's cut and fill criteria.
The on-site retention systems required by this section shall include the following:
<section prefix = "i">
Surface infiltration through grassed swales, or
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Underground disposal through exfiltration, or
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Disposal by drainage wells, or
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
Disposal through dry retention ponds, or
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
Surface storage in on-site wetlands following pretreatment, or
</section>
<section prefix = "vi">
Any combination of any of the foregoing as approved by the Director or the Director's designee.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
On-site retention combined with an overflow outfall may be used as an alternative to on-site retention in those cases where complete on-site retention is not feasible as determined by the Director or the Director's designee, when there is inadequate exfiltration capability of the soil or in cases where a higher degree of flood protection is desired by the applicant.
All inlet structures located within grassed areas or landscaped strips may receive a 0.2 inch retention credit.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Existing positive drainage systems which for any reason require modification or relocation shall be constructed in accordance with the standards set forth in Section 24-48.3(7)(a) and (b) above, except for those portions of the existing project which will remain unaltered under the new plan.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
In addition to the applicable evaluation factors contained within Section 24-48.3(1)(a) through (i) above, the following requirements shall apply to all work requiring a class VI permit:
<section prefix = "a">
Drainage systems shall be designed and built to comply with the following standards:
<section prefix = "i">
All requirements set forth in Section 24-48.3(7).
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
All inlet structures located within grassed areas or landscaping strips may receive a 0.2 inch retention credit. Furthermore, at least one (1) inch of pretreatment by means of dry detention or retention shall be provided as part of the required retention or detention prior to authorization of an overflow outfall.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Existing positive drainage systems which for any reason require modification or relocation shall be installed in a manner to comply with the standards set forth in Section 24-48.3(8)(a)(i) and (ii) above, except for those portions of the existing project which will remain unaltered under the new plan.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
An incomplete permit application shall become deactivated thirty-six (36) months from the date the permit application was filed. Permit applications are deemed filed with the Department on the date the application is stamped received by the Department.
<section prefix = "a">
A new application shall be required for obtaining a permit for all work previously proposed under a permit application which has been deactivated.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Department shall not process any permit application which has been deactivated.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08; Ord. No. 12-58, § 5, 7-3-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48.4. Mitigation plans for projects otherwise acceptable but having adverse environmental impact</catch_line>
<text>
For any project that is otherwise acceptable under the evaluation factors contained herein and permittable under all applicable laws, but that nevertheless results in adverse environmental impact, the applicant shall be required to mitigate this impact. The purpose of mitigation is solely to compensate for unavoidable adverse environmental impacts. Mitigation should not be used to make an otherwise nonpermittable project permittable. Mitigation plans must maximize the preservation of existing natural resources. In determining mitigation procedures the term mitigation includes the following methods, in the order of priority in which they should be utilized:
<section prefix = "1">
Avoiding the impact altogether by not taking a certain action or parts of an action;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Minimizing impacts by limiting the degree or magnitude of the action or its implementation;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Rectifying the impact by repairing, rehabilitating, or restoring the affected environment;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Reducing or eliminating the impact over time by preservation and maintenance operations during the life of the action;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Compensating for the impact by replacing or providing substitute resources or environments.

The Department of Environmental Resources Management shall adopt rules by ordinance to implement the foregoing evaluation factors.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48.5. Permit issuance; waiver of bonding requirements</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Issuance of a Department permit does not relieve the applicant from obtaining all required federal, State and local permits.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Following approval of a standard form permit application by the Board of County Commissioners or after submitting a short form application, a construction permit may be issued to the permit applicant and a contractor holding an applicable certificate of competency, provided:
<section prefix = "a">
Construction plans, calculations and specifications are submitted which have been prepared by an engineer or architect or land surveyor where applicable licensed in the State of Florida and which comply with the requirements of this Chapter and other particular conditions, including, but not limited to, requirements for riprap, and monitoring programs.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The permit fee has been paid.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
A performance bond and a mitigation bond, if applicable, is posted in an amount determined by the Director or the Director's designee. The maximum amount of said performance bond shall be one hundred (100) percent of the estimated cost of the work or one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00) whichever is less. In the event the Director or the Director's designee determines that a performance bond is necessary, the performance bond shall seek to ensure compliance with terms of the permit and to protect the interest of the public and of landowners in the vicinity of the work. The Director or Director's designee may waive the performance bond if the Director or Director's designee determines that the proposed project is not expected to affect the interests of the public or landowners in the vicinity of the work and noncompliance with the terms of the permit will only affect the permit applicant. The Director or Director's designee may also waive performance bonds for work performed by utility companies, for work performed by governmental agencies pursuant to Section 24-48.8 of this chapter and for work approved under a short form permit application pursuant to Section 24-48.2(I)(A)(22) and (23).
A separate mitigation bond may be required by the Director or the Director's designee to be posted in order to insure that environmental enhancement features associated with the project and required by the permit are completed in a satisfactory manner. These include, but are not limited to, the placement of riprap, the replanting of mangroves or seagrass, the installation of sewage pumpout stations, the construction of public piers or shoreline walkways and the construction of artificial reefs. The maximum amount of said mitigation bond shall be one hundred (100) percent of the cost of the environmental enhancement features of the project. The required performance and mitigation bonds may be required to remain in force for up to six (6) months after the approved completion date of the work covered by the bond.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Evidence of ownership, a lease, or a consent of use is submitted or evidence of an easement is submitted by the applicant for the submerged lands upon which the proposed work in tidal waters will occur under a class I permit. For proposed work on submerged lands owned by a federal, state, county, municipal, or other governmental entity, evidence of ownership or a lease of the upland and a.) the written consent of the federal, state, county, municipal, or other government entity owning the submerged lands upon which the work is proposed or, b.) lease from the federal, state, county, municipal, or other governmental entity owning the submerged lands upon which the work is proposed, shall be required. Written consent shall be in a form prescribed by the Director or the Director's designee.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Department may require inspections by a licensed engineer as part of the permit procedure. The engineer may be required to furnish a report to the Department a minimum of every three (3) months on the progress of the work and will produce appropriate drawings of record or other type of documentation as required by the Director or the Director's designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
If the engineer who provided certification pursuant to Section 24-48.2(I)(B)(2) or pursuant to Section 24-48.2(II)(B)(4) is discharged by the applicant, or if said engineer ceases to work on the proposed or approved work, the applicant shall be required to obtain a new engineer who shall meet all the requirements of an engineer required by this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
If the engineer who provided certification pursuant to Section 24-48.2(I)(B)(2) or pursuant to Section 24-48.2(II)(B)(4) is discharged by the applicant, or if said engineer ceases to work on work allowed under a permit, all work allowed by the permit shall immediately cease and shall not be resumed until a new engineer is obtained pursuant to the requirements of this article.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 07-175, § 2, 12-4-07; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08; Ord. No. 12-58, § 5, 7-3-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48.6. Owner-builder permits in lieu of owner-contractor permits</catch_line>
<text>
At the discretion of the Director or the Director's designee, owner-builder permits may be issued for the following types of work requiring a class I permit, and thereby waive the requirement that the permit be issued jointly to the owner and a contractor holding an applicable certificate of competency:
<section prefix = "1">
Repair of seawalls: Repair of seawalls or bulkheads at the mean high water line or at their existing location (excluding pile-driving operations and/or panel installations).
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Placement of riprap: The placement of riprap in front of an existing or new seawall, bulkhead or shoreline, provided there is no adverse environmental impact associated with the project.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Where the upland property is zoned as single-family residential:
<section prefix = "a">
Repair, replacement or restoration of docks which are limited to or less than their original dimensions and which together with associated tie-up facilities, do not protrude into the water more than twenty-five (25) percent of the width of the waterway (excluding pile-driving operations and any associated dredging and filling).
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Installation of buoys, when it is determined that the proposed installation will not present a hazard to navigation.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Other work that is nonstructural in nature.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48.7. Permit fees—Schedule</catch_line>
<text>
The Department shall charge and collect application and permit fees at the rate established by separate administrative order which shall not become effective until approved by the Board of County Commissioners.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48.8. Same—Waiver</catch_line>
<text>
The Department may waive the permit fee for all work covered under this article and performed by a federal, State, municipal or other local governmental agency, whether this work is performed by employees of said agency or by a private firm or corporation under contract with the agency. However, such federal, State, municipal or other local governmental agency or private firm or corporation under contract therewith shall not be relieved of the responsibility of obtaining a permit for work covered under the provisions of this article. The Director of said Department also may waive all requirements concerning posting of a performance bond by any governmental agency whenever the work is to be performed by employees of said agency, provided that, in lieu of the posting of a performance bond, said agency shall furnish said Department satisfactory written assurances that the work performed by its employees will comply fully with all requirements of the permit; and provided, further, that the Director of said Department may waive the posting of a performance bond by any private firm or corporation under contract with any governmental agency when said firm or corporation shall have posted a satisfactory and acceptable bond with the said governmental agency, proof of such bond having been furnished by said agency to the Department.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48.9. Time of completion of work; extension of completion time and new permits for incomplete work</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
All work authorized by a permit issued pursuant to this article shall be completed within the time periods set forth in the permit in accordance with the following schedule, unless another period of time is permitted as set forth in the resolution granting approval of the permit by the Board of County Commissioners:
Class I short form permits .....2 years
Class I short form permits for which a public hearing has been requested pursuant to Section 24-48.2(I)(B)(1) .....2 years
Class I standard form permits .....3 years
Class IV short form and standard form permits, including permits for which a public hearing has been requested pursuant to Section 24-48.2(I)(B)(1) .....5 years
Class I short form permits for trimming, cutting or any other alteration of mangrove tree(s) .....3 years
Class I short form permits for trimming, cutting or any other alteration of mangrove tree(s), for which a public hearing has been requested pursuant to Section 24-48.2(I)(B)(1) .....3 years
Class I standard form permits for trimming, cutting or any other alteration of mangrove tree(s) .....3 years
Class IV short form permits for rockmining .....10 years
Class IV short form permits for rockmining for which a public hearing has been requested pursuant to Section 24-48.2(I)(B)(1) .....10 years
Class IV standard form permits for rockmining .....10 years
Class II permits .....2 years
Class II permits for which a public hearing has been requested pursuant to Section 24-48.2(I)(B)(1) .....3 years
Class III permits .....2 years
Class III permits for which a public hearing has been requested pursuant to Section 24-48.2(I)(B)(1) .....3 years
Class V permits .....120 days
Class VI permits .....2 years
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Extensions of time for completion of work being performed pursuant to a permit issued pursuant to this article may be granted by the Director or the Director's designee provided that:
<section prefix = "a">
The application for the extension of time is in a form prescribed by the Director of the Department of Environmental Resources Management and is accompanied by the fee for such application.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The application for the extension of time is filed in the form prescribed by the Director or the Director's designee with the Director or the Director's designee at least thirty (30) calendar days prior to the time of expiration of the time period set forth in the permit or in a prior extension of time. For Class V permits the application for the extension of time is filed in the form prescribed by the Director or the Director's designee with the Director or the Director's designee at least seven (7) calendar days prior to the time of expiration of the time period set forth in the permit or in a prior extension of time.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Director or the Director's designee has determined that the applicant for the extension of time has affirmatively established by competent factual data and information in the application that:
<section prefix = "i">
There have been no substantial changes in the environment at the location of the work authorized by the permit occurring subsequent to the date of issuance of the permit or prior extension of time.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Neither an adverse environmental impact nor cumulative adverse environmental impact will occur if the extension of time is granted.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
The work authorized by the permit as well as authorized under any prior extension of time has been performed, to date, substantially in accordance with the permit and any restrictions, limitations or conditions which are part of the permit.
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
The applicant for the extension of time has agreed to any additional conditions, limitations or restrictions to the issued permit required by the Director or the Director's designee which are consistent with the approval of the Board of County Commissioners or, in the case of short form permits, consistent with the original approval of the issued short form permit by the Director or the Director's designee. In the case of rock mining, such conditions, limitations, or restrictions shall not reduce the deep mining area and volume previously permitted.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The requested time period for the extension of time when combined with all time periods previously approved for performance of authorized work pursuant to the original permit and prior extensions of time shall not exceed a total of twenty-five (25) years duration for rock mining and ten (10) years duration for all other work, unless another period of time is permitted as set forth in the resolution granting approval of the permit by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Applications for extensions of time which are not timely filed pursuant to Section 24-48.9(2)(b) hereinabove shall be returned to the applicant. The applicant shall be required to file an application for a new permit pursuant to the provisions of this article to obtain the authorization to complete the previously authorized incomplete work. The fee for the new permit shall be based upon the nature and amount of the incomplete work.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08; Ord. No. 12-58, § 5, 7-3-12; Ord. No. 13-27, § 3, 4-2-13)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48.10. Maintenance of permitted work; abatement of hazardous conditions</catch_line>
<text>
Any privately owned work or structure authorized by a permit issued pursuant to the requirements of this article shall be privately maintained by the applicant, his successors and assigns. Whenever, in the opinion of the Director, said work or structures are not maintained in such a manner as to prevent deterioration to the extent that they become a hazard to the public or to navigation, [or] an obstruction of flow, or prevent access for drainage maintenance purposes, or may damage adjacent property, then the Director shall notify the owner in writing to remedy the same by alteration, adjustment or removal at the owner's expense; provided, however, that within fifteen (15) days after receipt of written notice from the Director, the owner may appeal the matter by requesting in writing a hearing before the Environmental Quality Control Board. If no appeal is taken to the Environmental Quality Control Board and the owner has not performed remedial work within thirty (30) days from the date of such notice, or if an appeal is taken and the Board, after hearing and notice thereof, shall determine that remedial work is necessary and the owner does not perform the remedial work within the time established by the Board for the performance, the Director shall have the same or any other remedial work that in the Director's opinion will alleviate or eliminate the situation, including, but not limited to, total demolition of the structure, performed at the County's expense; and the County shall have a lien prior in dignity to all other liens, excepting city and County taxes and liens of equal dignity therewith, on the real property of the owner to the extent of the cost to the County, including administrative cost for the remedial work. Notice of such lien, executed in the name of the County Commission, shall be recorded in the proper books kept by the Clerk of the Circuit Court of the County and shall remain in full force and effect for a period of twenty (20) years from the date thereof, unless sooner paid and satisfied; and the Director shall, in writing, advise the County Attorney at least one (1) year prior to the expiration of the twenty-year period of any such liens that have not been satisfied, in order that the same may be foreclosed if necessary.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48.11. Inspection of permit work; notice of failure to comply with approved plans and specifications</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Any duly authorized representative of the Department may enter and inspect any property, premises or place, except a building, on or at which work is located or is being conducted, at any reasonable time for the purpose of ascertaining the state of compliance with this article, or rules and regulations of the Department. No person shall refuse immediate entry or access to any authorized representative of the Department who requests such entry or access for the purpose of inspection, and who presents appropriate credentials; nor shall any person obstruct, hamper or interfere with any such inspection. If requested, the owner of the premises shall receive a report setting forth all facts found which relate to compliance status.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
During work for which a permit has been issued, the Department shall make periodic inspections to insure conformity with the approved plans and specifications referred to in Section 24-48.5 of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
If during the work, the Department finds that the work is not being done in accordance with the said approved plans and specifications, it shall give the permittee and/or contractor and the engineer of record written notice, stating with which particulars of the approved plans and specifications the work is not in compliance. Failure to act in accordance with the requirements of the Department after receipt of written notice may result in the initiation of revocation proceedings in accordance with Section 24-48.13 of this article.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48.12. Filing of statement of completion of permitted work; exemptions; release of bonds; forfeiture of bonds</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Within thirty (30) days after completion of the work, the permittee or contractor shall file record drawings or as-built drawings certified by the engineer of record with the Department. Work exempt from submitting plans prepared by an engineer and an architect under this article shall also be exempt from the requirements of this provision. Work which has been determined by the Department, during its final inspection of the project, to be in compliance with the approved plans for the project with no significant deviation, as determined by the Director or the Director's designee, may be exempted by the Director or the Director's designee from the filing of record drawings or as-built drawings as required above. The Florida Departments of Transportation and Environmental Protection are exempt from the requirement to submit record drawings or as-built drawings for projects authorized by class I, class II, class III, class IV, class V, or class VI permits.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
At the discretion of the Director or the Director's designee the performance and mitigation bonds may be released upon completion of the final inspection by the Department and the submittal of the record drawings or as-built drawings, if required, or for a period up to six (6) months after the approved completion date of the work covered by the bond.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
If the Director or the Director's designee determines that work authorized by a class I, class II, class III, class IV, class V or class VI permit has not been performed in accordance with the approved plans upon which the permit was issued or has not complied with all of the conditions or special conditions of the permit, the Director or the Director's designee shall notify the permittee of such noncompliance and specify a period of time in which the permittee shall correct or otherwise bring the project into compliance with the permit. In the event that the permittee fails or is unable to comply with the requirements of the notice, the Director or the Director's designee may, in addition to available enforcement remedies, call the performance or mitigation bonds for the project. Funds from the forfeiture of mitigation bonds with respect to class I, class II, or class VI permits, shall be deposited into the Biscayne Bay Environmental Enhancement Trust Fund for use in the general restoration and enhancement of Biscayne Bay. Monies received from the forfeiture of mitigation bonds with respect to class IV permits shall be deposited into the Wetlands Trust Fund pursuant to Section 24-37
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08; Ord. No. 12-58, § 5, 7-3-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48.13. Suspension, revocation, modification, change of permit; notice</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
If the Director or the Director's designee determines that the permittee or contractor is not performing the work in accordance with the provisions of the permit or the approved plans upon which the permit was issued, the Director or Director's designee may order suspension of the permit or the stopping of work until such time as the permittee or contractor has complied with the permit or plans. In such cases, the permittee or contractor shall take all necessary precautions to leave the work area in a safe and secure condition.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Modification(s) to a permit issued for work hereunder and any associated covenant running with the land shall be approved by the Department. If, in the opinion of the Director, the proposed modification(s) will result in a substantial change to the project, said modification(s) shall be subject to a public hearing before the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
A violation of the conditions, restrictions or limitations imposed by the Board of County Commissioners or the Department and made part of the permit, or authorization, or failure of the permittee or contractor to perform said work in accordance with the approved plans and specifications thereof, or any material false statement in the application may result in the revocation in whole or in part of a permit issued for work hereunder.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08; Ord. No. 12-58, § 5, 7-3-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48.14. Judicial review of decisions concerning permits</catch_line>
<text>
Any person aggrieved by any decision of the Board of County Commissioners with regard to the granting, denial, granting with limitations, restrictions or conditions, or the revocation or modification of any permit in this article may seek judicial review in accordance with the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48.15. Comprehensive environmental impact statement</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Procedure.
<section prefix = "a">
The Director shall determine which of the comprehensive environmental impact statement assessment points described in Section 24-5 shall be addressed by a particular comprehensive environmental impact statement. The Director's decision shall be based upon a preapplication conference held between a permit applicant and the Department and based upon any other relevant information submitted by the applicant or available to the Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The criteria to be used at a preapplication conference for determining the scope of a comprehensive environmental impact statement shall include the following:
<section prefix = "i">
The relevance of the proposed work to each of the items described in Section 24-48.3(1)(a). Relevance shall be based upon both direct and indirect factors such as but not limited to location of the proposed work, proximity of the work to environmentally sensitive areas, past experience with similar work, and scope and magnitude of the proposed work.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
The extent to which each of the comprehensive environmental impact statement assessment points may provide useful information and data relating to each of the items for which the proposed work is determined to be relevant.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The format for a comprehensive environmental impact statement shall follow guidelines established by the Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
A comprehensive environmental impact statement shall not be required for any of the following work:
<section prefix = "a">
Construction of one (1) single-family residence consistent with existing zoning regulations.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Access driveway to a single-family residence within a lot zoned for one (1) single-family residence.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Agriculture on five (5) acres of land or less, ancillary to an existing single-family residence, or ancillary to a single-family residence under construction, as allowed under Miami-Dade County zoning regulations.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Rockplowing or other agricultural development in the East Everglades area of critical environmental concern when said agriculture is allowable under Chapter 33B of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and is consistent with the best management practices under Chapter 33B of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Rockmining within the transitional Northeast Everglades when said rockmining is consistent with Miami-Dade County lake criteria.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Elevated boardwalks.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Class I short form permit applications.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The Director may, in the Director's discretion, exempt an applicant from the requirement of preparing a new comprehensive environmental impact statement for a permit application for proposed work which work has been previously the subject of a deactivated application by the same applicant.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08; Ord. No. 12-58, § 5, 7-3-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48.16. Prohibition of top pruning of mangrove trees</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful for any person to top prune or authorize, allow, suffer or permit the top pruning of mangrove trees in a coastal band community, except for specified trimming activities exempt from permitting requirements pursuant to Section 403.9326, Florida Statutes, as may be amended from time to time. No class I permit shall be approved or issued for the top pruning of coastal band mangrove trees except for that top pruning which is necessary for the protection of overhead power lines.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48.17. Registration, examination, and certification requirements for professional mangrove trimmers</catch_line>
<text>
Pursuant to the authority granted by Section 403.9326, Florida Statutes, and except for work that is not required to be performed by a Professional Mangrove Trimmer pursuant to Section 403.9326, Florida Statutes, it shall be unlawful for any person to perform mangrove trimming or to authorize, allow, suffer, permit, or supervise mangrove trimming anywhere in Miami-Dade County without first having registered with the Department and having paid the registration fee authorized by Section 403.9329, Florida Statutes, in an amount established by administrative order of the County Manager and approved by the Board of County Commissioners. Prior to undertaking to perform any trimming activities authorized under the exemption provided by Sections 403.9326(1)(b) and 403.9326(1)(c), Florida Statutes, a registered professional mangrove trimmer shall:
<section prefix = "1">
Provide written notice to the Department a minimum of ten (10) days prior to the commencement of trimming activities on each property. The notice shall include the location, the property owner's name, principal address and phone number, and the date of the proposed commencement of work. Notice shall be required prior to each separate trimming event; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Personally supervise the trimming activity; and thereafter notify the Department within twenty-four (24) hours if any mangroves are "altered" (as defined in Section 403.9325(1), F.S.) as a result of the work. The professional mangrove trimmer's registration shall be valid for a period of one (1) year and may be renewed by the Department prior to its expiration upon prior payment of the registration renewal fee in an amount established by administrative order of the County Manager and approved by the Board of County Commissioners.

Upon the effective date of the ordinance from which this section derives, all applicants for certification as professional mangrove trimmers shall be required to have passed an examination designed to test the applicant's knowledge and ability in this field. The Department shall offer a written, oral or practical examination, or a combination of the aforesaid. The fee for examination and certification shall be in an amount established by administrative order of the County Manager and approved by the Board of County Commissioners. A person who has paid the required fee and obtained certification shall be exempt from the registration requirements and fees described in Section 24-48.17 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, for the time period the certification is valid.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48.18. Transfer of permits</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
The Director, or the Director's designee, is hereby authorized and empowered to transfer, in whole or in part, short form and standard form class I, class II, class III, class IV, class V or class VI permits issued pursuant to this Article from the person (transferor) who has obtained the issued permit to another person (transferee) and shall transfer same, provided:
<section prefix = "a">
The completed application for transfer is filed in writing with the Director, or the Director's designee, on or before one hundred and twenty (120) days after the date of transfer of fee simple ownership of the property which is the subject of the permit, and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The application for transfer is determined by the Director, or the Director's designee, to be completed on or before one hundred and twenty (120) days after the date of transfer of fee simple ownership of the property which is the subject of the permit approval, and
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
That all of the requirements of (3) below are fulfilled.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Director, or the Director's designee, is hereby authorized and empowered to transfer, in whole or in part, short form and class I, class II, class III, class IV, class V or class VI permit approvals by the Board of County Commissioners from the person (transferor) who obtained the permit approval from the Board of County Commissioners to another person (transferee) and shall transfer same, provided:
<section prefix = "a">
The completed application for transfer is filed in writing with the Director, or the Director's designee, on or before one hundred and twenty (120) days after the date of transfer of fee simple ownership of the property which is the subject of the permit approval, and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The application for transfer is determined by the Director, or the Director's designee to be completed on or before one hundred and twenty (120) days after the date of transfer of fee simple ownership of the property which is the subject of the permit approval, and
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All of the requirements of (3) below are fulfilled.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Requirements for transfer:
<section prefix = "a">
The subject project shall be in compliance with all of the restrictions, limitations, and conditions of the issued Class I, Class II, Class III, Class IV, Class V or Class VI permit or permit approval and any related covenants running with the land at the time of submittal of the application for transfer, and continuously throughout the time period during which the application for transfer is being processed by the Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The completed application for transfer shall be filed jointly in writing by the proposed transferor and transferee in a form prescribed by the Director, or the Director's designee, not later than ninety (90) days prior to the expiration date of the issued permit and, for permit approvals granted by the Board of County Commissioners for which a permit has not yet been issued, not later than ninety (90) days prior to expiration of the permit approval.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
If the person to whom the permit has been issued or permit approval granted transfers fee simple ownership of the property which is the subject of the permit or permit approval prior to submittal to the Department of the application for transfer, the proposed transferee shall be the current fee simple property owner and evidence of such fee simple property ownership shall be provided to the Department as part of the application for transfer.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The proposed transferee shall agree in writing, in a form prescribed by the Director or the Director's designee, to comply with all the existing conditions, limitations, and restrictions of the issued permit or granted permit approval as part of the application for transfer.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The proposed transferee shall post a performance and mitigation bond, if applicable, in the same amount and form as is currently required in the existing permit for the subject project as part of the application for transfer.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
All applicable fees for such transfer shall be paid as part of the application for transfer.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
All additional information requested by the Director or the Director's designee with respect to the subject property shall be provided to the Department as part of the application for transfer within the time period required by the Director or the Director's designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
The proposed transferee shall agree to any additional conditions, limitations or restrictions to the issued permit required by the Director or the Director's designee, which are consistent with the issued short form or issued standard form permit and, for permit approvals granted by the Board of County Commissioners, any additional conditions, limitations or restrictions which are consistent with the original granting of the approval by the Board of County Commissioners, as part of the application for transfer. In the case of rockmining, such conditions, limitations, or restrictions shall not reduce the deep mining area and volume previously permitted.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
The proposed transferee has not been convicted of a violation of any provision of Chapter 24 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida within the seven (7) year time period prior to the filing of the application for transfer.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
The proposed transferee has not been adjudicated in violation of any provision of Chapter 24 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, within the five-year time period prior to the filing of the application for transfer.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
The proposed transferee shall provide evidence of compliance with all of the following provisions of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida as part of the application for transfer:
<section prefix = "i">
Section 24-48.2(I)(B)(1)
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Section 24-48.2(I)(B)(2)
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Section 24-48.2(II)(B)(2)
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
Section 24-48.2(II)(B)(3)
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
Section 24-48.2(II)(B)(4)
</section>
<section prefix = "vi">
Section 24-48.2(II)(B)(7)
</section>
<section prefix = "vii">
Section 24-48.2(II)(B)(8)
</section>
<section prefix = "viii">
Section 24-48.2(II)(B)(9)
</section>
<section prefix = "ix">
Section 24-48.5(a)
</section>
<section prefix = "x">
Section 24-48.5(b)
</section>
<section prefix = "xi">
Section 24-48.5(c)
</section>
<section prefix = "xii">
Section 24-48.5(d)
</section>
<section prefix = "xiii">
Section 24-48.5(e)
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The Department is hereby prohibited from processing any application for transfer of a permit or permit approval which is:
<section prefix = "a">
Incomplete, or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Not timely filed, or
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Not timely completed in accordance with the provisions of Sections 24-48.18 (1), (2) and (3).
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The Department is hereby prohibited from approving any application for transfer of a permit or permit approval which does not fulfill each and every requirement set forth in this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
No later than sixty (60) days after the approval by the Director, or the Director's designee, of the date of transfer of a class I, class II, class III, class IV, class V, or class VI permit or permit approval, the transferee shall provide to the Department the same evidence of fee simple ownership of the property by the transferee required pursuant to the provisions of Section 24-48.2(I)(B)(1)(c) or Section 24-48.2(II)(B)(1) of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida if such evidence of fee simple ownership of the property by the transferee has not already been provided to the Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
A mortgagee or lien-holder who obtains fee simple ownership and possession of real property through foreclosure or settlement of an action for foreclosure shall be eligible to be a transferee after acquisition of the fee simple ownership of the property, subject to the fulfillment of all the requirements in (3) above, provided a complete application for transfer is filed in writing with the Department not later than one hundred and twenty (120) days after the mortgagee or lien-holder obtains the fee simple ownership of the property and not later than ninety (90) days prior to the expiration date of the issued permit or granted permit approval. The signature of the prior property owner shall not be required on the application for transfer.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
All transfers of class I, class II, class III, class IV, class V, and class VI issued permits and granted permit approvals by the Board of County Commissioners which have been processed by the Department prior to the effective date of Ordinance No. 90-130 are hereby approved, confirmed, and made effective retroactive to the dates of such transfers.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
It shall be unlawful for any person to perform work, or authorize, allow, suffer or permit work to be performed requiring a Class I, Class II, Class III, Class IV, Class V, or Class VI permit after a fee simple transfer of a property unless the Department has approved an application for transfer of the issued permit authorizing the current fee simple property owner to perform the work.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
The Environmental Quality Control Board shall not have any jurisdiction pursuant to Section 24-11, Section 24-8 or Section 24-12 of the Code of Miami-Dade County with respect to any of the provisions of this section contained herein.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08; Ord. No. 12-58, § 5, 7-3-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48.19. Permit issuance</catch_line>
<text>
Approvals of class I, class II, class III, class IV, class V and class VI permits by the Board of County Commissioners shall only be valid for a period of thirty (30) months, in the case of rockmining, or for a period of eighteen (18) months, for all other work, from the date of the approval unless another time period is stated in the resolution granting approval. If the applicant has not obtained a permit issued by the Department within thirty (30) months, in the case of rockmining, or within eighteen (18) months, for all other work, from the date of the approval by the Board of County Commissioners or within the time period stated in the resolution granting approval, then a new application for a permit shall be filed. Upon the timely application of any person, other than the person seeking the permit, filed in a court of competent jurisdiction which seeks judicial review in accordance with Section 24-48.14 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, of a decision granting or granting with limitations, restrictions or conditions of any permit in this article, the time periods hereinabove shall be tolled until disposition of the judicial review. All approvals of class I, class II, class III and class IV permits by the Board of County Commissioners prior to December 7, 1990 for which the applicant has not obtained a permit issued by the Department within twelve (12) months from the effective date of this ordinance shall be null and void and no permit shall be issued by the Department.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48.20. North Trail Basin Plan</catch_line>
<text>
Except as provided in Section 24-48.3(5)(e), all work performed in the North Trail Basin shall be consistent with the North Trail Basin Plan, which is hereby adopted by reference in its entirety. The Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners is directed to keep a copy of the North Trail Basin Plan on file as an attachment to this ordinance. All work in the North Trail Basin shall be consistent with the goals, guidelines, standards, and project design criteria set forth in the North Trail Basin Plan to ensure the maintenance of, or mitigation for the loss of, biological resources. All work in the North Trail Basin shall conform to the North Trail Basin cut and fill criteria which have been set forth in Department Technical Document 89-4 to ensure proper water management.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48.21. Bird Drive Everglades Wetland Basin Plan</catch_line>
<text>
Except as provided in Section 24-48.3(5)(e), all work performed in the Bird Drive Everglades Wetland Basin shall be consistent with the Bird Drive Everglades Basin Plan, which is hereby included by reference in its entirety. The Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners is directed to keep a copy of the Bird Drive Everglades Basin Plan on file as an attachment to this ordinance. All work in the Bird Drive Everglades Wetland Basin shall be consistent with the goals, guidelines, standards, and project design criteria set forth in the Bird Drive Everglades Basin Plan to ensure the maintenance of, or mitigation for the loss of, biological resources. Work in the Bird Drive Everglades Wetland Basin shall also conform with the Bird Drive Everglades Fill Encroachment and Water Management Criteria which have been set forth to ensure proper water management.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48.22. Biscayne Bay and environs designated aquatic park and conservation area</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
In recognition that is in the interest of the public welfare to protect and preserve unique, natural, aesthetic and recreational values, Biscayne Bay and its environs is hereby declared to be an "aquatic park and conservation area" for the use and benefit of the citizens of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The County Manager is hereby empowered to develop a plan for the protection and preservation of said "aquatic park and conservation area" including the initiation and coordination of appropriate research and analysis, the development of both short and long-range plans, and the promulgation of rules and regulations which, after ratification by the Board of County Commissioners and the appropriate agencies of the State of Florida and of the federal government, shall have the force and effect of law.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48.23. Prohibition of floating structures</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful for any person to construct, place, maintain, permit, let, allow, suffer or cause the construction, placement, maintenance or existence of any floating structure in, on, or upon any of the tidal waters of Miami-Dade County. This prohibition shall not apply to any floating structure placed, maintained or in existence in, on, or upon any of the tidal waters of Miami-Dade County on the effective date of Ordinance No. 84-56. This prohibition furthermore shall not apply to residential houseboats, floating boat docks, floating fishing docks, or other floating structures upon which only water dependent uses occur or exist. All floating structures which are not prohibited by this section, except residential houseboats, shall be required to obtain a class I permit.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48.24. Prohibition of non-water-dependent fixed structures</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful for any person to construct, place, install, maintain, permit, allow, suffer or cause the construction, placement, installation, maintenance or existence of any fixed structure in, on, over or upon any of the tidal waters of Miami-Dade County which does not have a water-dependent use. Fixed structures which do not have a water-dependent use include, but are not limited to, residences, offices, hotels, motels, restaurants, lounges, retail or wholesale stores, club houses, helicopter pads, meeting facilities, commercial signs, transmitting or receiving antennas and towers, or storage or parking facilities. This prohibition shall not apply to fixed structures that were fully permitted on the effective date of this section or to their repair providing permits are obtained.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-48.25. Procedure governing variances for prohibited floating structures and prohibited fixed structures</catch_line>
<text>
All applications for variances of floating structures and fixed structures prohibited by Sections 24-48.23 and 24-48.24 of this Code shall be heard and ruled upon by the Board of County Commissioners. Any person requesting said variance shall submit a standard form class I coastal construction application and application fee to the Department, which shall review said application and make a recommendation to the Board of County Commissioners for approval, denial or approval subject to conditions, limitations or restrictions for the proposed variance. The Board of County Commissioners shall hold a public hearing concerning the proposed variance. A notice of the time and place of said public hearing shall be published in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County a minimum of seven (7) days prior to the public hearing. Said notice shall include a brief description of the proposed work and the location of the proposed work. A courtesy notice containing substantially the same information set forth in said published notice shall be mailed to those parties whose names appear on the application as the owners of all riparian or wetland property within three hundred (300) feet of the proposed work. Failure to mail or receive said courtesy notice shall not affect any action or proceeding taken thereunder. The Director, when making the Director's recommendation to the Board of County Commissioners, and the Board of County Commissioners, when considering the variance request, may consider any or all of the following factors: Visual or physical access by the general public to Biscayne Bay and its adjacent tidal waters, historical significance, the need for covered vessel repair facilities, environmental impact or cumulative environmental impact, navigation, public safety, aesthetics, the provisions of Section 258.397 F.S., which established the Biscayne Bay Management Plan (Section 33D-1 through 33D-4), the Biscayne Bay Aquatic Preserve Act (Section 258.397 F.S.), the Rules of the Biscayne Bay Aquatic Preserve (Chapter 18-18 F.A.C.) as well as the evaluation factors contained within Section 24-48.3. The Board of County Commissioners shall, after holding the public hearing, approve, deny or approve subject to conditions, limitations or restrictions, the variance proposed under the application.
If the Board of County Commissioners approves a variance, the procedures concerning issuance of a permit contained within Section 24-48.5 shall be followed.
</text>
</law>
