<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="3">ARTICLE IV. PERSONNEL</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="4">DIVISION_5._DEFERRED_COMPENSATION_PROGRA</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-56.27.11. Established</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby established a Miami-Dade County Employees Deferred Compensation Program.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-56.27.12. County Manager to approve and administer plan</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager is hereby designated as the official to approve and administer a deferred compensation plan as required by state law.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-56.27.13. County Attorney to make certain determinations in accordance with Florida Statutes, Section 112.215(6)(b)</catch_line>
<text>
The County Attorney is hereby designated as the appropriate official to determine, in accordance with the requirements of Florida Statutes, Section 112.215(6)(b) (1976), whether the compensation deferred under any plan approved by the County Manager will not be included in the employee's taxable income under federal or state law until it is actually received by such employee under the terms of the plan, and that such compensation will nonetheless be deemed compensation at the time of the deferral for the purposes of social security, the retirement system of the County, or for any other retirement, pension or benefit program required by law.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-56.27.14. Plan to be in addition to any other retirement, pension or benefit systems</catch_line>
<text>
The deferred compensation plan authorized hereunder and any other plan approved and adopted as herein provided, will exist and serve in addition to any other retirement, pension or benefit systems established by the federal government, the State of Florida or Miami-Dade County, and shall not supersede, make inoperative or reduce any benefits provided by the Florida Retirement System or by any other retirement, pension or benefit program established by law.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-56.27.15—2-56.28.10. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (14) ---
Editor's note— Section 5 of Ord. No. 76-114, enacted Dec. 21, 1976, provided that such ordinance become a part of this Code, but did not specify the manner of codification, hence inclusion herein as Div. 5, §§ 2-56.27.11—2-56.27.14, was at the discretion of the editors. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
