<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="3">ARTICLE III. UNIFORM TRADE STANDARDS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="4">DIVISION_6._Miami-Dade_COUNTY_DRYCLEANIN</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-124.5. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Article shall mean Division 6 of Article III of Chapter 8A of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and any rules, regulations and standards promulgated pursuant to this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Customer shall be a person who inquires about, makes a request for, or purchases cleaning.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Miami-Dade County means Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Cleaner shall mean any person that is in the business of performing cleaning or presents itself to the public as being in the business of performing cleaning.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Cleaning shall mean the cleansing of clothing and other fabrics either with substantially nonaqueous organic solvents, including but not limited to petroleum naptha, or in any other manner.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Director shall mean the County Manager or the County Manager's designee. This definition shall apply to Section 8A-82.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, when utilizing the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Person shall mean an individual, partnership, joint venture, association, corporation, trust or any other legal entity.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Warranty shall mean an express or implied guarantee provided by a cleaner to a customer with respect to the cleaner's repair, replacement or compensation for defective cleaning.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 97-14, § 1, 2-25-97)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-124.6. Intent and application</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The provisions of this article shall be construed liberally to promote the following policies:
<section prefix = "1">
To establish the law governing consumer protection for drycleaning and laundering practices within this county.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To address drycleaning and laundering practices in this County in a manner that is not inconsistent with federal law and the laws of this state relating to consumer protection and drycleaning and laundering.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
It is the intent of this article to seek to secure the satisfaction and confidence of customers and members of the public when utilizing a cleaner. This article shall be effective in the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County and shall be liberally construed to effectuate the purposes set forth herein and to protect the public. This article shall be known and cited as the "Miami-Dade County Drycleaning and Laundering Ordinance."
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Nothing in this article shall be construed to remove the authority or jurisdiction of any state or local agency with respect to goods or services regulated or controlled under other provisions of law or ordinance.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
This article is not applicable to an act or practice required or expressly permitted by federal law or the laws of this state.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The provisions of this article shall be deemed supplemental to all county and municipal ordinances. In the event of a conflict between any of the provisions of this article and any provision of any county or municipal ordinance, the provision which establishes the most stringent standard shall prevail.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 97-14, § 1, 2-25-97)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-124.7. Claims</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
A customer shall have a period up to thirty (30) days after receipt of cleaning to notify a cleaner in writing of any claim for loss, damage or delay resulting from the cleaner's performance.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Each claim filed against a cleaner shall be promptly and thoroughly investigated by the cleaner. If the claim cannot be satisfied in fifteen (15) days, the cleaner shall advise the claimant of the status of the claim and the reason for the delay. A cleaner shall object to or satisfy a customer's claim no later than thirty (30) days after receipt of the claim.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 97-14, § 1, 2-25-97)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-124.8. Gender price discrimination forbidden</catch_line>
<text>
No cleaner may discriminate against a customer because of a customer's gender with respect to the price charged for like cleaning. Nothing in this section prohibits price differences based specifically upon the amount of time, difficulty, or cost of providing the cleaning.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-124.9. Private cause of action</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It shall be unlawful for a cleaner to refuse to perform its warranty if a warranty applies. When a warranty applies, a cleaner violates this article in bad faith by failing to perform an applicable warranty within thirty (30) days of a customer's written notice of claim.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Any person who suffers a loss as a result of a violation of any provision of this article may, in addition to any other available remedy, recover compensatory damages, attorney's fees and court costs from the person committing the violation.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Any person who proves the violation of any provision of this article occurred willfully or in bad faith shall recover from the person committing the violation as compensatory damages threefold the actual damages sustained, with minimum damages in the amount of two hundred dollars ($200.00), in addition to any other recovery available under law or this article.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 97-14, § 1, 2-25-97)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-124.10. Enforcement procedure; remedies; attorney's fees; costs</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It shall be unlawful for any person to violate any of the provisions of this article. In addition to any other judicial or administrative remedies provided by law, rule, regulation, ordinance or this article, the Director shall have the following judicial remedies available to enforce the provisions of this article:
<section prefix = "1">
The Director may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to seek temporary or permanent, prohibitory or mandatory injunctive relief to enforce compliance with or prohibit the violation of any of the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Director may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to impose and recover a civil penalty in an amount of not more than ten thousand dollars ($10,000.00) for each violation of any of the provisions of this article. Each day during any portion of which such violation occurs or continues to occur constitutes a separate violation. The right of trial by jury shall be available in any court to determine both liability for and the amount of the civil penalties to be imposed and recovered hereunder.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Director may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to seek restitution and other equitable relief:
<section prefix = "i">
To recover any sums and costs expended by the Director for tracing, investigating, preventing, controlling, abating or remedying any violation of any of the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
To provide restitution to any customers or consumers injured by any violation of any of the provisions of this article.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Upon the rendition of a judgment or decree by any of the courts of this state against any person and in favor of the Director under any of the provisions of this article, the trial court, or, in the event of an appeal in which the Director prevails, the appellate court, shall adjudge or decree against said person and in favor of the Director a reasonable sum as fees or compensation for the Director's attorney prosecuting the suit in which the recovery is had. Where so awarded, compensation or fees of the attorney shall be included in the judgment or decree rendered in the case. This provision shall apply to all civil actions, legal or equitable, filed after the effective date of this article by the Director. Cessation of any violation of any of the provisions of this article whatsoever, prior to rendition of a judgment or entry of a temporary or final decree, or prior to execution of a negotiated settlement, but after an action is filed by the Director under any of the provisions of this article, shall be deemed the functional equivalent of a confession of judgment or verdict in favor of the Director, for which attorney's fees shall be awarded by the trial court as set forth hereinabove.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All the judicial and administrative remedies in this article are independent and cumulative.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 97-14, § 1, 2-25-97)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-124.10.5. Dry cleaning and laundry price sign requirements</catch_line>
<text>
Every cleaner shall post a clear and conspicuous sign in plain view to all customers and potential customers that shall state the price the customer is to be charged for cleaning each article of clothing and other fabric. It is unlawful to charge a price that exceeds the applicable price on the sign. Nothing in this section shall prohibit a cleaner from charging a price higher than the applicable price stated on the sign when special handling is necessary that results in an increase to the price listed, provided that the amount of and reason for the difference in price is disclosed to the customer. Cleaning provided by means of a pick-up and drop-off delivery service shall be exempt from the requirements of this section.
</text>
</law>
