<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="3">ARTICLE IV. PERSONNEL</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="4">DIVISION_4._SERVICE-CONNECTED_DISABILITY</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-56.21. Title</catch_line>
<text>
This division shall be known and may be cited as the "Miami-Dade County Service-Connected Disability Program."
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-56.22. Intent and purpose of division</catch_line>
<text>
The intent and purpose of this division is:
<section prefix = "a">
To protect County employees from the economic hardships of service-connected disability of long duration, while preserving the incentive to return to work.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
To enable County departments to fill positions with medically able employees by making proper provision for those injured in the performance of their duties.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
To facilitate recruitment and retention of employees for the County service.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-56.23. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Employee shall mean anyone engaged full time by the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County and who is paid a salary or wage for services rendered provided he has attained permanent status in the classified service or, if exempt, has completed six (6) months' full-time employment prior to the onset of disability.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Long-term disability shall mean a disability of at least eight (8) months' duration, which disability incapacitates an employee from performing the duties of his job classification, and is the proximate result of an accident occurring at some definite time and place while in the actual performance of duty.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Disability leave shall be as defined in the personnel rules of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Disability-date salary shall mean an employees' gross monthly County salary at the time of incurring a disability.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
County physician shall mean any physician designated by the Disability Panel.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Disability Panel shall mean a committee composed of the Director of Risk Management, the Director of the Employee Relations Department, a representative of the County Manager's office, a representative of the disabled employee's department, and a representative of the disabled employee's collective bargaining unit, if any.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Disability payments shall mean the payments by the County to an employee with a long-term disability.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Secondary employment shall mean a disabled individual's employment by the County, or other employer, or self-employment.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 69-49, § 3, 7-23-69; Ord. No. 05-184, § 1, 10-18-05)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-56.24. Long-term benefits</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
A County employee who suffers a long-term disability shall be assured an income of sixty-six and two-thirds (662/3) percent of his disability-date salary for so long as such disability continues, subject to the following conditions:
<section prefix = "1">
The County disability payments shall consist of the difference between all other County-supported disability income payable to the employee and two-thirds of his disability-date salary.
<section prefix = "a">
"County-supported disability" income shall include but not be limited to income from Worker's Compensation, Social Security, State Retirement System, or other applicable State statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
In the event of lump sum payment under Worker's Compensation, disability payments shall be reduced by that portion of the lump sum figure representing the employee's weekly Worker's Compensation rate based upon his average weekly wage, for the number of weeks determined by dividing that portion of the lump sum figure as herein described by the weekly rate.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The disability-date salary shall be recomputed on October 1 each year to reflect upward or downward changes in the Consumer Price Index for Southeastern United States published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics, U.S. Department of Labor, for the previous twelve-month period.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The maximum County disability payments and all other County-supported disability income shall not exceed one thousand five hundred dollars ($1,500.00) per month, which shall be adjusted on October 1 each year to reflect upward or downward changes in the Consumer Price Index for the previous twelve-month period.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The employee shall have been examined by one (1) or more County physicians and found to be disabled as defined in Section 2-56.22(b).
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The employee's disability shall have been determined to be service-connected by the Disability Panel and not due to: intentional self-inflicted injury; commission or attempt to commit by the disabled employee an unjustified or criminal assault, battery, or felony; intoxication; gross negligence; or any other misconduct causing the employee's disability. "Misconduct" is defined to be that conduct, which, in the determination of the Disability Panel, is a substantial deviation from the personnel rules, the orders or rules of the employee's supervisor, or other rules applicable to the course of conduct of the employee in the pursuit of his employment, and which is the proximate cause of the disability.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Where a pre-existing condition, not attributable to or caused by a service-connected injury while serving as an employee of Miami-Dade County, is accelerated or aggravated by accidents arising out of and in the course of employment, only the acceleration or aggravation of disability reasonably attributable to the accident shall be considered.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Disability payments shall be adjusted as required so that the total income from all other County-supported sources, secondary employment, and this program, shall not exceed one hundred (100) percent of disability-date salary.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Any high hazard employee, as defined by Chapter 122, Florida Statutes, who incurs a disability for which benefits under this division or Chapter 122, Florida Statutes are payable, shall have the option of electing to choose which benefits he shall receive. Exercise of this option must be made by the employee in writing prior to the earlier date on which he would be entitled to benefits under either this division or Chapter 122, Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
With the exception of an award made as hereinafter provided, no provision of this division shall constitute a vested right in any employee and the Board of County Commissioners expressly reserves the legislative prerogative to alter, suspend or terminate any provision of this division.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 69-49, § 4, 7-23-69; Ord. No. 76-83, § 1, 9-21-76; Ord. No. 05-184, § 1, 10-18-05)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-56.25. Administration</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Disability Panel shall administer all matters arising under this program.
<section prefix = "1">
The Disability Panel, on its initiative or upon the request of the employee, shall arrange for such physical examinations as are considered necessary, and shall determine an employee's eligibility for the benefits provided herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Panel will guide the disabled employee in the full and continuing use of available vocational rehabilitation services.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Panel shall be authorized to place a disabled employee in any vacant position normally not filled by promotion, for which the employee would be eligible because of background, education, training, experience, and other factors. For positions normally filled by promotional competitive examinations, the Panel may waive qualifications for the disabled employee. The Director of the Employee Relations Department shall provide for seniority points for disabled employees on such examinations.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
When placed in employment pursuant to Section 2-56.25(a)(3) the employee shall serve a normal probationary period and the department shall submit periodic reports on the employee's performance to the Panel.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Failure of an employee to submit to physical examinations, or to take employment examinations, or to accept suitable employment, or refusal to make use of vocational rehabilitation services shall result in automatic and permanent forfeiture of all benefits of this program.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Recipients of disability payments under this program shall immediately report all changes in income from secondary employment and other County-supported disability payments to the Panel. Failure to provide such information when requested shall be cause for termination of benefits.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Recipients of disability payments may be required by the Panel to submit annual Federal income tax returns or such other proof of income as may be acceptable to the Panel. Failure to provide such information when requested shall be cause for termination of benefits.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Neither the awarding of other County-supported benefits, nor the acts of the Florida Industrial Commission or courts, nor other Florida Statutes, shall serve as presumptions for the decisions of the Disability Panel. In the absence of fraud an award or the denial or termination of an award by the Disability Panel shall be final and binding upon both the employee and Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Payments authorized by this program and related procedural matters shall be administered by the Risk Management Division.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Application for consideration under this plan may be initiated by the employee, his department head, or the Disability Panel, on forms provided by the Director of the Employee Relations Department.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 69-49, § 5, 7-23-69; Ord. No. 05-184, § 1, 10-18-05)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-56.26. Sick leave</catch_line>
<text>
An employee who suffers a service-connected disability shall not use or be charged sick leave if he is granted disability leave or disability payments.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-56.27. Eligibility</catch_line>
<text>
It is the intent of this division that any employee with a service-connected disability as of August 2, 1969 shall be eligible for consideration for benefits hereunder.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-56.27.1. Short-term disability leave and benefits</catch_line>
<text>
Unless otherwise provided by agreement with a County employee or bargaining representative of a County employee, any employee who sustains a service-connected disability may be entitled to the following benefits, only after the injury has been investigated by the Insurance Management Division and approval has been given by the Division and Personnel Division of the Employee Relations Department.
<section prefix = "a">
Career employees occupying permanently budgeted full time positions and who have competed nine (9) pay periods (four (4) months) of service, may be entitled to receive their normal salary, reduced by the Workmen's Compensation benefits due them, for a period not to exceed four (4) months.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Career employees occupying permanently budgeted full time positions, and who have not completed nine (9) pay periods (four (4) months) of service, shall be entitled to normal Workmen's Compensation benefits for the first fifteen (15) calendar days of disability. If at the end of this period, the employee is not able to return to duty, the employee may receive additional compensation, representing the difference between workmen's compensation and the usual salary, up to an inclusive period of four (4) months.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
If the employee is not able to return to work at the end of his period of entitlement, the case shall be reviewed by the Personnel Department and the Insurance Management Division. Upon the recommendation of these agencies and the approval of the County Manager, the employee may receive an extended period of entitlement up to another four (4) months. If the individual is a special risk employee as defined by Chapter 121, Florida Statutes, who has been disabled as a result of an assault and battery on his period in the performance of his duties, the employee may receive an additional period of entitlement up to one month. In no case will the total extended period of entitlement exceed five (5) months. If it is decided not to extend the employee beyond his initial period of entitlement, he shall, after using his accrued annual and sick leave, revert to Workmen's Compensation benefits. If the medical prognosis shows that the employee will continue to be disabled, he may apply for, or application may be made for him, for benefits of the extended disability program provided in Sections 2-56.21 through 2-56.27 of the Code.

When it has been determined by medical examination that an employee is able to resume his duties and the employee does not do so, all benefits under this section shall be immediately terminated.
Disability leave shall not be approved when it is determined by the Insurance and Safety Division and the Personnel Department that the disability occurred through the employee's negligence or willful misconduct. If the employee brings litigation against the County, while receiving Workmen's Compensation, supplemented by disability leave providing full salary, disability leave shall be terminated. The employee may then draw upon accrued vacation and sick leave.
Effective April 1, 1972, the Finance Department will make provision to pay Workmen's Compensation payments and the disability leave supplement on a single check, which will indicate the amounts attributable to each.
</section>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 71-76 amended this Code, but did not specify the manner thereof, hence inclusion of § 1 herein as § 2-56.27.1 was at the discretion of the editors.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Secs. 2-56.27.2—2-56.27.10. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (13) ---
Editor's note— Division 4, §§ 2-56.21—2-56.27, is derived from Ord. No. 69-49, §§ 1—7, enacted July 23, 1969. This ordinance was codified as a part of the Code pursuant to the provisions of § 9 of said ordinance. (Back)
Annotation—CAO 83-27. (Back)
Cross reference— Pensions, Ch. 23. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
