<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="3">ARTICLE IV. PERSONNEL</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="4">DIVISION_2._CIVIL_SERVICE_FOR_COUNTY_EMP</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-39. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
The following terms employed in this division shall have the following meanings unless the context clearly implies a different intent:
<section prefix = "a">
"Board" shall mean the Personnel Advisory Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
"Appointing authority," subject to the provisions of Section 8.01 of the Charter, shall mean the Manager for all County employees except those of elective officials whose offices are not affected by the Charter.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
"County service" shall mean employment, payment for which is made in whole or in part by the County Commission or by other elected officials of the County whose employees are affected by this division.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
"Public office" shall mean the Manager, any person appointed by the Manager who serves at his pleasure, and any elected official of the County or any municipality in the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
"Elected officials" and "elected officer" shall mean an elective public official whose employees are affected by this division.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
"Department head" and "division head" shall mean department or division heads established by ordinance of the County Commission.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
"Professional medical employees" shall mean those persons who must be licensed by the State of Florida as qualified to practice a healing art.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
"Conditional employees" shall mean those persons who occupied positions with the Miami-Dade Transportation Administration which, prior to the effective date of this ordinance [July 27, 1984], were excepted from the classified service and who shall be merged into the classified service in accordance with Section 2-45 herein.

(Ch. 30255, § 21, Laws 1955; Ord. No. 57-16, § 1, 10-7-57; Ord. No. 64-35, § 1, 7-21-64; Ord. No. 77-86, § 1, 12-6-77; Ord. No. 84-63, § 1, 7-17-84)
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-40. Merit system created</catch_line>
<text>
There is created a merit system of personnel administration for the County, which system shall be based on merit principles and scientific methods governing the selection, appointment, promotion, transfer, lay-off, removal, discipline, and welfare of the employees of the County, and other incidents of County employment. All appointments and promotions in the County merit system shall be made solely on the basis of merit and fitness.
(Ch. 30255, § 1, Laws 1955; Ord. No. 99-112, § 1, 9-9-99)
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-41. Classified service; exceptions therefrom</catch_line>
<text>
The classified service shall comprise all full-time positions in the County service existing on January 1, 1956, or thereafter established, except positions held by employees of the Public Health Trust of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and except the following:
<section prefix = "1">
The Mayor, County Commissioners and other officers elected by popular vote or appointed by the governor, and persons appointed to fill vacancies in elective offices, and all administrative assistants and secretaries to the foregoing.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Members of Boards and Commissions, appointed by the County Commissioners or by elected official or by the Manager; and all administrative assistants and all secretaries to the foregoing.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The County Manager, all Senior Assistants to the County Manager, all administrative assistants, all secretaries and all other employees of the County Manager's Office or its offices.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The County Attorney, all Assistant County Attorneys, law Clerks, secretarial, clerical and all other employees of the County Attorney's office.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
All members of the staff of the Eleventh Circuit and the employees of the Administrative Office of the Court.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Department directors, deputy department directors, assistant department directors, division directors, agency heads, board of directors, consumer advocates, program directors and all immediate assistants and all immediate assistants and all secretaries to the foregoing.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Persons employed in a professional or scientific capacity to make or conduct a temporary and specific inquiry, investigation or examination on behalf of the County Commissioners or a committee thereof, and other elected officials, or by the authority thereof, or persons employed in a highly specialized professional scientific or technical capacity needed to implement a mass transit system.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Physicians, attorneys and other professional medical employees, and licensed practical nurses.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
All employees of the Office of Management and Budget.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
All employees of the Cooperative Extension Division of the Department of Consumer Services.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
All administrative interns.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Persons who are jointly employed by the County and any institute of higher learning.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Director of art museums.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
All independent contractors.
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
Medical examiners and their professional personnel.
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
The Clerk of Circuit and County courts, Chief Deputy Clerk, Senior Deputy Clerk, division chiefs, assistant division chiefs, court operations officers, Deputy Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners, all administrative assistants and secretaries to the foregoing, and ex-parte clerks.
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
Employees who are hired and occupy positions that must be filled under guidelines inconsistent with merit employment principles.
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
The following employees of the Miami-Dade Police Department and the Department of Corrections and Rehabilitation: commanders of all bureaus and all police ranks above captain. It is the intention of the Board of County Commissioners that those positions shall be filled from the ranks of lieutenant or higher from within the departments whenever possible, in the judgment of the directors.
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
Employees of the Miami-Dade police department with the rank of police commander.
</section>
<section prefix = "20">
Employees of the fire department with the classifications of fire department special assistant 1 and 2.
</section>
<section prefix = "21">
Non-bargaining unit professional or managerial positions whose duties are determined to be inconsistent with the County's classified service rules, as recommended by the concerned department director and approved by the personnel director and County Manager.
</section>
<section prefix = "22">
All employees of the audit and management services department.
</section>
<section prefix = "23">
All non-bargaining unit professional and managerial employees of the Department of Business Development.
</section>
<section prefix = "24">
All employees of the Communications Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "25">
All non-bargaining unit professional and managerial employees of the Office of Building Code Compliance.
</section>
<section prefix = "26">
All employees of the Housing Finance Authority.
</section>
<section prefix = "27">
All employees of the Labor Management and Employee Appeals Division of the Employee Relations Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "28">
All employees of the Community Action Agency.

(Ch. 30255, § 2, Laws 1955; Ord. No. 57-16, § 1, 10-7-57; Ord. No. 58-31, § 1, 8-5-58; Ord. No. 64-35, §§ 2, 3, 7-21-64; Ord. No. 65-8, § 1, 1-25-65; Ord. No. 66-38, § 1, 7-26-66; Ord. No. 67-46, § 1, 7-11-67; Ord. No. 68-82, § 1, 12-17-68; Ord. No. 69-43, § 1, 7-16-69; Ord. No. 70-50, § 1, 6-16-70; Ord. No. 71-77, § 1, 9-22-71; Ord. No. 75-71, §§ 1, 2, 9-17-75; Ord. No. 75-102, § 1, 11-4-75; Ord. No. 76-26, §§ 1, 2, 3-2-76; Ord. No. 77-86, § 2, 12-6-77; Ord. No. 80-16, § 1, 3-4-80; Ord. No. 82-60, § 1, 7-6-82; Ord. No. 86-23, § 1, 3-18-86; Ord. No. 90-18, § 1, 3-6-90; Ord. No. 92-30, § 1, 4-21-92; Ord. No. 99-112, § 2, 9-9-99)
</section>

Annotation—All County employees in Miami-Dade County are required to be in the classified service (civil service) except for those specifically excluded therefrom. No exclusion or exemption is made for personnel in positions which would be engaged in work necessarily incident to the operation of the County owned transit system, Miami-Dade County v. Amalgamated Ass'n. of S.E.R.andM.C. Emp., Fla. 157 So. 2d. 176.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-42. Rules</catch_line>
<text>
The Director of the Personnel Department shall prepare and submit to the Personnel Advisory Board proposed rules for the classified service. The Board shall forthwith schedule and announce a public hearing on the rules, to be held within thirty (30) days following submission by the Director.
Such rules shall have the force and effect of law when adopted by a majority of the County Commissioners and the other elected officials whose employees are affected by this division, acting as a unit, following a review and recommendation by the Personnel Advisory Board, or when approved by a majority of the County Commissioners in an agreement or agreements with a County employee, County employees or a County employee organization and ratified by the County Commission by separate resolution. Amendments thereto may be made in the same manner. If not adopted, amended or rejected by a majority of the County Commissioners and other elected officials whose employees are affected by this division within ninety (90) days after submission to them, they shall automatically become effective. The rules shall provide:
<section prefix = "1">
For the preparation, maintenance, and revision of a position reclassification plan for all positions in the classified service, based upon similarity of duties performed and responsibilities assumed, so that the same qualifications may reasonably be required for and the same schedule of pay may be equitably applied to all positions in the same class. After such classification has been approved by the Board, the Director shall allocate the position of every employee in the classified service to one (1) of these classes in the plan. Any employee affected by the allocation of a position to a class, after filing with the Director a written request for reconsideration thereof in such manner and form as the Director may prescribe, shall be given a reasonable opportunity to be heard thereon by the Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
For a pay plan for all employees in the classified service, after consultation with the Manager, the County Commission and other elected officials. Such a pay plan shall become effective only after it has been approved by the Manager, the County Commission and other elected officials. Amendments to the pay plan may be made in the same manner. Each employee shall be paid at one (1) of the rates set forth in the pay plan for the class or position in which he is employed.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
For veterans' preference in accordance with the intent and requirements of Chapter 295, Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
For open competitive examinations to test the relative fitness of applicants for the respective competitive positions. Such examinations shall be announced publicly at least fifteen (15) days in advance of the date fixed for closing the filing of applications therefor, and must be advertised in a major newspaper of general circulation published in the County. Such further notice may be given as the Personnel Advisory Board may prescribe; provided, however, that in the event the examination is a promotional examination, notice by publication shall not be required. Notice of promotional examinations shall be posted in conspicuous places where they may be seen by all employees in line for the promotion. The Director, however, with the approval of the Personnel Advisory Board, may continue to receive applications and examine candidates long enough to assure a sufficient number of eligibles to meet the needs of the service; and may add the names of successful candidates to the existing lists in accordance with their respective ratings.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
For promotions which shall give appropriate consideration to the applicant's qualifications, record of performance, seniority, and conduct. Vacancies shall be filled by promotion whenever practicable and in the best interest of the service, and promotion shall be by competitive examination wherever practicable. An advancement in rank or grade or an increase in salary beyond the maximum fixed for the class shall constitute a promotion.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
For the establishment of eligible lists for appointment and promotion, upon which lists shall be placed the names of successful candidates in order of their relative excellence in the respective examinations. The duration of eligible lists for original appointment and promotion shall be for not more than one (1) year unless extended by the Director of Employment Services of the Employee Relations Department, or by the Personnel Advisory Board. An eligible list may be extended for up to two (2) additional years (for a total of three (3) years), beyond the original expiration date, providing qualified applicants remain on the list. This provision shall not be construed to deprive any employee of rights provided by a collective bargaining agreement.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
For the rejection of candidates who fail to comply with reasonable requirements of the Director in regard to such factors as age, physical condition, training and experience, or who have been guilty of infamous or disgraceful conduct; who are addicted to alcohol to excess or to narcotics, or who have attempted any deception or fraud in connection with an examination, or where in the judgment of the Board there is reasonable doubt of the loyalty of the candidate to the nation.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
For the appointment of any person on the appropriate eligible list, except in cases of promotion, in which latter cases the rules shall provide for the appointment of a person standing among the highest four (4) on the appropriate eligible list.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
For periods of probation which may vary, based on the duties of the various positions but in no event to exceed one (1) year before appointment or promotion may be made complete, and during which period a probationer may, without charges, hearing or right of appeal, be discharged or reduced in class or rank, or replaced on the eligible list; provided, however, in case of a promotional probationer, if reduced in class or rank, he shall be returned to the classification from which promoted. The appointing authority or departmental head or his designee as approved in an administrative order may at any time prior to the expiration of an employee's probationary period notify the employee in writing, with a copy thereof to the Personnel Director, that such employee shall not be retained in the appointed position or promoted position, as the case may be; however, if such written notice is not mailed or delivered to the employee on or before the expiration of the employee's probationary period such employee shall become a permanent employee in the appointed or promoted classification. It is intended that the probationary period is to be regarded as an integral part of the selection process and it is to be utilized for closely observing the employee's work, leadership, adjustment, abilities, conduct, performance, morals and character, attributes or deficiencies, in order to determine if the employee shall become a permanent employee in the appointed or promoted classification. The determination of the appointing authority shall be final and conclusive.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
For emergency employment for not more than thirty (30) days with or without examination, and for temporary or seasonal employment with or without examination, for period approved by the Board but not in excess of six (6) months in any one (1) year, unless approved by the Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
For provisional employment without competitive examination where there is no appropriate eligible list available. No such provisional employment shall continue longer than six (6) months, nor shall successive provisional appointments be allowed, except during the first year after the effective date of the law in order to avoid stoppage of orderly conduct of the business of the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
For transfer from a position in one (1) department to a similar position in another department involving similar qualifications, duties, responsibilities, and salary ranges.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
For reinstatement within two (2) years, only with the approval of the Director, of persons who resign in good standing.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
For keeping of records of performance of all employees in the classified service, which service records may be considered in counseling employees regarding improvement in work performance, in determining salary increases and decreases provided in the pay plan; as a factor in promotion tests; as a factor in determining the order of lay-offs because of lack of funds or work, and in reinstatement; and as a factor in demotions, discharges and transfers.
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
For lay-offs by reason of lack of funds or work, or abolition of a position, or material changes in duties or organization, and for reemployment of employees so laid off, giving consideration in both lay-offs and reemployment to performance record and seniority.
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
For imposition as disciplinary measures of a suspension from the service without pay.
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
For discharge or suspension without pay or reduction in rank or grade of permanent employees only for cause.
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
For establishment of a plan for resolving employee grievances and complaints.
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
For hours of work, holidays, and attendance regulations in the various classes of positions in the classified service; for vacation, sick and special leaves of absence, with or without pay, or reduced pay.
</section>
<section prefix = "20">
For the development and operation of programs to improve the work effectiveness and morale of employees in the County service, including training, safety, health, welfare, counseling, recreation, and employee relations.
</section>
<section prefix = "21">
For noncompetitive class within the classified service which shall consist of all employees requiring peculiar and exceptional qualifications of a scientific, managerial, professional or educational character, as may be determined by the rules.
</section>
<section prefix = "22">
For the automatic suspension of any person from the County service immediately upon being indicted by any grand jury or upon having an information filed against him by any prosecuting official, such suspension to continue until any such indictment or information shall have been disposed of by a trial and conviction or acquittal of the accused or by any dismissal or quashing or reversal of the same. In case any such person shall have been tried and found guilty and his conviction is not reversed, he shall automatically forfeit his position in the County service and shall not thereafter be eligible to any such service. This rule applies regardless of whether the person is placed on probation or given a suspended sentence. In the event any such person is tried and acquitted or the information or indictment is quashed or dismissed or a court of competent jurisdiction places the person in a pre-trial intervention program or withholds adjudication pending rehabilitation, the particular person shall be reinstated and entitled to back pay for the period of automatic suspension less any sums earned by the person in any other employment during the period of suspension and less any pay withheld by the County as a result of disciplinary action taken against the person. Disciplinary action under Section 2-47 may also be taken by the department head or appropriate designee at any time they feel the relevant facts warrant such action. When disciplinary action is taken, the procedures provided for in Section 2-47 shall prevail.
</section>
<section prefix = "23">
For nonlawyer representation of persons appearing at hearings held pursuant to Section 2-47 of the Code. Such rules shall set forth standards for determining whether a prospective nonlawyer representative is qualified to appear at the hearing and capable of representing the rights of the person desirous of nonlawyer representation.
</section>
<section prefix = "24">
For such other rules and administrative regulations, not inconsistent with this law, as may be proper and necessary for its enforcement.

(Ch. 30255, § 8, Laws 1955; Ord. No. 57-16, § 1, 10-7-57; Ord. No. 58-11, § 1, 4-16-58; Ord. No. 65-25, § 1, 4-6-65; Ord. No. 69-19, § 1, 4-1-69; Ord. No. 70-49, §§ 1—4, 6-16-70; Ord. No. 71-66, § 1, 8-3-71; Ord. No. 75-102, § 2, 11-4-75; Ord. No. 76-103, § 1, 11-2-76; Ord. No. 81-65, § 1, 6-2-81; Ord. No. 82-35, § 1, 5-4-82; Ord. No. 84-55, § 1, 6-19-84; Ord. No. 86-33, § 1, 5-6-86)
</section>

Annotations—AO's 7-13, 7-14; AO of 12-15-87; CAO 82-30.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-43. Use of County buildings for examinations, etc</catch_line>
<text>
All officers and employees of the County shall allow the Personnel Department any reasonable use of public buildings under their control, and furnish heat, light and furniture, for any examination, hearing or investigation authorized by this division.
(Ch. 30255, § 9, Laws 1955)
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-44. Compliance by County personnel; furnishing data</catch_line>
<text>
All officers and employees of the County shall comply with and aid in all proper ways in carrying out the provisions of this division and the rules, regulations and orders thereunder. All officers and employees shall furnish any records or information which the Director or the Personnel Advisory Board may request for any purpose of this division.
(Ch. 30255, § 10, Laws 1955; Ord. No. 57-16, § 1, 10-7-57)
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-45. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Section 2-45, pertaining to the merger of conditional employees into the classified service by Oct. 1, 1974, has been deleted as obsolete. The section was derived from Ord. No. 77-86, § 3, adopted Dec. 6, 1977 and Ord. No. 84-63, § 2, adopted July 17, 1984.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-46. Certification of payrolls</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
No elected official shall make or approve or take any part in making or approving any payment for personal service to any person holding a position in the County classified service unless the payroll bears the certification of the Director, or his authorized agent, that the persons named therein have been appointed and employed in accordance with the provisions of this law and the rules, regulations and order thereunder. The Director may for proper cause withhold certification from an entire payroll or from any specific item or items thereon. The Director may, however, provide that certification of payrolls may be made once every six (6) months, and such certification shall remain in effect except in the case of any officer or employee whose status has changed after the last certification of his payroll. In the latter case no payment of salary to such employee shall be made without further certification by the Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Any person appointed or employed in wilful contravention of any provision of this law or of any rule, regulation or order thereunder who performs service for which he is not paid, may maintain an action against the person or persons who purported so to appoint or employ him to recover the agreed pay for such services, or the reasonable value thereof, if no pay is agreed upon. No officer shall be reimbursed by the County or out of monies of his office at any time for any sum paid to such person on account of such services.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
If the Director wrongfully withholds certification of the pay of an employee, such employee may maintain a proceeding in the courts to compel the Director to certify such payroll.
(Ch. 30255, § 12, Laws 1955)
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-47. Suspension, dismissal, reduction in grade and appeals</catch_line>
<text>
Any employee may be suspended or reduced in grade or dismissed by the head of his department or designee thereof as approved in the manner provided for in an administrative order for any cause which will promote the efficiency of the service. In the case of dismissals or suspensions of five (5) or more consecutive days, prior to taking such action, the department head or approved designee may consult with the Personnel Director, unless such emergency conditions exist as would preclude such prior consultation. A written statement of the reasons for the action shall be furnished to every permanent employee suspended, reduced in grade, or dismissed. A probationary employee shall not, as a matter of right, be entitled to appeal the action taken. Any employee who has completed the probationary period may appeal the action to a hearing examiner within fourteen (14) days by requesting the same in writing of the Personnel Director. Such hearing examiner shall be assigned by the Personnel Director from:
<section prefix = "a">
A list supplied by the American Arbitration Association; or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A list of private attorneys, approved from time to time by the Board of County Commissioners, who have practiced not less than five (5) years and who have received a rating from a national rating service for attorneys.

Such hearing examiners may be paid a fee for their services but shall not be deemed County officers or employees within the purview of Sections 2-10.2, 2-11.1 or otherwise. The hearing examiner shall conduct a hearing after notice upon the charges and shall transmit his findings of facts, conclusions, and any recommendations together with a transcript of all evidence taken before him and all exhibits received by him, to the Manager who may sustain, reverse or modify the suspension, reduction in grade, or the dismissal. Such hearings shall be conducted insofar as is practicable in accordance with the rules of civil procedure governing the procedure in the Circuit Court, except as may be provided in this Code or by rules adopted by the Board of County Commissioners. Any interested party may procure the attendance of witnesses and the production of records at such hearings in the manner provided by Section 2-50. Any person appearing before a hearing examiner under the provisions of this section has the right, at his own expense, to be accompanied, represented and advised by counsel or other qualified representative. (Counsel shall mean a member of the Florida Bar.) If a person is not represented by counsel or does not appear on his own behalf, but is desirous of representation by a qualified representative, the hearing examiner shall make diligent inquiry of the prospective representative, under oath and on the record, prior to commencing the hearing to assure that the prospective representative is qualified to appear in the hearing and capable of representing the rights of the person.
All hearings requested pursuant to this section shall be commenced within sixty (60) days from the time the notice of appeal is received by the Personnel Director unless the employee requests additional time to prepare his appeal or requests that the hearing be continued pending the outcome of a related criminal proceeding, or requests additional time for other good reason. In the event a properly requested hearing is not commenced timely, the dismissed employee shall be entitled to temporary reinstatement until such time as a hearing is commenced. The County Manager shall reach his decision within thirty (30) days from the receipt of the hearing examiner's recommendations. In the event the County Manager does not reach a decision within thirty (30) days of receipt of the hearing examiner's recommendations, the dismissed employee shall be entitled to temporary reinstatement until such time as the decision by the County Manager is reached. However, at all times requirements of this section may be waived by mutual agreement between the dismissed employee and the County. This section shall also apply to exempt employees when required by the terms of a collective bargaining agreement or as approved in an administrative order.
(Ch. 30255, § 13, Laws 1955; Ord. No. 57-16, § 1, 10-7-57; Ord. No. 58-11, § 1, 4-16-58; Ord. No. 65-18, § 1, 3-16-65; Ord. No. 68-63, § 1, 11-5-68; Ord. No. 70-49, § 5, 6-16-70; Ord. No. 73-35, § 1, 4-3-73; Ord. No. 75-102, § 3, 11-4-75; Ord. No. 76-43, § 1, 5-4-76; Ord. No. 77-15, § 1, 3-1-77; Ord. No. 78-64, § 1, 10-4-78; Ord. No. 83-100, § 1, 11-1-83; Ord. No. 84-55, § 2, 6-19-84)

Annotation—AO 7-16.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-47.1. Review of County Manager's decision in personnel disciplinary actions</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager's decision shall be subject to review in accordance with Florida Appellate Rules. For purposes of such review, any original jurisdictional notices required to be filed under the Florida Appellate Rules, shall be filed with the Personnel Director of Miami-Dade County. The Personnel Department shall provide the index and record on appeal when required by and in accordance with the Florida Appellate Rules. A fee may be charged by the Personnel Department for the preparation and transmission of the record on appeal to the Circuit Court. Such fees shall not exceed the amount charged from time to time by the Clerk of the Circuit Court for similar services.
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 78-64, § 2, adopted Oct. 4, 1978, amended the Code by adding provisions designated as § 2-47A; in order to preserve Code format, the editor has redesignated said provisions § 2-47.1
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-48. Records of Department to be public</catch_line>
<text>
The records of the Personnel Department, except such records as the rules may properly require to be held confidential for reasons of public policy, shall be public records and shall be open to public inspection, subject to reasonable regulations as to the time and manner of inspection which may be prescribed by the Director.
(Ch. 30255, § 14, Laws 1955)
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-49. Services to political subdivisions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Subject to the approval of the County Commission, the Manager may enter into agreements with any municipality or other political subdivision of the County to furnish services and facilities of the Department to such municipality or political subdivision in the administration of its personnel on merit principles. Any such agreement shall provide for the reimbursement to the County of the reasonable cost of the services and facilities furnished, as determined by the County Commission. Each municipality and political subdivision of the County is hereby authorized to enter into such an agreement.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Director may cooperate with governmental agencies for other jurisdictions charged with personnel administration in conducting joint tests and establishing joint lists from which eligibles shall be certified for appointment in accordance with the provisions of this division.
(Ch. 30255, § 15, Laws 1955)
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-50. Oaths, testimony and the production of records</catch_line>
<text>
The hearing examiner shall have the power to administer oaths. When an appeal has been timely requested, the Director, at the written request of any interested party, may subpoena witnesses and may, with the approval of the Manager, compel the production of records, books or papers. Should the Director without good cause refuse to subpoena witnesses or request the Manager's approval for compelling the production of books, records or papers, or should the Manager, having been so requested without good cause, fail to compel the production of books, records or papers, then and in either event, any interested party may, without cost to the petitioner, petition the court of appropriate jurisdiction to order the appearance of any witness or witnesses or order the production of any books, records or papers necessary to a fair and proper hearing before the hearing examiner. Failure of any witness ordered to appear or failure of any person ordered to produce books, records or papers may constitute a contempt of court and may be punishable as may any other contempt of the court of appropriate jurisdiction. If any witness fails to honor a subpoena, the party requesting the same may apply to the court of appropriate jurisdiction for a rule to show cause why the witness should not appear and if after being ordered to appear by the court, the witness fails to comply therewith, the court after due notice and hearing may adjudge the witness in contempt of court and punish him accordingly. The subpoenaing party shall bear the cost of such subpoena.
(Ch. 30255, § 16, Laws 1955; Ord. No. 57-16, § 1, 10-7-57; Ord. No. 70-49, § 6, 6-16-70)
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-51. Election duties, required</catch_line>
<text>
Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code or the civil service rules and regulations, the County Manager, in the manager's sole discretion, may direct such county employees as the manager deems necessary to serve as election clerks, deputy custodians, inspectors, supervisors, officers and officials incident to the conduct of any election held within Miami-Dade County. The manager shall, however, first endeavor to secure County employees to serve in such capacities on a voluntary basis. The foregoing power shall be deemed to include all implied powers necessary and proper to carrying out such power including but not limited to providing appropriate instruction and training, and specifying the locations, hours, terms and conditions, duties and compensation for such election service.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-52. Political activities, prohibited</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
No person shall be appointed or promoted to, or demoted or dismissed from, any position in the classified service or in any way favored or discriminated against with respect to employment in the classified service because of his political or religious opinions or affiliations; but nothing herein shall be construed as precluding the dismissal of any employee who may be engaged in subversive activities or found disloyal to the nation.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
No person shall seek or attempt to use any political endorsement in connection with any appointment to a position in the classified service.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
No person shall use or promise to use, directly or indirectly, any official authority or influence, whether possessed or anticipated, to secure or attempt to secure for any person an appointment or advantage in appointment to a position in the classified service, or an increase in pay or other advantage in employment in any such position, for the purpose of influencing the vote or political action of any person, or for any consideration.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
No employee in the classified service or member of the Board or the Director shall, directly or indirectly, coerce or attempt to coerce, command or advise any other employee in the classified service or member of the Board or officer to pay, lend or contribute any part of his salary, kickback any sum of money, or anything else of value to any party, committee, organization, agency or person for political purposes.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Reserved.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Any person in the classified service of the County who violates any of the foregoing provisions of this section shall forfeit his office or position, and for one (1) year shall be ineligible for any office or position in the County classified service.
(Ch. 30255, § 18, Laws 1955; Ord. No. 74-64, § 1, 7-30-74; Ord. No. 75-15, §§ 1, 2, 3-4-75)

Annotation—AO 7-2
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-53. Misrepresentations on examinations, etc.; employees of Department unlawfully aiding or obstructing applicants</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
No person shall make any false statement, certificate, mark, rating or report with regard to any test, certification or appointment made under any provision of this law or in any manner commit or attempt to commit any fraud preventing the impartial execution of this law and the rules.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
No employee of the Department, examiner, or other person shall defeat, deceive or obstruct any person in his right to examination, eligibility, certification or appointment under this law, or furnish to any person any special or secret information for the purpose of affecting the rights or prospects of any person with respect to employment in the classified service.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Any person who is convicted of a violation of any provision of subsection (a) or (b) of this section shall, for a period of five (5) years, be ineligible for appointment to or employment in a classified position in the County service and if he is an employee in the classified County service, shall forfeit his employment.
(Ch. 30255, § 19, Laws 1955; Ord. No. 57-16, § 1, 10-7-57)
State law reference— Restrictions on political activities, F.S. § 104.31.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-54. Applicability of provisions</catch_line>
<text>
This division shall apply only to that part of the County service defined herein as the classified service.
(Ch. 30255, § 20, Laws 1955)
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-55. Penalty for violations</catch_line>
<text>
Any person who wilfully violates any provision of this division shall be guilty of an offense, triable in the court of appropriate jurisdiction, and shall upon conviction be punished by a fine of not to exceed one thousand dollars ($1,000.00), or by imprisonment in the County jail not to exceed twelve (12) months, or both.
(Ch. 30255, § 23, Laws 1955; Ord. No. 57-16, § 1, 10-7-57)
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-56. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Section 2-56, pertaining to the repeal of named Laws of Fla., has been deleted as obsolete. The section was derived from Laws of Fla. (1955), Ch. 30255, § 25

</EditorsNote>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (11) ---
Annotations—AO 7-18; CAO 78-60. (Back)
Charter reference— Authority of County to amend or change Ch. 30255, Laws of Florida, 1955, § 4.05(C). (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
