<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="3">ARTICLE VI. SIGNS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="4">DIVISION_6._COMMERCIAL_SIGNS_ON_RAPID_TR</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-121.20. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Rapid Transit System right-of-way shall mean an official map designating outside boundaries for the Fixed-Guideway Rapid Transit System for Miami-Dade County, Florida, which may from time to time be amended. The Rapid Transit System right-of-way map shall be so designated and recorded and on file in the public records of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Applicable regulations shall mean any pertinent zoning, building or other regulations in effect in the incorporated or unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County or the State of Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Protected areas shall mean all property in Miami-Dade County within three hundred (300) feet of the right-of-way of any Rapid Transit System right-of-way.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Sign shall mean any display of characters, letters, illustrations or any ornamentation designed or used as an advertisement, announcement or to indicate direction.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Erect shall mean to construct, build, rebuild (if more than fifty (50) percent of the structural members involved), relocate, raise, assemble, place, affix, attach, paint, draw, or in any other manner bring into being or establish.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Temporary sign shall mean signs to be erected on a temporary basis, such as signs advertising the sale or rental of the premises on which located; signs advertising a subdivision of property; signs advertising construction actually being done on premises on which the sign is located; signs advertising future construction to be done on the premises on which located and special events, such as public meetings, sporting events, political campaigns or events of a similar nature.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Point of sale sign shall mean any sign advertising or designating the use, occupant of the premises, or merchandise or products sold on the premises.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Outdoor advertising sign shall mean any sign which is used for any purpose other than that of advertising to the public the legal or exact firm name or type of business conducted on the premises, or of products or merchandise sold on the premises; or which is designed and displayed to offer for sale or rent the premises on which displayed, or the subdivision of such premises, or present or future construction or development of such premises, or advertising special events, and which shall constitute an outdoor advertising sign. Outdoor advertising sign shall not include a sign which is erected inside a building for the purpose of serving the persons within the building.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 78-74, ยง 3, 10-17-78; Ord. No. 83-85, ยง 1, 9-20-83)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-121.21. Applicability</catch_line>
<text>
This division shall apply to both the incorporated and unincorporated area. Any municipality may establish and enforce equivalent or more restrictive regulations, as such municipality may deem necessary.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-121.22. Signs prohibited in protected areas</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful hereafter for any person, firm or corporation, or any other legal entity, to erect, permit or maintain any sign in protected areas, except as provided for hereinafter.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-121.23. Exceptions to sign prohibition</catch_line>
<text>
Erection of the following signs shall be permitted in protected areas, subject to the conditions and limitations listed herein and further, subject to other applicable regulations where such regulations are more restrictive or more definitive than the provisions of this division and are not inconsistent therewith:
<section prefix = "a">
Temporary signs which are located and oriented to serve streets other than a Rapid Transit System, and are located at least one hundred (100) feet from the Rapid Transit System right-of-way, except that such signs may serve and be oriented to a Rapid Transit System if the property concerned abuts the Rapid Transit System right-of-way and is not served by a parallel Rapid Transit System service road or is abutting the Rapid Transit System right-of-way and has direct, permanent legal access to the Rapid Transit System. In no event shall any temporary sign be larger than one hundred twenty (120) square feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Point of sale signs which are located on and oriented to the frontage on the street which provides actual and direct access to the front of principal entrance of the place of business; however, on corner lots a second detached point-of-sale sign will be permitted provided that the same is not larger than forty (40) square feet, is located on and oriented to the street frontage of the street other than the one (1) serving the principal entrance of the place of business. "Oriented," in connection with point-of-sale signs, shall mean, in the case of detached signs, placed at a ninety-degree angle to the street being served; in the case of roof signs, parallel to and fronting such street and within the front twenty-five (25) percent of the building concerned; and in the case of pylon signs, within the front twenty (20) percent of the building concerned. Wall signs within two hundred (200) feet of a Rapid Transit System shall be confined to the wall of the building containing the principal entrance, except that a wall sign may be placed on one (1) other wall of such building and shall be limited to ten (10) percent of such other wall area. In no event shall any detached point of sale sign be erected within the protected area which is greater in height than twenty-five (25) feet above the average grade of the premises concerned, and no point of sale roof sign shall be erected which is greater in height above the roof than ten (10) feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Outdoor advertising signs shall not be erected for the purpose of serving any Rapid Transit System, and outdoor advertising signs in protected areas shall be erected and oriented to serve only streets other than Rapid Transit Systems, subject to the following conditions:
<section prefix = "1">
That in no event shall any outdoor advertising sign be erected or placed closer than three hundred (300) feet to the right-of-way lines of any Rapid Transit System.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
That outdoor advertising signs shall be erected and placed only in business and commercial (not including industrial) zoning districts which permit outdoor advertising under the applicable zoning regulations of the County or municipality having jurisdiction.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
That no outdoor advertising sign shall be erected that is larger than fifteen (15) feet in width and fifty (50) feet in length, whether single or multiple boards.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
That no detached outdoor advertising sign shall be erected which is more than twenty-five (25) feet above the average existing grade of the site on which such sign is erected or the flood criteria elevation (if property is filled to such elevation), whichever is the greater; nor shall an outdoor advertising roof sign be erected which is more than twenty (20) feet above the roof.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
That no advertising signs shall be erected or placed within three hundred (300) feet of another outdoor advertising sign, such distance to be measured in all directions from the outermost edges of such sign.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
That no outdoor advertising sign shall be erected or placed within one hundred (100) feet of any church, school, cemetery, public park, public reservation, public playground, State or national forest.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
That outdoor advertising signs shall be erected and placed at right angles to the street which they are serving and shall be located within the front seventy (70) feet of the lot or tract on which erected.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
That no outdoor advertising signs shall be erected or placed on a street dead-ended by the Rapid Transit System, between the Rapid Transit System and the first street running parallel to the Rapid Transit System and on the same side of the dead-end street, even though such distance may be greater than three hundred (300) feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
That outdoor advertising signs shall be erected and placed only on property conforming in size and frontage to the requirements of the zoning district in which located, and detached outdoor advertising signs shall not be erected on property already containing a use or structure.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
That detached outdoor advertising sign structures shall be of the so-called cantilever-type construction (double-faced sign, both faces of the same size, secured back to back on vertical supports with no supporting bracing).
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Any sign which fails to conform with the provisions of this division but is not visible from any Rapid Transit System due to an intervening obstruction.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-121.24. Nonconforming signs</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Signs which have been erected prior to the effective date of this division may continue to be maintained until January 1, 1984. Thereafter, unless such signs conform to the provisions of this division, they shall be removed. If a nonconforming spacing situation can be eliminated by the removal of one (1) sign, the sign which has been erected for the longest period of time shall have priority.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
[If] any sign [be] legally erected, permitted or maintained subsequent to the effective date of this division, which is not in violation of this division but upon the opening for public use of a Rapid Transit System or applicable portion thereof becomes nonconforming, the same may continue to be maintained for a period of three (3) years from the day of such opening, provided on or before the expiration of the three-year period, the nonconforming sign must be removed; provided any sign which is exempt from the provisions of this division pursuant to (d) of Section 33-121.23 hereof, but subsequently becomes nonconforming due to the elimination of the obstruction preventing its visibility from a Rapid Transit System, must be removed within three (3) years from the time of the elimination of such obstruction; further provided, after the effective date of this amendment any sign erected, permitted or maintained after a future Rapid Transit System right-of-way has been designated by the recording of a Rapid Transit System right-of-way map in the public records of Miami-Dade County, Florida, which becomes nonconforming due to the completion of such Rapid Transit System shall be removed within thirty (30) days after such Rapid Transit System or applicable portion thereof is opened for public use.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 78-74, ยง 3, 10-17-78)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-121.25. Variances</catch_line>
<text>
No variance shall be granted through provisions of applicable regulations which will in any way conflict with or vary the provisions of this article.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-121.26. Penalty; injunctive remedy</catch_line>
<text>
Any person violating any of the provisions of this division shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for a period not to exceed sixty (60) days, or by both such fine and imprisonment, in the discretion of the County Court. Any continuing violations of the provisions of this division may be enjoined and restrained by injunctive order of the Circuit Court in appropriate proceedings instituted for such purpose.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-121.27. Repeal clause</catch_line>
<text>
All County and municipal ordinances, County and municipal resolutions, municipal charters, special laws applying only to Miami-Dade County or any municipality in Miami-Dade County, or any general laws which the Board of County Commissioners is authorized by the Constitution to supersede, nullify, modify or amend, or any part of such ordinance, resolution, charter or law, in conflict with any provision of this division, is hereby repealed.
</text>
</law>
