<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="3">ARTICLE III. UNIFORM TRADE STANDARDS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="4">DIVISION_3._SALE_OF_COMMODITIES</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-93. Method of sale of commodities—General</catch_line>
<text>
Commodities in liquid form shall be sold only by liquid measure or by weight, and except as otherwise provided in this article, commodities not in liquid form shall be sold only by weight, by measure of length or area, or by count; provided, that liquid commodities may be sold by weight and commodities not in liquid form may be sold by count only if such methods give accurate information as to the quantity of commodity sold; and provided further that the provisions of this section shall not apply (1) to commodities when sold for immediate consumption on the premises where sold, (2) to vegetables when sold by the head or bunch, (3) to commodities in containers standardized by a law of the state or by federal law, (4) to commodities in package form when there exists a general consumer usage to express the quantity in some other manner, (5) to concrete aggregates, concrete mixtures, and loose solid materials such as earth, soil, gravel, crushed stone, and the like, when sold by cubic measure, or (6) to unprocessed vegetable and animal fertilizer when sold by cubic measure.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-94. Same—Packages; declarations of quantity and origin; variations; exemptions</catch_line>
<text>
Except as otherwise provided in this article, any commodity in package form introduced or delivered for introduction into or received in intrastate commerce, kept for the purpose of sale, or offered or exposed for sale in intrastate commerce shall bear on the outside of the package a definite, plain, and conspicuous declaration of (1) the identity of the commodity in the package unless the same can easily be identified through the wrapper or container, (2) the net quantity of the contents in terms of weight, measure, or count, and (3) in the case of any package kept, offered, or exposed for sale, or sold any place other than on the premises where packed, the name and place of business of the manufacturer, packer, or distributor; provided that in connection with the declaration required under clause (2), neither the qualifying term "when packed" or any words of similar import, nor any term qualifying a unit of weight, measure, or count (for example, "jumbo," "giant," "full," and the like) that tends to exaggerate the amount of commodity in a package shall be used.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-95. Same—Declarations of unit price on random</catch_line>
<text>
In addition to the declarations required by Section 8A-94 of this article, any commodity in package form, the package being one (1) of a lot containing random weights, measures, or counts of the same commodity and bearing the total selling price of the package, shall bear on the outside of the package a plain and conspicuous declaration of the price per single unit of weights, measure, or count.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-96. Same—Misleading packages</catch_line>
<text>
No commodity in package form shall be so wrapped, nor shall it be in a container so made, formed, or filled, as to mislead the purchaser as to quantity of the contents of the package, and the contents of a container shall not fall below such reasonable standard of fill as may have been prescribed for the commodity in question by the Director.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-97. Same—Advertising packages for sale</catch_line>
<text>
Whenever a commodity in package form is advertised in any manner and the retail price of the package is stated in the advertisement, there shall be closely and conspicuously associated with such statement of price a declaration of the basic quantity of contents of the package as is required by law or regulation to appear on the package; provided that where the law or regulation requires a dual declaration of net quantity to appear on the package, only the declaration that sets forth the quantity in terms of the smaller unit of weight or measure (the declaration that is required to appear first and without parentheses on the package) need appear in the advertisement; and provided further that there shall not be included as part of the declaration required under this section such qualifying terms as "when packed," "minimum," "not less than" or any other terms of similar import, nor any term qualifying a unit of weight, measure, or count (for example "jumbo," "giant," "full", and the like) that tends to exaggerate the amount of commodity in the package.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-98. Same—Packages and labeling, requirements, variations generally</catch_line>
<text>
Packaging and labeling regulations adopted by the National Conference on Weights and Measures, sponsored by the National Bureau of Standards, may be promulgated by the Director upon filing such regulations with the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners, which regulations shall thereafter have the force and effect of law.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-98.1. Perishable food packaged for sale to be labeled with terminal shelf life date; definitions; promulgation of rules and regulations</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It shall be unlawful for any perishable food, as defined below, to be packaged for sale, unless the packager thereof causes to be stamped, printed or otherwise conspicuously marked on its container or any label affixed thereto a clearly specified, uncoded, calendar date which shall be the terminal shelf life date of the food.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The following definitions shall apply whenever the term is used in this section:
<section prefix = "1">
Calendar date shall mean the month and day of the month.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Marked shall mean stamped, printed or otherwise conspicuously marked on its container or any label affixed thereto.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Perishable food shall mean fresh packaged perishable meat, poultry, fish, and dairy products, excluding canned, frozen or vacuum packaged products.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Director of the Consumer Protection Division, in consultation with the Miami-Dade County Health Department and the effected industry, shall have the authority to promulgate rules and regulations not inconsistent with the ordinance for the determination of the terminal shelf life date for individual food products, which rules and regulations, when approved by the County Commission is provided in subsection (e) below, shall have the force and effect of law in the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Notice of such rules and regulations and all proposed changes thereto shall be published once in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County at least thirty (30) days before the County Commission meeting at which they are to be considered. Said notice shall be sufficient if made in substantially the following form:
"Notice is hereby given that the Director of the Consumer Protection Division proposes rules and regulations relating to the shelf life dating of perishable foods, pursuant to Ordinance No. 71-80. In general, the proposed rules and regulations provide … [the dots represent a general description of the proposed rules and regulations]. A complete copy of the proposed rules and regulations is available upon request from the Miami-Dade County Consumer Protection Division. A public hearing will be held to consider any rules and regulations."
In addition, the notice shall state the address and telephone number of the Consumer Protection Division.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Rules and regulations shall be considered by the County Commission at public hearing.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 71-80, §§ 1—3, 10-5-71; Ord. No. 72-7, § 1, 2-1-72)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-98.2. Sale of certain meats, poultry, fish or seafood prohibited unless packaged in transparent containers</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It shall be unlawful for any owner, manager, or supervisor of a retail store or any independently operated department thereof to sell or offer or expose for sale, at retail, any prepackaged, unprocessed and untreated fresh meat (exclusive of viscera), poultry, (except poultry or poultry products subject to and not exempted from the application of 21 U.S.C.A. § 451-70, as amended), fish or seafood, unless the package is colorless and transparent on all sides, exclusive of labeling, or unless at least seventy (70) percent of the bottom of said packaging shall be transparent, such transparency to be uniformly distributed to expose the bottom of the meat, poultry, fish or seafood while the top shall be completely visible, exclusive of labeling, which labeling shall not occupy more than ten (10) percent of one (1) side or sides or five (5) square inches, whichever is greater, of the packages whereon such labeling is affixed.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The portion or segment of a product visible in a sealed package or container shall, at the time of packaging, accurately reflect a reasonably true representation of the quality, size and freshness of the total contents.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 71-95, §§ 1, 2, 12-1-71; Ord. No. 72-38, § 1, 7-5-72; Ord. No. 73-89, § 1, 10-16-73)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-99. Sale by net weight</catch_line>
<text>
The word "weight" as used in this article in connection with any commodity shall mean net weight. Whenever any commodity is sold on the basis of weight, the net weight of the commodity shall be employed, and all contracts concerning commodities shall be so construed.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-100. Meat, poultry, and seafood</catch_line>
<text>
Except for immediate consumption on the premises where sold, or as one (1) of several elements comprising a ready-to-eat meat sold as a unit for consumption elsewhere than on the premises where sold, all meat, meat products, poultry (whole or parts), and all seafood except shellfish, offered or exposed for sale or sold as food, shall be offered or exposed for sale and sold by weight. When meat, poultry, or seafood is combined with or associated with some other food element or elements to form either a distinctive food product or a food combination, such food product or combination shall be offered or exposed for sale and sold by weight, and the quantity representation may be the total weight of the product or combination, and a quantity representation need not be made for each of the several elements of the product or combination.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-101. Bread</catch_line>
<text>
Each loaf of bread and each unit of a twin or multiple load of bread, made or procured for sale, kept, offered, exposed for sale, or sold, whether or not the bread is wrapped or sliced, shall weigh one-half (½) pound, three-quarter (¾) pound, one (1) pound, one and one-quarter (1¼) pounds, one and one-half (1½) pounds, or a multiple of one (1) pound, avoirdupois weight, within reasonable variation of tolerance that shall be promulgated by regulation by the Director; provided that the provisions of this section shall not apply to biscuits, buns, or rolls, weighing four (4) ounces or less, or to "stale bread" sold and expressly represented at the time of sale as such, or to specialty breads offered for retail sale under refrigeration, or to "fancy breads", such as fruit breads and such other breads as shall be defined as "fancy breads" in rules and regulations promulgated by the Director of the Consumer Protection Division in the manner provided by subsections 8A-98.1(c), (d) and (e). The marking provisions of Section 8A-94 shall apply to wrapped and unwrapped, loaves of bread. If the bread is unwrapped, the information required by Section 8A-94 shall be stated on a label or by pan impression or other mechanical means. Each unwrapped loaf of bread, if labeled, shall have affixed thereon in a conspicuous place, a label of white paper at least one (1) inch square, or if round, at least one (1) inch in diameter, upon which shall be printed the required information in black or blue ink in type. If this information is given by pan impression or other mechanical means, the letters and figures showing the required information shall be plain and legible.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-102. Butter, oleomargarine and margarine</catch_line>
<text>
Butter, oleomargarine and margarine shall be offered and exposed for sale and sold by weight and only in units of one-quarter (¼) pound, one-half (½) pound, one (1) pound, or multiples of one (1) pound, avoirdupois weight.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-103. Fluid dairy products</catch_line>
<text>
All fluid dairy products, including but not limited to whole milk, skimmed milk, cultured milk, sweet cream, sour cream, and buttermilk, shall be packaged for retail sale only in units of one (1) gill, one-half (½) liquid pint, ten (10) fluid ounces, one (1) liquid pint, one (1) liquid quart, one-half (½) gallon, one (1) gallon, one and one-half (1½) gallons, two and one-half (2½) gallons or multiples of one (1) gallon; provided that packages in units of less than one (1) gill shall be permitted.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-104. Flour, corn meal and hominy grits</catch_line>
<text>
When in package form, and when packed, kept, offered or exposed for sale or sold, wheat flour, whole wheat flour, graham flour, self-rising wheat flour, phosphated wheat flour, bromated flour, enriched flour, enriched self-rising flour, enriched bromated flour, corn flour, corn meal, and hominy grits shall be packaged only in units of two (2), five (5), ten (10), twenty-five (25), fifty (50) or one hundred (100) pounds, avoirdupois weight; provided that packages in units of less than two (2) pounds or more than one hundred (100) pounds shall be permitted.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-105. Bulk deliveries sold in terms of weight and delivered by vehicle</catch_line>
<text>
When a vehicle delivers to an individual purchaser a commodity in bulk, and the commodity is sold in terms of weight units, the delivery shall be accompanied by a duplicate delivery ticket with the following information clearly stated, in ink or other indelible marking equipment, and, in clarity, equal to type or printing: (1) The name and address of the vendor, (2) the name and address of the purchaser, and (3) the net weight of the delivery expressed in pounds, and, if the net weight is derived from determinations of gross and tare weights, such gross and tare weights also shall be stated in terms of pounds. One (1) of these tickets shall be retained by the vendor, and the other shall be delivered to the purchaser at the time of delivery of the commodity, or shall be surrendered, on demand, to the Director or the Deputy Inspector, who, if he desires to retain it as evidence, shall issue a weight slip in lieu thereof for delivery to the purchaser; provided that if the purchaser himself carries away his purchase, the vendor shall be required only to give to the purchaser at the time of sale a delivery ticket stating the number of pounds of commodity delivered to him.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-106. Furnace and stove oil</catch_line>
<text>
All furnace and stove oil shall be sold by liquid measure or by net weight in accordance with the provisions of Section 8A-93 of this article. In the case of each delivery of liquid fuel not in package form, and in an amount greater than ten (10) gallons in the case of sale by liquid measure or one hundred (100) pounds in the case of sale by weight, there shall be rendered to the purchaser, either (a) at the time of delivery or (b) within a period mutually agreed upon in writing or otherwise between the vendor and the purchaser, a delivery ticket or a written statement on which, in ink or other indelible substance, there shall be clearly and legibly stated (1) the name and address of the vendor, (2) the name and address of the purchaser, (3) the identity of the type of fuel comprising the delivery, (4) the unit price (that is, the price per gallon or per pound, as the case may be), of the fuel delivered, (5) in the case of sale by liquid measure, the liquid volume of the delivery, together with any meter readings from which such liquid volume has been computed, expressed in terms of the gallons and its binary or decimal subdivisions, and (6) in the case of the sale by weight, the net weight of the delivery, together with any weighing scale readings from which such net weight has been computed, expressed in terms of tons or pounds avoirdupois.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-107. Berries and small fruits</catch_line>
<text>
Berries and small fruits shall be offered and exposed for sale and sold by weight, or by measure in open containers having capacities of one-half (½) dry pint, one (1) dry pint, or one (1) dry quart; provided that the marking provisions of Section 8A-94 of this article shall not apply to such containers.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-108. Misleading advertisements prohibited</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It is unlawful for any person, firm, corporation or association, or any employee thereof with intent directly or indirectly to dispose of real or personal property or to perform services, professional or otherwise, or any thing of any nature whatsoever, or to induce the public to enter into any obligation relating thereto, to make or disseminate or cause to be made or disseminated before the public in this County, in any newspaper or other publication, or any advertising device, or by public outcry or proclamation, or by any other manner or means whatever, any assertion, representation or statement of fact, concerning such real or personal property or services, professional or otherwise, or concerning any circumstances or matter of fact connected with the proposed performance or disposition thereof, which is untrue or misleading and which is known, or which by the exercise of reasonable care should be known, to be untrue or misleading.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
It shall be unlawful by means of exaggerated variations in the comparative size, location or position of letters, figures or other markings or characters on any price tag, sign, posters, notice, display or advertisement or other public representation of any nature whatsoever, to mislead or deceive, or to attempt to mislead or deceive the public, as to the true nature, price, quantity, quality, brand, or character of any goods, wares, merchandise, services, facilities, or accommodations, or as to the nature of, or the reason, if any is offered, for the sale or offering for sale, so being made to the public.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Where the property or services so advertised are available for purchase by the general public, the word "wholesale" or any grouping of words designed to impart a similar meaning as the word "wholesale," shall not be used in the advertisement unless the following words are clearly and prominently displayed: "This offer is available to distributors or dealers only, not to the public."
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
It shall be unlawful to advertise, or otherwise represent to the public in any manner whatsoever:
<section prefix = "1">
A representation of brand, quality, quantity, trade name or other character of any property or services that is untrue or misleading.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
A sale or an offer for sale of any property or service which is contingent upon the concurrent purchase of any other property or service, unless clearly spelled out in the advertising.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
A rate advertised on the premises of any motel, hotel, apartment, rooming house, or any other room accommodations of any nature or kind whatever if such accommodations are not in fact available at the advertised rate at the time advertised. It is the specific intent of this subsection that such advertised accommodations not be fully occupied and unavailable for rent or lease at the time advertised.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
This article does not apply to any publisher of a newspaper, magazine or other publications, or the owner or operator of a radio or television station, or any other owner or operator of a media primarily devoted to advertising, who publishes, broadcasts, or otherwise disseminates an advertisement in good faith without knowledge of its false, deceptive or misleading character.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 68-52, § 24, 9-19-68; Ord. No. 72-9, § 1, 2-15-72; Ord. No. 72-28, § 1.5, 5-30-72)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-109. Advertising meats for sale</catch_line>
<text>
Any advertising of the edible part of the muscle of U.S.D.A.-graded beef, veal, calf, lamb, yearling mutton or mutton for sale, whether by means of signs, posters, placards, handbills, newspaper displays, or by any other advertising media, where the price is advertised, shall show the grade marked in accordance with the United States Department of Agriculture official grading standards and any subsequent revisions thereof. When any of the aforesaid portions of meat are advertised with the price thereof and the meat is not U.S.D.A.-graded ("unrolled," "no-rolled") then the advertisement shall clearly disclose the fact that the meat is non-U.S.D.A.-graded by stating: "Not U.S.D.A.-graded." If the aforesaid non-U.S.D.A.-graded meat is imported from outside of the United States of America, then the advertisement shall clearly disclose the fact that the meat is non-U.S.D.A.-graded and imported by stating: "Not U.S.D.A.-graded—Imported." The following are United States Department of Agriculture official grades and marks of said grades:
<section prefix = "1">
For beef, veal or calf: (1) U.S. Prime, (2) U.S. Choice, (3) U.S. Good, (4) U.S. Standard, (5) U.S. Commercial, and (6) U.S. Utility.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
For lamb, yearling mutton and mutton: (1) U.S. Prime, (2) U.S. Choice, (3) U.S. Good, (4) U. S. Utility, and (5) U.S. Cull.

Grade marks shall be displayed in a plain and conspicuous manner and be no less in size or prominence than any trade or brand names denoting quality. Similarly, meats required hereby to be displayed with the statements "Not U.S.D.A.-graded" or "Not U.S.D.A.-graded—Imported," shall display such statements in a plain and conspicuous manner and be no less in size or prominence than any trade or brand names denoting quality.
All prepackaged individual packages of the aforesaid portions of meat sold or offered for sale shall display by label the prescribed grades and grade marks or, alternatively, either of the following statements: "Not U.S.D.A.-graded" or "Not U.S.D.A.-graded—Imported."
The absence of grade marks on cuts of meat stamped by the U.S. Department of Agriculture in its prescribed manner shall be prima facie evidence of violation of this section.
All grading shall be done by the U.S. Department of Agriculture.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-110. Complete price; representations; official terms</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful to advertise, or otherwise represent to the public in any manner whatsoever:
<section prefix = "a">
A price or price reference of a commodity, service or other thing of value unless such price presentation is the complete purchase price. The complete purchase price advertised must be the price most prominently emphasized.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A representation in any manner of brand, quality, quantity, trade name, or other character of any property or service that is untrue or misleading.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Terms such as "Public Notice," "Public Sale," "Ordered Sold," etc., unless there is an official act by a governmental agency concerning the subject of application for such terms.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
When an offer is made in an advertisement and there is a contingency, condition or limitation on the offer, such contingency, condition or limitation shall be conspicuously stated in a place contiguous to the complete purchase price quoted.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-110.1. Tipping policies</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Definitions.
<section prefix = "a">
Business shall mean any food service establishment in which tipping ordinarily occurs or which has a tipping policy.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Permit shall mean to allow, permit, accept, request or require.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Status shall mean the race, color, religion, ancestry, national origin, age, sex, sexual orientation, pregnancy, disability, marital status or familial status of an individual or any person associated with that individual.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Tip shall mean any gratuity or service charge associated with a business's provision of any goods or services.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Tipping shall mean the custom, policy or practice of permitting tips.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Nondiscrimination in Tipping. No business shall permit any tip based upon an individual's status.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Posting of Tipping Policies. Each business shall provide notice of (A) whether the business includes an automatic tip in its bill, and if so, the amount or method of calculation of the automatic tip; and (B) the following language: "IT IS ILLEGAL IN MIAMI-DADE COUNTY FOR ANY BUSINESS TO CONDONE IN ANY MANNER TIPPING BASED ON THE RACE, COLOR, RELIGION, ANCESTRY, NATIONAL ORIGIN, AGE, SEX, SEXUAL ORIENTATION, PREGNANCY, DISABILITY, MARITAL STATUS OR FAMILIAL STATUS OF THE PERSON OR PERSONS GIVING OR RECEIVING THE TIP. If you have a complaint, you may call the Miami-Dade County Consumer Services Department Hotline at (305) 375-3677." This notice shall be posted conspicuously, either on a sign or in a statement on the business's menu or price listing in the same form and manner as the other items on the menu or price listing, and written in a legible manner in English, Spanish and Creole.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Provisions Cumulative. The provisions of this section shall be cumulative and in addition to and not in derogation of any and all other provisions or laws prohibiting discrimination or regarding notification of tipping polices.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Applicability. The provisions of this section shall apply throughout the incorporated and unincorporated area of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-163, § 1, 12-7-99)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-111. Misrepresentation of price</catch_line>
<text>
Whenever any commodity or service is sold, or is offered, exposed, or advertised for sale, by weight, measure, or count, the price shall not be misrepresented, nor shall the price be represented in any manner calculated or tending to mislead or deceive an actual or prospective purchaser. Whenever an advertised, posted, or labeled price per unit of weight, measure, or count includes a fraction of a cent, all elements of the fraction shall be prominently displayed and the numeral or numerals expressing the fraction shall be immediately adjacent to and of the same general design and style as, and at least one-half (½) the height and width of the numeral representing the whole cents.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-111.1. Obstruction of price screen</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful for any person to sell at retail or offer to sell at retail any item or service to any retail customer by utilizing a cash register or similar device when:
<section prefix = "1">
The retail customer is within five (5) feet of such register or similar device at the time the retail sale occurs, and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The retail customer's view of the price screen of the cash register or similar device is obstructed in any way at the time the retail sale occurs.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-112. Scales for checkweighing of prepackaged commodities required</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful for any person engaged in the business of selling prepackaged meat, poultry, edible fish or produce in package form for retail sale and which is not weighed in the presence of customers to refuse or neglect to provide each retail outlet where said products are sold with a readily accessible price computing scale for customer checkweighing usage or to refuse to reweigh any of the aforesaid commodities in the presence of a prospective customer, when so requested. Decimal pound conversion charts or tables shall be provided where markings on packages are designated in the decimal system showing equivalents of the decimal pound (one hundred (100) divisions) to the customary ounce divisions, reduced to quarter ounce fractions thereof (sixty-four (64) divisions).
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-113. Deceptive trade practices</catch_line>
<text>
A person engages in a deceptive trade practice when, in the course of his business, vocation, or occupation, he:
<section prefix = "a">
Passes off goods or services as those of another;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Causes likelihood of confusion or of misunderstanding as to the source, sponsorship, approval, or certification of goods or services;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Causes likelihood of confusion or of misunderstanding as to affiliation, connection, or association with, or certification by another;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Uses deceptive representations or designations of geographic origin in connection with goods or services;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Represents that goods or services have sponsorship, approval, characteristics, ingredients, uses, benefits, or quantities that they do not have or that a person has a sponsorship, approval, status, affiliation, or connection that he does not have;
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Represents that goods are original or new if they are deteriorated, altered, reconditioned, reclaimed, used of secondhand;
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Represents that goods or services are of a particular standard, quality, or grade, or that goods are of a particular style or model, if they are of another;
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Disparages the goods, services or business of another by false or misleading representation of fact;
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Advertises goods or services with intent not to sell them as advertised;
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Advertises goods or services with intent not to supply reasonably expectable public demand, unless the advertisement discloses a limitation of quantity;
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Makes false or misleading statements of fact concerning the reasons for, existence of or amounts of price reductions.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Sells, causes to have sold, or promotes the sale of any residential or commercial habitable structure, located in the incorporated or unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, the permit for which was applied for after August 24, 1992 and prior to September 1, 1994, without including in the contract for such sale, or in a rider to such contract, and in all pamphlets, fliers, and marketing brochures used to promote the sale of such structures, the following disclosure in not less than ten-point bold-face type:
THIS RESIDENTIAL OR COMMERCIAL HABITABLE STRUCTURE WAS CONSTRUCTED PURSUANT TO A BUILDING PERMIT APPLIED FOR PRIOR TO SEPTEMBER 1, 1994. AS A RESULT, THE CONSTRUCTION OF SUCH STRUCTURE WAS NOT REQUIRED TO MEET CERTAIN POST-HURRICANE ANDREW AMENDMENTS TO THE SOUTH FLORIDA BUILDING CODE. A SUMMARY OF THE SEPTEMBER 1, 1994 AMENDMENTS TO THE SOUTH FLORIDA BUILDING CODE MAY BE OBTAINED FROM THE Miami-Dade COUNTY BUILDING CODE COMPLIANCE OFFICE LOCATED AT 140 W. FLAGLER STREET, SUITE 1603 (PH. 375-2901).
Notwithstanding the foregoing, this subsection shall not apply to: (i) sales of used residential habitable structures owned by individuals where such owners are natural persons not affiliated with any business entity in connection with such sale, or (ii) sales of any residential or commercial habitable structure being constructed pursuant to approved building plans for which a statement of building code compliance has been issued and sealed by a professional engineer or architect stating that such building plans are in compliance with the Post-Andrew Building Code Amendments identified in the following sentence, provided such plans do in fact comply with the Post-Andrew Building Code Amendments. For purposes of this section, Post-Andrew Building Code Amendments shall refer to all building code amendments adopted by Miami-Dade County Ordinance No. 93-141 (impact tests), No. 94-65 (shutters), No. 94-79 (wind load), and No. 94-100 (roofing).

In order to prevail under this section, a complainant need not prove competition between the parties or actual confusion of misunderstanding.
Any person who engages in a deceptive trade practice as defined in this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and be punished as specified in Section 8A-116 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
</text>
A person engages in a deceptive trade practice when, in the course of his business, vocation, or occupation, he:
<section prefix = "a">
Passes off goods or services as those of another;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Causes likelihood of confusion or of misunderstanding as to the source, sponsorship, approval, or certification of goods or services;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Causes likelihood of confusion or of misunderstanding as to affiliation, connection, or association with, or certification by another;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Uses deceptive representations or designations of geographic origin in connection with goods or services;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Represents that goods or services have sponsorship, approval, characteristics, ingredients, uses, benefits, or quantities that they do not have or that a person has a sponsorship, approval, status, affiliation, or connection that he does not have;
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Represents that goods are original or new if they are deteriorated, altered, reconditioned, reclaimed, used of secondhand;
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Represents that goods or services are of a particular standard, quality, or grade, or that goods are of a particular style or model, if they are of another;
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Disparages the goods, services or business of another by false or misleading representation of fact;
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Advertises goods or services with intent not to sell them as advertised;
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Advertises goods or services with intent not to supply reasonably expectable public demand, unless the advertisement discloses a limitation of quantity;
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Makes false or misleading statements of fact concerning the reasons for, existence of or amounts of price reductions.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Sells, causes to have sold, or promotes the sale of any residential or commercial habitable structure, located in the incorporated or unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, the permit for which was applied for after August 24, 1992 and prior to September 1, 1994, without including in the contract for such sale, or in a rider to such contract, and in all pamphlets, fliers, and marketing brochures used to promote the sale of such structures, the following disclosure in not less than ten-point bold-face type:
THIS RESIDENTIAL OR COMMERCIAL HABITABLE STRUCTURE WAS CONSTRUCTED PURSUANT TO A BUILDING PERMIT APPLIED FOR PRIOR TO SEPTEMBER 1, 1994. AS A RESULT, THE CONSTRUCTION OF SUCH STRUCTURE WAS NOT REQUIRED TO MEET CERTAIN POST-HURRICANE ANDREW AMENDMENTS TO THE SOUTH FLORIDA BUILDING CODE. A SUMMARY OF THE SEPTEMBER 1, 1994 AMENDMENTS TO THE SOUTH FLORIDA BUILDING CODE MAY BE OBTAINED FROM THE Miami-Dade COUNTY BUILDING CODE COMPLIANCE OFFICE LOCATED AT 140 W. FLAGLER STREET, SUITE 1603 (PH. 375-2901).
Notwithstanding the foregoing, this subsection shall not apply to: (i) sales of used residential habitable structures owned by individuals where such owners are natural persons not affiliated with any business entity in connection with such sale, or (ii) sales of any residential or commercial habitable structure being constructed pursuant to approved building plans for which a statement of building code compliance has been issued and sealed by a professional engineer or architect stating that such building plans are in compliance with the Post-Andrew Building Code Amendments identified in the following sentence, provided such plans do in fact comply with the Post-Andrew Building Code Amendments. For purposes of this section, Post-Andrew Building Code Amendments shall refer to all building code amendments adopted by Miami-Dade County Ordinance No. 93-141 (impact tests), No. 94-65 (shutters), No. 94-79 (wind load), and No. 94-100 (roofing).

In order to prevail under this section, a complainant need not prove competition between the parties or actual confusion of misunderstanding.
Any person who engages in a deceptive trade practice as defined in this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and be punished as specified in Section 8A-116 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
Note—Ord. No. 95-196, adopted Nov. 7, 1995, amended § 8A-113(l) to read as herein set out. Section 4 of said ordinance enacted sunset provisions which provided as follows: This article shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of enactment and shall sunset five years from the effective date hereof. Upon becoming effective, the exemption contained in Section 8A-113(l)(ii) hereof shall apply retroactively to August 4, 1995, provided, however, that to be eligible for such retroactive application of exemption (ii) a person or entity must meet all of the requirements enumerated in such exemption no later than November 17, 1995, and provided further that such exemption shall not apply retroactively whenever such application would impair or diminish substantial substantive rights, including, without limitation, contract rights or defenses.
</section>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-113.1. Negative option marketing programs</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Negative option marketing programs restricted. It shall be unlawful for a person to engage in a negative option marketing program without a written contract with the consumer in which the consumer expressly agrees to participate in the negative option marketing program. No contract provisions binding a consumer to participate in a negative option marketing program shall be valid for a period longer than twenty-four (24) months from the date they were signed by the consumer.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Definition. "Negative option marketing program" as used in this section means a contract under which a seller either:
<section prefix = "a">
Sends to a consumer an announcement, advertising or notice that:
<section prefix = "i">
The supplier proposes to send goods or provide services to the consumer (other than periodic supplements to previously acquired merchandise), and
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
The consumer is required to pay for those goods or services unless the consumer affirmatively communicates that the consumer refuses to accept the goods or services; or
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Sends to a consumer a notice accompanying goods or services unless the customer affirmatively communicates that the consumer refuses to accept the goods or services.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Contract provisions. Any negative option contract without the following provisions shall be unlawful.
<section prefix = "a">
All negative option contracts. All negative option contracts must advise the consumer that the consumer's future silence in the face of an offer will constitute an acceptance of the offered goods or service. The contract must specify the terms of the negative option including the type of goods or service to be offered; the time period (of not less than ten (10) days) in which the goods or service can be declined; the methods by which the consumer can decline the goods or service; the right of a consumer to withdraw from the negative option at any time; and the method by which the consumer can withdraw from the negative option program.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Avoiding adhesion contracts. If the contract contains any provision concerning matters other than the negative option, the negative option provisions of the contract will be invalid unless; (1) they contain all of the terms required in subsection (3)(a); (2) they are printed in type as large as the second largest type used on the contract and under no circumstances less than ten (10) point type; (3) they contain the following language in a separate, blocked section in immediate proximity to the signature line in the largest type used on the contract: "WARNING: IF YOU SIGN THIS CONTRACT, THE COMPANY WILL HAVE THE RIGHT, FOR THE NEXT 24 MONTHS, TO BILL YOU FOR GOODS OR SERVICES THAT YOU DO NOT SPECIFICALLY ORDER, IF YOU FAIL TO RESPOND TO THEIR NOTICES AND DECLINE THE GOODS OR SERVICES WITHIN THE PERIOD PRESCRIBED BY THIS CONTRACT."; (4) they are located together near the warning required in subsection (3)(b)(3); (5) they provide a place next to the negative option provisions on which the consumer can check and initial whether she accepts or rejects the negative option provisions; (6) they provide and state that there is no penalty for declining to participate in the negative option.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Unordered goods or services. Any goods or services delivered pursuant to a negative option marketing program that is not in compliance with this section shall be deemed unordered goods or services which the consumer may use or dispose of without any cost or obligation.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Scope of regulation. This section will not apply to any type of negative option marketing program which is subject to federal or State regulations or laws when such regulations or laws have the effect of preempting local ordinances. This section shall apply to consumer goods and services that are purchased for personal, home, or residential use.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Legal effect. This section shall not be construed to authorize contracts otherwise illegal or to create any contractual obligation or duty on the part of a consumer that does not exist under the common law of contracts of the State of Florida.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 91-68, § 2, 7-9-91)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-114. Baby diaper-changing accommodations</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Requirement to provide accommodations. After the effective date of the ordinance from which this section derives, every new establishment or use as defined herein shall be required to provide baby diaper-changing accommodations in accordance with the requirements of this section. Each such establishment or use shall be required to provide, at each floor level containing restrooms, at least one (1) accommodation that is accessible to women and one (1) that is accessible to men, or a single accommodation accessible to both. Each such establishment shall provide signage indicating the location of the baby diaper-changing accommodations. Any shopping center, mall or other facility encompassing multiple establishments and having a central directory shall indicate on the directory the location of all such accommodations.
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Definitions.
<section prefix = "1">
New establishment or use under this section shall mean the following establishments or uses that are instituted or substantially modified after the effective date of the ordinance from which this section derives:
<section prefix = "a">
Theaters and movie-houses;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Sports arenas, complexes and coliseums;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Stadiums;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Convention centers, auditoriums, cultural complexes and exhibition halls;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Libraries;
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Passenger terminals;
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Permanent amusement park structures;
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Shopping centers of more than 25,000 square feet;
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Restaurants with seating capacity of at least fifty (50) seats serving food for consumption on premises, except where there is a centrally located restroom facility with diaper-changing accommodations within 300 feet of the entrance of the restaurant;
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Tourist attractions; and
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Retail stores in excess of 5,000 square feet in size.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
A new establishment or use shall be deemed to be instituted on the date a certificate of use and occupancy or comparable certification regarding lawful occupancy is issued, or if the establishment or use has unlawfully failed to obtain such certification prior to occupancy, upon the first date of occupancy for its present use. A new establishment or use shall be deemed to be substantially modified so as to require compliance with this section upon any reconstruction, rehabilitation, addition or other improvement of the existing building or facility occupied by the establishment or use, if such reconstruction, rehabilitation, addition or other improvement requires more than fifty (50) percent of the gross floor area occupied by the establishment or use to be rebuilt. It is provided, however, that no establishment or use shall be deemed to be substantially modified if no structural changes are made to any existing restroom in the building or facility occupied by the establishment or use.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Baby diaper-changing accommodation shall mean a safe, sanitary and convenient baby diaper-changing station, deck, table or similar amenity which is installed or placed in a separate, designated location in an establishment or use subject to the provisions of this section. Such accommodations may include, but are not limited to, stations, decks and tables in women's and men's restrooms or unisex/family restrooms.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Exemptions. A new establishment or use shall not be subject to the provisions of this section if compliance would create a hardship. Under this section, a hardship shall mean that:
<section prefix = "1">
No reasonable physical alternative exists for providing baby diaper-changing accommodations; or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The cost of providing such accommodation exceeds ten (10) percent of the cost of constructing, purchase or substantially modifying the building or facility occupied by the establishment or use.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
Violation. Failure to comply with the provisions of this section shall result in a violation subject to the penalties in Section 8CC-10 of this Code.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 98-184, § 1, 12-15-98)</history>
</law>
