<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="3">ARTICLE IV. DUTIES OF PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="4">DIVISION_2._RATES</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-62. Schedule of existing rates to be filed</catch_line>
<text>
Within thirty (30) days after the effective date of this chapter [5] each public utility shall file with the Board a preliminary schedule showing all rates, classifications and charges for service of every kind furnished by it, and all rules and regulations in force and effect relating thereto. Thereafter, upon notice from the Board current schedules shall be submitted, in lieu of the preliminary schedules previously filed, and maintained on file with the Board on such forms and under such rules and regulations as the Board may prescribe. Provided, however, the provisions of this section shall not be applicable to charges for contributions in aid of construction, refundable or nonrefundable agreements or other advances.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-63. Initial rates declared unlawful; exception</catch_line>
<text>
All rates and charges of every public utility in effect and actually being collected or received on the effective date of this chapter*, shall be the lawful rates and charges for said public utility until changed in accordance with the provisions of this chapter or by court decree.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-64. Change in rates</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Application. Any public utility holding a valid certificate, and not in violation of any of the provisions of this chapter, desiring to change any rate, or change any rule or regulation relating thereto, shall file with the Board a written application showing the change or changes proposed and shall file with such application a written explanation of the reasons for and the reasonableness of the proposed change or changes and a verified financial statement, together with such other information as may be prescribed by rules or regulations adopted by the Board. Notwithstanding any other provision of Chapter 32 of the Code ofMetropolitan Miami-Dade County, no application, except as provided in subsections (b), (c) and (d), below, to change any rate or to change any rule or regulation relating thereto may be filed with the Board unless and until such application includes a statement of the Environmental Quality Control Board or DERM, the Director, Environmental Resources Management, of approved water service or approved sewage service, as appropriate to such application issued pursuant to Section 24-28 or 24-29 of the Code. No application for a change in rates may be considered unless the application is filed within one hundred eighty (180) days from the date of issue of such statement of approved service and such statement must be valid at the time the Board renders its decision on the application. A valid statement of approved water or sewer service filed by a public utility shall be conclusive proof of the quality of service furnished to the public by said public utility. The Board shall have the power to request and receive updated information from the Department of Environmental Resources Management regarding statements of approved service. The Board shall consider the quality of service as certified by the Environmental Quality Control Board or the Director of Environmental Resources Management in setting water or sewer rates. However, additional evidence concerning the quality of water or sewer service shall not be considered by the Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Cost pass-through clause. Any public utility holding a valid certificate, and not in violation of any of the provisions of this chapter, and
<section prefix = "1">
Which receives all or any part of its utility service (that is, water and sewer service on a bulk basis) from a governmental agency or based on rates set by a governmental agency and which redistributes all or a portion of that service to its utility consumers;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Which receives electrical power for its water or sewer system operations from a governmental agency, or which pays electrical power rates for water or sewer system operations set by a governmental agency; or
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Which is subject to the payment of County or municipal taxes or service fees on its utility property or revenues;
may apply to the Board for an increase or decrease in the rates it charges when the charges for services or service fees or the taxes it is required to pay under (1), (2) or (3) above are changed. Notwithstanding other provisions of this section, the Board shall have the power to determine whether an increase or decrease in rates for service should be granted, after hearing and without the necessity of a statement of approved service from the Environmental Quality Control Board, or DERM, upon verified notice that the charges of or permitted by the governmental agency have changed. Any rate increase granted under this section shall not exceed the amount of the change in charges of or permitted by the governmental agency. Nothing herein shall prohibit the Board, upon its own motion or upon complaint, after notice to the utility and public hearing, from considering, investigating, changing or fixing those portions of the rates and charges of any public utility described in (1), (2) or (3) above.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Fire-flow surcharge.
<section prefix = "1">
Any public utility holding a valid certificate, and not in violation of any of the provisions of this chapter, which is required to upgrade its water system to meet the fire-flow requirements specified by Section 2-103.21 of this Code may apply to the Board for a fire-flow surcharge. Notwithstanding other provisions of this section, the Board shall have the power to determine whether a fire-flow surcharge should be granted, after notice and public hearing, without the necessity of a statement of approved service from the Environmental Quality Control Board or DERM. Said surcharge shall be assessed in those areas that require improvements to meet fire-flow standards and shall be based on required fire-flow gallonage, number of building units to be protected, the area of each such unit or any other factor or factors reasonable related to fire-flow protection of the particular area. Any fire-flow surcharge granted under this section shall be set forth separately on each periodic billing.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The funds collected by the utility as such surcharge shall be deposited in a separate account by the utility in a state or national banking institution or federal savings and loan institution at no less than the prevailing rate of interest. No expenditures shall be made of such funds including the interest thereon except for the purpose of constructing water system improvements which have been determined by the Board as needed to meet Miami-Dade County's fire-flow standards. As soon as reasonably possible after the implementation of this fire-flow surcharge, the utility shall present its plans for expenditure of such funds to the Board for approval and thereafter begin construction. Should the utility provide for phased construction of fire-flow improvements, each phase of construction shall be approved by the Board prior to the expenditure of surcharge funds on that phase.
In the event the public utility is prohibited from depositing such surcharge funds in a separate account, or is prohibited from restricting the expenditure of such surcharge funds and interest thereon to fire-flow improvements, or such deposit or expenditure would cause a default, under existing water system financial agreements of the public utility, including, but not limited to, bond covenants, then such public utility may request a waiver of such requirements from the Board of County Commissioners. Such waiver may be granted by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners, after public hearing. Notwithstanding the granting of a waiver by the Board of County Commissioners, the utility, as soon as reasonably possible after the implementation of the surcharge, shall present its plans for expenditure of funds for the fire-flow improvements to the Board for approval, and thereafter begin construction. Furthermore, notwithstanding the granting of a waiver, should the utility provide for phased construction of fire-flow improvements, each phase of construction shall be approved by the Board prior to the expenditure of any funds therefor.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
In consideration of the privilege to collect and spend the funds obtained by means of this surcharge, each utility shall include with its application filed with the Board an agreement that said utility shall transfer, deed and convey all improvements constructed with fire-flow surcharge funds to Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority without receiving further consideration, within ten (10) days of the date, if every, upon which Miami-Dade County files its petition for condemnation or upon which Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority signs a contract to purchase that utility.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The utility shall permit the Board, with reasonable notice given, to review on an annual basis the separate surcharge funds account to ensure compliance with the terms of this section. When the Board determines that there are sufficient funds in the trust account reasonably to assure the upgrading of the water system to meet fire-flow standards, it shall immediately order the utility to cease making the surcharge.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Changes in supplementary charges, rules and regulations. Any public utility holding a valid certificate, and not in violation of any of the provisions of this chapter, may apply to the Board to change such supplementary charges for turn-on, turn-off, deposit, developer contributions in aid of construction and any other rate which is supplementary to the rates charged for the furnishing of water and sewer service, as well as changes in any rule or regulation relating thereto. Notwithstanding other provisions of this section, the Board shall have the power to determine whether such increase or decrease in supplementary rate or change in rule or regulation relating thereto should be granted, after notice and public hearing and without the necessity of a statement of approved service from the Environmental Quality Control Board or DERM. Nothing herein shall prohibit the Board, upon its own motion or upon complaint, after notice to the utility and public hearing, from considering investigating, changing or fixing the supplementary rates and charges and any rule or regulation relating thereto of any public utility.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Notice of hearing date. The public utility shall notify all of its customers of:
<section prefix = "1">
The date, time and place of the public hearing as set by the Board;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The present rate charged by the public utility;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The new rate proposed by the public utility in its application to the Board;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The name, address and phone number of the Water and Sewer Board; and
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The name, address and phone number of the consumer advocate.
Such notice shall be received not less than fifteen (15) days before the date of the public hearing as set by the Board. Notice under this section may be given by special letter, may be included in the public utility's billing correspondence, or may be stamped on the public utility's billing forms; provided, however, that notice in any form provided herein must be received not less than the said fifteen (15) days before the date of the hearing as set by the Board. Said special letter or other form of notice must be reviewed and approved by the Board's staff prior to mailing.
However, notice of hearing held pursuant to subsections (b) and (d) above, "cost pass-through clause," and "changes in supplementary changes and rules" shall be by one (1) publication in a newspaper of general circulation no less than seven (7) days before the date of the hearing.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Public hearing. The Board shall hold the public hearing at the date, time and place as scheduled to determine whether the proposed rates are just, reasonable, sufficient, compensatory or excessive. Every public hearing shall be conducted with all practicable and feasible expedition and with only such continuances or other delays as in the judgment of the Board are imperatively and unavoidably necessary in the public interest. At such public hearing it shall be the burden of the public utility to justify any increase in existing rates by appropriate and proper testimony and evidence. Any continuance or adjournment must be to a date, time and place certain, and such date, time and place must be determined and announced at the public hearing before the continuance or adjournment is made.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Decision of Board within specified time. Within sixty (60) days after concluding such public hearing, the Board shall render its decision upon the application, which decision shall embody a statement by the Board of the reasons therefor and finding of the facts upon which the determination is predicated.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 60-20, § 22, 7-5-60; Ord. No. 69-8, § 1, 2-4-69; Ord. No. 75-28, §§ 12—14, 5-7-75; Ord. No. 77-14, § 3, 3-1-77; Ord. No. 77-41, § 1, 6-21-77; Ord. No. 78-88, § 1, 12-12-78; Ord. No. 78-92, § 1, 12-12-78; Ord. No. 80-73, § 1, 7-1-80; Ord. No. 80-111, § 1, 10-7-80; Ord. No. 83-101, § 1, 11-1-83)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-65. Board shall fix just and reasonable rates</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Rates must be as filed with Board. No public utility shall charge or receive, directly or indirectly, any rates not on file with the Board for the particular class of service involved and no change shall be made in any such rates without the approval of the Board, after due notice and public hearing.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Public hearing on rates. The Board, after due notice, may hold a public hearing, on its own motion or upon complaint, for the purpose of considering, investigating, changing or fixing the rates and charges of any public utilities. If as a result of any such hearing and investigation, the Board finds that the rates, charges, classifications or practices of any such public utility are unjust, unreasonable, unjustly discriminatory, or unduly preferential, or that the rates and charges are insufficient to yield reasonable compensation for the service rendered, the Board shall determine and fix just and reasonable rates, charges, classifications and practices to be thereafter observed and conformed to by said public utility.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Investment basis of fixing rates. In fixing and determining just and reasonable rates and charges the Board shall investigate and determine the actual legitimate costs of the property of each public utility, actually used and useful or having present value for future use in the public service, which costs as determined by the Board shall be utilized for rate-making purposes, and shall be the money honestly and prudently invested by the public utility in such property used and useful in serving the public, less accrued depreciation, and shall not include any goodwill or going-concern value in excess of payments made therefor. Should it be determined by the Board, on its own or after judicial review and remand, that any utility for some presently unforeseen reason (the possibility of which is set forth in the decision of the Supreme Court of the State of Florida in Westwood Lake, Inc. v. Miami-Dade County, Fla. 1972, 264 So. 2d 7) is entitled to recover depreciation on contributed assets, then such amount shall be set forth as a surcharge on each periodic billing. The funds collected by the utility as such surcharge shall be deposited by the utility in a state or national banking institution or federal savings and loan institution at no less than the prevailing rate of interest. Such funds shall be held by the utility in trust for the customers thereof. No expenditures shall be made of such funds including the interest thereon except for the purpose of replacing contributed assets which have been determined by the Board to be in need of replacement or for constructing water system improvements which have been determined by the Board to be in need of replacement or for constructing water system improvements have been determined by the Board to be needed to meet Miami-Dade County fire-flow standards. The Board shall determine that the separate surcharge funds account shall be utilized in the best interests of the utility system in order to ensure sufficient funding for the replacement of contributed assets. In consideration of the privilege to collect and spend on fire-flow improvements the funds obtained by means of this surcharge, each utility shall include with its application filed with the Board an agreement that said utility shall transfer, deed and convey such improvements to Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority without receiving further consideration, within ten (10) days of the date if ever, upon which Miami-Dade County files its petition for condemnation or upon which Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority signs a letter of intent with said utility to purchase that utility. The utility shall permit the Board, with reasonable notice given, to review on an annual basis the separate surcharge funds account to ensure compliance with the terms of this section. When the Board determines that there are sufficient funds in the trust account reasonably to assure replacement of contributed assets as such replacement becomes necessary and for the upgrading of the water system to meet fire-flow standards, it shall immediately order the utility to cease making the surcharge.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Cash requirements basis of fixing municipal utilities' rates. Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the Board, in fixing and determining just and reasonable rates for municipally owned and/or operated utilities pursuant to Section 32-66, may utilize a cash requirements approach which shall be the money honestly and prudently necessary to meet operation and maintenance expenditures, debt service reoperation and maintenance expenditures, debt service requirements on outstanding bond issues, and renewals and replacements.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Decision on rate changes. The Board shall make a decision on all rate matters within sixty (60) days after conclusion of the public hearings, and such decision shall be in the form of orders which shall embody the reasons for the determination made and findings of fact upon which the decision is predicated. Such orders shall provide the effective date upon which any change in rates shall become effective.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Cost of rate hearing. Where a rate hearing is held pursuant to application filed by a public utility, the direct costs to the County shall be paid by the applicant; such costs shall include the salary or fee of any independent consultant attributable to the rate hearing and the cost of providing a full and complete original record of the proceedings before the Board, taken down by a reporter appointed, selected or approved by the Board. Where a rate hearing is initiated by the Board, the Board shall pay these costs of such proceedings.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 60-20, § 23, 7-5-60; Ord. No. 64-23, §§ 6, 7, 7-7-64; Ord. No. 72-32, § 1, 6-20-72; Ord. No. 72-54, § 1, 9-19-72; Ord. No. 75-28, § 15, 5-7-75; Ord. No. 75-56, § 1, 7-3-75; Ord. No. 78-71, § 1, 10-17-78; Ord. No. 78-88, § 2, 12-12-78; Ord. No. 83-101, § 1, 11-1-83)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-66. Jurisdiction over publicly owned and operated systems</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Anything herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding, the Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Water and Sewer Board shall have full power and jurisdiction to regulate the rates charged by all municipally owned or operated systems to any consumers not within the boundaries of said municipality and to other municipally or privately owned water or sewer utilities; provided, however, that the Board shall not have jurisdiction in respect to rates charged by municipally owned or operated utilities:
<section prefix = "a">
To consumers within the boundaries of that municipality, or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
To customers being served by a municipally owned or operated system pursuant to an agreement with Miami-Dade County which by its terms either prescribes the rates to be charged or prescribes a method by which rates shall be established, or
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
To consumers not within the boundaries of said municipality so long as ninety (90) percent of the gross revenues generated by water and sewer rates are derived from consumers within the boundaries of said municipality and the rates are uniformly applied to consumers inside and outside the municipal boundaries.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Anything herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding, the Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Water and Sewer Board shall have no jurisdiction whatever over the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority or Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Neither Miami-Dade County nor the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority shall be required to pay any fees or charges imposed by the provisions of this chapter.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 60-30, § 1, 10-11-60; Ord. No. 62-28, § 7, 7-3-62; Ord. No. 64-23, § 8, 7-7-64; Ord. No. 70-60, § 2, 7-21-70; Ord. No. 72-94, § 3, 12-6-72; Ord. No. 75-28, § 16, 5-7-75; Ord. No. 75-68, § 1, 9-3-75; Ord. No. 76-62, § 2, 7-6-76; Ord. No. 79-41, § 2, 6-19-79; Ord. No. 83-101, § 1, 11-1-83; Ord. No. 85-17, § 1, 4-2-85)</history>
Annotation—CAO 78-55.
<catch_line>Sec. 32-67. Schedule of existing municipal rates to be filed</catch_line>
<text>
Within thirty (30) days after the effective date of this section [6], each municipality owned or operated public utility serving an unincorporated area of Miami-Dade County shall file with the Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Water and Sewer Board a preliminary schedule showing all rates, classifications and charges for services of every kind furnished by such public utility and all rules and regulations relating thereto presently in effect. The rates and charges of municipally owned or operated utilities actually being collected or received on the effective date hereof in the unincorporated areas shall be the lawful rates and charges for said public utility in the unincorporated areas until changed in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-68. Standard rate structure required for billing of water and sewer service</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
On or before October 1, 1986, each public utility as defined in Section 32-4 may adopt and put into use a standard rate structure, as defined herein, for the purpose of billing retail customers for water and sewer service.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Standard rate structure shall comprise the following components:
<section prefix = "1">
Base facility charge to recover the utility's cost associated with readiness to serve the demand on the system created by each customer. The base facility charge shall be billed at a fixed rate at the regular billing cycle and shall be estimated to recover the fixed cost of providing the customer with his maximum month's usage. The monthly billing unit for the base facility charge shall be ten thousand (10,000) gallons, considered as an equivalent residential connection (ERC) or such other gallonage criteria that is historically appropriate for that utility. The charge shall be prorated for the number of days of service provided during the billing cycle.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Customer charge to recover the utility's costs related to such cost components as meter reading, accounting, billing, collections, etc., which shall be billed as a separate item on each invoice issued by the utility or in combination with the base facility charge in paragraph (1) above. This charge shall be a fixed equal amount on each bill issued by the utility.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Commodity charge to recover the utility's costs associated with the pumping and treatment of water and/or sewage including cost of water purchased and sewage disposal fees payable to Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
(1) This standardization of rate structure shall not constitute a change in rates contemplated in Section 32-64 herein. Accordingly, any rate changes arising by virtue of this section may become effective without written notice to customers, public hearing, or a statement of approved water or sewer service generally required from the Environmental Quality Control Board.
<section prefix = "2">
Ninety (90) days prior to the proposed effective date of any change in rates resulting from this section, each utility shall file with the Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Water and Sewer Board a schedule of the proposed rates, together with a sworn statement that the annual revenues to be generated by the proposed rate subject to the Board's jurisdiction will not exceed a five (5) percent variance from the annual revenues at the then prevailing rate under the Board's jurisdiction.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
This section does not contemplate and shall not constitute any additional revenue source. Any change in rates under the Board's jurisdiction producing additional revenues shall conform with the provisions of Sections 32-64 and 32-65
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
This section shall not increase the existing regulatory provisions of Section 32-66, Miami-Dade County Code, and does not in any way supersede any existing municipal or County ordinances except such ordinance that may establish rates which do not conform to the standard rate structure mandated by this section of the Code.
<section prefix = "c">
Any municipally owned or operated system servicing no more than two thousand five hundred (2,500) customers within its municipal boundaries shall be exempt from the requirements of this section.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 84-9, § 1, 2-7-84; Ord. No. 86-21, § 1, 3-18-86; Ord. No. 86-63, § 1, 9-16-86)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-69. Base facility charge criteria</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The monthly billing unit for the base facility charge (BFC) shall be the equivalent residential connection (ERC). An ERC shall be ten thousand (10,000) gallons or the utility may elect to use the actual average monthly consumption of all single-family customers as an ERC. If a utility elects to use a volume other than ten thousand (10,000) gallons as an ERC, that elected volume shall be used by that utility instead of the ten thousand-gallon monthly ERC in complying with this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Subsequent to the initial change to the ERC method of billing the base facility charge, the number of ERC billing units assigned to a customer shall be adjusted when the utility proposes a change in rates. The twelve-month period (test year) used in support of the rate change shall be used to determine an average single-family monthly usage ERC and a customer's maximum usage.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
A different evaluation and adjustment period may be used to establish customers' billing units provided the revised customers' billing units do not result in an increase in total revenues.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The number of billing units assigned to each customer shall be obtained by dividing the maximum month's use of each customer billed monthly or the estimated maximum month's usage for customers billed quarterly (customer's maximum quarterly usage divided by the number of days usage in that billing period times thirty and four-tenths (30.4) days) by the volume of consumption considered an ERC for that utility.
<section prefix="1" type="table">
<table class="thead0 table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="120px" /> 
  <col width="24px" /> 
  <col width="67.19999999999999px" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <cite class="ulsingle">Customer Maximum Monthly Usage</cite> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Number of Gallons Comprising</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">=</td> 
   <td style="" align="left" valign="top" class="">;mb=-4;Customer Billing<br /></td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">an ERC</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" align="left" valign="top" class="">Units of Service<br /></td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The minimum monthly BFC to any customer shall not be for less than one-half of a billing unit. Monthly billing units for customers exceeding the one-half billing unit minimum shall be computed to the nearest one-tenth of a billing unit (ERC).
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 84-9, § 2, 2-7-84)</history>
<EditorsNote>
At the discretion of the editor, §§ 2 and 3 of Ord. No. 84-9, adopted Feb. 7, 1984, have been codified as §§ 32-69 and 32-70
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-70. Base facility charge consumption</catch_line>
<text>
The base facility charge per billing unit shall be determined by dividing the annual base facility costs for all retail customers by the number of billing units on a utility's system. The number of billing units on a system of a utility using ten thousand (10,000) gallons as an ERC shall be computed as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
Multiply by five thousand (5,000) the number of customers with a maximum monthly usage of five thousand (5,000) gallons or less;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Add to the number determined in (1) the total maximum months usage of all customers with a maximum usage in excess of five thousand (5,000) gallons;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Divide the total of (1) and (2) by ten thousand (10,000) gallons to determine the monthly billing units;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Multiple the total monthly billing units by twelve (12) months to obtain the total billing units on that utility's system:
<section prefix="2" type="table">
<table class="table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="48px" /> 
  <col width="42.857142857142854%" /> 
  <col width="24px" /> 
  <col width="42.857142857142854%" /> 
  <col width="24px" /> 
  <col width="14.285714285714286%" /> 
  <col width="48px" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="4" align="center" valign="top" class="">Base facility costs &#215; retail %<br /></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">;mb=10q;=</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Base Facility</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="5" valign="top" class=""> _____</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Charge<br />per 10,000<br />Gallons</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="font-size:40pt; " align="left" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH12EL.html#PTIIICOOR_CH12EL"> 12</a> &#215;<br />(<br /> </td> 
   <td style="" align="left" valign="top" class="">No. of customers in min. group &#215; one-half of the number of gallons comprising an ERC<br /></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">+</td> 
   <td style="" align="left" valign="top" class="">Maximum monthly usage of all customers with a maximum monthly usage in excess of 5,000 gal.<br /></td> 
   <td style="font-size:40pt; " valign="top" class="">)</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 

 
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
A customer's base facility charge equals the number of billing units assigned to that customer times the base facility charge per billing unit determined in accordance with this section. This amount is multiplied by three (3) for quarterly customers.

</section>
</text>
The base facility charge per billing unit shall be determined by dividing the annual base facility costs for all retail customers by the number of billing units on a utility's system. The number of billing units on a system of a utility using ten thousand (10,000) gallons as an ERC shall be computed as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
Multiply by five thousand (5,000) the number of customers with a maximum monthly usage of five thousand (5,000) gallons or less;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Add to the number determined in (1) the total maximum months usage of all customers with a maximum usage in excess of five thousand (5,000) gallons;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Divide the total of (1) and (2) by ten thousand (10,000) gallons to determine the monthly billing units;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Multiple the total monthly billing units by twelve (12) months to obtain the total billing units on that utility's system:
<section prefix="3" type="table">
<table class="table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="48px" /> 
  <col width="42.857142857142854%" /> 
  <col width="24px" /> 
  <col width="42.857142857142854%" /> 
  <col width="24px" /> 
  <col width="14.285714285714286%" /> 
  <col width="48px" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="4" align="center" valign="top" class="">Base facility costs &#215; retail %<br /></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">;mb=10q;=</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Base Facility</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" colspan="5" valign="top" class=""> _____</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Charge<br />per 10,000<br />Gallons</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="font-size:40pt; " align="left" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH12EL.html#PTIIICOOR_CH12EL"> 12</a> &#215;<br />(<br /> </td> 
   <td style="" align="left" valign="top" class="">No. of customers in min. group &#215; one-half of the number of gallons comprising an ERC<br /></td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">+</td> 
   <td style="" align="left" valign="top" class="">Maximum monthly usage of all customers with a maximum monthly usage in excess of 5,000 gal.<br /></td> 
   <td style="font-size:40pt; " valign="top" class="">)</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 

 
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
A customer's base facility charge equals the number of billing units assigned to that customer times the base facility charge per billing unit determined in accordance with this section. This amount is multiplied by three (3) for quarterly customers.

Note—See the editor's note for § 32-69
</section>
<catch_line>Sec. 32-71. Fire hydrant service</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
The Board hereby approves the rates for fire hydrant service as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
For all Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority Department water customers located within the City of Miami and for all Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority Department water customers provided fire protection by Metropolitan Miami-Dade County whenever said customer is located within six hundred sixty (660) feet of a fire hydrant; forty cents ($0.40) per month.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
For all Metro-Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Utility water customers provided fire protection by Metropolitan Miami-Dade County whenever said customer is located within six hundred sixty (660) feet of a fire hydrant: thirty-eight cents ($0.38) per month.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The rates for fire hydrant service set forth in subsection (a) shall cover the costs of fire hydrant water service, repairs, maintenance and installation. Said rates shall become effective for all billings based upon fire hydrant service provided on and after January 1, 1984; where fire hydrant service being billed encompasses periods both prior to January 1, 1984, and after, fire hydrant service prior to January 1, 1984, shall be determined by proration according to the number of days for which the old and new rates were in effect.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The fire hydrant service charges authorized herein shall be held and restricted in a separate group of accounts by the Department and by the Metro-Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Utility and funds collected as a result of said charges are to be used solely to reimburse Department costs for fire hydrant water service, repairs, maintenance and installation.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 84-1, §§ 1—3, 1-17-84)</history>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 84-1, §§ 1—3, adopted Jan. 17, 1984, did not specify manner of amendment; therefore, codification as § 32-71 has been at the editor's discretion.

</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Secs. 32-72—32-75. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (5) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 60-20 from which this chapter is derived became effective "thirty (30) days after enactment" on July 5, 1960. (Back)

--- (6) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 64-23, § 110, provided that said ordinance shall be effective ten (10) days after enactment. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
