<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="3">ARTICLE III. WATER AND SOIL QUALITY</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="4">DIVISION_2._WELLFIELD_PROTECTION_DOMESTI</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-43. Protection of public potable water supply wells</catch_line>
<text>
The provisions of this section which impose upon land uses within the West Wellfield Interim protection area regulations which are more restrictive than those regulations applicable to the other public utility potable water supply wellfields in Miami-Dade County shall be deemed interim in nature. Said more restrictive regulations shall be reviewed by such technical review task force(s) or committee(s) as provided by the Board of County Commissioners or its designee upon recommendation of the Director. The Director shall submit to the Board of County Commissioners progress reports, as necessary, pertaining to said review, and recommendations necessary to protect the public health, safety and welfare arising out of said review shall be presented to the Board of County Commissioners. The Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance (Section 2-11.1 of this Code) shall not be applicable to task forces or committees provided for in this section.
<section prefix = "1">
Legislative intent. The intent and purpose of this section is to safeguard the public health, safety and welfare by providing scientifically established standards for land uses within the cones of influence thereby protecting public potable water supply wells from contamination.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Short title; applicability; construction. This section shall be known as the "Potable Water Supply Well Protection Ordinance." The provisions of this section shall be effective in the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County and shall be liberally construed to effect the purposes set forth herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Maps of cones of influence, the Northwest Wellfield protection area, the West Wellfield Interim protection area, and the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex protection area. The Director or the Director's designee, shall maintain maps of cones of influence of public utility potable water supply wells, map(s) of the Northwest Wellfield protection area, map(s) of the West Wellfield Interim protection area, and the map(s) of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex wellfield protection area dated November, 2005. The cone of influence maps dated December 30, 1980, as may be amended from time to time, prepared by the Department are incorporated herein by reference hereto. Any changes, additions or deletions to said maps shall be approved by the Board of County Commissioners by ordinance. The cone of influence maps of the Northwest Wellfield dated December 30, 1980, as amended effective May 31, 1985, shall hereinafter be referred to as the Northwest Wellfield protection area map(s). The Northwest Wellfield protection area map(s) dated May 31, 1985, the West Wellfield Interim protection area map(s) dated February 28, 1989 and the map(s) of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex wellfield protection area dated November, 2005, as all of same may be amended from time to time, prepared by the Department, are incorporated herein by reference hereto. Any changes, additions or deletions to said Northwest Wellfield protection area map(s), West Wellfield Interim protection area map(s) or South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex wellfield protection area map(s) shall be approved by the Board of County Commissioners by ordinance. The Director, or the Director's designee, shall maintain the DERM Technical Report: "Development of a Groundwater Model to Determine Wellfield Protection Zones for the Miami-Dade County, Florida, South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex". The wellfield protection zones of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex have been established using the procedures and input parameters set forth in the aforesaid Technical Report dated, November, 2005. The aforesaid Technical Report dated, November, 2005, a copy of which is attached hereto, is hereby incorporated by reference, as same may be amended from time to time. Any changes, additions or deletions to the aforesaid Technical Report dated November, 2005 shall be approved by the Board of County Commissioners by ordinance.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Septic tanks, sanitary sewers, storm water disposal, liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment and violations of this chapter within wellfield protection area. Notwithstanding any provisions of this Code, no County or municipal officer, agent, employee or board shall approve, grant or issue any building permit, certificate of use and occupancy (except for changes in ownership), municipal occupational license (except for changes in ownership), platting action (final plat, waiver of plat or equivalent municipal platting action) or zoning action (district boundary change, unusual use, use variance or equivalent municipal zoning action) for any land use served or to be served by a septic tank, sanitary sewer, storm water disposal method, or liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment method, and which is within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex or within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield or Hialeah Wellfield or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, until the County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board has obtained the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee. Furthermore, not withstanding any provision of this Code, no person shall construct, utilize, operate, occupy or cause, allow, let, permit or suffer to be constructed, utilized, operated or occupied any land use served or to be served by septic tank, sanitary sewer, storm water disposal method, or liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment method, and which is within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex or within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield or Hialeah Wellfield or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, until the person has obtained the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee. The Director or the Director's designee shall issue the Director's or the Director's designee's written approval only if the Director or the Director's designee finds that all septic tanks, septic tank drain fields, storm water disposal methods and liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment methods will be installed upon the property as far away as is reasonably possible from all potable water supply wells, and:
<section prefix = "a">
Septic tanks. That the septic tank sewage loadings will not exceed the number of gallons per day for each unsubmerged acre of land as set forth in Tables A-1, A-2, A-3 and A-4, except that neither the Director nor the Director's designee shall issue the Director's or the Director's designee's written approval for any land use served or to be served by a septic tank within the Northwest Wellfield protection area unless the septic tank was installed prior to September 30, 1983, or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area unless the septic tank was installed prior to the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80], or that the land use served or to be served by a septic tank within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within that portion of the West Wellfield Interim protection area which is west of the Urban Development Boundary of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan as may be amended from time to time, is residential or is an ancillary rockmining use necessary for extracting and processing subsurface materials and which residential or ancillary rockmining use shall not exceed a maximum sewage loading of seventy (70) gallons per day per acre and which septic tanks shall be located within an area of twenty-one thousand seven hundred eighty (21,780) square feet of unsubmerged land, or that the property served or to be served by septic tanks is residential, uses a public water supply, has not been the subject of any zoning action (district boundary change, unusual use, use variance, or equivalent municipal zoning action) or any platting action (final plat, waiver of plat, or equivalent municipal platting action) after March 13, 1981, and is in compliance with Section 24-43.1, or that the owner of the property served or to be served by septic tanks is applying for the original certificate of use and occupancy or original municipal occupational license pursuant to a valid building permit obtained prior to June 1, 1983, for property within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, or, in the case of property within the Northwest Wellfield protection area obtained prior to September 30, 1983, or, in the case of property within the West Wellfield Interim protection area obtained prior to the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80] or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex obtained prior to the effective date of this ordinance, or, in the case of property not within the basic wellfield protection area but within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield and Southwest Wellfield, obtained prior to February 1, 1985, or, in the case of property not within the basic wellfield protection area but within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield and Hialeah Wellfield, obtained prior to December 12, 1986, which permit has been valid and continuously in full force and effective since its issuance, or that the owner of the property is applying for a certificate of use and occupancy or municipal occupational license for a land use served or to be served by a septic tank installed prior to March 13, 1981 for property within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, or, in the case of property within the Northwest Wellfield protection area installed prior to September 30, 1983, or, in the case of property within the West Wellfield Interim protection area installed prior to the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80] or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex obtained prior to the effective date of this ordinance or, in the case of property not within the basic wellfield protection area but within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, and Southwest Wellfield, installed prior to February 1, 1985, or, in the case of property not within the basic wellfield protection area but within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield and Hialeah Wellfield, installed prior to December 12, 1986, which uses a public water supply and which is in compliance with Section 24-43.1
<section prefix = "i">
Notwithstanding the provisions of Section 24-43(4)(a), there shall be required within the Northwest Wellfield protection area, within the West Wellfield Interim protection area, within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex, and within the maximum day wellfield protection area of all public utility potable water supply wells a minimum separation equivalent to ten (10) days travel time between any potable water supply well (other than a public utility potable water supply well) and any septic tank or septic tank drainfield.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Sanitary sewers. That the sewage loading into sanitary sewers will not exceed the number of gallons per day for each unsubmerged acre of land as set forth in Table B-1, or that the property served or to be served by sanitary sewers is residential, uses a public water supply, has not been the subject of any zoning action (district boundary change, unusual use, use variance, or equivalent municipal zoning action) or any platting action (final plat, waiver of plat, or equivalent municipal platting action) after March 13, 1981, and is in compliance with Section 24-42.4, or that the owner of the property served or to be served by sanitary sewers is applying for the original certificate of use and occupancy or original municipal occupational license pursuant to a valid building permit obtained prior to June 1, 1983, for property within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, or, in the case of property within the Northwest Wellfield protection area, obtained prior to September 30, 1983, for property within the Northwest Wellfield protection area, or, in the case of property within the West Wellfield Interim protection area, obtained prior to the effective date of this ordinance, or for property within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex obtained prior to the effective date of this ordinance, or, in the case of property not within the basic wellfield protection area, but within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield and Southwest Wellfield, obtained prior to February 1, 1985, or, in the case of property not within the basic wellfield protection area but within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield and Hialeah Wellfield, installed prior to December 12, 1986, which permit has been valid and continuously in full force and effect since its issuance.
<section prefix = "i">
Notwithstanding the provisions of Section 24-43(4)(b), all sanitary sewers installed within the Northwest Wellfield protection area, or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area, or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex, or within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, or Hialeah Wellfield, or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, after June 13, 1986, shall comply with the following standards:
Residential land use—No gravity sanitary sewer shall have an exfiltration rate greater than fifty (50) gallons per inch pipe diameter per mile per day. Sewer lateral lines located in the public right-of-way shall be a minimum of six (6) inches in diameter.
Nonresidential land use—No gravity sanitary sewer shall have an exfiltration rate greater than twenty (20) gallons per inch pipe diameter per mile per day. Sewer lateral lines located in the public right-of-way shall be a minimum of six (6) inches in diameter.
Sanitary sewer force mains—All sanitary sewer force mains installed within the Northwest Wellfield protection area, or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area, or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex, or within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, or Hialeah Wellfield, or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, shall be constructed of either ductile iron or reinforced concrete pressure sewer pipe. No such ductile iron sanitary sewer force main shall, exfiltrate at a rate greater than the allowable leakage rate specified in American Water Works Association Standard C600-82 at a test pressure of one hundred (100) pounds per square inch. No such reinforced concrete pressure sanitary sewer force main shall exfiltrate at a rate greater than one-half (½) the allowable leakage rate specified for ductile iron pipe in American Water Works Association Standard C600-82 at a test pressure of one hundred (100) pounds per square inch.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Notwithstanding the provision of Section 24-43(4)(b), all gravity sanitary sewers with invert elevations above the average surrounding water table elevation and all sanitary sewer force mains shall be tested to ensure compliance with the aforementioned exfiltration rate standards.
A registered professional engineer shall provide written certification of the exfiltration rate for all manhole/gravity sewer pipe systems installed, in equivalent gallons per inch pipe diameter per mile of pipe per day (twenty-four (24) hours), and the exfiltration rate for all sanitary sewer force mains in gallons per hour per one thousand (1,000) feet of sanitary sewer force main installed. Existing gravity sanitary sewers with pipe diameters of eight (8) inches or more shall be visually inspected by television every five (5) years by the responsible utility or property owner to ensure both structural and pipe joint integrity. Existing manholes shall be visually inspected for both structural and incoming pipe connection integrity every five (5) years.
Certified test and inspection results and repair logs shall be submitted to the Department within thirty (30) days after completion of the particular test, inspection, or repair.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Storm water disposal methods. That the storm water disposal methods utilized or to be utilized will be limited as set forth in Table C-1.
Furthermore, land uses adjacent to the Snapper Creek extension canal and secondary canals directly connected to the Snapper Creek extension canal shall provide an earth berm, or alternative structure as approved by the Director or the Director's designee, which shall be constructed upon the perimeter of all canals to prevent overland storm water runoff from entering the canal. The berm shall be constructed adjacent to the canal top of slope on the landward side. Said berm shall extend one (1) foot above the canal bank elevation. The landward slope of the berm shall have a gradient not steeper than one (1) foot vertical to four (4) feet horizontal. The canalward slope shall not be steeper than the canal slope. The construction of berming and backsloping shall be subject to the approval of the Director or the Director's designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment methods other than septic tanks utilized for the disposal, discharge, storage or treatment of domestic sewage; sanitary sewer lift stations; and public sanitary sewers. That liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment methods (other than septic tanks utilized for the disposal, discharge, storage or treatment of domestic sewage; sanitary sewer lift stations; and public sanitary sewers); shall be prohibited within the Northwest Wellfield protection area, the West Wellfield Interim protection area, the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex, the average day pumpage wellfield protection areas of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, and Hialeah Wellfield, and the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well unless, in the case of property within the Northwest Wellfield protection area, said liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment method was installed prior to September 30, 1983, or, unless, in the case of property within the West Wellfield Interim protection area, said liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment method was installed prior to the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80] or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights wellfield complex installed prior to the effective date of this ordinance, or, unless, in the case of property within the average day pumpage wellfield protection area but not within the basic wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield and Southwest Wellfield, said liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment method was installed prior to February 1, 1985, or, in the case of property not within the basic wellfield protection area but within the average day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, and Hialeah Wellfield, said liquid waste, storage, disposal or treatment method was installed prior to December 12, 1986, unless in the case of property within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, said liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment method was installed prior to June 13, 1986.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Violations of this chapter. That the septic tank, sanitary sewer, storm water disposal method or liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment method utilized or to be utilized will serve an existing land use within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex, or within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, and Hialeah Wellfield, or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well and which is required by the Director or the Director's designee to correct violation(s) of this chapter. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the Director or the Director's designee shall not issue the Director's or the Director's designee's written approval unless the Director or the Director's designee determines that the land use will comply with all the provisions of this chapter and that the following water pollution prevention and abatement measures and practices shall be provided:
<section prefix = "i">
Monitoring and detection of water pollution caused by hazardous materials, and
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Secondary containment of water pollution caused by hazardous materials, and
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Inventory control and record keeping of hazardous materials, and
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
Storm water management of water pollution caused by hazardous materials, and
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
Protection and security of facilities utilized for the generation, storage, usage, handling, disposal or discharge of hazardous materials.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Prohibition of hazardous materials within wellfield protection areas. Notwithstanding any provisions of this Code, no County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board shall approve, grant or issue any building permit, certificate of use and occupancy (except for changes in ownership), municipal occupational license (except for changes in ownership), platting action (final plat, waiver of plat or equivalent municipal platting action) or zoning action (district boundary change, unusual use, use variance or equivalent municipal zoning action) for any nonresidential land use, other than a bona fide agricultural land use, a bona fide rockmining use (lake excavation), a public sewer facilities use, or a public water supply facilities use, within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex, or within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, or Hialeah Wellfield or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, without obtaining the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee. The Director or the Director's designee shall issue the Director's or the Director's designee's written approval only if the Director or the Director's designee determines that the nonresidential land use is in compliance with Sections 24-43(5)(a), 24-43(5)(b) or 24-43(5)(c).
Furthermore, notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no person shall construct, utilize, operate, occupy or cause, allow, let, permit or suffer to be constructed, utilized, operated or occupied any nonresidential land use, other than a bona fide agricultural land use, a public sewer facilities use, or a public water supply facilities use, within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex, or within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, or Hialeah Wellfield, or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, and which uses, generates, handles, disposes of, discharges or stores hazardous materials, until the person has obtained the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee.
Pursuant to the foregoing, the Director or the Director's designee shall issue his written approval only if the Director or the Director's designee determines that all potential sources of pollution will be installed upon the property as far away as is reasonably possible from all potable water supply wells; hazardous materials will not be used, generated, handled, disposed of, discharged or stored on that portion of the property within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well; and hazardous wastes will not be used, generated, handled, disposed of, discharged or stored on that portion of the property within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex, or within the average day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, or Hialeah Wellfield.
Notwithstanding the foregoing, fuels and lubricants required for rockmining operations (lake excavations, concrete batch plants, rock crushing and aggregate plants) within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area; electrical transformers serving nonresidential land uses; small quantity generators of hazardous wastes as defined in this chapter, within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex or within the average day pumpage wellfield protection area but not within the basic wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, Hialeah Wellfield, and the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex and existing land uses required by the Director or the Director's designee to correct violations of this chapter; shall not be prohibited when the water pollution prevention and abatement measures and practices set forth in Sections 24-43(5)(a)(i), (ii), (iii), (iv) and (v) will be provided and the Director or the Director's designee has approved same.
Notwithstanding the foregoing, the use, handling or storage of factory prepackaged products intended primarily for domestic use or consumption determined by the Director or the Director's designee to be hazardous materials shall not be prohibited; provided, however, that the requirements of Sections 24-43(5)(a)(vi), (vii), (viii) and (ix) are fulfilled.
<section prefix = "a">
The owner of the property has submitted to the Director or the Director's designee a covenant running with the land executed by the owner of the property in favor of Miami-Dade County which provides that hazardous materials shall not be used, generated, handled, disposed of, discharged or stored on that portion of the property located within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well; and that hazardous wastes shall not be used, generated, handled, disposed of, discharged or stored on that portion of the property within the average day pumpage wellfield protection area but not within the basic wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, or Hialeah Wellfield, or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex.
Furthermore, the aforesaid covenant shall provide that fuels and lubricants required for rockmining operations (lake excavations, concrete batch plants, rock crushing and aggregate plants) within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area; electrical transformers serving nonresidential land uses; small quantity generators of hazardous wastes as defined in this chapter, within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex or within the average day pumpage wellfield protection area but not within the basic wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, and Hialeah Wellfield and existing land uses required by the Director or the Director's designee to correct violations of this chapter; shall not be prohibited when the following water pollution prevention and abatement measures and practices will be provided:
<section prefix = "i">
Monitoring and detection of water pollution caused by hazardous materials, and
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Secondary containment of water pollution caused by hazardous materials, and
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Inventory control and record keeping of hazardous materials, and
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
Storm water management of water pollution caused by hazardous materials, and
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
Protection and security of facilities utilized for the generation, storage, usage, handling, disposal or discharge of hazardous materials.
Said water pollution prevention and abatement measures and practices shall be subject to the approval of the Director or the Director's designee.
Furthermore, the aforesaid covenant shall provide that use, handling or storage of factory pre-packaged products intended primarily for domestic use or consumption determined by the Director or the Director's designee to be hazardous materials shall not be prohibited, provided, however, that:
</section>
<section prefix = "vi">
The use, handling or storage of said factory prepackaged products occurs only within a building, and
</section>
<section prefix = "vii">
The nonresidential land use is an office building use (or equivalent municipal land use) or a business district use (or equivalent municipal land use) engaged exclusively in retail sales of factory prepackaged products intended primarily for domestic use or consumption, and
</section>
<section prefix = "viii">
The nonresidential land use is served or is to be served by public water and public sanitary sewers, and
</section>
<section prefix = "ix">
Said building is located more than thirty (30) days' travel time from any public utility potable water supply well.
Said covenants shall be in a form(s) prescribed by the Director and approved by the Board of County Commissioners. The covenants shall be recorded in the public records of Miami-Dade County, Florida, by the Department at the expense of the owner of the property, or
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
If the Director or the Director's designee determines that the owner of the property is applying for the original certificate of use and occupancy or original municipal occupational license pursuant to a valid building permit obtained prior to June 1, 1983, for property within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, or, in the case of property within the Northwest Wellfield protection area, obtained prior to September 30, 1983, or, in the case of the West Wellfield Interim protection boundary, obtained prior to the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80] or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex obtained prior to the effective date of this ordinance, or, in the case of property within the average day pumpage wellfield protection area, but not within the basic wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield or Southwest Wellfield, obtained prior to February 1, 1985 or, in the case of property not within the basic wellfield protection area but within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield or Hialeah Wellfield, obtained prior to December 12, 1986 and which permit has been valid and continuously in full force and effect since its issuance, or
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
If the Director or the Director's designee determines:
<section prefix = "i">
That the application for a building permit, certificate of use and occupancy (except for changes in ownership), municipal occupational license (except for changes in ownership), platting action (final plat, waiver of plat or equivalent municipal platting action) or zoning action (district boundary change, unusual use, use variance or equivalent municipal zoning action) is for the replacement, modification or limited expansion of an existing facility, provided in no case shall such replacement, modification or limited expansion cause, permit, let, suffer or allow the use, generation, handling, disposal, discharge or storage of hazardous materials on the property to be increased by more than fifty (50) percent over the use, generation, handling, disposal, discharge or storage of hazardous materials which existed on the property on September 30, 1983, for properties within the Northwest Wellfield protection area, or which existed on the property on the effective date of this ordinance [Ord. No. 89-80] for properties within the West Wellfield Interim protection area, or which existed on March 13, 1981 for properties within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, and
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
That the proposed replacement, modification or limited expansion of the existing facility will substantially reduce the existing risk of pollution from the hazardous materials to the closest public utility potable water supply well. In determining whether there will be a substantial reduction of the existing risk of pollution as aforesaid, the Director or the Director's designee shall consider the following factors and shall render written findings as to the Director's or the Director's designee's assessment of each:
<section prefix = "1">
Whether the proposed replacement, modification or limited expansion of the facility will provide adequate and increased monitoring and detection of pollution which may be or which has been caused by the hazardous materials on the property.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Whether the proposed replacement, modification or limited expansion of the facility will provide adequate and increased secondary containment of pollution which may be or which has been caused by the hazardous materials on the property.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Whether the proposed replacement, modification or limited expansion will provide adequate and increased inventory control and record keeping of hazardous materials on the property.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Whether the proposed replacement, modification or limited expansion will provide adequate and increased storm water management of pollution which may be or which has been caused by the hazardous materials on the property.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Whether the proposed replacement, modification or limited expansion will provide adequate and increased protection and security of the facilities utilized for the generation, storage, usage, handling, disposal, or discharge of hazardous materials on the property.
The Director or the Director's designee shall determine that there will be a substantial reduction of the existing risk of pollution from the hazardous materials to the closest public utility potable water supply well only if the Director or the Director's designee makes affirmative findings as to all of the aforesaid factors, and
<section prefix = "iii">
That the owner of the property has submitted to the Director or the Director's designee a covenant running with the land executed by the owner of the property in favor of Miami-Dade County which provides that the hazardous materials to be used, generated, handled, disposed of, discharged or stored on the property after the proposed replacement, modification or limited expansion is approved by the Director or the Director's designee, pursuant to this section, shall not be more hazardous than the hazardous materials used, generated, handled, disposed of, discharged or stored on the property at the time of the aforesaid approval and which furthermore shall require written notice by the owner of the property to the Department of any change in the kind of hazardous materials on the property after the aforesaid approval. Said covenants shall be in a form(s) prescribed by the Director and approved by the Board of County Commissioners. The covenants shall be recorded in the public records of Miami-Dade County, Florida, by the Department at the expense of the owner of the property.
<section prefix = "6">
Applicability of travel time ranges within wellfield protection areas. The Director or the Director's designee shall utilize the following procedures when making a determination under Tables A-1, A-2, A-3, A-4 or B-1:
<section prefix = "a">
Property wholly located within one (1) travel time range having restrictions shall be governed by the restrictions under that travel time range.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Property within two (2) or more travel time ranges having restrictions shall be governed by the total sewage loading for the property. The total sewage loading shall be derived by adding the sewage loading within each travel time range and dividing the resultant amount by the gross acreage for the property.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Property within both restricted and unrestricted travel time ranges shall be governed in accordance with Section 24-43(6)(b) herein except that portion of the property outside of the restricted travel time ranges shall be excluded from averaging the applicable restrictions as aforesaid. However, all septic tanks, septic tank drainfields, storm water disposal methods and liquid waste storage, disposal and treatment methods shall be installed upon the property as far away as is reasonably possible from all potable water supply wells.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Excavations. Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board shall approve, grant, or issue any permit, of any kind whatsoever, certificate of completion, platting action (final plat, waiver of plat or equivalent municipal platting action) or zoning action (district boundary change, unusual use, use variance or equivalent municipal zoning action) for any excavation within the Northwest Wellfield protection area, or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area, or the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, or within one-quarter (¼) of a mile of the perimeter of the Miami-Dade County 58th Street landfill, United Sanitation landfill, or the resources recovery facility until the County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board has obtained the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee.
Furthermore, notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no person shall cause, allow, let, permit or suffer any excavation within the Northwest Wellfield protection area, or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area, or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well until the person has obtained the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee.
The Director or the Director's designee shall issue his written approval only if the Director or the Director's designee determines that the excavation will comply with the following:
<section prefix = "a">
The property upon which the excavation has occurred or will occur and that portion of the property which has not been excavated or will not be excavated shall be provided with protection and security measures to prohibit the handling, disposal of, discharge or storage of hazardous materials, solid waste, or liquid waste in the excavation or on the property which has not been excavated or will not be excavated. Said protection and security shall be subject to the approval of the Director or the Director's designee.
Furthermore, the owner of the property upon which the excavation has occurred or will occur and that portion of the property which has not been excavated or will not be excavated shall submit to the Director or the Director's designee a covenant running with the land executed by the owner of the property in favor of Miami-Dade County which provides that protection and security measures shall be provided subject to the approval of the Director or the Director's designee. Said covenants shall be executed by the owner of the property upon which the excavation has occurred or will occur and that portion of the property which has not been excavated or will not be excavated in form(s) prescribed by the Director and approved by the Board of County Commissioners. The covenants shall be recorded in the public records of Miami-Dade County, Florida, by the Department at the expense of the owner of the property upon which the excavation has occurred or will occur and the property which has not been excavated or will not be excavated, and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The excavation will not be located within thirty (30) days' travel time from any public utility potable water supply well or within thirty (30) days' travel time from potable water supply wells as set forth on the West Wellfield Interim protection area map(s) and the excavation will not exceed a depth of forty (40) feet below existing grade within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, or
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The excavation will not be located within thirty (30) days' travel time from any public utility potable water supply well and there exists property without excavation which will provide an additional thirty (30) days' travel time between the excavation and any public utility potable water supply well.
Furthermore, the owner of the property upon which the excavation is to occur shall submit to the Director or the Director's designee a covenant running with the land executed by the owner of the property in favor of Miami-Dade County which provides that the property without excavation aforesaid will not be subject to excavation at any time. Said covenants shall be executed by the owner of the property without excavation aforesaid and in a form(s) prescribed by the Director and approved by the Board of County Commissioners. The covenants shall be recorded in the public records of Miami-Dade County, Florida, by the Department at the expense of the owner of the property upon which the excavation is to occur, or
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The excavation has a valid excavation permit or equivalent municipal permit for excavation and a valid Class IV permit, if required by Article IV of this chapter, which was obtained prior to September 30, 1983, which permits have been valid and continuously in full force and effect since their issuance.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Pipelines for hazardous materials. Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board, after July 13, 1984 shall approve, grant or issue any permit of any kind whatsoever for the installation, modification, or expansion of that portion of any pipeline used or to be used for the transmission or storage of any hazardous materials and which portion is within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield or Southwest Wellfield or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well or, in the case of that portion of any pipeline not within the basic wellfield protection area but within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield or Hialeah Wellfield, after December 12, 1986, or, in the case of that portion of any pipeline within the West Wellfield Interim protection area, after the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80] or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex after the effective date of this ordinance.
Furthermore, notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no person shall install, construct, utilize, operate, occupy or cause, allow, let, permit or suffer to be installed, constructed, utilized, operated or occupied any pipeline or portion of any pipeline used or to be used for the transmission or storage of any hazardous materials within the Northwest Wellfield Protection Area or the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield or Southwest Wellfield or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, after July 13, 1984, unless said person installed, constructed, utilized, operated or occupied said pipeline used or to be used for the transmission or storage of hazardous materials before July 13, 1984, or, in the case of the West Wellfield Interim protection area, no person shall install, construct, utilize, operate, occupy or cause, allow, let, permit or suffer to be installed, constructed, utilized, operated or occupied any pipeline or portion of any pipeline used or to be used for the transmission or storage of any hazardous materials within the West Wellfield Interim protection area after the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80] or, in the case of that portion of any pipeline within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex after the effective date of this ordinance unless said person installed, constructed, utilized, operated or occupied said pipeline used or to be used for the transmission or storage of hazardous materials prior to the effective date of this ordinance, unless said person installed, constructed, utilized, operated or occupied said pipeline used or to be used for the transmission or storage of hazardous materials prior to the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80].
Furthermore, notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no person shall install, construct, utilize, operate, occupy or cause, allow, let, permit or suffer to be constructed, utilized, operated or occupied any pipeline or portion of any pipeline used or to be used for the transmission or storage of any hazardous materials within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area but not within the basic wellfield protection area of the Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield or Hialeah Wellfield after the effective date of this subsection [December 12, 1986], unless said person installed, constructed, utilized, operated or occupied said pipeline used or to be used for the transmission or storage of hazardous materials before the effective date of this subsection [December 12, 1986].
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Water conservation restrictions for the protection of the Northwest Wellfield. The Director or the Director's designee shall evaluate the data from a groundwater elevation monitoring program and a groundwater quality monitoring program for the Northwest Wellfield which programs shall be conducted by the Department or a contractor designated by the County. If the Director or the Director's designee, after evaluating the aforesaid monitoring data, determines that a reduction in wellfield pumpage is necessary to prevent contamination of the Northwest Wellfield, the Director or the Director's designee shall impose water conservation restrictions in the unincorporated and incorporated areas of Miami-Dade County. These water conservation restrictions shall consist of one (1) of, or any combination of, the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Ordering public utilities owning or operating public water systems to reduce water system pressure.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Mandatory water conservation restrictions similar to the applicable water use restrictions set forth in the rules of the South Florida Water Management District, Chapter 40E-21, Florida Administrative Code, as may be amended from time to time.
The duration of these water conservation restrictions shall be determined by the Director or the Director's designee after periodic evaluation of wellfield pumpage data and pertinent monitoring program data. The water conservation restrictions in effect may be subsequently changed or rescinded by the Director or the Director's designee after such periodic evaluation.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Land uses within the Northwest Wellfield protection area and West Wellfield Interim protection area. Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no County officer, agent, employee or board shall approve, grant or issue any building permit, certificate of use and occupancy (except for changes in ownership), platting action (final plat, waiver of plat) or zoning action (district boundary change, unusual use, use variance, new use, similar use) for any land use within the Northwest Wellfield protection area, or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area, without obtaining the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee. Furthermore, notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no person shall construct, utilize, operate, occupy or cause, allow, let, permit or suffer to be constructed, utilized, operated or occupied any land use within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area without obtaining the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee.
The Director or the Director's designee shall issue his written approval only if:
<section prefix = "a">
The Director or the Director's designee determines that the property is within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area and the existing land use(s) for the property or the land use(s) requested for the property is one (1) or more of the land uses set forth in Table E-1 and the land use(s) is not a land use found exclusively in the following Miami-Dade County zoning classifications or that the zoning classification requested is not one (1) or more of the following Miami-Dade County zoning classifications:
<section prefix = "i">
BU-3 (excluding those land uses permitted by BU-1, BU-1A or BU-2),
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
IU-1,
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
IU-2,
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
IU-3,
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
IU-C, or
<section prefix = "b">
The Director or the Director's designee determines that the land use is not listed in Table E-1, the land use(s) is not set forth as a permitted use, special exception, unusual use or conditional use in Chapter 33 of this Code, the land use(s) is not a land use(s) found exclusively in the zoning classifications listed in Sections 24-43(10)(a)(i), (ii), (iii), (iv), (v), above the land use(s) is comparable to a land use(s) set forth in Table E-1, and the land use(s) will not have an adverse environmental impact on groundwater quality in the North Wellfield protection area and within the West Wellfield protection area. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the Director or the Director's designee shall not determine that the land use is comparable to land use(s) set forth in Table E-1 if the land use is permitted in one (1) or more of the following Miami-Dade County zoning classifications and if the land use is not permitted in one (1) or more Miami-Dade County zoning classifications which are less restrictive than the following BU-3; IU-1; IU-2; IU-3; and IU-C.
<section prefix = "i">
In determining whether a land use is comparable to one (1) or more land use(s) set forth in Table E-1, the Director or the Director's designee shall consider the following factors:
<section prefix = "1">
The materials used, handled and stored, and the products and wastes produced;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The activities, processes and methods which are employed and utilized;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The machinery and other facilities utilized and maintenance requirements of said machinery and facilities;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Uses commonly attendant to or associated with the primary use.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
In determining whether a land use does not or will not have an adverse environmental impact on the groundwater quality in the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield protection area, the Director or the Director's designee shall consider the following factors:
<section prefix = "1">
The land use will not be detrimental to the public health, welfare and safety and will not create a nuisance and will not materially increase the level of water pollution within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The use, generation, handling, disposal of, discharge or storage of hazardous materials will not occur within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The only liquid waste (excluding stormwater) which will be generated, disposed of, discharged, or stored within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area shall be domestic sewage discharged to a public sanitary sewer or septic tank;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Stormwater runoff shall be retained on the property and disposed of through infiltration drainage systems supplemented with seepage drainage systems, or
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Director or the Director's designee, determines that: The property is within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area; the owner of the property is applying for the original certificate of use and occupancy or original municipal occupational license pursuant to a valid building permit obtained prior to December 12, 1986, in the case of the Northwest Wellfield protection area, or August 6, 1989, in the case of the West Wellfield Interim protection area, which permit has been valid and continuously in full force and effect since its issuance; the property is served or will be served by a public water main and public sanitary sewer no later than the date that the original certificate of use and occupancy or original municipal occupational license is issued; and the property is in compliance with Sections 24-43(4), (5) and (6) of this Code and was in compliance with Sections 24-43(4), (5) and (6) of this Code no later than the date of issuance of the aforesaid valid building permit.
TABLE E-1
Allowable Land Uses Within the Northwest Wellfield Protection Area and Within the West Wellfield Interim Protection Area
Land Use

Abstract title
Accounts, bookkeeping
Actuaries
Advertising office only; no printing
Agricultural use
Alcoholic beverage district, sales
Amusement, game room
Animals, birds, and tropical fish, retail only
Antique shops
Apparel sales, rentals
Apartment house
Appliance and fixture sales (no service)
Appraisers (no merchandise)
Archery range
Art gallery
Art goods and bric-a-brac shops
Artist studios
Auction sales (no hazardous materials)
Auditoriums
Bait and tackle shop
Bakeries, retail
Bakeries, wholesale
Banks
Barbecue restaurants, stands, pits (wood for cooking) drive-in theaters
Barbershop
Bars
Baseball field
Bath and massage parlors
Bathing beaches
Bicycle sales (no service)
Billiard parlor/pool hall
Bindery (books, publications, etc.)
Bingo
Boat piers, docks
Book store (new and used)
Bottled gas storage (liquefied petroleum gas and natural gas only)
Bowling alleys
Box lunches—Wholesale and retail with delivery trucks (no truck maintenance)
Broadcasting studios (radio and TV, including transmitting station and tower, incidental electrical generation by LP or natural gas only)
Business machines sales (typewriters, calculators, etc.) (no service)
Camps
Card club/public
Card shops
Carpet sales
Caterers
Churches
Cigar making and sales
Cigarette vending
Clubs (private)
Coin laundries (no dry cleaning machines)
Coin shop
Cold storage warehouses and pre-cooling plants
Colleges (no hazardous materials)
Computer service
Concrete, cement, clay products—Storage and sales (no vehicle maintenance; no on-site fuel storage)
Confectionery (and ice cream stores)
Conservatories
Convent
Convention halls
Costuming shops
Curio stores
Dance halls, schools, academies
Day camp
Day care, nursery
Department store
Dependent children (home for)
Drive shop
Docks, piers—Boat
Dog obedience training, training tracks, schools
Dormitories
Drapery stores, drapery making
Dressed poultry and sea food stores
Drive-through banks and restaurants
Drug store
Dry cleaning (no cleaning on premises)
Dynamite storage
Electric substations
Electrolysis office (removal of hair by electrolytic process)
Employment agencies
Entrance gates
Escort service
Farms
Fire station (no hazardous materials)
Fishing camps
Fish houses, market, smoking
Fish, tropical, aquariums (retail sales only)
Flea market
Florist shops
Flower importers
Food distribution (no on-site vehicle maintenance)
Food sales
Foster home
Fraternities
Fruit packing, fruit stores, fruit stands
Furniture sales, rental and storage (no restoration, no manufacturing)
Furriers (sales and storage)
Garment manufacturing (no dyeing)
Gas (natural gas, LP gas including distribution system and bottling plant)
Gift stores
Glass blowing
Golf course, clubhouse
Golf driving range
Grocery store
Gun shop
Haberdashery
Hall for hire
Handball court
Health spa
Homes for dependent children
Hotels, motels
Houses of worship
Ice cream stores
Ice manufacturing, distributing (emergency electrical generation by LP or natural gas only)
Import-export office
Insurance office
Interior decorators office, showroom
Jai alai
Jewelry sales (no manufacturing)
Judo and karate instructions
Key shop
Kindergartens, day care
Lake excavation
Laundries (all types, no dry cleaning)
Leather goods stores (retail)
Libraries (public)
Limestone quarrying, rock crushing and aggregate plants ancillary to section in connection with limestone quarrying (no on-site fuel storage except that the use of fuels and lubricants and LP and natural gas storage are permitted)
Liquefied petroleum (LP) gas
Liquor package stores
Livery stable
Lodges (private)
Lounges
Luggage sales
Lunches (packaging, catering)
Mail order office
Massage parlor
Meat market
Men's store
Messenger office
Milk store (drive-in)
Miniature golf course
Mission
Mobile homes
Mobile homes, sales (no manufacturing or repair; and no motor homes or recreational vehicles)
Monastery
Motel
Modeling (agencies, schools)
Motion picture studio (no film developing)
Motion picture theatre, indoor and outdoor
Motion pictures and equipment, sales and rental (no equipment servicing, no film developing)
Moving and storage company (no on-site vehicle maintenance)
Municipal recreation building
Museums, public
Music stores, teaching
Newsstand
Night club
Notions sales
Office building
Office, professional
Open air theaters
Optical stores
Package stores
Palmistry
Paneling (wall/retail sales)
Paper salvage
Park or playground, public or private
Parking lot, parking garage (no auto pound, no tow yard, no on-site vehicle repair)
Passenger stations (railroad, bus)
Pawn shops (swap shops)
Pet shops, retail sales only (in air conditioned building)
Pharmaceuticals (retail)
Photographic studio (no developing, no printing)
Pillow renovating
Plant sales (no propagation)
Plaster products
Plasterers, storage area
Police station
Pool rooms
Post office
Pottery (retail sales only/no manufacturing)
Private clubs
Produce or fruit market
Professional and semiprofessional offices (no medical laboratory or clinic)
Public art galleries, museums
Racquet ball clubs
Radio, broadcasting station, studio, transmitting station/tower (emergency electrical power by LP or natural gas only)
Railroad and bus passenger stations (no freight terminal, no vehicle maintenance)
Real estate office
Recording studios
Recreational facilities
Rentals (household equipment, appliances, tools, hardware, etc.) (no hazardous materials)
Residential uses
Restaurants, including outdoor patios and service
Retirement villages
Rifle, pistol range
Rock and sand yards
Rock yards (crushing)
Saloons and bars
Savings and loan associations
Schools (no hazardous materials)
Seafood stores
Secondhand stores (inside only)
Shoe store (no manufacturing)
Shooting gallery
Shooting range, trap and skeet
Shopping center (no hazardous materials)
Showrooms, salesrooms (no hazardous materials)
Skating rink
Sororities
Souvenir stores
Sporting goods store
Stationery stores
Storage warehouse (no hazardous materials)
Swap shops
Swimming pools
Synagogues
Tailor shops
Tattoo parlor
Telegraph stations (emergency electrical power by LP or natural gas only)
Telephone answering service
Telephone exchange
Television (broadcasting studio)
Tennis courts
Textile sales
Theaters
Tile sales (no manufacturing)
Tourist attractions (no hazardous materials)
Trading post
Trailer park
Travel agency
Upholstery shop
Utilities: Public and private water production, treatment and distribution facilities; and sewage except that wastewater treatment plants are not permitted (emergency electrical power by LP or natural gas only)
Vegetable stands
Wall paper, paneling (retail sales)
Warehouses (storage of food, fodder, apparel, and other nonhazardous materials)
Watchman's quarters
Water tanks or towers
Water treatment plants (emergency electrical power by LP or natural gas only)
Wearing apparel stores (sales, rentals)
Wholesale salesrooms and attendant storage rooms (no hazardous materials)
<section prefix = "11">
Prohibition of resources recovery and management facility within wellfield protection areas. Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board shall approve, grant, modify or issue any permit (except for renewal of valid operating permits, issued pursuant to this chapter, no later than March 12, 1987), certificate of use and occupancy (except for changes in ownership), platting action (final plan, waiver of plat or equivalent municipal platting action) or zoning action (district boundary change, unusual use, use variance or equivalent municipal zoning action) for any resource recovery and management facility within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, or Hialeah Wellfield, or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well after December 12, 1986, unless said resource recovery and management facility was in operation and had obtained all other applicable permits prior to June 25, 1986 and obtained a valid operating permit issued pursuant to this chapter no later than March 12, 1987 or, in the case of a resource recovery and management facility within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex, was in operation and had obtained all other applicable permits prior to the effective date of this ordinance.
Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board shall approve, grant, modify or issue any permit (except for renewal of valid operating permits issued pursuant to this chapter, renewed no later than ninety (90) days after the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80]), certificate of use and occupancy (except for changes in ownership), platting action (final plat, waiver of plat or equivalent municipal platting action) or zoning action (district boundary change, unusual use, use variance or equivalent municipal zoning action) for any resource recovery and management facility (unless the facility's primary purpose is to collect paper, glass, plastics or aluminium for transport out of the West Wellfield Interim protection area or the facility provides composting for on-site organic plant materials at plant nurseries) within the West Wellfield Interim protection area after the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80], unless said resource recovery and management facility was in operation and had obtained all other applicable permits prior to the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80] and obtained a valid operating permit issued pursuant to this chapter no later than ninety (90) days after the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80].
Furthermore, notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no person shall construct, utilize, operate, occupy or cause, allow, let, permit or suffer to be constructed, utilized, operated or occupied any resource recovery and management facility within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, or Hialeah Wellfield, or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well after December 12, 1986, unless said resource recovery and management facility was in operation and had obtained all other applicable permits prior to June 25, 1986 and obtained a valid operating permit pursuant to this chapter, no later than March 12, 1987 or, in the case of a resource recovery and management facility within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex, was in operation and had obtained all other applicable permits prior to the effective date of this ordinance.
Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no person shall construct, utilize, operate, occupy or cause, allow, let, permit or suffer to be constructed, utilized, operated or occupied any resources recovery and management facility within the West Wellfield Interim protection area after the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80], unless said resource recovery and management facility was in operation and had obtained all other applicable permits prior to the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80] and obtained a valid operating permit pursuant to this chapter, no later than ninety (90) days after the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80].

TABLE A-1 Residential Property Served by Septic Tank and Using Public Water Supply
<section prefix="1" type="table">
<table class="table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Travel Time in Days or Distance in Feet from Property to Nearest Public Utility Potable Water Supply Well</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Maximum Allowable Sewage Loading for Property Not Having Indigenous Sandy Substrata (Gallons Per Day Per Unsubmerged Acre)</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Maximum Allowable Sewage Loading for Property Having Indigenous Sandy Substrata (Gallons Per Day Per Unsubmerged Acre)</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than 100 days but not exceeding 210 days</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">850</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">As allowed by<a href="../level4/PTIIICOOR_CH24ENPRBIBAENDEAQPACOARBIBAENENTRFUENENLAPR_ARTIIIWASOQU_DIV2WEPRDOWESYPOWAST.html#PTIIICOOR_CH24ENPRBIBAENDEAQPACOARBIBAENENTRFUENENLAPR_ARTIIIWASOQU_DIV2WEPRDOWESYPOWAST_S24-43.1LIWADIPOWASUSY"> Section 24-43.1</a> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than 30 days but not exceeding 100 days</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">600</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">850</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than 10 days but not exceeding 30 days</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">350 with minimum of 24 inches in Class II silica sand under drainfield</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">600 with minimum of 24 inches of Class II silica sand or indigenous sand under drainfield</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than 100 feet but not exceeding 10 days</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">140 with minimum of 24 inches of Class II silica sand under drainfield</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">350 with minimum of 24 inches of Class II silica sand or indigenous sand under drainfield</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">100 feet or less</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 

TABLE A-2 Residential Property Served by Septic Tank and Not Using Public Water Supply
<section prefix="2" type="table">
<table class="table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Travel Time in Days or Distance in Feet from Property to Nearest Public Utility Potable Water Supply Well</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Maximum Allowable Sewage Loading for Property Not Having Indigenous Sandy Substrata (Gallons Per Day Per Unsubmerged Acre)</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Maximum Allowable Sewage Loading for Property Having Indigenous Sandy Substrata (Gallons Per Day Per Unsubmerged Acre)</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than 100 days</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">750 with minimum of 24 inches of Class II silica sand under drainfield</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">750 with minimum of 24 inches of Class II silica sand or indigenous sand under drainfield</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than 30 days but not exceeding 100 days</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">600 with minimum of 24 inches of Class II silica sand under drainfield</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">750 with minimum of 24 inches of Class II silica sand or indigenous sand under drainfield</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than 10 days but not exceeding 30 days</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">350 with minimum of 24 inches of Class II silica sand under drainfield</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">600 with minimum of 24 inches of Class II silica sand or indigenous sand under drainfield</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than 100 feet but not exceeding 10 days</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">140 with minimum of 24 inches of Class II silica sand under drainfield</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">350 with minimum of 24 inches of Class II silica sand or indigenous sand under drainfield</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">100 feet or less</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 

TABLE A-3 Nonresidential Property Served by Septic Tank, Using Public Water Supply, and Not Using, Generating, Handling, Disposing, Discharging or Storing Hazardous Materials
TABLE INSET:
<section prefix="3" type="table">
<table class="table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Travel Time in Days or Distance in Feet from Property to Nearest Public Utility Potable Water Supply Well</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Maximum Allowable Sewage Loading for Property Not Having Indigenous Sandy Substrata (Gallons Per Day Per Unsubmerged Acre)</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Maximum Allowable Sewage Loading for Property Having Indigenous Sandy Substrata (Gallons Per Day Per Unsubmerged Acre)</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than 100 days but not exceeding 210 days</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">850</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1,500</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than 30 days but not exceeding 100 days</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">600</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">850</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than 10 days but not exceeding 30 days</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">350 with minimum of 24 inches of Class II silica sand under drainfield</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">600 with minimum of 24 inches Class II silica sand or indigenous sand under drainfield</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than 100 feet but not exceeding 10 days</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">140 with minimum of 24 inches of Class II silica sand under drainfield</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">350 with minimum of 24 inches of Class II silica sand or indigenous sand under drainfield</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">100 feet or less</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 

TABLE A-4 Nonresidential Property Served by Septic Tank, Not Using Public Water Supply, and Not Using, Generating, Handling, Storing, Disposing or Discharging Hazardous Materials
<section prefix="4" type="table">
<table class="table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Travel Time in Days or Distance in Feet from Property to Nearest Public Utility Potable Water Supply Well</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Maximum Allowable Sewage Loading for Property Not Having Indigenous Sandy Substrata (Gallons Per Day Per Unsubmerged Acre)</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Maximum Allowable Sewage Loading for Property Having Indigenous Sandy Substrata (Gallons Per Day Per Unsubmerged Acre)</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than 100 days</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">750 with minimum of 24 inches of Class II silica sand under drainfield</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">750 with minimum of 24 inches of Class II silica sand or indigenous sand under drainfield</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than 30 days but not exceeding 100 days</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">600 with minimum of 24 inches of Class II silica sand under drainfield</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">750 with minimum of 24 inches of Class II silica sand or indigenous sand under drainfield</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than 10 days but not exceeding 30 days</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">350 with minimum of 24 inches of Class II silica sand under drainfield</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">600 with minimum of 24 inches of Class II silica sand or indigenous sand under drainfield</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than 100 feet but not exceeding 10 days</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">140 with minimum of 24 inches of Class II silica sand under drainfield</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">350 with minimum of 24 inches of Class II silica sand or indigenous sand under drainfield</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">100 feet or less</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 

TABLE B-1 Residential Property Served by Sanitary Sewers; Nonresidential Property Served by Sanitary Sewers and Not Using, Generating, Handling, Disposing, Discharging or Storing Hazardous Materials
<section prefix="5" type="table">
<table class="table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Travel Time in Days or Distance in Feet from Property to Nearest Public Utility Potable Water Supply Well</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Maximum Allowable Sewage Loading for Property Not Having Indigenous Sandy Substrata (Gallons Per Day Per Unsubmerged Acre)</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Maximum Allowable Sewage Loading for Property Having Indigenous Sandy Substrata (Gallons Per Day Per Unsubmerged Acre)</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than 30 days</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">No additional restrictions</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">No additional restrictions</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than 10 days but not exceeding 30 days</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1600</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">No additional restrictions</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than 100 feet but not exceeding 10 days</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">850</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1600</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">100 feet or less</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 

TABLE C-1 Allowable Storm Water Disposal Methods for Residential and Nonresidential Property
<section prefix="6" type="table">
<table class="table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Travel Time in Days or Distance in Feet from Property to Nearest Public Utility Potable Water Supply Well</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Allowable Methods for Storm Water Disposal</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than 30 days but not exceeding 210 days</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Infiltration or seepage or overflow outfalls only</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than 10 days but not exceeding 30 days</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Infiltration or seepage only</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">More than 100 feet but not exceeding 10 days</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Infiltration only</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">100 feet or less</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">None</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 

 
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-43.1. Liquid waste disposal and potable water supply systems</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
The intent and purpose of this section is to safeguard the public health, safety, and welfare by regulating liquid waste storage, disposal and treatment methods other than sanitary sewers and any source of potable water supply.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
No person shall discharge or cause, allow, permit, let or suffer to be discharged any liquid waste or other substance of any kind whatsoever into a septic tank other than domestic sewage.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board shall approve, grant or issue any building permit, certificate of use and occupancy (except for changes in ownership), municipal occupational license (except for changes in ownership), platting action (final plat, waiver of plat or equivalent municipal platting action) or zoning action (district boundary change, unusual use, use variance or equivalent municipal zoning action) for any residential land use served or to be served by a septic tank or any source of potable water supply until the County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board affirmatively determines that the residential land use will comply with one (1) or more of the requirements as set forth in Sections 24-43.1(3)(a), (b), (c), (d), (e), and (f) and Section 24-43.2(1) of this Code, and, additionally, that the property is not within a feasible distance for a public water main or public sanitary sewers.
Furthermore, notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no person shall construct, utilize, operate, occupy or cause, allow, let, permit or suffer to be constructed, utilized, operated or occupied any residential land use served or to be served by a septic tank or any source of potable water supply until the County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board affirmatively determines that the residential land use will comply with one (1) or more of the requirements set forth in Sections 24-43.1(3)(a), (b), (c), (d), (e) and (f) and Section 24-43.2(1) of this Code, and, additionally, that the property is not within a feasible distance for a public water main or public sanitary sewers.
<section prefix = "a">
Where public water is used:
<section prefix = "i">
The minimum lot size for a single-family residence shall be fifteen thousand (15,000) square feet of unsubmerged land;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
The minimum lot size for a duplex residence shall be twenty thousand (20,000) square feet of unsubmerged land;
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
The maximum sewage loading for all other residential uses shall be one thousand five hundred (1,500) gallons per day per unsubmerged acre; or
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Where public water is not used:
<section prefix = "i">
The minimum lot size for a single-family residence shall be twenty thousand three hundred twenty-eight (20,328) square feet of unsubmerged land;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
The minimum lot size for a duplex residence shall be twenty-nine thousand forty (29,040) square feet of unsubmerged land;
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
The maximum sewage loading for all other residential uses shall be seven hundred fifty (750) gallons per day per unsubmerged acre; or
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
In the case of a property owner who has requested to use a tract of land for a single-family residence or duplex residence but which tract of land fails to comply with the minimum lot size requirements of Section 24-43.1(3)(a)(i) or Section 24-43.1(3)(a)(ii) hereof and a public right-of-way containing an available and operative public water main or easement containing an available and operative public water main abuts said tract of land, the Director or the Director's designee has issued his written approval for the use of a septic tank for such single-family residence or duplex residence. The Director or the Director's designee shall issue his written approval only if he finds that said tract of land was created by deed prior to January 1, 1958, or was created by plat approved by the governmental authorities having jurisdiction prior to January 1, 1972, provided that said tract of land, as created by the originally recorded plat or originally recorded deed, has continuously remained in the same form as set forth in the originally recorded plat or deed, or
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The Director or the Director's designee has issued his written approval for any residential land use served or to be served by a public water main and a septic tank. The Director or the Director's designee shall issue his written approval only if he finds the following:
<section prefix = "i">
That extension of public sanitary sewers to serve the property from the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer is not within a feasible distance for public sanitary sewers, and
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
That more than fifty (50) percent of an area, consisting of a minimum of one-quarter (¼) mile square extending a minimum of one-eighth (1/8) of a mile radially from the perimeter of the property, contains land uses served by septic tank(s) and a public water supply, and
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
That the property complies with the minimum lot size requirements and the maximum lot size requirements and the maximum daily domestic sewage flow (sewage loading) requirements of Chapter 10D-6 of the State of Florida Rules of the Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services as same may be amended from time to time, or has obtained a variance from the aforementioned requirements of Chapter 10D-6, and
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
The property was part of a recorded subdivision which was created by plat or deed but said subdivision has not continuously remained as a legally recorded subdivision and the size of each proposed lot is the same or larger than the lots set forth in the recorded subdivision, and
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
That if the property is located within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, the property complies with Section 24-43(4)(a) and Section 24-43(4)(d) of this Code, and
</section>
<section prefix = "vi">
That residential land uses other than a single-family residence or a duplex residence shall be in compliance with Sections 24-43.1(3)(a)(iii), or
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The Director or the Director's designee has issued the Director's or the Director's designee's written approval for a platting action (final plat, waiver of plat, or equivalent municipal platting action) for a residential subdivision which was in existence prior to the effective date of this subsection served or to be served by a public water main and septic tanks. The Director or the Director's designee shall issue the Director's or the Director's designee's written approval only if the Director or the Director's designee finds the following:
<section prefix = "i">
The extension of public sanitary sewers to serve the property from the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer is not within a feasible distance for public sanitary sewers, and
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
The original subdivision was created by deed prior to January 1, 1958, or was created by plat prior to January 1, 1972, provided that said tract of land, as created by the originally recorded plat or deed, has continuously remained in the same form as set forth in the originally recorded plat or deed, and
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
The individual lots created by the platting action fail to comply with the minimum lot size requirements of Sections 24-43.1(3)(a)(i) or Section 24-43.1(3)(a)(ii) hereof, and
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
The proposed subdivision of the originally recorded plat or deed will result in a subdivision containing less than or equivalent number of lots as the original subdivision described in subsection Section 24-43.1(3)(e)(ii), and
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
That residential land uses other than a single-family residence or a duplex residence shall be in compliance with Section 24-43.1(3)(a)(iii), or
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The Director or the Director's designee has issued the Director's or the Director's designee's written approval for a platting action (final plat, waiver of plat or equivalent municipal platting action) for a residential subdivision which was not in existence prior to the effective date of this subsection which subdivision is served or to be served by a public water main and septic tanks. The Director or the Director's designee shall issue the Director's or the Director's designee's written approval only if the Director or the Director's designee finds the following:
<section prefix = "i">
The extension of public sanitary sewers to serve the property from the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer is not within a feasible distance for public sanitary sewers, and
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
The number of lots in the subdivision created by the platting action is derived by dividing the gross area of the property by the minimum lot size for a single-family residence or duplex residence as set forth in Sections 24-43.1(3)(a)(i) and 24-43.1(3)(a)(ii) hereof, and
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
At least one-fourth (¼) of the lots in the subdivision exceed the minimum lot size requirements set forth in Section 24-43.1(3)(a)(i) and Section 24-43.1(3)(a)(ii) hereof and the remaining three-fourths (¾) of the lots are equal to or exceed ninety-five (95) percent of the lot size requirement set forth in Sections 24-43.1(3)(a)(i) and Section 24-43.1(3)(a)(ii).

In calculating the square footage of lots in Sections 24-43.1(a), (b), (c), (d), (e) and (f) above, abutting easements and rights-of-way shall be considered to the center lines thereof.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board shall approve, grant or issue any building permit (except building permits for repair and maintenance of existing facilities), certificate of use and occupancy (except for changes in ownership), municipal occupational license (except for changes in ownership), platting action (final plat, waiver of plat or equivalent municipal platting action) or zoning action (district boundary change, unusual use, use variance or equivalent municipal zoning action) for any nonresidential land use served or to be served by any source of potable water supply and a septic tank without obtaining the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee.
Furthermore, notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no person shall construct, utilize, operate, occupy, or cause, allow, let, permit or suffer to be constructed, utilized, operated or occupied any nonresidential land use served or to be served by any source of public water supply and a septic tank without obtaining the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee.
The Director or the Director's designee shall issue the Director's or the Director's designee's written approval if the only liquid waste (excluding liquid wastes associated with the processing of agricultural produce in agricultural packing houses and liquid wastes associated with agricultural vehicle or, agricultural equipment maintenance facilities, stormwater and water used within a self-contained water recycling car wash facility, provided said facility does not backwash the recycling filters) which shall be generated, disposed of, discharged, or stored on the property shall be domestic sewage discharged into a septic tank and additionally, that the property is not within a feasible distance for public water mains and public sanitary sewers, and only:
<section prefix = "a">
After the owner of the property (excluding property upon which an agricultural vehicle or agricultural equipment maintenance facility operates) submits to the Director or the Director's designee a covenant running with the land executed by the owner of the property in favor of Miami-Dade County which provides that the only liquid waste (excluding liquid wastes associated with the processing of agricultural produce in agricultural packing houses and liquid wastes associated with agricultural vehicle or agricultural equipment maintenance facilities, stormwater and water used within a self-contained water recycling car wash facility, provided said facility does not backwash the recycling filters) which shall be generated, disposed of, discharged, or stored on the property shall be domestic sewage discharged into a septic tank. Said covenants shall be in a form(s) prescribed by the Director and approved by the Board of County Commissioners. The covenants shall be recorded by the Department at the expense of the owner of the property; and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
If the Director or the Director's designee determines that the proposed nonresidential land use is in accordance with the following:
<section prefix = "i">
Where public water is used the maximum allowable sewage loading shall be one thousand five hundred (1,500) gallons per day per unsubmerged acre, or
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Where public water is not used the maximum allowable sewage loading shall be seven hundred fifty (750) gallons per day per unsubmerged acre.
In calculating the square footage of lots in Sections 24-43.1(b)(i) and (ii) above, abutting easements and rights-of-way shall be considered to the center lines thereof; and
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
If the Director or the Director's designee determines that the existing nonresidential land use for the property or the nonresidential land use requested for the property is served or to be served by an on site domestic well system and a septic tank and is not one (1) or more of the following nonresidential land uses:
<section prefix = "i">
Establishments primarily engaged in the handling of food and drink except factory prepackaged products and agricultural crops,
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Educational institutions,
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Intermediate care facilities,
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
Health care facilities.

Notwithstanding the above, the Director or the Director's designee shall approve the issuance of a building permit for the repair or maintenance of existing facilities.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The following table shall be utilized by the Director or the Director's designee to determine sewage flows for sanitary sewers and the maximum allowable septic tank sewage loading requirements set forth in this chapter. If the Director or the Director's designee receives competent factual data and information such as actual on-site measured sewage flows or actual metered water bills, or an engineering flow study which utilizes recognized standard practices of the engineering profession, is signed and sealed by an engineer licensed by the State of Florida, and approved by the Director or the Director's designee, the Director or the Director's designee may utilize this data and information to determine sewage flows for sanitary sewers and the maximum allowable septic tank sewage loading requirements set forth in this chapter in lieu of the table below. This table shall not be utilized for the sizing of septic tanks. Sizing of septic tanks shall be in accordance with Florida Statutes regarding septic tanks.
Type of Land Use, Gallons Per Day (GPD)
Residential Land Uses:
Single-Family Residence:
 Less than 3001 sq. ft: 220 gpd/unit
 3001—5000 sq. ft: 320 gpd/unit
 More than 5000 sq. ft: 550 gpd/unit
Townhouse Residence: 180 gpd/unit
Apartment: 150 gpd/unit
Mobile Home Residence/Park: 180 gpd/unit
Duplex or Twin Home Residence: 180 gpd/unit

Commercial Land Uses:
Airport:
 (a) Common Area/Concourse: 5 gpd/100 sq. ft.
 (b) Retail: 10 gpd/100 sq. ft.
 (c) Food Service: See Restaurant use for allocation
Banquet Hall: 15 gpd/100 sq. ft.
 With Kitchen:50 gpd/100 sq. ft.
Bar or Cocktail Lounge: 20 gpd/100 sq. ft.
Barber Shop: 15 gpd/100 sq.ft.
Beauty Shop: 25 gpd/100 sq. ft.
Bowling Alley: 100 gpd/lane
Car Wash:
 (a) Manual Washing: 350 gpd/bay
 (b) Automated Washing: 5500 gpd/bay
  With recycle system: Based on system design and evaluation by the Department
Coin Laundry: 145 gpd/washer
Country Club: 15 gpd/100 sq. ft.
 With Kitchen: 50 gpd/100 sq. ft.
Dentist's Office: 25 gpd/100 sq. ft.
Food Preparation Outlets (Bakeries, Meat Markets, Commissaries, etc.): 35 gpd/100 sq. ft.
Funeral Home: 10 gpd/100 sq. ft.
Gas Station/Convenience store/Mini-Mart:
 (a) Without car wash: 450 gpd/unit
 (b) With single automated car wash: 1750 gpd/unit
Fitness Center or Gym: 10 gpd/100 sq. ft.
Hospital: 250 gpd/bed
Hotel or Motel: 100 gpd/room
House of Worship: 10 gpd/100 sq. ft.
Industrial:
 (a) Warehouse/Spec. Bldg.: 1 gpd/100 sq. ft.
 (b) Self-service storage units: 1.5 gpd/100 sq. ft.
 (c) Industrial—Wet: 20 gpd/100 sq. ft.
 (d) Industrial—Dry: 2.5 gpd/100 sq. ft.
Kennel: 15 gpd/cage
Marina: 60 gpd/slip
Motor Vehicle Service Station: 10 gpd/100 sq. ft.
Nursing/Convalescent Home: 50 gpd/bed
Office Building: 5 gpd/100 sq. ft.
Other Residential Facility/Institution:
 (a) Congregate Living Facility (CLF): 75 gpd/bed
 (b) Jail: 150 gpd/person
 (c) Other: 100 gpd/person
Pet Grooming: 55 gpd/100 sq. ft.
Physician's Office: 20 gpd/100 sq. ft.
Public Park:
 (a) With toilets only: 5 gpd/person
 (b) With toilets and showers: 20 gpd/person
Public Swimming Pool Facility: 30 gpd/person
Restaurant:
 (a) Full Service: 100 gpd/100 sq. ft.
 (b) East Food: 50 gpd/100 sq. ft.
 (c) Take Out: 100 gpd/100 sq. ft.
Retail: 10 gpd/100 sq. ft.
School:
 (a) Day Care/Nursery (adults and children): 20 gpd/100 sq. ft.
 (b) Regular school: 12 gpd/100 sq. ft.
Shopping Center/Mall:
 Shell/Common Area: 10 gpd/100 sq. ft.
Stadium, Ballpark, Racetrack, Fronton, Auditorium, etc.: 3 gpd/seat
Theater:
 (a) Indoor: 3 gpd/seat
 (b) Outdoor: 5 gpd/space
 (c) Drive-in: 5 gpd/space
Trailer or Tourist Park: 150 gpd/space
Veterinarian Office: 20 gpd/100 sq. ft.


</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no County or municipal officer, agent, employee, or Board shall approve, grant or issue any building permit, certificate of use and occupancy (except for changes in ownership), platting action (final plat, waiver of plat or equivalent municipal platting action) or zoning action (district boundary change, unusual use, use variance or equivalent municipal zoning action) for any nonresidential land use served or to be served by any liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment method other than public sanitary sewers or any source of potable water supply other than a public water main without obtaining the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee.
Furthermore, notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no person shall construct, utilize, operate, occupy or cause, allow, let, permit or suffer to be constructed, utilized, operated or occupied any nonresidential land use served by any liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment method other than public sanitary sewers or any source of potable water supply other than a public water main without obtaining the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee.
The Director or the Director's designee shall issue his written approval only if:
<section prefix = "a">
The Director or the Director's designee determines that the existing nonresidential land use for the property or the nonresidential land use for the property is a nonresidential land use served or to be served by a public water main and is not one (1) or more of the nonresidential land uses permitted under the following Miami-Dade County zoning classifications:
<section prefix = "i">
BU-1A (excluding those land uses permitted by BU-1),
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
BU-2 (excluding those land uses permitted by BU-1),
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
BU-3 (excluding those land uses permitted by BU-1),
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
IU-1,
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
IU-2,
</section>
<section prefix = "vi">
IU-3,
</section>
<section prefix = "vii">
IU-C, or
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Director or the Director's designee determines that the existing nonresidential land use for the property or the nonresidential land use requested for the property is a nonresidential land use served or to be served by an on site domestic well system and is not an establishment primarily engaged in the handling of food and drink (except factory prepackaged products), educational institutions, intermediate care facilities and health care facilities and is not one (1) or more of the nonresidential land uses permitted under the following Miami-Dade County zoning classifications:
<section prefix = "i">
BU-1A (excluding those land uses permitted by BU-1 except an establishment primarily engaged in the handling of food and drink (except factory prepackaged products), educational institutions, intermediate care facilities and health care facilities),
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
BU-2 (excluding those land uses permitted by BU-1 except an establishment primarily engaged in the handling of food and drink (except factory prepackaged products), educational institutions, intermediate care facilities and health care facilities),
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
BU-3 (excluding those land uses permitted by BU-1 except an establishment primarily engaged in the handling of food and drink (except factory prepackaged products), educational institutions, intermediate care facilities, and health care facilities),
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
IU-1,
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
IU-2,
</section>
<section prefix = "vi">
IU-3,
</section>
<section prefix = "vii">
IU-C,
</section>
<section prefix = "viii">
Unusual uses (excluding fruit and vegetable stands (no food or drinks processing) on a seasonal basis; lake excavation; concrete batching plant; concrete block plant; rock crushing and screening plant; filling of rock pits; rock quarries; radio and television towers and transmitting stations; trailers as watchman's quarters), or
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The owner of the property submits to the Director or the Director's designee a covenant running with the land executed by the owner of the property in favor of Miami-Dade County which provides that prior to the approval, granting or issuance of any building permit, certificate of use and occupancy (except for changes in ownership) or municipal occupational license (except for changes in ownership) the property shall be connected to a public water main and a public sanitary sewer. Said covenants shall be in a form(s) prescribed by the Director and approved by the Board of County Commissioners. The covenant shall be recorded in the public records of Miami-Dade County, Florida, by the Department at the expense of the owner of the property, or
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
An application has been filed for certificate of use and occupancy or municipal occupational license for a land use served or to be served by a public water main and any liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment method approved prior to September 30, 1983, or, an application has been filed for a certificate of use and occupancy or municipal occupational license for a land use served or to be served by an on site domestic well system and any liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment method other than public sanitary sewers approved prior to June 13, 1986, or
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The Director or the Director's designee determines that the property is served or to be served by a public water main and is served or to be served by any liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment method other than public sanitary sewers, is in compliance with Sections 24-43.1(4)(a) and (b), and that the existing nonresidential land use for the property or the nonresidential land use requested for the property is one (1) or more of the nonresidential land uses permitted under the Miami-Dade County zoning classifications set forth in Sections 24-43.1(6)(a)(i), (ii), or (iii) above, and the owner of the property has executed a covenant running with the land in favor of Miami-Dade County which provides that the property shall only be used for those nonresidential uses permitted under Miami-Dade County zoning classification BU-1 until such time as the property is connected to public sanitary sewers. Said covenants shall be in a form(s) prescribed by the Director and approved by the Board of County Commissioners. The covenants shall be recorded in the public records of Miami-Dade County, Florida by the Department at the expense of the owner of the property, or
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The Director or the Director's designee determines that the property is served or is to be served by an on site domestic well system and is served or to be served by any liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment method other than public sanitary sewers, is in compliance with Sections 24-43.1(4)(a), (b) and (c), and that the existing nonresidential land use for the property or the nonresidential land use requested for the property is one (1) or more of the nonresidential land uses permitted under the Miami-Dade County zoning classifications set forth in Sections 24-43.1(6)(b)(i), (ii), or (iii) above, and the owner of the property has executed a covenant running with the land in favor of Miami-Dade County which provides that the property shall only be used for those nonresidential uses permitted under Miami-Dade County zoning classification BU-1 (excluding establishments primarily engaged in the handling of food and drink, except factory prepackaged products, educational institutions, intermediate care facilities and health care facilities) until such time as the property is connected to a public water main and a public sanitary sewer. Said covenants shall be in a form(s) prescribed by the Director and approved by the Board of County Commissioners. The covenants shall be recorded in the public records of Miami-Dade County, Florida, by the Department at the expense of the owner of the property, or
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
The Director or the Director's designee determines that no portion of the property is located within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area or within the maximum day wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield or Hialeah Wellfield or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, that the owner of the property is applying for a land use prohibited by Section 24-43.1(6)(a) above, and:
<section prefix = "i">
That extension of public sanitary sewers to serve the property from the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer is not within a feasible distance for public sanitary sewers, and
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
That more than fifty (50) percent of an area, consisting of a minimum of one-quarter (¼) mile square extending a minimum of one-eighth (1/8) of a mile radially from the perimeter of the property, contains land uses served by septic tank(s) and public water, and
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
That the property complies with Sections 24-43.1(4)(a) and (b), and
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
That if the nonresidential land use will handle, use, or store hazardous materials on the property then the water pollution prevention and abatement measures and practices set forth in Sections 24-43(5)(a)(i), (ii), (iii), (iv), and (v) of this Code shall be provided. Said water pollution prevention and abatement measures and practices shall be subject to the approval of the Director or the Director's designee, and
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
That the owner of the property submits to the Director or the Director's designee a covenant running with the land executed by the owner of the property in favor of Miami-Dade County which sets forth the nonresidential land uses to be allowed on the property served by septic tank(s). Said covenant shall only include the nonresidential land uses permitted by the existing Miami-Dade County or municipal zoning classification for the property or permitted by the Miami-Dade County or municipal zoning classification requested by the owner of the property and which are determined by the Director or the Director's designee to generate, dispose of, discharge, or store only domestic sewage discharged into a septic tank and not to generate, dispose of, discharge, or store any other liquid waste except storm water or water used within a self-contained water recycling car wash facility, provided said facility does not backwash the recycling filters.
Said covenants shall be in a form(s) prescribed by the Director and approved by the Board of County Commissioners. The covenants shall be recorded by the Department at the expense of the owner of the property, and
</section>
<section prefix = "vi">
That the property is served or is to be served by a public water supply, or
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
The Director or the Director's designee determines that no portion of the property is located within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area or within the maximum day wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield or Hialeah Wellfield or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, that the owner of the property is applying for a land use prohibited by Section 24-43.1(6)(b)(i), (ii), and (iii) above, and:
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
That extension of a public water main and public sanitary sewer(s) to serve the property from the nearest available point of connection to an available public water main and public sanitary sewers is not within a feasible distance for public water mains and public sanitary sewers.
<section prefix = "ii">
That the property complies with Sections 24-43.1(4)(a), (b) and (c), and 24-43.1(6)(g)(v), and 24-43.2(1).
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
That the nonresidential land use will not use, generate, handle, dispose of, discharge or store hazardous materials on the property.
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
That the nonresidential land use(s) will not have an adverse environmental impact on groundwater quality within the property.
In determining whether a land use does not or will not have an adverse environmental impact on the groundwater quality within the property, the Director or the Director's designee shall consider the following factors:
<section prefix = "1">
The land use will not be detrimental to the public health, welfare and safety and will not create a nuisance and will not materially increase the level of water pollution within the property;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The use, generation, handling, disposal of, discharge or storage of hazardous materials will not occur on the property;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The only liquid waste (excluding stormwater) which will be generated, disposed of, discharged, or stored on the property shall be domestic sewage discharged to a public sanitary sewer or septic tank;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Stormwater runoff shall be retained on the property and disposed of through infiltration drainage systems supplemented with seepage drainage systems, or
<section prefix = "i">
The Director or the Director's designee determines that no portion of the property is located within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area or within the maximum day wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield or Hialeah Wellfield or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, that the property is located within the boundaries of a sanitary sewer improvement district approved by the Board of County Commissioners or a municipal governing body, that the owner of the property is applying for a land use prohibited by subsection Section 24-43.1(6)(a) above, and
<section prefix = "i">
That the property is served or will be served by a public water supply, and
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
That the property complies with the requirements of Section 24-43.1(4)(b), and
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
That if the nonresidential land use will generate, handle, store or use hazardous waste on the property then the water pollution prevention and abatement measures and practices listed below shall be provided. Said water pollution prevention and abatement measures and practices shall be subject to the approval of the Director or the Director's designee.
<section prefix = "1">
Monitoring of groundwater, and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Secondary containment of hazardous wastes stored on the property, and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Disposal of hazardous wastes by a liquid waste transporter with a valid liquid waste transporters operating permit issued by the Director, and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Inventory control and recordkeeping of hazardous wastes generated or stored on the property, and
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Stormwater management.
<section prefix = "iv">
That if the nonresidential land use will generate, handle, use or store liquid wastes (excluding hazardous wastes and domestic sewage) on the property then the best management practices listed below shall be provided. Said best management practices shall be subject to the approval of the Director or the Director's designee.
<section prefix = "1">
Disposal of liquid wastes, other than domestic sewage, by a liquid waste transporter with a valid liquid waste transporter operating permit issued by the Director, and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Inventory control and record keeping of liquid wastes, other than domestic sewage, generated and stored on the property.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
The Director or the Director's designee determines that the property is located within the maximum day wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield or Hialeah Wellfield or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, that the property is located within the boundaries of a sanitary sewer improvement district approved by the Board of County Commissioners or a municipal governing body, that the owner of the property is applying for a land use prohibited by Section 24-43.1(6)(a) above, and
<section prefix = "i">
That the property is served or is to be served by a public water supply, and
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
That the property complies with Section 24-43.1(4)(b), and
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
That the property complies with the requirements of Sections 24-43(5)(a), (b), and (c), and
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
That if the nonresidential land use will handle, generate, store, or dispose of liquid wastes (excluding hazardous wastes), other than domestic sewage discharged to a septic tank, on the property, then the following best management practices shall be provided:
<section prefix = "1">
Monitoring of groundwater, and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Secondary containment of liquid wastes stored on the property, and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Disposal of liquid wastes by a liquid waste transporter with a valid liquid waste transporter operating permit issued by the Director, and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Inventory control and recordkeeping of liquid wastes other than domestic sewage discharged to a septic tank, and
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Stormwater management.

Said best management practices shall be subject to the approval of the Director or the Director's designee, and
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, when an approved public gravity sanitary sewer or approved sanitary sewer force main is available and operative in a public right-of-way or easement abutting the property, the use of any liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment methods shall cease within ninety (90) days of the date that the Director or the Director's designee determines that the approved public sanitary sewer is available and operative. Thereafter, all liquid wastes that are generated, handled, disposed of, discharged or stored on the property shall be discharged to an approved and operative gravity sanitary sewer or approved sanitary sewer force main except those liquid wastes, other than domestic sewage, that are permitted by this chapter to be generated, handled, treated or stored on the property. Notwithstanding the foregoing, graywater may, at the option of the property owner, be discharged to a graywater disposal system approved by the Director or the Director's designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, the use of any liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment methods (excluding public sanitary sewers and stormwater disposal methods) for any nonresidential land use within the Northwest Wellfield protection area, within the West Wellfield Interim protection area, the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection areas of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield or Hialeah Wellfield or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights wellfield complex or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well shall cease within six (6) months from the date that the Director or the Director's designee determines that an approved public gravity sanitary sewer has been made available and operative in any portion of the public right-of-way or easement abutting the property, or the use of any liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment methods (excluding public sanitary sewers and stormwater disposal methods) for any nonresidential land use which exceeds the maximum allowable sewage loading permitted by Section 24-43.1(4)(b) of this Code, shall cease within six (6) months from the date that the Director or the Director's designee determines that an approved public gravity sanitary sewer has been made available and operative in any portion of the public right-of-way or easement abutting the property. Thereafter, all liquid wastes that are generated, handled, disposed of, discharged or stored on the property shall be discharged to an approved and operative gravity sanitary sewer except those liquid wastes, other than domestic sewage, that are permitted by this chapter to be generated, handled, treated or stored on the property.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Interim sewage treatment plants which serve any property within one-quarter (¼) mile from a public sanitary sewer which ultimately discharges to a regional sewage treatment plant of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department shall cease operation when the aforesaid public sanitary sewer is made operable and available. The sewage flowing to the aforesaid interim sewage treatment plants shall be diverted and transmitted to public sanitary sewers for ultimate discharge to a regional sewage treatment plant of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department. Private interim sewage treatment plants shall cease to operate within six (6) months from the date the said public sanitary sewer is made operable and available. Public interim sewage treatment plants operated by a utility shall cease to operate within two (2) years from the date the said public sanitary sewer is made operable and available. The aforesaid one-quarter (¼) mile distance shall be measured from the closest point of any of the properties served by the aforesaid interim sewage treatment plants and the nearest available point of connection within a public right of way or public easement to the aforesaid public sanitary sewer.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 06-125, § 4, 9-12-06; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08; Ord. No. 11-47, § 1, 7-7-11)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-43.2. Regulation of on-site domestic well systems and other water supply wells</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Regulation of on-site domestic well systems generally.
<section prefix = "a">
Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board shall approve, grant or issue any building permit, certificate of use and occupancy (except for changes in ownership), municipal occupational license (except for changes in ownership), platting action (final plat, waiver of plat or equivalent municipal platting action) or zoning action (district boundary change, unusual use, use variance or equivalent municipal zoning action) for any land use served or to be served by an on-site domestic well system without obtaining the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee.
Furthermore, notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no person shall construct, utilize, operate, occupy or cause, allow, let, permit or suffer to be constructed, utilized, operated or occupied any land use served or to be served by a domestic well system without obtaining the prior written approval of the Director or of the Department of Environmental Resources Management designee.
Pursuant to the foregoing, the Director or the Director's designee shall issue his written approval only if the Director or the Director's designee determines that:
<section prefix = "i">
That the existing land use for the property or the land use requested for the property is in compliance with Section 24-43.1 of this chapter, and
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
That the installation of a public water main to serve the property from the nearest available point of connection to an available public water main is not within a feasible distance for public water mains, and
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
That the groundwater at the site does not require treatment in order to meet the primary drinking water quality standards specified in Chapter 62-55, Florida Administrative Code, as same may be amended from time to time, and
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
That the groundwater at the site does not contain more than two hundred fifty (250) milligrams per liter (mg/l) of chlorides at a depth of thirty (30) feet from ground elevation.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
No construction may be begun on any project within Miami-Dade County involving the construction of a well capable of withdrawing water without obtaining approval from the Director. No well that withdraws water in excess of five thousand (5,000) gallons per day from groundwater, surface water or any other water or waters of Miami-Dade County may be maintained or operated without a permit. All permit applications shall be filed with the Director on forms provided by the Director and shall include but shall not be limited to the following information:
<section prefix = "i">
The name and address of the applicant (if the applicant is a corporation include the address of the principal business office);
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
The date the application is filed;
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
The source of water supply (if the water is from a lake, spring, river, stream or other source of surface water the name generally given to the source by the people in the vicinity. If the water is from a groundwater source this fact shall be stated on the application);
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
The quantity of water applied for;
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
The use to be made of the water and any limitation thereon (the description shall include the nature of the proposed use, the method of withdrawal or division of the water and facts, figures and other information on which the amount of water requested was based);
</section>
<section prefix = "vi">
The place where the water is to be used;
</section>
<section prefix = "vii">
The location of the well and for surface waters, the point of diversion;
</section>
<section prefix = "viii">
The total related land area owned by the applicant;
</section>
<section prefix = "ix">
The necessity for the well;
</section>
<section prefix = "x">
Any known persons who may be directly affected by the granting of the application;
</section>
<section prefix = "xi">
The signature of the applicant or his agent (if the signer is signing in a representative capacity he shall attach proof of his authority—in the case of a corporation, governmental body or public utility the applicant shall attach a certified copy of the authority under which the application is made);
</section>
<section prefix = "xii">
Other information as may be requested by the Department.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Conditions for a well permit.
<section prefix = "a">
In order to obtain a well permit an applicant must show that the intended use:
<section prefix = "i">
Is a reasonable, beneficial use, and
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Will not interfere with any legal use of water existing at the time of the application, including both exempted domestic uses and uses exercised under the authority of a valid permit, and
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Is consistent with the public interest.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
In determining whether a use is consistent with the public interest, the Director may consider the following factors:
<section prefix = "i">
The maximum economic development of the water resources consistent with present and future uses;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
The control of such waters for such purposes as environmental protection, drainage, flood control and water storage;
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
The quantity of water available for application to a reasonable-beneficial use;
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
Preservation of wasteful, uneconomic, impractical or unreasonable uses of water resources;
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
The preservation and enhancement of water quality of the County and the provisions of the water quality standards and classifications established pursuant to Chapter 24 of the Code of Miami-Dade County;
</section>
<section prefix = "vi">
The County's water resources policy as expressed in Chapter 24 of the Code;
</section>
<section prefix = "vii">
The availability and proximity of public water supply; and
</section>
<section prefix = "viii">
The satisfaction of the requirements of Section 24-43.3 of the Code.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Director may reserve water from use by permit applicants in such locations and quantities and for such seasons of the year as may reasonably be necessary to protect the public health, safety or fish and wildlife. Such reservations shall be subject to periodic review and revision in light of changed conditions except that all legal uses of water existing at the time of the reservation shall not be subject to this regulation so long as such uses are not contrary to the public interest. Any applicant aggrieved by an action of the Director or the Director's designee may appeal to the Environmental Quality Control Board under the procedures and standards set forth in Section 24-11 of the Code.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Permits for existing uses. All uses of water in existence before the effective date of this section, unless otherwise exempted from regulation by law, may be continued after the adoption of this permit system. A permit for any existing use shall be issued upon proper application. Failure to apply for a permit for any existing use for one (1) year after the effective date of this ordinance shall constitute an abandonment of the right granted by this section.
Notwithstanding the above, when an approved public water main has been made available and operative in any portion of the public right-of-way or easement abutting the property, the use of any on site domestic well system shall cease and connection shall be made to a public water main within ninety (90) days from the date that the Director or the Director's designee determines that the approved public water main is made available and operative, and
<section prefix = "a">
The existing sewage loading on the property exceeds the maximum allowable sewage loading permitted by Sections 24-43.1(3) or 24-43.1(4)(b) of this Code, or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The groundwater quality for the property exceeds the potable water standards in Section 24-43.3(2) of this chapter.

</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Competing applications.
<section prefix = "a">
If two (2) or more applications, otherwise in compliance with the provisions of this chapter, are pending for a quantity of water that is inadequate for both (or all) or which for any other reason are in conflict, the Director shall have the right to modify or approve the application or applications to best serve the public interest. In considering the relative benefit to be derived by the public from such proposed uses of water the Director may within the same type of use and source consider the following:
<section prefix = "i">
Public users should be preferred over private users;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Economically more productive uses should be preferred over less productive uses;
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
The purposes expressly declared to be in the public interest in Chapter 24 of the Code should be given primary consideration.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
In the event two (2) or more competing applications which have equally qualified under Section 24-43.2(4)(a) above cannot be reconciled by modification by the Director, the Director shall give preference to:
<section prefix = "i">
Renewal application, or
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
If none or all are renewal applications, to the first properly filed application.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Modification, renewal and transfer of permits. A permittee may apply to the Director for approval of any modification of a permit use. The Director may approve any modification of use which involves a decrease in the quantity of water required. Modification of any other term or terms of a permit may be granted at the discretion of the Director provided that such modification does not effect substantially the public interest.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Revocation of permits.
<section prefix = "a">
Pursuant to a hearing, the Environmental Quality Control Board may upon application by the Director:
<section prefix = "i">
Revoke any permit for complete nonuse of water supply allowed by the permit for a period of one (1) year or more;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Permanently revoke in whole or in part any permit for any material false statement in the application to continue, to initiate, or to modify a use, or for any material false statement in any report or statement of fact required by the user pursuant to the provisions of this section;
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Permanently or temporarily revoke in whole or in part any permit for the willful violation of conditions of the permit;
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
Revoke in whole or in part for a period not to exceed one (1) year any permit for the violation of any provision of Chapter 24 or regulation adopted thereunder;
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
Revoke, in whole or in part, any permit where adequate public water becomes available.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Director may cancel any permit with the written consent of the permittee.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Emergency drought conditions. Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit the exercise of emergency powers to control the use, withdrawal or diversion of water during periods of emergency water shortage.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Violation of section. It shall be unlawful for any person without a permit to construct, operate or maintain a well as required by this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Effect of denial. When an application for a permit has been denied by the Director and that denial, pursuant to a timely appeal, has not been overruled by the Environmental Quality Control Board a new application for a permit shall not be resubmitted within one (1) year of such final denial unless the applicant can demonstrate a substantial change in conditions or unless the permit applied for is substantially modified and is in compliance with the Director's reason for denial.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Definitions.
<section prefix = "a">
Domestic use shall mean any use of water for individual personal needs or for household purposes such as drinking, bathing, eating, cooking or sanitation.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Emergency shall mean that situation where the public health, safety or welfare or the health of animals, fish or aquatic life or of a public water supply or recreational, commercial, industrial, agricultural or other reasonable use of water is immediately in danger or threatened by an insufficient supply, restricted source, deleterious quality or other conditions of the water within the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Director shall mean the Director of the Department of Environmental Resources Management with powers as provided by Section 24-7 of the Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Groundwater shall mean water beneath the surface of the ground whether or not flowing through known and definite channels.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Person shall mean any and all persons including but not limited to any individual, firm, association, organization, partnership, business trust, corporation, company, United States of America, the State of Florida and all the municipalities and public agencies thereof located within Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Reasonable-beneficial use shall mean the use of water in such quantity as is necessary for economic and efficient utilization for a purpose and in a manner which is both reasonable and consistent with the public interest.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Surface water shall mean water upon the surface of the earth whether contained in bounds created naturally or artificially or diffused. Water from a natural spring or well shall be classified as surface water when it exits from the spring or well onto the earth's surface.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Water or waters of the County shall mean any and all waters on or beneath the surface of the ground including natural or artificial water courses, lakes, ponds or diffused surface water and water percolating, standing or flowing beneath the surface of the ground as well as all coastal waters in the geographic boundaries of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Water shortage shall mean that situation within all or part of Miami-Dade County, Florida wherein insufficient water is available to meet the requirements of the permit system or where the conditions are such as to require temporary reduction in the total use within the area to protect water resources from serious harm.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Well shall mean any excavation that is drilled, cored, bored, washed, driven, dug, jetted or otherwise constructed when the intended use of such excavation is for the location, acquisition, development or artificial recharge of groundwater or removal of water from beneath the ground. The term well does not include sandpoint wells or any wells for the purpose of obtaining or prospecting for oil, natural gas, minerals or products of mining or quarrying or the inserting of media to dispose of oil brinds or to repressure an oil or natural gas-bearing formation or for storing petroleum, natural gas or other products.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-43.3. Potable water standards</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
GENERAL PROHIBITIONS. It shall be unlawful for any person, firm, corporation, private or public utility, to cause, permit or otherwise allow any potable water supply to breach the values set forth in Section 24-43.3(2).
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
POTABLE WATER STANDARDS FOR MIAMI-DADE COUNTY.
<section prefix = "a">
Bacteriological quality; sampling. Compliance with the bacteriological requirements of these standards shall be based on examinations of samples collected at representative points throughout the distribution system. The frequency of sampling and the location of sampling points shall be established by the Director or the Director's designee after investigation of the source, method of treatment, and protection of the water concerned. In no event shall the frequency be less than as set forth below:
<section prefix="7" type="table">
<table class="table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Populations Served</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Minimum Number of Samples Per Month</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">25—2,500</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2,501—3,300</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3,301—4,100</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">4</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">4,101—4,900</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">5</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">4,901—5,800</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">5,801—6,700</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">7</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6,701—7,600</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">8</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">7,601—8,500</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">9</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">8,501—9,400</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">9,401—10,300</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH11CO.html#PTIIICOOR_CH11CO">11</a> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10,301—11,100</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">12</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">11,101—12,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH13EX.html#PTIIICOOR_CH13EX">13</a> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">12,001—12,900</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH14FIPR.html#PTIIICOOR_CH14FIPR">14</a> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">12,901—13,700</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH15SOWAMA.html#PTIIICOOR_CH15SOWAMA">15</a> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">13,701—14,600</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH16GEOBBO.html#PTIIICOOR_CH16GEOBBO">16</a> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">14,601—15,500</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH17HO.html#PTIIICOOR_CH17HO">17</a> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">15,501—16,300</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH18IMSPRPDI.html#PTIIICOOR_CH18IMSPRPDI">18</a> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">16,301—17,200</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH19REPROWMEAC.html#PTIIICOOR_CH19REPROWMEAC">19</a> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">17,201—18,100</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">20</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">18,101—18,900</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH21OFMIPR.html#PTIIICOOR_CH21OFMIPR">21</a> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">18,901—19,800</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH22WATH.html#PTIIICOOR_CH22WATH">22</a> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">19,801—20,700</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH23PE.html#PTIIICOOR_CH23PE">23</a> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">20,701—21,500</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH24ENPRBIBAENDEAQPACOARBIBAENENTRFUENENLAPR.html#PTIIICOOR_CH24ENPRBIBAENDEAQPACOARBIBAENENTRFUENENLAPR">24</a> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">21,501—22,300</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">25</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">22,301—23,200</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH26PAREDERURE.html#PTIIICOOR_CH26PAREDERURE">26</a> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">23,201—24,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH27SWPOPU.html#PTIIICOOR_CH27SWPOPU">27</a> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">24,001—24,900</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH28SU.html#PTIIICOOR_CH28SU">28</a> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">24,901—25,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <a href="../level2/PTIIICOOR_CH29TA.html#PTIIICOOR_CH29TA">29</a> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">25,001—28,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">30</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">28,001—33,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">35</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">33,001—37,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">40</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">37,001—41,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">45</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">41,001—46,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">50</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">46,001—50,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">55</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">50,001—54,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">60</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">54,001—59,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">65</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">59,001—64,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">70</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">64,001—70,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">75</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">70,001—76,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">80</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">76,001—83,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">85</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">83,001—90,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">90</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">90,001—96,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">95</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">96,001—111,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">100</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">111,001—130,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">110</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">130,001—160,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">120</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">160,001—190,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">130</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">190,001—220,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">140</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">220,001—250,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">150</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">250,001—290,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">160</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">290,001—320,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">170</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">320,001—360,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">180</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">360,001—410,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">190</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">410,001—450,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">200</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">450,001—500,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">210</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">500,001—550,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">220</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">550,001—600,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">230</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">600,001—660,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">240</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">660,001—720,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">250</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">720,001—780,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">260</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">780,001—840,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">270</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">840,001—910,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">280</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">910,001—970,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">290</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">970,001—1,050,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">300</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1,050,001—1,140,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">310</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1,140,001—1,230,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">320</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1,230,001—1,320,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">330</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1,320,001—1,420,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">340</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1,420,001—1,520,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">350</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1,520,001—1,630,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">360</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1,630,001—1,730,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">370</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1,730,001—1,850,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">380</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1,850,001—1,970,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">390</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1,970,001—2,060,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">400</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2,060,001—2,270,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">410</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2,270,001—2,510,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">420</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2,510,001—2,750,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">430</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2,750,001—3,020,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">440</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3,020,001—3,320,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">450</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3,320,001—3,620,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">460</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3,620,001—3,960,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">470</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">3,960,001—4,310,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">480</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">4,310,001—4,690,000</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">490</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">4,690,001—</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">500</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Laboratories in which water examinations are made for required reports shall be subject to inspection at any time by the Director or the Director's designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Bacterial limits. The presence of organisms of the coliform group as indicated by samples examined shall not exceed the following limits:
<section prefix = "i">
When ten (10) ml standard portions are examined not more than ten (10) percent in any month shall show the presence of the coliform group. The presence of the coliform group in three (3) or more ten (10) ml portions of a standard sample shall not be allowable if this occurs:
<section prefix = "1">
In two (2) consecutive samples;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
In more than one (1) sample per month when less than twenty (20) are examined per month; or
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
In more than five (5) percent of the samples when twenty (20) or more are examined per month.
When organisms of the coliform group occur in three (3) or more of the ten (10) ml portions of a single standard sample, daily samples from the same sampling point shall be collected promptly and examined until the results obtained from at least two (2) consecutive samples show the water to be of satisfactory quality.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
When one hundred (100) ml standard portions are examined, not more than sixty (60) percent in any month shall show the presence of the coliform group. The presence of the coliform group in all five (5) of the one hundred (100) ml portions of a standard sample shall not be allowable if this occurs:
<section prefix = "1">
In two (2) consecutive samples;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
In more than one (1) sample per month when less than five (5) are examined per month; or
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
In more than twenty (20) percent of the samples when five (5) or more are examined per month.
When organisms of the coliform group occur in all five (5) of the one hundred (100) ml portions of a single standard sample, daily samples from the same sampling point shall be collected promptly and examined until the results obtained from at least two (2) consecutive samples show the water to be of satisfactory quality.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
When the membrane filter technique is used, the arithmetic mean coliform density of all standard samples examined per month shall not exceed one (1) per one hundred (100) ml. Coliform colonies per standard sample shall not exceed 3/50 ml, 4/100 ml, 7/200 ml, or 13/500 ml in:
<section prefix = "1">
Two (2) consecutive samples;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
More than one (1) standard sample when less than twenty (20) are examined per month; or
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
More than five (5) percent of the standard samples when twenty (20) or more are examined per month.
When coliform colonies in a single standard sample exceed the above values, daily samples from the same sampling point shall be collected promptly and examined until the results obtained from at least two (2) consecutive samples show the water to be of satisfactory quality.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Physical characteristics; sampling. The frequency and manner of sampling shall be determined by the Director or the Director's designee. Under normal circumstances the Director or the Director's designee may require that samples be collected one (1) or more times per week from representative points in the distribution system and examined for turbidity, color, threshold odor, and taste.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Physical limits. The water shall contain no impurity which would cause offense to the sense of sight, taste, or smell. Under general use, the following limits shall not be exceeded:
Turbidity—5 nephelometric turbidity units
Color—15 units
Threshold odor number—3
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Chemical characteristics; sampling. The frequency and manner of sampling shall be determined by the Director or the Director's designee. Under normal circumstances, analyses for substances listed in Section 24-43.3(2)(h) need be made only annually. If, however, there is some presumption of unfitness because of the presence of undesirable elements, compounds, or materials, periodic determinations for the suspected toxicant or material shall be made more frequently and an exhaustive sanitary survey shall be made to determine the source of the pollution. Where the concentration of a substance is not expected to increase in processing and distribution, available and acceptable source water analyses performed in accordance with standard methods may be used as evidence of compliance with these standards.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Chemical limits. The water shall not contain impurities in concentrations which may be hazardous to the health of the consumers. It should not be excessively corrosive to the water supply system. Substances used in its treatment shall not remain in the water in concentrations greater than required by good practice. Substances which may have deleterious physiological effect, or for which physiological effects are not known, shall not be introduced into the system in a manner which would permit them to reach the consumer. Each public water supply utility shall test the finished water produced by each of its water treatment plants on an annual basis for the materials identified as priority pollutants by the United States Environmental Protection Agency as set forth in Schedule A, attached hereto and made a part hereof [but not reproduced at length herein], and such other materials as may be designated by the Director or the Director's designee. Each of the other community water systems shall test the finished water produced by its water treatment system every third year for the aforesaid materials identified as priority pollutants by the United States Environmental Protection Agency, and such other materials as may be designated by the Director or the Director's designee.
The first of the previously mentioned analyses shall be performed, and the results submitted to the Director or the Director's designee, no later than one hundred fifty (150) days after the effective date of Ordinance No. 84-41. Subsequent analyses shall be performed, and the results submitted to the Director or the Director's designee, no later than July first of the respective year.
Analyses conducted to determine compliance with this section shall be made in accordance with an analytical method acceptable to the Director or the Director's designee in accordance with Schedule A, attached hereto and made a part hereof, and at the detection limits achievable using the specific technique. The laboratory performing these tests shall have appropriate experience in these types of drinking water analyses and shall be certified by the State of Florida.
After submittal of the test results to the utilities and community water systems for their review and comments at a public workshop, the Director or the Director's designee shall make available to the public thirty (30) days thereafter an annual publication of the test results. Said publication shall contain the test results of all public water supply utilities and other community water systems in Miami-Dade County including comments regarding the test results by the utilities and community water systems.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
The following chemical substances shall not be present in a water supply in excess of the listed concentrations:
<section prefix="8" type="table">
<table class="table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Substance</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Concentration in mg/l</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Arsenic (As)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0.01</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Chloride (Cl)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">250</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Copper (Cu)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1.0</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Cyanide (Cn)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0.01</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Iron (Fe)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0.3</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Manganese (Mn)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0.05</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Methylene Blue Active Substances (MBAS)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0.5</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Nitrate Nitrogen (NO<sub>3</sub>—N) </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Phenols</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0.001</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Sulphate (SO<sub>4</sub>) </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">250</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Total dissolved solids</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">500</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Zinc (Zn)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">5</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
The presence of the following substances in excess of the concentrations listed shall constitute grounds for rejection of raw water supply:
<section prefix="9" type="table">
<table class="table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Substance</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Concentration in mg/l</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Arsenic (As)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0.05</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Barium (Ba)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1.0</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Cadmium (Cd)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0.01</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Chromium (hexavalent) (CR VI)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0.05</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Cyanide (Cn)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0.2</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Lead (Pb)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0.05</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Selenium (Se)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0.01</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Silver (Ag)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0.05</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Mercury (Hg)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">0.002</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Nitrate (as N)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">45</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Analytical methods. Analytical methods to determine compliance with the requirements of these standards shall be those specified in Standard Methods for the Examination of Water and Waste Water, sixteenth edition.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
All public water supply systems shall employ an approved method of disinfection acceptable to the Director or the Director's designee. Such disinfection shall be accomplished continuously in such a manner as to assure the continued feeding of the disinfection agent.
<section prefix = "i">
Those systems utilizing gas chlorine shall provide duplex systems that will assure the continued application of chlorine to the water even as containers are expended and replaced;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Those systems utilizing chlorine shall maintain a minimum three-tenths (0.3) milligrams per liter as free chlorine throughout its distribution system. In no case shall a chlorine residual in excess of two (2.0) milligrams per liter be maintained in the distribution system;
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Utilization of other methods of disinfection acceptable to the Director or the Director's designee shall have established limits set by the Director;
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
The minimum amount of chlorine to be stored at the water treatment facility or immediately accessible to the facility shall be a thirty-day supply. In lieu of this requirement the utility may provide to the Director or the Director's designee copies of long term contracts indicating available quantity together with transportation contracts;
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
All public water supply systems shall provide to the Director or the Director's designee breakpoint chlorination curves for:
<section prefix = "1">
All individual wells which are used as a supply of raw water;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Composite breakpoint curves for the raw water supply used for average and maximum day demand.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Every public water supply shall install a suitable measuring device at each source of supply and at the point that water is pumped to the distribution system in order that a record may be maintained of the water produced and treated. The quantities indicated by these measuring devices shall be tabulated daily and recorded.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
When the annual average of the maximum daily air temperatures for the location in which the public water system is situated is the following, the corresponding concentration of fluoride shall not be exceeded:
<section prefix="10" type="table">
<table class="table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
  <col width="33.333333333333336%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Temperature (in degrees F)</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>(Degrees C)</i> </td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> <i>Level (mg/l)</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">50.0—53.7</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">10.0—12.0</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1.8</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">53.8—58.3</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">12.1—14.6</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1.7</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">58.4—63.8</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">14.7—17.6</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1.5</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">63.9—70.6</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">17.7—21.4</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1.4</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">70.7—79.2</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">21.5—26.2</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1.2</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">79.3—90.5</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">26.3—32.5</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">1.1</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 
</section>
<section prefix = "n">
Public water supply systems cleaning and disinfection. No person, Board, or municipality charged with the management or control of a public water supply shall put into service any new plant, pumping station, main, standpipe, reservoir, tank, or other pipe or structure through which water is delivered to consumers for potable or household purposes, nor resume the use of any such structure, facilities, or main after it has been cleaned, until such structure, facilities or main has been effectively sterilized or disinfected. Provided, that this may not necessarily apply to mains, reservoirs, tanks, or other structures, the waters from which are subsequently treated or purified.
</section>
<section prefix = "o">
Adequate pressure shall be maintained in the mains to deliver the water for which they were designed, whether it be for fire, industrial, or domestic use. In no event, however, shall the pressure at the point of delivery to any customer fall below twenty (20) pounds per square inch, nor shall the static pressure exceed one hundred (100) pounds per square inch.
</section>
<section prefix = "p">
By-passing unlawful. Where a potable water treatment facility has been provided, it shall be unlawful to by-pass the facility or any part thereof. In the event of an emergency, the supplier may temporarily utilize a by-pass. However, it shall be unlawful to fail to immediately notify the Director or the Director's designee of such an emergency. Such notification shall not be a defense to any civil liability under this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "q">
When an approved public water main is made available and operative in a public right-of-way or easement abutting the property, any existing individual potable water supply system, device, or equipment shall, within ninety (90) days, be abandoned and the source of potable water for the residence or building shall be from the approved public water supply main.
</section>
<section prefix = "r">
Public water supply systems; cross-connections and use of dual supplies.
<section prefix = "i">
Certain cross-connections prohibited. No officers, Board, corporation, municipality or other persons having the management of a public water supply shall permit any physical connection between the distribution system of such supply and that of any other water supply unless such other supply is regularly examined as to its quality by those in charge of the public supply to which the connection is made and is also found to be safe and potable. This provision shall apply to all water distribution systems either inside or outside of any building or buildings.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Permissible arrangement where dual supplies are used. If a potable water supply is used as an auxiliary supply delivered to an elevated tank, or to a suction tank, which tank is also supplied with water from a source with which cross-connections are not permitted by Section 24-43.3(2)(r)(i), such tank shall be opened to atmospheric pressure and the potable water supply shall be discharged at an elevation above the high water line of the tank.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "s">
Facilities in actual use and operation as of the date of the enactment of this section which exceed the criteria set forth in any of the provisions of Section 24-43.3 hereof, certified by a competent state or county agency as a present or potential health hazard, shall be designated by the Director as priority public water supply areas. Upon such designation the Miami-Dade County Water and Sewer Department and the County Manager shall initiate proceedings for the creation of a special taxing district for public water system for the elimination of the potable water wells therein or take such other commensurate steps as to assure the elimination of the potable water wells therein, on a timely basis.
</section>
<section prefix = "t">
All treatment facilities shall be designed to have a treatment capacity equal to maximum day demand.
</section>
<section prefix = "u">
Any cross-connections in the treatment facility or distribution system are to be eliminated upon direction of the Director, Environmental Resources Management. In the event such a cross-connection is maintained by a user after an order to disconnect is given by the Director or the Director's designee, the Director or the Director's designee may order the discontinuance of service by the utility to the user until the cross-connection is eliminated.
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
No water supply well shall be constructed or used until a written approval from the Director or the Director's designee has been received by the owner and/or driller of the well:
<section prefix = "i">
The Director or the Director's designee shall be notified by the well driller at least twenty-four (24) hours prior to initiating construction of a permitted well;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
In wells where the casing is driven it shall be known as drive pipe, and shall be equipped with couplings allowing for butt joints between lengths of casing. For wells in which the casing is not driven "merchant casing," standard pipes or pipe especially constructed for gravel wall wells will be acceptable;
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Where telescoped casing is utilized, an approved watertight seal shall be made where increases or reductions occur in casing size. The initial stage of the telescope casing shall extend a minimum of thirty (30) feet into the groundwater table;
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
When water is to be obtained from limestone strata, the casing shall extend sufficiently far into unbroken limestone to be seated firmly in it but in no case shall it be less than thirty (30) feet into the aquifer;
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
Wells drilled by the rotary method shall have an annular space sealed by the use of a neat cement grout at the bottom of the hole and to the surface by neat cement or other approved material;
</section>
<section prefix = "vi">
Once the construction of the well is completed it shall be protected at all times to prevent entrance of contaminating material until such time as the pump may be placed;
</section>
<section prefix = "vii">
The top of the casing shall be so constructed as to exclude any influent but shall not extend less than one (1) foot above the surface of the ground;
</section>
<section prefix = "viii">
A concrete pad shall be constructed around the well a minimum of twelve (12) inches thick, two (2) feet horizontal from the casing;
</section>
<section prefix = "ix">
Pump houses or pump pits shall be constructed so as to provide for positive drainage. Where such is not possible, sump pumps or an alternative acceptable to the Director or the Director's designee shall be provided. Such systems shall be installed as duplex systems;
</section>
<section prefix = "x">
Where provided, well vents shall be adequately protected;
</section>
<section prefix = "xi">
In those situations where suction lines from a well casing are indicated, the suction pipe shall be so constructed to prohibit inundation. Minimum requirement shall be twelve (12) inches of clearance between the invert and ground surface;
</section>
<section prefix = "xii">
A sampling tap shall be provided on the discharge of the well pump piping or in such a location as to assure a true raw water sample;
</section>
<section prefix = "xiii">
The use of dynamite for the construction of wells shall be prohibited;
</section>
<section prefix = "xiv">
Dug wells, infiltration galleries and other sources of water supply requiring rearrangement of natural features are hereby prohibited as a source of public water supply;
</section>
<section prefix = "xv">
The use of surface water as a raw water source is prohibited;
</section>
<section prefix = "xvi">
All wells shall be located on terrain not subject to ponding or flooding. Furthermore, the slope of the ground surface in the vicinity of the well(s) shall be away from the well. In level areas, well compacted earth shall be placed around the well so as to elevate the platform, pad or apron;
</section>
<section prefix = "xvii">
As far as is practical, wells shall be located on the upstream side of possible sources of pollution;
</section>
<section prefix = "xviii">
The minimum separation between a well or wells and possible sources of contamination shall be a function of the drawdown and radius of influence of the well or wells. It shall be the responsibility of the design engineer to present data showing the radius of influence and drawdown together with a sanitary survey of the area influenced by the well. Such a survey shall extend one-half (½) mile beyond the radius of influence of the well field. In the cases involving multiple wells the interference among wells shall be determined. It shall be the design engineer's responsibility to show that the top thirty (30) feet of the aquifer is not tapped by the well(s). In no case shall the well be located less than one hundred (100) horizontal feet from any source of contamination. However, the Director or the Director's designee shall have the power to require additional spacing when conditions justify;
</section>
<section prefix = "xix">
All wells shall be accessible for such attention as necessary;
</section>
<section prefix = "xx">
All wells shall be equipped with an opening suitable for introduction of a disinfecting agent and measurement of drawdown and static water level;
</section>
<section prefix = "xxi">
When using chlorine as a disinfecting agent, a quantity, at least equal to the volume of the casing, of a strength of fifty (50) milligrams per liter shall be injected into the well. The solution shall be permitted to stand a minimum of twenty-four (24) hours and then pumped out for a sufficient length of time to remove the disinfecting agent;
</section>
<section prefix = "xxii">
Once the well has been evacuated in accordance with subsection (21), a series of twenty (20) or more daily samples, twenty (20) series, shall be collected and submitted to the Division of Health laboratory, the well being pumped for a minimum of thirty (30) minutes each day at its proposed capacity just prior to collecting the samples. At the discretion of the Director or the Director's designee the samples may be reduced to duplicate daily samples for a minimum of ten (10) days. Such samples will necessitate pumping for a minimum of thirty (30) minutes as indicated above;
</section>
<section prefix = "xxiii">
Interpretation of the laboratory results in the well survey will be made in accordance with applicable parts of the water supply standards;
</section>
<section prefix = "xxiv">
Once the series of twenty (20) or more consecutive satisfactory samples have been collected a complete analysis shall be performed of the raw water for both physical and chemical characteristics of the complete analysis shall be furnished to the Director or the Director's designee.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history>
</law>
