<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="3">ARTICLE III. UNIFORM TRADE STANDARDS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="4">DIVISION_4._OFFENSES;_PROSECUTION;_PENAL</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-115. Specific penalties and offenses</catch_line>
<text>
Any person who, by himself or by his servant or agent, or as the servant or agent of another person, performs any one (1) of the acts enumerated in subsections (a) through (j) of this section shall be guilty of a violation of this article, and upon a first conviction thereof shall be punished by a fine of not less than twenty dollars ($20.00) nor more than two hundred dollars ($200.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for not more than sixty (60) days, or by both such fine and imprisonment in the discretion of the court of appropriate jurisdiction; and upon a second conviction thereof, he shall be punished by a fine of not less than fifty dollars ($50.00) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for not less than ten (10) days nor more than sixty (60) days or by both such fine and imprisonment in the discretion of the court of appropriate jurisdiction and upon a third conviction, he shall be punished by a fine of not less than five hundred dollars ($500.00) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000.00) and by imprisonment in the County Jail for not less than thirty (30) days nor more than one (1) year.
<section prefix = "a">
Using, or having in possession for the purpose of using, for any commercial purpose specified in Section 8A-83, selling, offering or exposing for sale or hire, or having in possession for the purpose of selling or hiring, an incorrect weight or measure or any device or instrument used to or calculated to falsify any weight or measure.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Using or having in possession for the purpose of current use, for any commercial purpose specified in Section 8A-83, a weight or measure that does not bear a seal or mark such as is specified in Section 8A-87, unless such weight or measure has been exempted from testing by the provisions of Section 8A-83
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Disposing of any rejected or condemned weight or measure in a manner contrary to law or regulation.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Removing from any weight or measure, contrary to law or regulation, any tag, seal, or mark placed thereon by the appropriate authority.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Selling or offering or exposing for sale, less than the quantity represented of any commodity, thing or service.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Taking more than the quantity represented of any commodity, thing, or service when, as buyer, he furnishes the weight or measure by means of which the amount of the commodity, thing, or service is determined.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Keeping for the purpose of sale, advertising or offering or exposing for sale, or selling any commodity, thing, or service in a condition or manner contrary to law or regulation.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Using in retail trade, except in the preparation of packages put up in advance of sale and of medical prescriptions, a weight or measure that is not so positioned that its indications may be accurately read and the weighing or measuring operation observed from some position which may reasonably be assumed by a customer.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Packaging for sale perishable food without a label specifying the terminal shelf life date expressed as a calendar date.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Selling or offering or exposing for sale, at retail, any prepackaged, unprocessed or untreated, fresh meat, exclusive of viscera, unless the package is colorless and transparent on all sides, exclusive of labeling, or unless at least seventy (70) percent of said packaging shall be transparent to expose the bottom of the meat while the top shall be completely visible, exclusive of labeling which labeling shall not occupy more than ten (10) percent of one (1) side or sides or five (5) square inches, whichever is greater, of the package whereon such labeling is affixed.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-116. General penalty for violation of article</catch_line>
<text>
Unless otherwise specifically provided herein, any persons violating any of the provisions of this article shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for a period not to exceed sixty (60) days or by both such fine and imprisonment in the discretion of the court of appropriate jurisdiction.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-117. Hindering or obstructing officer; penalties</catch_line>
<text>
Any person who shall hinder or obstruct in any way the Director or an inspector in the performance of his official duties shall be guilty of a violation of this article and upon conviction thereof shall be punished by a fine of not less than twenty dollars ($20.00) nor more than two hundred dollars ($200.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for not more than sixty (60) days, or by both such fine and imprisonment in the discretion of the court of appropriate jurisdiction.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-118. Impersonation of officer; penalties</catch_line>
<text>
Any person who shall impersonate in any way the Director or an inspector by the use of his seal or a counterfeit of his seal, or in any other manner, shall be guilty of a violation of this article and upon conviction thereof shall be punished by a fine of not less than one hundred dollars ($100.00) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for not more than one (1) year, or by both such fine and imprisonment in the discretion of the court of appropriate jurisdiction.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-119. Adoption by reference of certain state misdemeanor statutes</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
All statutes of the State of Florida defining and prohibiting false advertising and offenses relating to consumer protection, trade standards, and weights and measures, defined by State law as misdemeanors, are adopted and incorporated by reference as part of this article to the same extent and to the same effect as if the provisions of each such statute were set out in full herein defining and prohibiting each such offense against the State to be an act prohibited by or an offense in violation of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
All such acts defined as misdemeanors in said State statutes are hereby prohibited and declared to be violations of this article, and any person or corporation shall, upon conviction in the court of appropriate jurisdiction for violation thereof, be punished by a fine not exceeding five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for not more than sixty (60) days, or by both such fine and imprisonment in the discretion of the court.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 68-52, § 44, 9-19-68)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-120. Court of appropriate jurisdiction vested with trial jurisdiction</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
All violations of this article shall be prosecuted only in the court of appropriate jurisdiction which shall have original, exclusive jurisdiction to try all cases arising hereunder; provided, however, that where an act is recognized by State law as a misdemeanor and by this article as an offense, complaints against persons charged with such unlawful acts may be filed and prosecuted in the court of appropriate jurisdiction.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
When and if any officer of a State agency deems it desirable and in the public interest to prosecute in the court of appropriate jurisdiction violators of State laws, rules and regulations adopted by reference herein, he shall do so with the permission of the prosecuting attorney, and may have summonses or warrants issued as he deems appropriate.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 68-52, § 47, 9-19-68)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-120.1. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Section 3 of Ord. No. 91-65, adopted June 20, 1991, repealed former § 8A-120.1, relative to costs, which derived from Ord. No. 81-7, § 1, adopted Feb. 3, 1981.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-121. Summons and complaint</catch_line>
<text>
This County may provide, in quadruplicate, suitable serial numbered forms of summons and complaint for notifying alleged violators to appear and answer to charges of violating this article. Such forms may be issued to and receipted for by the law enforcement officials. The County Court Clerk shall each month report to the County Court Judges the disposition made by the law enforcement officials of all such forms issued to them. All law enforcement officials making arrests or issuing summons with promise to appear shall use this form.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-122. Presumptive evidence</catch_line>
<text>
For the purpose of this article proof of the existence of a weight or measure or a weighing or measuring device in or about any building enclosure, stand, or vehicle in which or from which it is shown that buying or selling is commonly carried on, shall in the absence of conclusive evidence to the contrary, be presumptive proof of the regular use of such weight or measure or weighing or measuring device for commercial purposes and of such use by the person in charge of such building, enclosure, stand or vehicle.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-123. Validity of prosecutions</catch_line>
<text>
Prosecutions for violation of any provision of this article are declared to be valid and proper notwithstanding the existence of any other valid general or specific statute of the State or ordinance of this County dealing with matters that may be the same as or similar to those covered by this article.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-124. Enforcement procedure; remedies; attorneys fees; costs</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It shall be unlawful for any person to violate any of the provisions of Article III, Article XI and Article XIA of this chapter. In addition to any other judicial or administrative remedies provided by law or this chapter, the Director of the Miami-Dade County Consumer Protection Division shall have the following judicial remedies available to enforce the provisions of Article III, Article XI and Article XIA of Chapter 8A of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida:
<section prefix = "1">
The Director may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to seek temporary or permanent, prohibitory or mandatory injunctive relief to enforce compliance with or prohibit the violation of any of the provisions of Article III, Article XI, and Article XIA of Chapter 8A of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Director may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to impose and recover a civil penalty in an amount of not more than ten thousand dollars ($10,000.00) for each violation of the provisions of Article III, Article XI, and Article XIA of Chapter 8A of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. Each day during any portion of which such violation occurs or continues to occur constitutes a separate violation. The right of trial by jury shall be available in any court to determine both liability for and the amount of the civil penalties to be imposed and recovered hereunder.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Director may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to seek restitution and other equitable relief:
<section prefix = "i">
To recover any sums and costs expended by the Director for tracing, investigating, preventing, controlling, abating or remedying violations of Article III, Article XI, and Article XIA of Chapter 8A of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
To provide restitution to any consumers injured by any violation of Article III, Article XI, and Article XIA of Chapter 8A of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Upon the rendition of a judgment or decree by any of the courts of this State against any person and in favor of the Director of the Miami-Dade County Consumer Protection Division under any of the provisions of Article III, Article XI, or Article XIA of this chapter, the trial court, or, in the event of an appeal in which the Director prevails, the appellate court, shall adjudge or decree against said person and in favor of the Director a reasonable sum as fees or compensation for the Director's attorney prosecuting the suit in which the recovery is had. Where so awarded, compensation or fees of the attorney shall be included in the judgment or decree rendered in the case. This provision shall apply to all civil actions, legal or equitable, filed after the effective date of this article by the Director. Cessation of any violation of any of the aforesaid provisions of this chapter whatsoever, prior to rendition of a judgment or entry of a temporary or final decree, or prior to execution of a negotiated settlement, but after an action is filed by the Director under any of the aforesaid provisions of this chapter, shall be deemed the functional equivalent of a confession of judgment or verdict in favor of the Director, for which attorney's fees shall be awarded by the trial court as set forth hereinabove.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All the judicial and administrative remedies in Article III, Article XI, and Article XIA of Chapter 8A of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, are independent and cumulative.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 68-52, § 40, 9-19-68; Ord. No. 91-65, § 4, 6-20-91)</history>
</law>
