<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="1">ARTICLE IV. NATURAL AND BIOLOGICAL ENVIRONMENTAL RESOURCES PERMITTING AND PROTECTION; REGULATION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS AND STORMWATER MANAGEMENT</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="4">DIVISION_2._TREE_PRESERVATION_AND_PROTEC</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-49. Permits for tree removal and relocation, improperly issued permits, violation of permit conditions, exemptions from tree removal permits; mortgagee exemption from liability</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
It shall be unlawful for any person, unless otherwise permitted by the terms of this section, to do tree removal work or to effectively destroy any tree, or to effectively destroy any understory in a natural forest community, without first obtaining a permit from the Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
No municipal or County official shall issue a tree removal permit that does not comply with the provisions of this section. Any such permit shall be void. A municipality shall not be limited from requiring tree removal permits for species exempt from tree removal permits required by this section, provided the tree is not within a natural forest community.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
It shall be unlawful for any person to violate or not comply with any of the conditions of a Miami-Dade County tree removal permit.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The following activities are exempt from tree removal permits:
<section prefix = "a">
Removal of trees within the yard area of an existing single-family residence, provided the trees are not within a natural forest community, and are not specimen trees. This exemption does not apply to trees which are growing on County rights-of-way adjoining existing single-family residences;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Removal of trees for the construction of a new single-family residence, provided that:
<section prefix = "i">
The lot is one (1) acre or less in size (43,560 square feet), if an AU zoned lot, or one-half (½) acre or less in size (21,780 square feet), for any other zoned lot; and
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
The lot is being developed as the principal residence of the owner-builder; and
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
The lot is not within an area designated as a natural forest community; and
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
The trees are not specimen trees.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Removal of any dead tree, provided the tree is not within a natural forest community.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Removal of trees within State-approved plant nurseries and botanical gardens, provided said trees were planted and are growing for the display, breeding, propagation, sale or intended sale to the general public in the ordinary course of business.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Removal of trees for the establishment, maintenance and operation of a bona fide grove or bona fide tree nursery, except when the proposed tree removal is to occur in a natural forest community designated under Resolution No. 1764-84 or under subsequent revisions of the natural forest community maps or when the proposed tree removal will affect specimen trees as defined herein. Any person desiring to remove trees pursuant to this provision shall obtain written approval from the Department prior to the commencement of any such activities under this exemption.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Removal of any of the following tree species with scientific nomenclature as set forth in Wunderlin, Richard P. and Hansen, Bruce F., Guide to the Vascular Plants of Florida, 2nd Ed. University of Florida Press, Gainesville, FL. (2003), a copy of which shall be maintained by the Director or Director's designee and available for review by the public. If the activity is within a natural forest community or lands protected by a covenant running with the land in favor of Miami-Dade County including, but not limited to, Environmentally Endangered Lands (EEL), Environmentally Sensitive Lands, or Tree Preservation Areas, a permit shall be required, but all application and permit fees shall be waived by the Department:
<section prefix = "i">
All trees listed in Section 24-49.9
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Any of the following species:
Araucaria heterophylla (Norfolk Island pine)
Bauhinia purpurea (Orchid tree)
Bauhinia variegata (Orchid tree)
Calophyllum antillanum (Mast wood)
Eugenia uniflora (Surinam cherry)
Hibiscus tiliaceus (Mahoe)
Metopium toxiferum (Poisonwood)
Murraya paniculata (Orange jasmine)
Pittosporum petandrum (Taiwanese cheesewood)
Pongamia pinnata (Tallow tree)
Pouteria campechiana (Eggfruit)
Psidium cattleianum (Cattley guava)
Psidium guajava (Guava)
Syzygium cumini (Java plum)
Syzygium jambos (Rose apple)
Terminalia catappa (Tropical almond)
Washingtonia spp. (Washington palm)
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Removal of any tree which has been destroyed or effectively destroyed by an Act of God, or by acts outside of the control of any person, individually or otherwise, who has or had a legal, beneficial or equitable interest in the real property upon which such tree is located, which acts could not have been prevented by the exercise of reasonable care by any such person, individually or otherwise, who has or had a legal, beneficial or equitable interest in the real property upon which such tree is located. Where a tree has been destroyed or effectively destroyed by acts outside of the control of a person who has or had a legal, beneficial or equitable interest in the real property upon which such tree is located, which acts could not have been prevented by the exercise of reasonable care by such person, this provision shall be construed to impose joint and several liability upon the person(s) destroying or effectively destroying such tree, and to exempt from liability for such destruction or effective destruction the person who has or had a legal, beneficial or equitable interest in the real property upon which such tree is located.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Removing, trimming, cutting or altering of any mangrove tree or removal of any tree located upon land which is wetlands as defined in Section 24-5. Trees located upon land which is wetlands as defined in Section 24-5 and mangrove trees located anywhere in Miami-Dade County shall be subject to the permitting requirements of Article IV of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Removal of a tree or trees within a bona fide fruit grove for the express purpose of converting said bona fide fruit grove to another bona fide agricultural purpose, provided however, that the owner of the real property upon which the bona fide fruit grove is planted has entered into a covenant agreement with Miami-Dade County in the form approved by the Board of County Commissioners, which covenant requires that said property shall only be used for bona fide agricultural purposes for a period of five (5) years from the date of execution. The form for said covenant agreement shall be approved by the Board of County Commissioners by resolution concurrently with the approval of this ordinance so that all covenant agreements submitted pursuant to this provision can be executed and accepted by the Director and then recorded in the Official Records of Miami-Dade County without the necessity of additional public hearings. In the event that the provisions of said covenant are not complied with, the Director may commence an action in law or equity to ensure adherence with the replanting requirements contained in Section 24-49.4 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Any mortgagee with respect to property upon which any violation of this tree ordinance has occurred shall not be liable for such violation unless, prior to said violation, said mortgagee has foreclosed upon said property or participated in the management or control of said property, or unless said mortgagee has effected or caused the tree ordinance violations occurring on said property.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Notwithstanding the provisions of Section 24-31(7) herein, if actions or omissions constituting a violation of this article occurred at a time when the completed actions or omissions were not prohibited by law, such completed actions or omissions shall not constitute a violation of this article.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08; Ord. No. 13-24, § 1, 3-5-13)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-49.1. Permits generally</catch_line>
<text>
Tree removal permits are required for the removal or relocation of any tree not specifically exempted under Section 24-49(4). The Department shall provide permit application forms which shall be used by permit applicants. An owner, agent of the owner, or lessee of a property may apply for a tree removal permit. If the permit application is a lessee or agent of the owner, a statement from the owner of the property indicating that the owner has no objection to the proposed tree removal shall be submitted with the application. The permit applicant shall submit to the Department a completed application form. Permit application forms shall be accompanied by two (2) sets of site plans which are subject to review and approval by the Department. The site plan shall include the locations of all existing tree resources and all proposed structures or utilities which may require removal or relocation of trees. The Department may require that said plans be prepared by either a landscape architect, architect or an engineer registered in the State of Florida. If the submitted site plan does not provide sufficient information to determine which trees will be affected by the proposed development, the Department may require that a tree survey of the site be prepared and submitted to the Department for review.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-49.2. Review and evaluation of permit applications, natural forest community standards, specimen tree standards</catch_line>
<text>
A review of each completed tree removal permit application shall be conducted by the Department. This review and all actions taken by the Department under the provisions of this article shall be conducted using best available practices from biology, botany, forestry, landscape architecture and other relevant fields, and shall be conducted in a manner that is consistent with all applicable goals, objectives and policies in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan for Miami-Dade County, Florida. Upon receipt of a completed permit application, the Department shall determine whether the site contains any portion of a natural forest community, specimen trees or any other trees subject to the provisions of this article as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
If a site contains any portion of a natural forest community, then the provisions of Section 24-49.2(I) shall apply. If any person is in doubt as to whether a particular property has been designated as a natural forest community, said person may request a written determination from the Department. Said written determination shall state whether or not a particular property has been so designated by the Board of County Commissioners in the forest community maps under Resolution 1764-84 and shall be prepared by the Department within twenty (20) days of receipt of said request.
Any property owner of a designated natural forest community site may request that the Department verify the designated boundaries of a specific natural forest community site or may request that a specific site be deleted from the approved natural forest community maps. Requests for verification of the designated boundaries of a specific natural forest community site or the deletion of a specific site from the approved maps shall be made in writing to the Department. Upon receipt of such requests, Departmental staff shall inspect the site and make a determination whether the approved boundaries accurately reflect the current boundaries of a natural forest community as defined herein, or whether a site should be deleted from the approved maps. If it is determined that the approved boundaries of a specific natural forest community site are no longer accurate, the Director or the Director's designee shall modify the approved boundary of the natural forest community. One (1) copy of the modified boundary shall be furnished to the person who originated the request within thirty (30) days of receipt of the original request and another copy shall be made permanently available at the Department for reference by the public. If it is determined that a specific natural forest community site in its entirety no longer meets the definition of a natural forest community as defined herein, the Director shall recommend to the Board of County Commissioners that the site be deleted from the approved natural forest community maps.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
If a site contains any specimen trees, then the provisions of Section 24-49.2(II) shall apply.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
If there are trees present on a site other than any portion of a natural forest community or specimen trees, then the replacement provisions of Section 24-49.4 shall apply.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
In the event that a site contains any combination of natural forest community, specimen trees or other trees, then Sections 24-49.2(I), 24-49.2(II), and 24-49.4 shall be applied in proportion to the presence of each type of tree or community.
The standards to be applied in reviewing tree removal permit applications involving natural forest communities or specimen trees are as follows:
<section prefix = "I">
Natural Forest Community Standards.
<section prefix = "1">
Upon receipt of an application for tree or understory removal work in a natural forest community, Departmental staff shall verify that the site currently meets the definition of a natural forest community as defined herein. If Departmental staff determine that a site no longer meets the definition of a natural forest community, then the Director shall recommend to the Board of County Commissioners that the site be deleted from the natural forest community maps. Upon approval by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners, the site will no longer be subject to the provisions of Section 24-49.2(I), but may nevertheless be subject to the provisions of Sections 24-49.2(II) and 24-49.4. In the event that Departmental staff determine that the site currently meets the definition of a natural forest community as defined herein, but the boundary line shown on the approved maps no longer accurately reflects the boundary of a natural forest community as defined herein, the boundary of the natural forest community as shown on the approved maps shall be modified by the Director or the Director's designee. One (1) copy of the modified boundary shall be furnished to the property owner and another copy shall be made permanently available at the Department for reference by the public. If the boundaries of a natural forest community are modified, only that area encompassed within the modified boundary of the natural forest community shall be subject to the provisions of this section.
<section prefix = "a">
Except as provided in Section 24-49.2(I)(1)(c) below, a permit shall not be issued to clear more than ten (10) percent of the canopy and understory of any hardwood hammock natural forest community or more than twenty (20) percent of the canopy and understory of any pineland natural forest community, provided said sites are five (5) acres or greater. If a site has a total area of less than five (5) acres and the natural forest community covers all or a portion of the site, a permit may be issued to clear up to one-half (½) acre within a hammock natural forest community and up to one (1) acre within a pineland natural forest community, only if the clearing of ten (10) percent or twenty (20) percent, respectively, does not allow some use of the property.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The remaining portions of all natural forest community sites, outside of the areas where tree and understory removal have been permitted by the Department, shall be deemed preserve areas and shall be left in a natural state. Additional clearing of trees or understory shall be prohibited in these preserve areas, except as authorized by other provisions of this article. Firebreaks for pineland natural forest community preserves shall be permitted, and the total area encompassed by the firebreaks (up to a maximum of ten (10) percent of the natural forest community site) shall not be included in the total area which is permitted to be cleared, pursuant to Section 24-49.2(I)(1)(a) and (c). Required dedicated public rights-of-way and required public utility easements in pineland and hammock natural forest communities shall be excluded (up to a maximum of ten (10) percent of the natural forest community site) from the total areas permitted to be cleared, pursuant to Section 24-49.2(I)(1)(a) and (c). The criteria for determining which portion of a natural forest community shall be preserved are as follows:
<section prefix = "i">
Whether the preservation area affords maximum protection to rare, threatened and endangered species.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Whether the preservation area affords maximum protection to areas of high wildlife utilization such as, but not limited to, nesting or breeding areas.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Whether the preservation area is located to minimize the number of trees and understory vegetation that is to be removed and disturbed for development.
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
Whether the preservation area is located to protect the geological and archaeological value of the site.
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
Whether the preservation area is located contiguous with another natural forest community.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Permits for tree and understory removals within natural forest communities that are issued in accordance with Section 24-49.2(I)(1)(a) and (b) above shall not require any tree or understory replacement. As an alternative to Section 24-49.2(I)(1)(a). above, a permit may be issued to clear up to an additional ten (10) percent of a pineland natural forest community, provided that tree and understory replacement are a requirement of the permit. Said tree and understory replacement shall provide for the replacement of one hundred (100) percent canopy coverage equal to the square footage of the additional area to be cleared regardless of the actual tree canopy contained therein to account for the replacement of the trees and understory, pursuant to the provisions of Section 24-49.4(1)(b)(i).
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Any permit issued for the removal of trees and understory within a natural forest community shall include a specific requirement which allows a minimum of fifteen (15) days for the salvaging of native plant materials within the area which is permitted to be cleared. However, any person desirous of salvaging plant materials must first have authorization from the permittee or owner of the property, which authorization shall not be unreasonably withheld. The Department shall maintain a list of persons interested in salvaging native plant materials and shall notify them immediately upon issuance of such a permit.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Alternatives to the provisions of Section 24-49.2(I)(1). In order to provide for unique design considerations for the replacement requirements in Section 24-49.2(I)(1)(c) above, and to address natural forest community sites which are within the 1990 Urban Development Boundary, the following shall apply:
<section prefix = "a">
Alternative tree and understory replacement plans may be submitted for projects which require mitigation, pursuant to Section 24-49.2(I)(1)(c) above, that are outside of the 1990 Urban Development Boundary. Said alternative plan shall be prepared by a landscape architect or other individual knowledgeable in the field of natural area restoration, and shall indicate the deviations from the standard requirement and justification for approval.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Alternative tree and understory replacement and preservation plans may be submitted for projects which affect natural forest communities which are located within the 1990 Urban Development Boundary and which cannot meet the express terms of Section 24-49.2(I)(1). In such cases, the applicant shall have the burden of demonstrating that a proposed project meets the intent of this article and that the provisions of Section 24-49.2(I)(1) cannot be met.
<section prefix = "i">
At a minimum, an alternative tree and understory replacement and preservation plan shall include:
<section prefix = "1">
A statement sealed by a landscape architect registered in the State of Florida that indicates that he has prepared the submitted plan and that the intent of this article can effectively be met through the submission of an alternative plan; provided, however, if the project only encompasses a single family residence with ancillary facilities, then said statement and plan may be made by an individual knowledgeable in the field of natural area restoration;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The proposed location of all vegetation preservation and replantings (consisting exclusively of native species), all property lines, and all proposed or existing structures, driveways and utility easements; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
A tabulation that identifies any deviations from the requirements of Section 24-49.2(I)(1) and explicitly provides for equivalent compensation by alternative replanting (consisting exclusively of native species) or trust fund contributions.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Approval of the plan shall be determined by the Department. The Department shall consider the following factors in evaluating the alternative preservation plan:
<section prefix = "1">
Whether the proposed plan preserves a portion of the natural forest community.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Whether the proposed plan provides for on-site or off-site replanting, including understory replanting.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Whether the proposed plan provides for an equitable contribution to the Miami-Dade County Tree Preservation Trust Fund when the minimum preservation standards of Section 24-49.2(I)(1) are not met.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Modified preservation and replacement plan based upon justifiable, detrimental reliance allowed. In order to address these cases in which a person has purchased natural forest community property in justifiable, detrimental reliance upon written representations of Department staff made prior to the enactment of Chapter 24-49 of the Code of Miami-Dade County regarding replacement and preservation requirements for said property, the following shall apply:
Any owner of a natural forest community property who has purchased natural forest community property in justifiable, detrimental reliance upon written representations of Department staff made prior to the enacting of Chapter 24-49 [Article IV] of the Code of Miami-Dade County may submit to the Department an application for approval of a modified replacement and preservation plan which shall incorporate the replacement and preservation requirements reflected in the agreement relied upon. In such cases, the applicant shall have the threshold burden of demonstrating to the Department and the Board of County Commissioners the detrimental, justifiable reliance which provides the basis for his application.
<section prefix = "a">
The Department shall make its recommendation to the Board of County Commissioners, and the Board of County Commissioners shall make its decision, for denial or approval with conditions of the modified replacement and preservation plan. In evaluating the proposed modified preservation and replacement plan, and in making the threshold determination of whether the applicant has purchased natural forest community property in justifiable, detrimental reliance upon written representations of Department staff made prior to the enactment of Chapter 24-49 [Article IV] of the Code of Miami-Dade County, the Department shall make its recommendation, and the Board of County Commissioners shall make its decision, based upon the following factors:
<section prefix = "i">
At a minimum, the application for modified replacement and preservation plan shall reflect that the elements provided for in Section 24-49.2(I)(2)(b)(i)1, 2, and 3 above are included in the proposed plan, provided, however, that, if the Board of County Commissioners determines that the applicant purchased natural forest community property in justifiable, detrimental reliance upon written representations of Department staff made prior to enactment of Chapter 24-49 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, and if the written representations relied upon did not address tree replacement or tree compensation requirements, then the tree replacement or tree compensation requirements applicable at the time of such justifiable, detrimental reliance may be made a part of the modified replacement and preservation plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
In addition to the elements provided for in Section 24-49.2(I)(2)(b)(i)1, 2, and 3, the application for modified replacement and preservation plan shall include information regarding the following factors:
<section prefix = "1">
The nature of the written representations relied upon: Whether the representations by the Department could be construed to be a final determination regarding preservation and replacement requirements for the subject property; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The existence of a permit or written consent agreement with the Department: Whether a tree removal permit or consent agreement with the Department was entered into by the owner of the subject property or his immediate predecessor in title prior to purchase of the subject property; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The circumstances of the property purchase: Whether (a) the purchase of the subject property occurred before or after enactment of Chapter 24-49 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, and (b) the purchase of the subject property occurred close in time to the date of the written representations relied upon, and (c) the owner has legal representation or other professional assistance in negotiating and concluding said purchase; and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Subsequent dealings with the Department: Whether the applicant had dealings with the Department occurring subsequent to the date of the written representations relied upon and prior to the date of purchase of the subject property.
The Board of County Commissioners shall hold a public hearing concerning the application. A notice of the time and place of said public hearing shall be published in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County a minimum of seven (7) days prior to the public hearing. Said notice shall include a brief description of the proposed replacement and preservation plan and the location of the subject natural forest community property.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Appeal from denial of modified preservation and replacement plan. Any person aggrieved by any decision of the Board of County Commissioners pursuant to this Section 24-49.2(I)(3) may seek judicial review in accordance with the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "II">
Specimen Trees Standards.
<section prefix = "1">
Specimen trees application. Specimen trees shall be preserved whenever reasonably possible. Upon receipt of an application to remove a specimen tree, the Department shall consider the following factors in evaluating said application:
<section prefix = "a">
Size and configuration of the property.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Size and configuration of any proposed development.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Location of the tree relative to any proposed development.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Whether or not the tree can be preserved under the proposed plan or any alternative plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Health, condition and aesthetic qualities of the tree.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Whether the tree poses a threat to persons or property.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Alternate plans. If, upon review of the factors enumerated in Section 24-49.2(II)(1), the Department determines that a specimen tree cannot reasonably be preserved under the proposed plan, then the applicant shall provide an alternate plan when feasible, which shall include preservation of the specimen tree and design alterations consistent with the scope and intent of the initially-proposed plan. Alterations consistent with the scope and intent of the initially-proposed plan may include, but shall not be limited to:
<section prefix = "a">
An adjustment of building orientation on a site.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
An adjustment of lot lines within a site proposal for more than one (1) lot when said adjustment will not cause an unreasonable loss of usable space. An applicant shall have the burden of proof in the determination of what constitutes an unreasonable loss of usable space.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Specimen tree relocation. If preservation of the specimen tree and any alternate design consistent with the scope and intent of the initial plan are mutually exclusive, then the Department may issue a permit to relocate the specimen tree. If the tree removal permit requires relocation, then the applicant shall be required to relocate the tree in accordance with the standards set forth in Section 24-49.6
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Removal of specimen trees. If relocation of the specimen tree is not feasible, due to the size, health, location, species or any other factor, then a permit may be issued for removal, and tree replacement shall be required.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Replacement requirements for specimen trees. As a condition of the issuance of a tree removal permit for the removal of a specimen tree, tree replacement requirements shall be twice those specified in Section 24-49.4(2)(c). In the event that replacement is not feasible on-site, then alternative off-site replacement shall be required, or, as a last alternative, there shall be a contribution to the Miami-Dade County Tree Trust Fund for the full value of the replacement trees. Notwithstanding the above, there shall also be an equitable contribution to the Miami-Dade County Tree Trust Fund for the irreplaceable loss of the aesthetic and environmental contributions of the specimen tree(s), according to the contribution schedule established by the Board of County Commissioners, pursuant to Section 24-49.9
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Exemptions from specimen tree replacement requirements. An applicant may be exempt from the replacement requirements of Section 24-49.2(II)(5), but subject to the tree replacement requirements in Section 24-49.4(2)(c), under the following circumstances:
<section prefix = "a">
Upon submittal of a statement from a landscape architect registered in the State of Florida which indicates that a specimen tree, due to disease, condition, growth habit or any other reasonable botanical factor, does not provide the aesthetic or environmental contribution associated with a specimen tree. Said statement shall include the specific reason(s) for the claimed exemption from the provisions of Section 24.49.4(2).
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
When preservation of the specimen tree would cause a foreseeable risk to property.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
When a site contains more than one (1) specimen tree, and fifty (50) percent or more of the existing specimen trees and at least fifty (50) percent of the existing specimen tree canopy area is preserved.

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-49.3. Preliminary review of projects involving tree removal or relocation</catch_line>
<text>
The Department shall review and comment on the following actions: Any application for zoning relief which requires a public hearing before the Miami-Dade County Community Zoning Appeals Board or the Board of County Commissioners; applications for plat approval; administrative site plan review; applications for approval of development plans by the developmental impact committee and the South Florida Regional Planning Council; proposed plans for new roadways or improvements to highway design projects; proposed plans for new public park and recreational areas and other public facilities. This review procedure shall determine if a tree removal permit is required under Section 24-49, and whether the following standards, when applicable, are adhered to:
<section prefix = "1">
Any proposed action that does not involve specimen trees or development in a natural forest community shall be subject to the replacement standards in Section 24-49.4
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Development within natural forest communities or involving specimen trees:
<section prefix = "a">
If it is determined that the proposed development site is within a natural forest community or involves removal of a specimen tree, the standards set forth in Section 24-49.2 shall apply. Proposed site actions that are not in accordance with said standards shall receive a recommendation of denial from the Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board shall approve, grant or issue any building permit, certificate of use and occupancy (except for changes in ownership), platting action (final plat, waiver of plat or equivalent municipal platting action) or zoning action requiring a public hearing before the Miami-Dade County Community Zoning Appeals Board or the Board of County Commissioners for any land use involving division of property into parcels less than five (5) acres within natural forest communities without obtaining the prior written recommendation of the Director or the Director's designee. The Director or the Director's designee shall issue his written recommendation of approval only if the Director or the Director's designee determines that a preservation area equivalent in size to the minimum preservation area required for the site under Section 24-49.2(I) has been designated prior to the proposed action.

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-49.4. Replacement requirements for tree removal</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Tree replacement requirements. As a condition of the issuance of a tree removal permit, the permittee shall be required to replace trees that are authorized to be removed under the provisions of this section. The number of trees and number of species of trees required for replacement shall be determined according to the procedures contained herein. When the replacement canopy area exceeds ten thousand (10,000) square feet, replacement shall be described in a landscape replacement plan which shall meet the minimum requirements of Section 24-49.4(3), and no tree removal permit shall be issued until said plan has been approved by the Department, except as provided in Section 24-49.4(4).
<section prefix = "a">
The following are exempt from this section:
<section prefix = "i">
All tree removal activities included in Section 24-49(4).
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
All tree removal permits affecting natural forest community sites which meet the specific preservation requirements of Section 24-49.2(I)(1)(a) and (b).
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Trees which have been successfully relocated, pursuant to Section 24-49.6
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Natural forest community replacement requirements.
<section prefix = "i">
Pursuant to Section 24-49.2(I)(1)(c)., tree and understory replacement for pineland natural forest communities shall include the following:
<section prefix = "1">
All species proposed for replanting shall be native to Miami-Dade County's pinelands.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
For each additional one-half (½) acre which is permitted to be cleared, fifty (50) replacement pine trees (Pinus elliotti var. densa) shall be provided. Said pine trees shall meet the standards in either Section 24-49.4(4)(a)(i) or (ii); if the pine trees meet the standards of Section 24-49.4(4)(a)(i), then six hundred twenty-six (626) pineland understory and ground cover plants which meet the standards of Section 24-49.4(4)(a)(ii) shall be provided; if the pine trees meet the standards of Section 24-49.4(4)(a)(ii), then six hundred seventy-six (676) pineland understory and ground cover plans which meet the standards of Section 24-49.4(4)(a)(ii) shall be provided. The number of replacement plants for areas which are less than one-half (½) acre shall be determined on a prorated basis.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The diversity of understory and ground cover species provided shall be maximized to the greatest extent possible based on availability of materials.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
An eighty (80) percent survival rate after one (1) year shall be guaranteed for all pineland natural forest community replacement plantings.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
As an alternative to Section 24-49.4(1)(b)(i) above, a monetary contribution, equal to the cost of the replacement plants, labor costs for installation, and survival rate guarantee costs, may be made to the Miami-Dade County Tree Trust Fund. Said funds shall be utilized by the County to reestablish pineland on County-owned property or to purchase pinelands for preservation purposes.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
All other applications for the removal of trees or understory within natural forest communities which meet the requirements of Section 24-49.2(I)(1)(a) and (b) or Section 24-49.2(I)(2) shall not require any tree or understory replacement.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Specimen tree replacement requirements. As required in Section 24-49.2(II)(5), the replacement requirements for the removal of a specimen tree shall be twice those specified in this section, except as noted in Section 24-49.2(II)(6).
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Procedures for determining tree replacement requirements. The Department shall determine the total number of replacement trees required for the issuance of a tree removal permit according to the following procedural steps:
<section prefix = "a">
Step 1: Determining existing tree canopy coverage on-site. The area of existing tree canopy coverage of a site shall be determined by the Department, using one (1) or any combination of the following methods: Review of aerial photography; on-site inspection; and review of a tree survey. The Department may require the applicant to submit a tree survey for the purpose of this determination.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Step 2: Determining impact area of proposed project. The area of existing canopy coverage which will be affected (impact area) by the applicant's proposed development shall be determined by the Department. This determination shall be based on a site plan and completed tree removal permit application form submitted to the Department by the applicant.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Step 3: Determining number of replacement trees required to be planted. The total number of trees required for replacement shall be based on the area of impact and the category of replacement tree selected by the applicant. Each replacement tree shall compensate for a portion of the tree canopy lost in the impact area. The following table shall be used as a standard for determining the required number of replacement trees:
<section prefix="1" type="table">
<table class="thead1 table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">Category<br />Replacement<br />Tree:</td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class="">Portion of Impact Area that each replacement tree compensates for in square feet:</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Shade Tree 1</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">500</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Shade Tree 2</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">300</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Palm Tree 1</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">300</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Palm Tree 2</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">100</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Small Tree</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">200</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 
Any combination of shade trees, palm trees, or small trees shall be acceptable replacement, provided the total number of trees from all replacement categories compensate for the lost canopy. In the event that a replacement tree actually has more canopy coverage at the time of planting than the amount of credit allowed under the tree replacement formula above, then the applicant shall receive full credit for the canopy coverage provided by the replacement tree at the time of planting. The applicant shall submit a list of proposed replacement trees on a form provided by the Department, except when the total number of replacement trees exceeds twenty (20), and then the applicant shall be required to submit a landscape replacement plan consistent with the provisions of Section 24-49.4(3). Proposed replacement lists or plans are subject to Departmental approval. The Department shall approve proposed replacement trees that are consistent with the standards of Section 24-49.4(3).
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Step 4: Location of replacement trees. Specific placement of replacement trees on-site shall be determined by the applicant. If the site cannot accommodate the required replacement trees because of insufficient planting area as determined by the Department, then the applicant shall be required to plant replacement trees at an off-site location subject to Departmental approval, or, as a last alternative, shall provide an equitable contribution to the Miami-Dade County Tree Trust Fund to compensate for those replacement trees which cannot be accommodated on site. The amount of the contribution shall be determined according to the provisions of Section 24-49.8. If any applicant is in doubt as to whether a particular site can sufficiently accommodate the required number and species of replacement trees as initially determined by the Department, then the applicant shall submit a statement prepared by a landscape architect registered in the State of Florida, indicating whether, in his professional opinion, the site can accommodate the required number of trees and species. Upon receipt of said statement, the Department shall reevaluate its initial determination and provide the applicant with a revised determination of requirements. In the event that the landscape architect is in agreement with the Department's determination of available planting space, however, due to design considerations, the applicant would elect to propose an alternative landscape enhancement plan or an equitable contribution to the Miami-Dade County Tree Trust Fund, then the provisions of Section 24-49.4(4) or 24-49.2(II)(5), respectively, shall apply.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Step 5: Minimum species diversity standards. When more than ten (10) trees are required to be planted in accordance with the provisions of this section, a diversity of species shall be required. The number of species to be planted shall be based on the overall number of trees required. The applicant shall be required to meet the following minimum diversity standards:
<section prefix="2" type="table">
<table class="thead1 table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class=""> <i>Required Number<br />of Trees</i> </td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class=""> <i>Minimum Number<br />Species of</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">11—20</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">2</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">21—50</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">4</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">51 or more</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">6</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 
Permittees shall not be required to plant in excess of six (6) species. The number of trees of each species planted shall be proportional to the number of species required. A minimum of fifty (50) percent of all replacement trees planted shall be native to Miami-Dade County, and no more than thirty (30) percent of the replacement trees shall be palms. However, when native trees are removed, all replacement trees shall be native species. As an alternative to the minimum species diversity required herein, an applicant may propose an alternative species diversity in an alternative landscape enhancement plan described in Section 24-49.4(4).
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Step 6: Minimum standards for replacement trees.
<section prefix = "i">
All replacement trees shall have a minimum quality of a Florida No. 1 grade or better.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
The Department shall maintain a list of species for each category of replacement tree. This list may be amended from time to time, as necessary. Replacement tree heights shall be determined by overall height measured from where the tree meets the ground to the top-most branch.
<section prefix = "1">
All category 1 replacement shade trees shall be a minimum of twelve (12) feet in height at the time of planting and at maturity should have a canopy coverage of five hundred (500) square feet under normal growing conditions.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
All category 2 replacement shade trees shall be a minimum of eight (8) feet in height at the time of planting and at maturity should have a canopy coverage of three hundred (300) square feet under normal growing conditions.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
All category 1 replacement palm trees shall have a minimum height of ten (10) feet at the time of planting and at maturity should have a canopy coverage of three hundred (300) square feet under normal growing conditions.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
All category 2 replacement palm trees shall have a minimum height of three (3) feet at the time of planting and at maturity should have a canopy coverage of one hundred (100) square feet under normal growing conditions.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
All replacement small trees shall have a minimum height of six (6) feet at the time of planting and at maturity should have a canopy coverage of two hundred (200) square feet under normal growing conditions.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Requirements for a landscape replacement plan. Except as provided in Section 24-49.4(4), a landscape replacement plan shall be submitted to the Department by the permit applicant when a minimum of ten thousand (10,000) square feet of replacement canopy is required under the provisions of Section 24-49.4(2). All landscape replacement plans shall meet the following minimum standards:
<section prefix = "a">
The number of trees, number of species of trees, and size of trees proposed for planting shall be consistent with Section 24-49.4(2).
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The applicant shall submit a site plan that includes the proposed replacement locations of all replacement plantings and tree relocations, all property lines, and all proposed and existing structures, driveways and utility easements.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The canopy spread of any tree that is proposed for preservation shall be shown on the plan. Where a portion of the canopy of a tree or trees shall be removed without removal of the trees, a notation shall be made on the plan.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Alternatives to the provisions of Sections 24-49.4(2) and 24-49.4(3). Instead of replacing all affected trees pursuant to the provisions of Sections 24-49.4(2) and 24-49.4(3), an applicant may propose to relocate existing trees or propose a unique project design which provides reasonable assurance that the project complies with the intent to maintain tree canopy.
<section prefix = "a">
Generally, as an exception to the requirements of Section 24-49.4(2), and in order to provide for development of exceptional or unique landscape designs which cannot meet the express terms of Section 24-49.4(2), an applicant may submit an alternative landscape enhancement plan. As an alternative to the requirements in Section 24-49.4(2)(c), tree replacement credit may be granted for planting shrubs or ground covers, based upon the following table, provided, however, that a minimum of fifty (50) percent of the required canopy replacement is achieved by using shade trees and palm trees as required by Section 24-49.4(2)(c).
<section prefix="3" type="table">
<table class="thead1 table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class=""> <i>Category of Tree<br />Alternative Shrub<br />or Ground Cover:</i> </td> 
   <td style="background-color:LightGray; color:Black; " valign="top" class=""> <i>Portion of Impact Area that Each Tree Alternative Shrub, or Ground Cover Compensates for in Square Feet:</i> </td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Shrub 1 (including small palms)</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">60</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">Shrub 2/Ground Cover</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">30</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 
<section prefix = "i">
All category 1 tree alternative shrubs shall be a minimum of two (2) feet in height at the time of planting and at maturity should have a canopy coverage of sixty (60) square feet under normal growing conditions.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
All category 2 tree alternative shrubs or ground covers shall have a root system sufficient to sustain growth and at maturity should have a canopy coverage of ten (10) to twenty (20) square feet under normal growing conditions.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The applicant shall have the burden of demonstrating that a design meets the intent of this article. At a minimum, an alternative landscaping enhancement plan shall include, without limitation:
<section prefix = "i">
A statement, prepared by a landscape architect registered in the State of Florida, which indicates that the intent of this article can be effectively met through the submission of the alternative design; and
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
A site plan, prepared by a landscape architect registered in the State of Florida, that includes the proposed location, scientific name or description of all vegetation to be preserved or planted, all property lines, and all proposed or existing structures, driveways and utility easements; and
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
A tabulation that identifies any deviations from the requirements of Section 24-49.4(2) and explicitly provides tree replacement alternatives.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Department shall approve an alternative landscape enhancement plan when:
<section prefix = "i">
The design preserves and incorporates existing vegetation; and
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
The design exceeds the minimum requirements or equivalent of Section 24-49.4(2).
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Preservation credit for relocated trees. Permittees who successfully relocate trees shall receive full credit for the relocated trees and the tree replacement requirements herein shall not apply to such relocated trees. All relocated trees shall meet the standards set forth in Section 24-49.6 for tree relocation.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08; Ord. No. 13-24, § 2, 3-5-13)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-49.5. Tree protection requirements during construction</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
During site development, protection requirements for trees designated for preservation under an approved tree removal permit shall include, but not be limited to, the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Protective barriers shall be placed around each tree, cluster of trees, or the edge of the preservation area no less than six (6) feet (in radius) from the trunk of any protected tree, cluster of trees, or preservation area unless a lesser distance is specified by the Department. Protective barriers shall be a minimum of four (4) feet above ground level and shall be constructed of wood, plastic or metal, and shall remain in place until development is completed and the Department has authorized their removal. Protective barriers shall be in place prior to the start of any construction.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Understory plants within protective barriers shall be protected.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
No excess oil, fill, equipment, building materials or building debris shall be placed within the areas surrounded by protective barriers, nor shall there be disposal of any waste material such as paints, oils, solvents, asphalt, concrete, mortar or any other material harmful to trees or understory plants within the areas surrounded by protective barriers.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Trees shall not be braced in such a fashion as to scar, penetrate, perforate or otherwise inflict damage to the tree.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Natural grade shall be maintained within protective barriers. In the event that the natural grade of the site is changed as a result of site development such that the safety of the tree may be endangered, tree wells or retaining walls are required.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Underground utility lines shall be placed outside the areas surrounded by protective barriers. If said placement is not possible, disturbance shall be minimized by using techniques such as tunneling or overhead utility lines.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Fences and walls shall be constructed to avoid disturbance to any protected tree. Post holes and trenches located close to trees shall be dug by hand and adjusted as necessary, using techniques such as discontinuous footings, to avoid damage to major roots.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Exceptions to the provisions of Section 24-49.5(1). Exceptions to the requirements of Section 24-49.5(1) shall be approved only when the permittee receives specific written authorization from the Director or the Director's designee. The Director or the Director's designee shall not issue written approval unless the Director or the Director's designee determines that the affected tree(s) can be adequately protected without meeting the requirements of Section 24-49.5(1), or due to exceptional circumstances it is not practical or reasonable to meet the requirements of Section 24-49.5(1).
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
If the requirements of Section 24-49.5(1)(a) through (g) are not adhered to by the permittee and the trees are effectively destroyed, then all such trees shall be replaced according to the standards of Section 24-49.4(2), in addition to being subject to the penalty provisions of Sections 24-29, 24-30 and 24-31 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-49.6. Tree relocation standards</catch_line>
<text>
The relocation of any tree that is subject to the provisions of this article shall be consistent with the following minimum standards:
<section prefix = "1">
Trees other than palms:
<section prefix = "a">
Tree roots shall be severed in such a manner as to provide a root ball which is sufficient to ensure survival of the tree when relocated. A sufficiently-sized planting hole shall be provided at the relocation site to ensure successful regrowth.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
After root severing, adequate time shall be allowed prior to replanting to ensure survival of the tree(s). After root severing and prior to relocation, tree(s) shall be watered a minimum of twice weekly. After relocation, tree(s) shall be watered a minimum of twice weekly until the tree(s) are established.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
During removal and transportation of the tree, the root ball and vegetative portions of the tree shall be protected from damage from wind or injury.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Any tree that dies or becomes nonviable within one (1) year of relocation shall be replaced according to the standards set forth in Section 24-49.4(2).
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Palms:
<section prefix = "a">
A ball of earth at least one (1) foot from the base of the tree shall be moved with the tree.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Fronds shall be securely tied around the bud prior to relocation and shall remain securely tied around the bud during the entire relocation process and for a minimum of one (1) week after relocation.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The bud shall be protected from damage or injury during relocation.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Any palm that dies or becomes nonviable within one (1) year of relocation shall be replaced according to the standards set forth in Section 24-49.4(2).

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-49.7. Permit issuance, confirmation of natural forest community maps, existing permits, approvals and consent agreements</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
The Department shall deny an application, or approve an application and issue a permit (subject to conditions, limitations or restrictions), for the activity proposed under the permit application, provided:
<section prefix = "a">
The required application fee and permit fee is submitted to Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A performance bond, if required, has been posted. As a condition of issuing a tree removal permit, the Department may require the posting of a performance bond to guarantee compliance with all other conditions, limitations, and restrictions of the tree removal permit (the permitted activity), including, without limitation, planting of all required replacement trees. The bond shall be equivalent to one hundred (100) percent of the estimated cost of the permitted activity and may be in the form of a letter of credit, surety, cash, or certificate of deposit. All performance bonds shall remain in force for a minimum of either one (1) year after the actual completion date of the permitted activity (to ensure that any replanted trees which perish are replaced), or until viability of all replanted trees has been achieved, whichever occurs last. However, at the discretion of the Director or the Director's designee, performance bonds may be partially released in phases based upon partial completion of planting or other permit requirements.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All required plans or covenants are submitted and are in compliance with the standards herein.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
All permits shall clearly specify all conditions, limitations and restrictions required by the Department. The permit applicant shall acknowledge that the permit applicant fully understands and agrees to comply with all of said conditions, limitations or restrictions by signing the permit prior to its issuance.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
All tree removal permit applications which remain incomplete for a period of one hundred twenty (120) days shall be denied. A new tree removal permit application shall be required for all work previously proposed under a permit application which has been denied.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The natural forest community maps approved by the Board of County Commissioners on December 12, 1984, by Resolution No. 1764-84, all tree removal permits issued pursuant to Chapter 26B, Department approvals, and all consent agreements executed in order to resolve alleged violations of Chapter 26B of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, are hereby confirmed and shall remain in full force and effect, and all conditions, restrictions and limitations contained therein shall continue to apply, and compliance therewith shall be enforceable pursuant to the provisions of this chapter.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-49.8. Permit fees; schedule</catch_line>
<text>
The Department shall charge and collect application and permit fees and trust fund contributions at the rates established by separate administrative order which shall not become effective until approved by the Board of County Commissioners. Applications from government agencies for tree removals in areas dedicated to public use may, in the discretion of the Director, be exempted from application fees and permit fees.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-49.9. Prohibited plant species and controlled plant species</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Controlled plant species listed in the Miami-Dade County Landscape Manual on the effective date of this ordinance shall not be planted within 500 feet of native plant communities as defined pursuant to Section 18-3, Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. Additionally, the following exotic pest plant and nuisance species, with scientific nomenclature as set forth in Wunderlin, Richard P. and Hansen, Bruce F., Guide to the Vascular Plants of Florida, 2nd Ed. University of Florida Press, Gainesville, FL. (2003), a copy of which shall be maintained by the Director or Director's designee and available for review by the public, may not be sold, propagated or planted anywhere in Miami-Dade County. If present on a development or redevelopment site, they shall be removed prior to development or redevelopment, and their sale, propagation, planting, importation or transportation shall be prohibited. Pursuant to this subsection and in accordance with Chapter 19 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, developed sites shall be maintained to prevent the growth or accumulation of prohibited species including grass, weeds and non-native undergrowth.
Abrus precatorius (Rosary pea)
Acacia auriculiformis (Earleaf acacia)
Adenanthera pavonina (Red beadtree, red sandalwood)
Albizia lebbeck (Woman's tongue, lebbeck tree, siris tree)
Antigonon leptopus (Coral vine, queen's jewels)
Ardisia crenata (Scratchthroat, coral ardisia)
Ardisia elliptica (Shoebutton, shoebutton ardisia)
Bischofia javanica (Javanese bishopwood, bishopwood, bischofia, toog)
Casuarina spp. (Australian pine, sheoak, beefwood)
Cestrum diurnum (Dayflowering jessamine, day blooming jasmine, day jessamine)
Cinnamomum camphora (Camphortree, camphor tree)
Colubrina asiatica (Asian nakedwood, leatherleaf, latherleaf)
Cupaniopsis anacardioides (Carrotwood)
Dalbergia sissoo (Indian rosewood, sissoo)
Dioscorea alata (White yam, winged yam)
Dioscorea bulbifera (Air potato, bitter yam, potato vine)
Eichhornia crassipes (Common water-hyacinth, water-hyacinth)
Ficus altissima (Council tree, lofty fig, banyan tree, false banyan)
Ficus benghalensis (Banyan tree, banyan fig, Indian banyan, East Indian fig tree, Bengal fig)
Ficus microcarpa (Indian laurel, laurel fig, Malay banyan, Chinese banyan, glossy leaf banyan)*
Flacourtia indica (Governor's plum, Madagascar plum, batoko plum, ramonchi)
Hydrilla verticillata (Water thyme, hydrilla)
Hygrophila polysperma (Indian swampweed, green hygro)
Hymenachne amplexicaulis (Trompetilla, West Indian marsh grass)
Imperata cylindrica (Cogongrass)
Ipomoea aquatica (Water-spinach)
Jasminum dichotomum (Gold Coast jasmine)
Jasminum fluminense (Brazilian jasmine, jazmin de trapo)
Leucaena leucocephala (White leadtree, lead tree, jumbie bean, tan-tan)
Ludwigia peruviana (Peruvian primrosewillow)
Lygodium spp. except L. palmatum (Climbing fern, e.g. Old World climbing fern, Japanese climbing fern)
Macfadyena unguis-cati (Catclaw vine)
Melaleuca quinquenervia (Punk tree, melaleuca, cajeput, paperbark tree, tea tree, swamp tea tree)
Melia azedarach (Chinaberrytree, Chinaberry)
Merremia tuberosa (yellow morning-glory, woodrose, Hawaiian woodrose)
Mikania micrantha (Mile-a-minute, bittervine)
Mimosa pigra (Black mimosa, Catclaw mimosa)
Neyraudia reynaudiana (Burmareed, silkreed)
Paederia spp. (Sewervine, skunkvine, onion vine)
Panicum repens (Torpedograss)
Pennisetum purpureum (Elephantgrass, Napiergrass)
Pistia stratiotes (Water lettuce)
Pueraria montana var. lobata (Kudzu)
Rhodomyrtus tomentosa (Rose myrtle, Downy rose-myrtle)
Rhynchelytrum repens (Rose natalgrass, Natal grass)
Ricinus communis (Castorbean, castor oil plant, palma christi, wonder tree)
Sapium sebiferum (Popcorntree, Chinese tallowtree)
Scaevola taccada (Beach naupaka, scaevola, half-flower)
Schefflera actinophylla (Australian umbrella tree, octopus tree, Queensland umbrella tree)
Schinus terebinthifolius (Brazilian pepper, Christmas berry tree, Florida holly)
Senna pendula var. glabrata (Valamuerto, Climbing cassia, Christmas cassia, Christmas senna)
Solanum tampicense (Aquatic soda apple, wetland nightshade)
Solanum viarum (Tropical soda apple)
Talipariti tiliaceum (Mahoe, sea hibiscus, yellow mahoe)
Tectaria incisa (Incised halberd fern)
Thespesia populnea (Portia tree, seaside mahoe, cork tree, false rosewood)
Tribulus cistoides (Puncture vine, burrnut, Jamaican feverplant, billy-goat weed, large yellow caltrop)
Urochloa mutica (Paragrass)
* Ficus microcarva may be propagated for export outside of the State of Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Definitions for Section 24-49.9(1), Sections 24-49.9(3)(a), 3(b), and 3(c):
<section prefix = "a">
Importation shall mean the conveyance by any means of plants into Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Planting shall mean the placing on or setting into the ground of live plant material.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Propagation shall mean the physical act of causing plants to multiply by any process of reproduction from plant stock.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Sale shall mean the act of transferring or conveying plants to a purchaser for consideration.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Transportation shall mean the act of carrying or conveying plants from one (1) place to another for the purpose of sale, planting, importation or propagation.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Variances.
<section prefix = "a">
A variance by the Director from the requirements or prohibitions of this section may be requested, subject to the conditions justifying variance approval outlined below in Section 24-49.9(3)(b). Said variance request shall be made in writing to the Director and shall include the following information:
<section prefix = "i">
Name and address of the person or persons requesting the variance.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Location of the property for which the variance is requested.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
A sketch or drawing indicating the location within the subject property where the planting or field propagation of the otherwise prohibited plant species will occur. (Container propagation shall be exempt from said sketch or drawing requirements.)
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
The reason or reasons for requesting the variance.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Director may, in the Director's discretion, issue a variance from the provisions of this subsection based upon the following factors:
<section prefix = "i">
Proximity of the subject planting or propagation to any environmentally sensitive areas (e.g., wetlands, hammocks, pinelands, dunes).
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Lack of appropriate alternative plant species to fulfill the same purpose or purposes for planting.
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
The designation of a tree as a Historic Tree by the local Historic Preservation Board.
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
Compensatory actions proposed to offset impacts for any adverse environmental impact or cumulative adverse environmental impact which may result from granting the variance.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Director shall issue or deny a variance request within thirty (30) days of receipt of the variance request, provided the required information described in Section 24-49.9(3)(a)(i) through (iv) above has been submitted.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08; Ord. No. 13-24, § 3, 3-5-13)</history>
</law>
