<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="3">ARTICLE VI. SIGNS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="4">DIVISION_2._GENERAL_PROVISIONS</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-85. Interpretation</catch_line>
<text>
Only those signs that are specially authorized by this sign code shall be permitted. Those that are not listed or authorized shall be deemed prohibited. It is provided, however, that any sign authorized herein may contain, in lieu of any other message or copy, any lawful noncommercial message, so long as such sign complies with the size, height, area and other requirements of this article.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-86. Permits required</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Applications and permits. No sign, unless excepted by this article, shall be erected, constructed, posted, painted, altered, maintained, or relocated, except as provided in this article and until a permit has been issued by the Department. Before any permit is issued, an application for such permit shall be filed together with three (3) sets of drawings and/or specifications (one (1) to be returned to the applicant) as may be necessary to fully advise and acquaint the issuing department with the location, method of construction, type of materials, manner of illumination, method of erection, securing or fastening, number and type of signs applied for, and advertisement to be carried. All signs which are electrically illuminated by neon or any other means shall require a separate electric permit and inspection.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Consent of property owner. No sign shall be placed on any property unless the applicant has the written consent of the owner and lessee, if any, of the property.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Calculating number of signs. A single sign containing advertisement on each side shall be counted as one (1) sign. Every other sign shall be counted as a separate sign for each face thereof. Excepting class C signs, "V" type signs will be considered as one (1) sign if the spread of the "V" at the open end is not greater than the length of its narrowest side.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Calculating sign size. The area of a sign shall include borders and framing. Heights shall be measured to the top extremity of the sign and distances to the farthest point. The square footage in a circular rotating or revolving sign shall be determined by multiplying one-half (½) of the circumference by the height of the rotating sign, except in the case of the flat rotating sign, the area will be determined by the square footage of one (1) side of such sign. The Director shall have the discretion of determining the area of any sign which is irregular in shape, and in such cases will be guided by calculations as made by a licensed, registered engineer when same are shown on the drawing.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Review of the application. The Department shall complete its review of a sign permit application for the unincorporated area within 30 calendar days after filing, and shall render a decision either for approval or denial within that time. Failure by the Department to render a decision within 30 calendar days shall be deemed a denial, appealable as provided herein. If the permit is denied based upon grounds set forth in this article, the applicant may file an appeal to the appropriate Community Zoning Appeals Board. Such appeal shall be heard at the next regular meeting of such board after notice pursuant to the requirements of Section 33-310(c) of this code. Further appeal shall be as authorized pursuant to the Florida rules of court. It is provided that the procedures for the review of a sign permit application pursuant to this section shall be limited to the Department of Planning and Zoning and shall not apply to other county departments' review of a sign permit application pursuant to the Florida Building Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Restrictions on Certain Class C Sign Permits.
<section prefix = "1">
No permit shall be issued for a mural on property where a civil violation notice pursuant to Chapter 8CC of this code has been issued for an unauthorized mural until such civil violation notice has been resolved.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
No permit shall be issued for a mural to an erector or affiliate of such erector who has been issued a civil violation notice pursuant to Chapter 8CC of this code for erecting an unauthorized mural until such civil violation notice has been resolved.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
No permit shall be issued to a property owner or owner of a mural or affiliate thereof who has been issued a civil violation notice pursuant to Chapter 8CC of this code for erecting an unauthorized mural, until such civil violation notice has been resolved.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
No permit shall be issued for an existing mural in violation of this article if authorization for such mural was obtained from a municipality.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
No permit for a mural shall be issued to an owner, erector or affiliate thereof, if such owner, erector or affiliate has an existing agreement with a municipality purporting to allow the establishment or continuation of a mural upon payment of fines, penalties or other payments to the municipality, if such mural is not in compliance with the requirements of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
For purposes of this subsection, the term "affiliate" shall mean (i) a person, corporation, partnership or other business organization ("entity"), directly controlling, controlled by, or under common control with, another entity, or (ii) any entity owning or controlling ten percent or more of the ownership interest of another entity.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 85-59, § 2, 7-18-85; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 07-61, § 4, 4-26-07)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-87. Compliance with codes</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
[Required.] All signs shall conform to the requirements of the building, electrical, and other applicable technical codes, except as may be otherwise provided herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Advertising conflicting with zoning rules. No sign shall be erected or used to advertise any use or matter which would conflict with the regulations for the district in which it is located or be in conflict with the use permitted under the certificate of use or occupancy for the property.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 85-59, § 2, 7-18-85)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-88. Qualification and certification of erector</catch_line>
<text>
Where the erection of any sign requires compliance with any Miami-Dade County technical code, the erector of the sign shall qualify with the respective examining board.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-89. Fees required</catch_line>
<text>
No sign, where a permit is necessary shall be exhibited unless the required permit fees are paid.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-90. Time limitation of permits</catch_line>
<text>
All signs shall be erected on or before the expiration of ninety (90) days from the date of issuance of the permit. If the sign is not erected within said ninety (90) days, the permit shall become null and void, and a new permit required; provided, however, that the Director may extend such permit for a period of ninety (90) days from the date of the expiration of the permit if written application for such extension is received and approved by the Director prior to the expiration date of the initial permit and provided that the proposed sign complies with all requirements in effect at the date of such renewal.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-91. Identification of permit holder on sign</catch_line>
<text>
Each sign requiring a permit shall carry the permit number and the name of the person or firm placing the sign on the premises; such marking shall be permanently attached and clearly visible from the ground.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-92. Responsibility for sign</catch_line>
<text>
The owner and/or tenant of the premises, and the owner and/or erector of the sign shall be held responsible for any violation of this chapter; provided, however, that when the sign has been erected in accordance with this chapter, the sign company shall be relieved of further responsibility after final approval of the sign.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-93. Inspection</catch_line>
<text>
No sign shall be approved for use, unless the same shall have been inspected by the Department issuing the permit, and no sign shall be erected or used unless it complies with all the requirements of this chapter and applicable technical codes. The holder of a permit for a sign shall request inspections of a sign as follows:
<section prefix = "1">
Foundation inspection (this shall include method of fastening to building or other approved structure).
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Shop inspection (electrical and/or structural where indicated on the permit and/or approved plan).
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Final inspection (this shall include structural framing, electrical work identification of permit number and erector of sign, etc.).
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Any additional inspections which may be specified on the permit and/or approved plans.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-94. Signs permitted without a sign permit</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Class A temporary signs not exceeding six (6) square feet in area, not electrically illuminated will not require a sign permit, but must otherwise comply with this article and applicable technical codes.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Traffic signs, provisional warnings and signs indicating danger, are exempt from this chapter. Such exempted signs shall not contain any commercial advertisement.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Awning, canopy, roller curtain, or umbrella sign or signs shall be limited to eight-inch letters in height, and shall not exceed a total coverage of twenty-four (24) square feet. Any such sign shall be limited to the identification of the occupant and/or use of the property. No sign permit shall be required for the awning, canopy, roller curtain or umbrella sign, but the same shall comply with applicable technical codes.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Disabled or handicapped parking signs. Signs required by State law or County ordinance for parking spaces reserved for disabled or handicapped persons shall not require a sign permit.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Signs not exceeding one and one-half (1½) square feet in area and bearing only property street numbers, post box numbers, or name of occupant of premises.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Flags and insignia of any government, except when displayed in connection with commercial promotion.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Legal notices, identification, information, or directional signs erected by or on behalf of governmental bodies.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Integral decorative and architectural features of buildings except letters, logos, trademarks, moving parts or moving lights.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Signs within enclosed buildings or structures which are so located that they are not visible from public or private streets or adjacent properties such as signs in interior areas of malls, commercial buildings, ball parks, stadiums and similar structures or uses, providing said signs are erected in such a manner as not to be hazardous. If illuminated, the necessary electrical permits shall be obtained.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Temporary holiday decorations provided said decorations carry no advertising matter and further provided that such decoration is not up more than sixty (60) days for a single holiday and is removed within seven (7) days after the holiday ends.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
"Danger," "No Parking," "Post No Bills," "Bad Dog," and similar warning signs, provided such signs do not exceed an area of one (1) and one-half (1.5) square feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Banners and other decorative materials in conjunction with an event conducted pursuant to a dedication or a grand opening, are permitted without a sign permit. Such banners and decorative materials are not to be posted more than thirty (30) days preceding the event, and are to be removed within seven (7) days following the grand opening day of the event.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
Signs required by law.
</section>
<section prefix = "n">
Signs which are incorporated within bus passenger benches and shelters in compliance with Sections 33-121.14 and 33-121.17(b).
</section>
<section prefix = "o">
Baby stroller parking signs. Signs required for parking spaces reserved for persons transporting young children and strollers shall not require a sign permit.
</section>
<section prefix = "p">
"No Trespassing" signs, provided such signs do not exceed an area of three (3) square feet.
</section>
<section prefix = "q">
The Director of the Miami-Dade County Park and Recreation Department, or designee, shall be permitted to post banners promoting park activities, special events and sponsorships relating to same, provided (i) such banners are posted on the Miami-Dade County park property where the activity or special event will occur; (ii) that each banner shall be limited in size to no more than thirty (30) square feet; (iii) that the banner shall not be posted more than sixty (60) days preceding the activity or event and shall be removed within seven (7) days following the activity or event. Banners complying with the conditions specified in this subsection shall be permitted without a sign permit.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 85-59, § 2, 7-18-85; Ord. No. 90-24, § 1, 3-20-90; Ord. No. 96-161, § 1, 11-12-96; Ord. No. 96-162, § 1, 11-12-96; Ord. No. 06-35, § 1, 3-7-06)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-95. Prohibited signs</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
No sign shall be so located as to constitute a danger to public safety.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
No sign shall exhibit thereon any lewd or lascivious matter.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
No sign shall be attached to trees, utility poles or any other unapproved supporting structure.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Roof signs are prohibited in all the districts.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
No signs shall be erected or painted on fence and wall enclosures in residential districts. Fence and wall signs shall be prohibited in the residential districts. These restrictions do not apply to Class B signs in the AU district.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
In both the incorporated and unincorporated areas of the County even if not classified as a sign, blinking or flashing lights, streamer lights, pennants, banners, streamers, and all fluttering, spinning or other type of attention attractors or advertising devices are prohibited except for national flags, flags of bona fide civic, charitable, fraternal and welfare organizations and further except during recognized holiday periods such attention-attractors that pertain to such holiday periods may be displayed on a temporary basis during such periods. The flags permitted by this subsection shall not be used in mass in order to circumvent this subsection by using said flags primarily as an advertising device.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
No revolving or rotating sign shall be permitted or erected except as a class B (point of sale) sign in the BU and IU Districts. Such signs shall be illuminated by internal lighting only.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Any signs which are not traffic signs as defined in Section 33-94(b) which use the word "stop" or "danger" or present or imply the need or requirement of stopping, or which are copies or imitations of official signs. Red, green or amber (or any color combination thereof) revolving or flashing light giving the impression of a police or caution light is a prohibited sign, whether on a sign or on an independent structure.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Unless specifically permitted by this chapter or other law, portable signs shall be prohibited, including those that are tied down with metal straps, chaining, or otherwise temporarily anchored to an existing structure or other similar method of anchoring.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Signs painted or affixed in any manner to any vehicle, trailer or pickup truck, van or similar transportable device and which is used to advertise a place of business or activity as viewed from a public road shall be prohibited. This shall not be interpreted to prohibit identification of commercial vehicles provided such vehicles are operational and moved and used daily for delivery or service purposes and are not used, or intended for use, as portable signs. This sign shall also not be interpreted to apply to buses, taxicabs, and similar common carrier vehicles which are licensed or certified by Miami-Dade County or other governmental agency.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 85-59, § 2, 7-18-85; Ord. No. 10-90, § 1, 12-7-10)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-96. Illumination</catch_line>
<text>
Except as provided in Section 33-96.1, signs illuminated by flashing, moving, intermittent, chasing or rotating lights are prohibited. Signs may be illuminated by exposed bulbs, fluorescent tubes, interior lighting, or by indirect lighting from any external source. Indirect lighting, such as floodlights, shall not shine directly on adjacent property, motorists or pedestrians. Illumination shall be such that it will provide reasonable illumination and eliminate glare and intensity which might pose safety hazards to drivers and pedestrians. Revolving and rotating signs shall be illuminated by internal lighting only.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-96.1. Automatic electric changing signs</catch_line>
<text>
Subject to the following mandatory conditions, Automatic Electric Changing Signs ("ACS"), shall be permitted in BU and IU districts, seaports, airports, sports stadiums, racetracks, and other similar uses as follows:
<section prefix = "a">
This provision shall apply to Class B (Point of Sale) signs only.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
An ACS shall conform to all sign size, placement, setback, and quantity limitations as provided elsewhere in this chapter and shall comply with all building code requirements.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Incandescent lamps/bulbs in excess of 9 watts are prohibited in an ACS. Incandescent lamps/bulbs in an ACS shall not be exposed but shall be covered by a translucent lenses or filters.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
An ACS shall be equipped with an automatic operational night dimming device.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The following operating modes are prohibited:
<section prefix = "1">
Flash — the condition created by displaying the same message intermittently by turning it on and off, on and off, with rapidity, or any other delivery mode that creates a flashing effect.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Zoom — the look or condition created by expanding a message from a central point to its full size.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Any signs which use the word "stop" or "danger" or imply the need or requirement of stopping, or which are copies or imitations of official signs.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Red, green or amber (or any color combination thereof) revolving or flashing light giving the impression of a police or caution light shall be prohibited.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
A minimum of ten (10) acres gross improved land area shall be required for the placement of an ACS.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
With the exception of airports or seaports, the subject ACS shall be located only on a major or minor roadway as depicted on the adopted Comprehensive Development Master Plan Land Use Plan map.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
A detached ACS shall be surrounded by a minimum of twenty-five (25) square feet of landscaped area. A plan indicating such landscape area shall be submitted to the Director at the time of building permit application.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
The content of the ACS shall be limited solely to the promotion of products or services offered on the premises. The only fixed message shall be the name of the company possessing a valid Certificate of Use and Occupancy for the subject premises.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
The applicant for an ACS shall file of record a declaration of use, on a form prescribed and approved by the Director, which will govern the operation of the ACS and contain penalties for abatement and removal of the ACS for violations of the declaration of use and the provisions herein.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33-97. Maintenance of signs</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
[Required.] All signs shall be properly maintained in a safe and legible condition at all times. In the event that a use having a sign is discontinued for a period of forty-five (45) days, all signs identifying the use are to be removed from the site or in the case of a painted sign, painted out. Sign removal shall be the responsibility of the owner of the property.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Latticework, painting, etc. Where the rear of any sign is visible from a street, waterway, park or residence, or from a EU, RU, or BU District, the exposed structural members of such sign shall be either concealed by painted latticework, slats or be suitably painted or decorated, and such back screening shall be designed, painted and maintained to the satisfaction of the Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Cutting weeds. The owner of each sign not attached to a building shall be responsible for keeping the weeds cut on his property within a radius of fifty (50) feet or to the nearest highway or waterway.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Removal of dilapidated signs. The Director may cause to be removed any sign which shows neglect or becomes dilapidated or where the area around such sign is not maintained as provided herein after due notice has been given. The owner of the sign and/or the property shall be financially responsible for the removal of the sign.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 85-59, § 2, 7-18-85)</history>
</law>
