<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="3">ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="4">DIVISION_4._TRUSTS_AND_FEES</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-32. Collection of fees</catch_line>
<text>
The Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management shall charge and collect fees at the rates established by separate administrative order, which shall not become effective until approved by the Board of County Commissioners. To preclude duplication of collection responsibility, fees to be collected for services of the Public Works Department and the Department of Environmental Resources Management for one (1) and the same project may be jointly collected if and as designated within the administrative order.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-33. Refund of fees</catch_line>
<text>
If a person, firm or corporation to whom a permit has been issued decides to cancel the work for which a permit fee has been collected by the Department of Environmental Resources Management, the person, firm or corporation shall be entitled to a refund. Refunds for permit fees previously collected shall be made by the Finance Department, but must be requested prior to the beginning of any work and no later than the date on which the permit expires. No refunds shall be made on permit fees of ten dollars ($10.00) or less. In lieu of a refund, a credit for the amount of the permit fee in excess of the ten dollars ($10.00) may be given to the person, firm, or corporation which may be applied to the charge for a subsequent permit of equal or greater amount.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-34. Service fee payable to County</catch_line>
<text>
Each water or sewer utility shall collect from its customers and pay to the County a County service fee equal to seven dollars and fifty cents ($7.50) per each one hundred dollars ($100.00) of the receipts of said utility derived from its water and/or sewer utility operations conducted within the County to cover the cost of providing certain environmental services to and certain environmental regulation of said water or sewer utilities. Receipts from bulk water and sewerage service to other water or sewer utilities shall be excluded from the imposition of the County service fee provided for herein. Said service fee shall be due and payable to the County annually and shall be based upon receipts from water and/or sewerage service for the period from the first of October through the thirtieth of September of the following year. The fee shall be paid to Miami-Dade County no later than the first of December of each year for the period ending September 30 of that year. The first such period shall be October 1, 1980, through September 30, 1981, and the first fee payment shall be paid to the County on or before December 1, 1981. Failure to pay said service fee to the County on or before each December 1 shall obligate the utility to pay to the County a late charge. Said late charge shall be one and one-half (1½) percent of the unpaid balance of the fee for each month or part of each month that the fee remains unpaid.
Each water and sewer utility shall collect from its customers the service fee imposed upon said utility by this section, including but not limited to those utilities whose rates are not regulated by the Miami-Dade County Water and Sewer Board. Said County service fee imposed by this section shall be deemed a pass-through cost as defined by Section 32-64(b)(3) of the Code of Miami-Dade County, but no hearing shall be required of any water and sewer utility before the Miami-Dade County Water and Sewer Board, nor shall the approval of the Miami-Dade County Water and Sewer Board be necessary for the imposition of this fee by the utility upon its customers. Approval of this provision by the County Commission shall constitute approval of the necessary rate increase for the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department pursuant to Chapter 32A.
Payment of the fee to the County shall be accompanied by a statement verified by the utility showing its receipts upon which such fee is computed. This statement shall be in such form as the Director shall prescribe and shall be subject to audit by the County.
The service fee payable hereunder shall be deposited in a separate County fund and shall be used exclusively by the Department to pay for the costs of the following environmental services to and environmental regulation of said water and sewer utilities:
<section prefix = "1">
Monitoring and evaluating water and sewerage systems of said water and sewer utilities.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Responding to and attempting to resolve citizen complaints against said water and sewer utilities.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Investigation, preparation, and prosecution of enforcement actions, pursuant to Chapter 24 of this Code, to protect the groundwater, surface water and drinking water.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Ambient monitoring of groundwater and surface water.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Special studies of groundwater, drinking water, and surface water when deemed necessary by the Director to protect the groundwater, surface water and drinking water.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Water supply protection, planning and programming, including without limitation, municipal solid waste landfill closure, environmental remediation at landfill sites, and land acquisition for purposes of water supply protection.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Laboratory analyses of groundwater, surface water, drinking water, waste water, and other effluents affecting water quality.

No part of said fund shall be used for purposes other than the aforesaid.
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-35. Separate County enforcement fund</catch_line>
<text>
The following sums recoverable by the County shall be deposited in a separate County fund:
<section prefix = "1">
The compensatory and punitive damages recoverable by the County pursuant to Section 24-29(1) of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The civil penalties recoverable by the County pursuant to Section 24-31(2) of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The compensatory damages, punitive damages, costs, expenses and civil penalties recoverable by the County pursuant to Section 24-31(1) of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The sums recoverable by the County pursuant to Section 24-31(2) of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The sums recoverable by the County as reimbursement pursuant to Section 24-20(2) of the Code of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Notwithstanding subsections (1) through (5) hereinabove, any sums recoverable by the County pursuant to any of the foregoing provisions of Chapter 24 of the Code of Miami-Dade County which qualify for deposit in the Biscayne Bay Environmental Enhancement Trust Fund shall be deposited in said Biscayne Bay Environmental Enhancement Trust Fund.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Notwithstanding subsections Sections 24-35(1) through (6) hereinabove, any sums recoverable by the County pursuant to any of the foregoing provisions of Chapter 24 of the Code of Miami-Dade County which qualify for deposit in the Tree Trust Fund shall be deposited in said Tree Trust Fund.
This fund may only be used to pay for the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Tracing, controlling and abating of air pollution, water pollution, nuisances and sanitary nuisances in the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Enforcement of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Restoration of the air, waters, property, animal life, aquatic life, and plant life of the County to their former condition.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
All interest generated from the sources identified in Section 24-35(1) through 24-35(7) hereinabove, except where monies received have been otherwise designated or restricted.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Reimbursement of sums given to the County by the State of Florida or the United States of America, or both, as reimbursement for expenditures by the County to trace, control and abate air pollution, water pollution, nuisances and sanitary nuisances in the County and to restore the air, waters, property, animal life, aquatic life and plant life of the County to their former condition. Said reimbursement to the State of Florida or the United States of America, or both, from this fund shall not in any case exceed the amount of monies actually recovered and collected by the County from the persons liable for the particular air pollution, water pollution, nuisances and sanitary nuisances and furthermore shall not include any monies recovered by the County from said persons liable as compensatory damages, punitive damages or civil penalties. Said reimbursement of sums by the County to the State of Florida or the United States of America, or both, shall be upon such terms and conditions deemed appropriate and approved by the Board of County Commissioners.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-36. Pollution Prevention Trust Fund</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
The Pollution Prevention Trust Fund is created for use in developing, promoting and conducting environmental workshops, expositions, symposia, conferences and other forms of public information for the purpose of educating industry, government and the public about pollution prevention. The Finance Director is hereby authorized and directed to establish the Pollution Prevention Trust Fund and to receive and disburse monies in accordance with the provisions of this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Pollution Prevention Trust Fund shall receive monies from the following sources:
<section prefix = "a">
All revenues or fees collected by the Department from exhibitors, attendees, and sponsors participating in a pollution prevention event.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
All monies accepted by Miami-Dade County in the form of federal, state, or other governmental grants, allocations, or appropriations, as well as foundation or private grants and donations, for the conducting of pollution prevention environmental education workshops, expositions, symposia, conferences and other forms of public information.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Such additional allocations as may be made by the Board of County Commissioners from time to time for the purposes set forth herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
All interest generated from the sources identified in Section 24-36(2)(a), (b) and (c) hereinabove, except where monies received have been otherwise designated or restricted.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Pollution Prevention Trust Fund shall be maintained in trust by the Finance Director for the Board of County Commissioners solely for the purposes set forth herein, in a separate and segregated fund of the County which shall not be commingled with other County funds until disbursed for an authorized purpose pursuant to Section 24-36(4).
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The procurement of goods and services by the Department which are funded from the Pollution Prevention Trust Fund, shall be exempt from the formal bidding procedures and the provisions of Miami-Dade County Administrative Orders 3-2 and 3-4. Disbursements therefor shall not exceed twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000.00) per vendor, per event and shall only be made for the following purposes:
<section prefix = "a">
Development, promotion and conducting of aforementioned Pollution Prevention educational activities as approved by the Director or the Director's designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Costs associated with said educational activities including, but not limited to, facility rental, equipment rental, professional and trade labor services, speakers' services, travel expenses, printing and mailing expenses, insurance, administrative costs, and any other goods or services necessary.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-37. Wetlands Trust Fund</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
The Wetlands Trust Fund is created for use in acquiring, restoring, enhancing, managing or monitoring (or any combination of the above) wetlands within Miami-Dade County as well as any associated hammock and pineland communities. Monies also may be disbursed for such purposes for wetlands located outside of Miami-Dade County so long as they benefit wetland ecosystems in Miami-Dade County. The Finance Director is hereby authorized and directed to establish the Wetlands Trust Fund and to receive and disburse monies in accordance with the provisions of this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Wetlands Trust Fund shall receive monies from the following sources:
<section prefix = "a">
All monies collected by the Department pursuant to Section 24-48.5(2)(e).
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
All monies accepted by Miami-Dade County in the form of federal, state, or other governmental grants, allocations, or appropriations, as well as foundation or private grants and donations, for the acquisition, restoration, enhancement, management or monitoring of wetlands as provided for in Section 24-37(4).
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All monies received from the forfeiture of mitigation bonds pursuant to Section 24-48.12(3).
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Such additional allocations as may be made by the Board of County Commissioners from time to time for the purposes set forth herein.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
All interest generated from the sources identified in Section 24-37(2)(a), (b), (c) and (d) hereinabove, except where monies received have been otherwise designated or restricted.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The Wetlands Trust Fund shall be maintained in trust by the Finance Director for the Board of County Commissioners solely for the purposes set forth herein, in a separate and segregated fund of the County which shall not be commingled with other County funds until disbursed for an authorized purpose pursuant to Section 24-37(4).
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Disbursements from the Wetlands Trust Fund shall only be made for the following purposes:
<section prefix = "a">
Acquisition, including by eminent domain, restoration, enhancement, management or monitoring of wetland properties located within Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
All costs associated with each such acquisition including, but not limited to, appraisals, surveys, title search work, real property taxes, documentary stamps and surtax fees, and other transaction costs.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Costs of administering the activities enumerated in Section 24-37(4)(a) and (b), hereinabove, will be funded from the proceeds of the Wetlands Trust Fund until such time as the fund is closed.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Disbursements from the Wetlands Trust Fund for the acquisition of eligible properties shall require approval by the Board of County Commissioners after a public hearing on the proposed acquisition. A notice of the time and place of said public hearing shall be published in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County a minimum of seven (7) days prior to the public hearing. Said notice shall include the location and a brief statement of the reason for the proposed acquisition.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08; Ord. No. 12-58, § 4, 7-3-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-38. Miami-Dade Stormwater Compensation Trust Fund</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
The Stormwater Compensation Trust Fund is hereby created for use in land acquisition and constructing, managing, operating or maintaining stormwater management areas within the Bird Drive Everglades Wetland Basin, and Basin B and the North Trail Basin. The Finance Director is hereby authorized and directed to establish the Stormwater Compensation Trust Fund and to receive and disburse monies in accordance with the provisions of this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Stormwater Compensation Trust Fund shall receive monies from the following sources:
<section prefix = "a">
All revenues collected by the Department pursuant to Section 24-48.2(I)(B)(1)(h) of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
All monies accepted by Miami-Dade County in the form of federal, state, or other governmental grants, allocations, or appropriations, as well as foundation or private grants and donations that are made for the purposes of acquiring land or constructing, managing, operating or maintaining stormwater management areas.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Such additional allocations as may be made by the Board of County Commissioners from time to time for the purposes set forth in this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
All interest generated from the sources identified in Section 24-38(2)(a), (b) and (c) of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, except where monies received have been otherwise designated or restricted.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The Stormwater Compensation Trust Fund shall be maintained by the Finance Director for the Board of County Commissioners solely for the purposes set forth herein, in a separate fund of Miami-Dade County, which shall not be commingled with other county funds until disbursed for an authorized purpose pursuant to Section 24-38(4) of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The Director shall only make disbursement from the Stormwater Compensation Trust Fund for the following purposes:
<section prefix = "a">
Acquisition, including by eminent domain, construction, management, operation or maintenance of stormwater management areas within the Bird Drive Everglades Wetland Basin, the North Trail Basin and Basin B as defined in Section 24-5 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
All costs associated with each such acquisition including, but not limited to, appraisals, surveys, title search work, real property taxes, documentary stamps and surtax fees, and other transaction costs.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Costs of administering the activities enumerated in Section 24-38(4)(a) and (b) of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall be funded from the Stormwater Compensation Trust Fund.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-39. Tree Trust Fund and Tree Forest Resources Advisory Committee</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Creation of the Tree Trust Fund. There is hereby created a Tree Trust Fund, the purpose of which is to acquire, protect and maintain natural forest communities in Miami-Dade County and to plant trees on public property.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Creation of the Tree and Forest Resources Advisory Committee. The Tree and Forest Resources Advisory Committee is hereby established for the purpose of providing the Board of County Commissioners with recommendations regarding the Tree Trust Fund, and recommendations to the Director regarding the establishment of Departmental policies relating to Ordinance Number 89-8.
<section prefix = "a">
Composition and qualifications of members. The Committee shall be composed of thirteen (13) members which shall be appointed by the Board of County Commissioners. The Director or the Director's designee shall submit recommendations for appointments to the Miami-Dade County Manager. Members of the Committee shall be residents of Miami-Dade County who possess outstanding reputations for civic pride, interest, integrity, responsibility, and business or professional ability. Appointments shall be made by the County Commission on the basis of experience or interest in the fields of conservation, botany, horticulture, landscape architecture, agriculture, land use, land planning, or land development. The Director or the Director's designee shall serve as executive secretary to the Committee. The process of appointment and other requirements of Ordinance 80-136 (Chapter 2, Article I B, Sections 2-11.36 through 2-11.40 of this Code) shall be followed.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Terms of office and organization. In order that the terms of office of all appointed members of the Committee shall not expire at the same time, the initial appointments to the Committee shall be as follows: seven (7) members shall be appointed for a term of one (1) year, and six (6) members shall be appointed for a term of two (2) years. Thereafter, all members shall be appointed for a term of two (2) years. Appointments to fill any vacancy on the Committee shall be for the remainder of the unexpired term of office. The members of the Committee shall elect a chairman and such other officers as may be deemed necessary or desirable, who shall serve at the will of the Committee. Appointed members shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties, in accordance with County policy, upon approval of the County Manager. A majority vote of a quorum shall be necessary to take any action. Seven (7) members shall constitute a quorum.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Meetings and authority. The Committee shall hold a minimum of one (1) publicly-advertised meeting per year. The Committee shall have the authority to make recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners concerning any matter relating to the tree trust fund. The Committee shall also have the authority to make recommendations to the Director regarding Departmental policies relating to Ordinance Number 89-8, and shall review and approve the quantitative evaluation form which the Department shall use for evaluating natural forest communities. In addition, upon request, the Committee shall have the authority to make recommendations to the Environmental Quality Control Board concerning variance requests made pursuant to this Ordinance Number 89-8, natural forest community site additions or deletions, and natural forest community boundary line modifications being proposed by the Director or the Director's designee.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Disbursement and maintenance of the Tree Trust Fund. Monies obtained for the Tree Trust Fund shall be disbursed for the acquisition, maintenance, management and protection of natural forest communities, or for planting trees on public property. Such monies may be used as a matching fund contribution towards the acquisition of natural forest communities in Miami-Dade County in association with other public land acquisition programs, such as, but not limited to, the State of Florida Conservation and Recreational Lands Trust Fund. Said trust fund shall be kept and maintained in trust by the Board of County Commissioners solely for the purposes set forth in this section in a separate and segregated fund of the County which shall not be commingled with other County funds until disbursed for an authorized purpose pursuant to this section. Disbursement from the tree trust fund shall require approval by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners, provided, however, that any funds received pursuant to the conditions of any tree removal permit shall be used as required by the permit conditions without the necessity of approval, appropriation, or action of any kind by the Board of County Commissioners. Prior to approving disbursements, the Board of County Commissioners shall consider the recommendations of the County Manager and the Tree and Forest Resources Advisory Committee. The County Manager, prior to making any such recommendations, shall consider the recommendations of the Department pertaining to the proposed disbursement(s) for the acquisition of natural forest communities or planting of trees on public property. The Finance Director is hereby authorized to establish the Tree Trust Fund and to receive and disburse monies in accordance with the provisions of this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Source of monies for the Tree Trust Fund. Said Tree Trust Fund shall consist of the following monies:
<section prefix = "a">
All monies collected by the Department for environmental damages to tree or forest resources and environmental mitigation for the loss of tree or forest resources which are obtained through civil lawsuits, consent agreements or after-the-fact tree removal permits, except penalties and administrative costs.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
All monies offered to and accepted by Miami-Dade County for the Tree Trust Fund in the form of federal, State, or other governmental grants, allocations or appropriations, as well as foundation or private grants and donations, shall be disbursed strictly in accordance with terms and conditions of the grant, allocation, appropriation or donation and shall be earmarked accordingly.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Contributions in lieu of, or in conjunction with, the replacement planting provisions of Section 24-49.4(2). The Department shall collect funds designated for the Tree Trust Fund when the replacement planting requirements of Section 24-49.4(2) cannot be met, and in accordance with Section 24-49.2(II)(5).
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Interest. Unless otherwise restricted by the terms and conditions of a particular grant, gift, appropriation or allocation, all interest earned by the investment of all monies in the Tree Trust Fund shall be disbursed by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners for any project authorized consistent with Section 24-39. Trust fund monies shall be invested only in accordance with the laws pertaining to the investment of County funds.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Decisions to grant or deny tree removal permits shall be made without consideration of the existence of this fund or offers of donations of monies thereto.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-40. Biscayne Bay Environmental Enhancement Trust Fund</catch_line>
<text>
There is hereby created a Biscayne Bay Environmental Enhancement Trust Fund, the monies of which shall be disbursed only for the environmental enhancement of Biscayne Bay and its foreshore, consistent with the objectives adopted by this Board by Resolution R-1610-79, as may be amended from time to time; the prioritized list of projects adopted by this Board by Resolution R-1609-79, as may be amended from time to time; and with the forthcoming comprehensive Biscayne Bay management plan.
<section prefix = "1">
Definitions:
<section prefix = "a">
Excess monies shall be defined as those monies which are necessary to enhance the particular area(s) of Biscayne Bay and the foreshore environmentally damaged or degraded, and which remain in the trust fund after all monies from a particular action, claim, assessment, grant, appropriation, allocation, permit condition or donation have been disbursed.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Environmental enhancement shall be defined as restoration or improvement of natural and indigenous habitats within Biscayne Bay or its foreshore through the establishment, restoration or improvement of biological communities in order to increase the net habitat value of the bay. Environmental enhancement may also be defined as those alterations in hydrodynamics, water and sedimentary chemistry that may be necessary to establish or reestablish natural and indigenous biotic communities within Biscayne Bay or its foreshore. Further, it is presumed that those enhancement activities contemplated by the forthcoming comprehensive Biscayne Bay management plan, the prioritized list of projects (except studies) as adopted by Resolution R-1609-79, as may be amended from time to time; and those projects consistent with the objectives adopted by Resolution R-1610-79, as may be amended from time to time; are for the environmental enhancement of Biscayne Bay and its foreshore and qualify for funding from this trust fund.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Mitigation includes any of the following:
<section prefix = "i">
Avoiding the impact altogether by not taking a certain action or parts of an action;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Minimizing impacts by limiting the degree or magnitude of the action or its implementation;
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Rectifying the impact by repairing, rehabilitating, or restoring the affected environment;
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
Reducing or eliminating the impact over time by preservation and maintenance operations during the life of the action;
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
Compensating for the impact by replacing or providing substitute resources or environments.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Said trust fund shall be kept and maintained in trust by the Board of County Commissioners for the purposes set forth in this section in a separate and segregated fund of the County which shall not be commingled with other County funds until disbursed for an authorized purpose pursuant to this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Said trust fund shall consist of the following monies and shall be disbursed in accordance with the following requirements:
<section prefix = "a">
All monies available to or recovered by the County from enforcement and damage actions and claims against persons who have environmentally damaged or degraded Biscayne Bay and its foreshore:
<section prefix = "i">
Such monies shall be first disbursed for the environmental enhancement of the particular area(s) of Biscayne Bay and its foreshore damaged or degraded unless enhancement in the particular area(s) is clearly shown to be not possible. In the event of the latter, such monies shall be disbursed for environmental enhancement of other area(s) of Biscayne Bay and its foreshore.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Any excess monies derived from such enforcement and damage actions and claims may be disbursed for environmental enhancement of other areas of Biscayne Bay and its foreshore as authorized and approved by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
All monies available to and received by Miami-Dade County from environmental mitigation assessments from all private persons and all governmental bodies, units, agencies, authorities and departments, including, but not limited to, Miami-Dade County, for environmental damage or degradation to Biscayne Bay and its foreshore:
<section prefix = "i">
Such monies shall be disbursed for environmental enhancement of Biscayne Bay and its foreshore as authorized and approved by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners. However, if mitigation activities are specified as conditions of any permit, then said mitigation funds shall be used as required by the permit conditions, without the necessity of the Board of County Commissioners' approval, appropriation, or action of any kind.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All monies offered to and accepted by Miami-Dade County for the environmental enhancement of Biscayne Bay and its foreshore in the form of federal, State, and other governmental grants, allocations, and appropriations as well as foundation and private grants and donations:
<section prefix = "i">
Such monies shall be disbursed for the environmental enhancement of Biscayne Bay and its foreshore strictly in accordance with terms and conditions of the grant, allocation, appropriation, or donation and shall be earmarked accordingly.
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Any excess monies derived from such grant, allocation, appropriation, or donation shall be disbursed or allocated in accordance with the terms and conditions, if any, of such grant, allocation, appropriation, or donation. If no such terms or conditions attach to such excess, then such excess, if any, shall be disbursed for the environmental enhancement of Biscayne Bay and its foreshore as authorized and approved by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Unless otherwise specified herein, no disbursements whatsoever shall be made from the Biscayne Bay Environmental Enhancement Trust Fund until and unless authorized and approved by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners. Prior to authorizing and approving said disbursements, the Board of County Commissioners shall receive and consider the recommendations of the County Manager. The County Manager, prior to making any such recommendations, shall receive and consider the recommendations of the Department pertaining to the proposed particular disbursement for environmental enhancement of Biscayne Bay and its foreshore. The Finance Director is hereby authorized to establish the Biscayne Bay Environmental Enhancement Trust Fund and to receive monies therefor in accordance with provisions of this section and shall disburse monies from said trust fund only upon authorization pursuant to resolution of the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Unless otherwise restricted by the terms and conditions of a particular grant, gift, appropriation, allocation, or permit condition, all interest earned by the investment of all monies in the trust fund shall be disbursed by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners for any project authorized by the Board which will environmentally enhance Biscayne Bay and its foreshore. Trust fund moneys shall be invested only in accordance with the laws pertaining to the investment of County funds.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
No moneys or interest accrued in such trust fund shall be disbursed for environmental studies of Biscayne Bay or its foreshore unless required by the terms and conditions of a particular grant, donation, appropriation, allocation, or permit condition.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Decisions to grant or deny permits for any activities within Biscayne Bay or its foreshore shall be made without consideration of the existence of this trust fund. Each application for any permit must be evaluated independently of the existence of this fund or offers of donation of moneys thereto.

</section>
</text>
</law>
