<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="3">ARTICLE II. EAST EVERGLADES</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="4">DIVISION_2._OVERLAY_ZONING_REGULATIONS</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 33B-21. Title</catch_line>
<text>
This division shall be known as the "East Everglades Zoning Overlay Ordinance."
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33B-22. Purpose</catch_line>
<text>
In order to protect and preserve the public and private resources of the East Everglades and to achieve the goals and objectives of the East Everglades Resources Planning Project, it is necessary and appropriate to create a system of comprehensive land management and development regulations for the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern. This division is adopted in order to protect the East Everglades resources and to limit growth and development in the area to that development which is compatible with the long term integrity of the public and private economic and environmental values of the East Everglades. This division is in furtherance of the goals and objectives of Ordinance No. 81-1 [Division 1 of Article II of this chapter].
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33B-23. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Agricultural support housing means a single residential or housekeeping unit for the employees of an agricultural use.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Agricultural use means horticulture and floriculture, horticultural and floricultural uses and purposes, including row crop farms, groves, nurseries, horticultural farming, truck farming and barns, sheds, or other nonhabitable structures which are used for the storage of farm machinery, fertilizer, seed or other items or equipment which are ancillary to an on-site agricultural use. The propagation, sale, maintenance, or transport of noxious exotic species as defined hereunder is prohibited. The maintenance and raising of animals for commercial purposes is not included.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Conservation means any activity which protects or enhances the vitality of a parcel's native flora and fauna.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Critical habitat means those land areas which are described as critical habitat by the U.S. Department of Interior.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Cumulative impact means the total impact, over time, of a proposed development and a proliferation of the same or similar developments on the environment throughout the management area.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Developer means any person undertaking development.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Development means the carrying out of any use permitted on land by applicable zoning and environmental regulations (e.g., Chapters 9, 24 and 33 of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Code) or making any material change in the use or character of land, including, but not limited to, excavation, filling, rock plowing or other alteration of the topographic, geologic or hydrologic character of land in preparation or as a part of the commencement of new agricultural activities, the placement of structures on land, the clearing of land or a change in the intensity of use of land. Development shall include ancillary activities such as road building and sewer construction that occur along with or as a result of any proposed land use. When appropriate to the context, development refers to the act of developing or the result of development.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Established agricultural operation means an agricultural use in existence on January 14, 1981.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Land means the earth, water and air above, below or on the surface.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Management Area 1 means that land that is shown as Management Area 1 on the attached map entitled "Management Areas of the East Everglades" which is filed with the Clerk of the County Commission. An official map of the East Everglades Management Area will be maintained by the Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Management Area 2 means that land that is shown as Management Area 2 on the attached map entitled "Management Areas of the East Everglades" which is filed with the Clerk of the County Commission. An official map of the East Everglades Management Area will be maintained by the Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning.
The south half of Section 19, Township 58 South, Range 39 East lying westerly of U.S. Highway No. 1, less canal and road rights-of-way, containing three hundred twenty (320) acres, more or less, Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall be excluded from Management Area 2.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Management Area 3 means that land that is shown as Management Area 3 on the attached map entitled "Management Areas of the East Everglades" which is filed with the Clerk of the County Commission. An official map of the East Everglades Management Area will be maintained by the Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
Noxious exotic plants includes but is not limited to any of the following plant species: Cajeput (Melaleuca quinquenervia); Australian pine (Casuarina spp.); Brazilian pepper (Schinus terebinthifolius); castor bean (Ricinus communis); colubrina Colubrina asiatica); aerial potato (Discorea bulbifera); and day-blooming jasmine (Cestrum diurnum).
</section>
<section prefix = "n">
Owner means the person with legal and/or equitable title to real property.
</section>
<section prefix = "o">
Passive recreation means those recreational opportunities afforded by such resources as the native flora, fauna, and aesthetic appeal of a natural setting and requiring minimum development to utilize and enjoy such resources, including but not limited to nature study, primitive camping, hiking, canoeing, picnicking, hunting and fishing.
</section>
<section prefix = "p">
Parcel of land means any quantity of land capable of being described with such definiteness that its locations and boundaries may be established and which is designated by its owner or developer as land to be used as a unit.
</section>
<section prefix = "q">
Person means any and all persons, including but not limited to an individual, firm, association, organization, partnership, business trust, trust, corporation or company.
</section>
<section prefix = "r">
Road means any cleared, plowed, bulldozed, filled, graded, excavated or paved area capable of being used for the passage of vehicles, persons or animals. Roads shall not mean trails used or capable of being used solely by off-road vehicles such as airboats, swamp buggies and all-terrain vehicles.
</section>
<section prefix = "s">
Secondary/induced impact means those impacts which may result from a development that is generated as an ancillary or subsequent use to the proposed development, including but not limited to the disposal of runoff from a primary use.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 81-121, § 3, 10-27-81; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 23, 9-3-98)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33B-24. Applicability of division to development; disclaimer statement</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
All development in the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern shall comply with each and every provision of this division.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The requirements of this division shall be in addition to each and every other requirement of the rules, regulations and ordinances of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, and in the case of conflict, the provisions of this division shall control.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
No permit for use or development of any land within the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern shall be issued by any agent of Miami-Dade County government which permit does not contain the following statement:
The subject parcel is located in the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern and is subject to seasonal flooding. Neither Miami-Dade County nor the South Florida Water Management District plans to construct flood protection works which would benefit the subject parcel. Moreover, neither Miami-Dade County nor the Water Management District will allow the owner (or permittee) to use public canal systems to provide drainage that is not now available to the subject parcel. In addition, it is against county policy either to provide new roads or to maintain and/or improve privately built roads in this area.
I hereby certify that I have read and understand the foregoing statement.
<section prefix="1" type="table">
<table class="thead0 table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> _____</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> _____</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">   Signature</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">  Date</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 

The foregoing statement is to be included in all permits as a courtesy to owners, and failure to include such statement in any permit shall not be construed as a waiver of any other provision of this division.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 81-121, § 4, 10-27-81)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33B-25. Authorized uses</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Management Area 1:
<section prefix = "1">
Permitted uses:
<section prefix = "a">
Agricultural use, and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Agricultural support housing at a density of no greater than one (1) unit per forty (4) acres, or
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Single-family detached dwelling units at a density of no greater than one (1) unit per forty (40) acres.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Conditional uses:
<section prefix = "a">
Single-family detached dwelling units at a density of no greater than one (1) unit per five (5) acres in that portion of Management Area 1 which had an established residential character as of January 14, 1981, provided that positive drainage flood control facilities are available to protect the area from a one-in-ten-year flood event. This area is defined as all of Sections 14, 21, 22, 23, 27, 28; the south one-half of Section 11 and the south one-half of the north one-half of Section 11; the east one-half of Section 15; the east one-half of Section 16; all land in Section 26 which lies northerly and westerly of Levee L-31-N; the east one-half of the east one-half of Section 29; all within Township 55 South and Range 38 East.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Residential dwelling units at a density of no greater than one (1) dwelling unit per twenty (20) acres, provided that:
<section prefix = "1">
The dwelling unit is ancillary to an established agricultural operation involving less than forty (40) acres, and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Occupancy of the dwelling is limited to the owner, operator or employees of the established agricultural operation, and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The parcel was not in common ownership with any adjacent parcel of land on or after January 14, 1981.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Management Area 2:
<section prefix = "1">
Permitted uses:
<section prefix = "a">
Residential dwellings at a density of no greater than one (1) unit per forty (40) acres.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Passive recreation and conservation and traditional ORV and airboat use.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Conditional uses:
<section prefix = "a">
One (1) residential dwelling unit on parcels of less than forty (40) acres provided that:
<section prefix = "1">
The parcel proposed for development was entitled to a density of at least one (1) dwelling unit as of January 14, 1981, under the provisions of Chapter 33 of the Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Code; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The parcel proposed for development has at least two hundred (200) feet of frontage on U.S. Highway 41 (Tamiami Trail) or on U.S. Highway 1; and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The parcel proposed for development is at least five (5) acres in size and was not in common ownership with any adjacent parcel of land on or after January 14, 1981; and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The only filling allowed on the parcel proposed for development is that amount necessary for an individual on-site waste water disposal system and the fill pad for such a system is placed adjacent to the highway; and
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
When not located on the waste water disposal fill pad, the residential unit and driveway access shall be elevated to the appropriate flood criteria by the use of pilings.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Management Area 3:
<section prefix = "1">
Permitted uses:
<section prefix = "a">
Residential dwellings at a density no greater than one (1) unit per forty (40) acres.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Passive recreation and conservation and traditional ORV and airboat use.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Conditional uses:
<section prefix = "a">
Agricultural use, provided that:
<section prefix = "1">
The parcel of land proposed for development is located in Management Area 3B or 3C,
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The parcel proposed for agricultural use in Management Area 3C is adjacent to an established agricultural use or separated from an adjacent agricultural use by a parcel of land that cannot be farmed due to natural conditions such as a slough or tree island or by the refusal of the adjacent property owner to allow his/her land to be farmed,
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
When the parcel proposed for development is within Management Area 3C, there are no alternative locations for the establishment of an agricultural use in Management Areas 1 and 3B,
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The applicant can demonstrate that the parcel is hydrologically capable of supporting farming, and all required federal permits are obtained.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 81-121, § 5, 10-27-81)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33B-26. Environmental performance standards</catch_line>
<text>
All development in the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern shall comply with the standards listed below. The cumulative and/or secondary/induced impacts of the proposed development shall be considered in determining whether the development meets the environmental performance standards of this section.
<section prefix = "a">
Fill:
<section prefix = "1">
The placement of fill including the construction of roadways shall not impede the rate or volume of surface water flow or create significant backwater conditions.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The area of fill shall not exceed the following limitations:
<section prefix = "a">
In Management Areas 1 and 3B—One-half acre; and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
In Management Areas 2A, 2B, 3A and 3C—The minimum area necessary to install an on-site waste water treatment system, not to exceed one-half acre.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Excavation: No excavation shall be carried out in the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern, except:
<section prefix = "1">
Discontinuous shallow ditching for agricultural purposes shall be permitted; however, it shall not serve as a continuous conduit for transporting water to the extent that it has a significant adverse effect on the natural hydrologic regimen of the immediate vicinity of the parcel proposed for development.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Excavation of shallow lakes for recreation and/or fill for uses permitted under this division shall be evaluated on a case-by-case basis, and all such lakes shall meet all applicable Miami-Dade County criteria for lakes.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Roads:
<section prefix = "1">
No roads shall be permitted in Management Areas 2A and 2B.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Where permitted, roads in the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern must be designed so that they will not interrupt or divert natural sheet flow. Elevated roads must be sufficiently bridged and culverted to allow the passage of high water flows without causing significant backwater conditions. The Miami-Dade County Public Works Manual on road design, as amended from time to time, is incorporated herein by reference. No roads shall be permitted in Management Areas 2A and 2B.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Clearing of native vegetation: Tree islands characterized by native vegetation shall be preserved in all management areas, including agricultural areas. Residential and hunting camp uses on tree islands shall be permitted only if the tree island canopy is preserved intact and the proposed use will not have a significant adverse impact on the wildlife habitat value of the island.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Landscaping: Species to be used in ornamental planting shall not include noxious exotic plants. All ornamental planting shall be subject to the approval of the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Solid waste disposal: No solid waste not degradable by approved on-site systems shall be disposed of or deposited in the area of critical environmental concern.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Agriculture:
<section prefix = "1">
Agricultural activities shall be managed so that exotic plants will not become established, maintained or propagated. All practicable methods of control, subject to County approval, which do not significantly degrade the environment shall be employed. Affirmative steps shall be taken to eliminate the noxious exotic species defined herein.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Any agricultural practice which reduces infiltration rate from that of natural (or present) conditions shall be compensated for by an on-site retention technique (e.g., ditch, depression). The design of such facilities shall ensure that collected water will percolate into the groundwater system and that no net change in infiltration rate or volume occurs.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
After completing rock plowing and regrading activity, elevated planting beds shall not inhibit surface water sheet flow.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Farm roads built above grade must meet Public Works Manual criteria with regard to the passage of flood flows and sheet flow.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Construction of structures ancillary to agricultural use such as equipment storage sheds should be located and designed so that they minimize the impact on surface water flow.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33B-27. Conditional uses—Application process</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Application contents. An application for a permit for development approval for a conditional use authorized by Section 33B-25 of this division shall be submitted to the Department of Environmental Resources Management in accordance with the provisions of this section and shall be accompanied by a nonrefundable fee in an amount to be established from time to time by the Board of County Commissioners of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County. The application shall be in such form and contain such information and documentation as shall be prescribed from time to time by the Department of Environmental Resources Management and the Department of Planning and Zoning and shall contain at least the following information:
<section prefix = "1">
Name and address of applicant;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Legal description and lot number of the property which is the subject of the application;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Statement of ownership;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Size of the subject property;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
A written statement describing in general terms the proposed development;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
A written statement setting forth how the proposed development meets each standard specified in Section 33B-28 for the conditional use;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
A site plan at a scale of not more than fifty (50) feet to the inch, on one (1) or more sheets, illustrating the proposed development and use, and including the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Location of the property by lot number, block number, and street address, if any.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The boundary lines of the property, the dimensions of the property, existing subdivision, and easements, roadways and public rights-of-way on or adjacent to the property.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The location and dimensions of all structures designed to maintain the natural flow of surface waters.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The location, height and use of all proposed and existing buildings and structures and filled areas.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The approximate location and dimensions of all proposed lots.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
All existing and proposed surface and subsurface drainage facilities, waste treatment facilities, septic tank and potable well location.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Scale of drawing and north arrow.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Such other information or documentation as may be necessary or appropriate to a full and proper consideration and disposition of the development application.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
An aerial photograph(s) taken within one (1) year of the application at the scale of three hundred (300) feet to the inch of the subject parcel and all adjacent property within two thousand six hundred forty (2,640) feet or, if an aerial photo is not available, a vicinity sketch at the scale of three hundred (300) feet equals one (1) inch showing all existing development within two thousand six hundred forty (2,640) feet of any boundary of the subject parcel.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
An environmental description of the parcel proposed for development including:
<section prefix = "a">
A topographical survey signed by a registered engineer or licensed land surveyor,
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A general description of the existing vegetation as well as all other natural features including sloughs, tree islands, geological formation, and soil type.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Review of application.
<section prefix = "1">
Within fifteen (15) days after an application for conditional use approval is submitted, the Director of Environmental Resources Management shall determine whether the application is complete. If the application is determined to be incomplete, a written statement specifying the deficiencies shall be sent to the applicant and no further action shall be taken on the application until the deficiencies are remedied.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Within sixty (60) days after receipt of a complete application, the Directors of the Planning and Zoning and the Environmental Resources Management Departments shall review the application for conditional use approval and shall decide whether the proposed conditional use permit should be issued or denied and the grounds for such decision. Such review and decision shall be based on the comments and recommendations of all other relevant County departments and a determination of whether the applicant has demonstrated compliance with the standards for conditional use approval set forth in Section 33B-28. The Department of Environmental Resources Management shall give notice of projects accepted for conditional use approval by publication in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County and posting a notice on property adjacent to the proposed project. If an appeal is filed with the Department of Environmental Resources Management within ten (10) days of said publication, a public hearing before the Board of County Commissioners shall be held for the project. If no appeal is requested, a conditional use permit shall be issued by the Department of Environmental Resources Management subject to the provisions herein.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Appeal to the Board of County Commissioners.
<section prefix = "1">
An applicant for conditional use approval under the provisions of this section may appeal the decision of the Directors of the Planning and Zoning and the Environmental Resources Management Departments to the Board of County Commissioners of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Notice of appeal shall be filed with the Clerk of the County Commission within fifteen (15) days.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Upon receipt of a notice of appeal, the Clerk of the Commission shall place the appeal on the agenda of the next regular meeting of the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Action by the Board of County Commissioners. The Board of County Commissioners of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County shall review the application for which an appeal has been properly filed, the decision of the Directors of the Departments of Planning and Zoning and Environmental Resources Management and any additional information which may be submitted. Following a full evidentiary hearing, the Commissioners may affirm, reverse or modify the decision of the Directors of the Departments of Environmental Resources Management and Planning and Zoning. Such affirmance, reversal or modification shall be based on the extent to which the applicant has demonstrated compliance with the standards for conditional use approval set forth in Section 33B-28. An aggrieved party may appeal the decision of the Board to the Circuit Court with the applicable Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 81-121, § 7, 10-27-81; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 23, 9-3-98)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33B-28. Same—General standards</catch_line>
<text>
A conditional use permit may be granted only if the applicant demonstrates that:
<section prefix = "a">
The conditional use is consistent with the purposes, goals, objectives and standards of the East Everglades Management Plan;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The design of the proposed development minimizes adverse effects, including visual impacts of the proposed use on adjacent properties;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The proposed use will not have singular or cumulative adverse effect on the value of adjacent property;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The proposed use, singly or cumulatively, will not unduly burden essential public facilities and services including roadways, parking spaces, police and fire protection, drainage systems, refuse disposal, water and sewers, and schools;
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The proposed use, singly or cumulatively, will not have any of the following irreversible effects on the ecological integrity of the East Everglades:
<section prefix = "1">
Harmful obstruction or undesirable alteration of the natural flow of water within the area of work.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Harmful or increased erosion, or adverse environmental impact resulting from changes in water quality or quantity.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Adverse impact upon wetland flora and fauna within adjacent parcels.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Adverse impact upon wetland flora and fauna within those portions of the subject property not proposed for development under the application.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Material injury to adjoining land.

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33B-29. Vested rights</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Notwithstanding any other provision of this division, any landowner who claims a vested right to develop his property at a density greater than permitted under this division may submit an application for a determination of vested rights to the Department of Planning and Zoning during the effective period of this division.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Any person who claims a vested right shall file an application for a determination of vested rights with the Department of Planning and Zoning, and shall attach a sworn affidavit setting forth the facts upon which the applicant bases his claim for vested rights. In addition to any other submission required by the Department of Planning and Zoning, the applicant shall include copies of any contracts, letters and other documents upon which a claim of vested rights is based. The mere existence of zoning prior to the effective date of this division shall not vest rights. Grandfathered rights which preceded this division shall be extinguished.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Department of Planning and Zoning shall review the application and determine whether the applicant has demonstrated:
<section prefix = "1">
An act of development approval by an agency of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County,
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Upon which the developer has in good faith relied to his detriment,
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Such that it would be highly inequitable to deny the landowner the right to complete the previously approved development.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Effect of vested rights determination. A determination that a landowner is entitled to a vested right to develop at a density greater than permitted under this division does not except the development from compliance with the standards set forth in Section 33B-26 of this division.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 81-121, § 9, 10-27-81; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 23, 9-3-98)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33B-30. Management areas</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Criteria:
<section prefix = "1">
Management Area 1: Management Area 1 is defined as that land in the East Everglades area of Miami-Dade County which is adjacent to Levee L-31-N and Canal C-111 and has been directly and permanently altered by human activity as of January 14, 1981. Management Area 1 includes Sections 11, 14, 15, 21, 22, 23, 27, 28; the east one-half of Section 16; all land in Section 26 which lies northerly and westerly of Levee L-31-N; the east one-half of the northeast one-quarter (¼) and the east one-half of the southeast one-quarter of Section 29; all within Township 55 South and Range 38 East; and all land adjacent to Levee L-31-N or Canal C-111, and south of Southwest 168th Street which has been directly and permanently altered by human activity as of January 14, 1981. An official map of Management Area 1 will be maintained by the Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Management Area 2: Management Area 2 is defined as that land within the East Everglades area of Miami-Dade County which is flooded (i.e., water level within one (1) foot of the land surface) for at least nine (9) months of the year in a year with average rainfall. (The boundary is determined by comparing the duration and elevation of water levels to the elevation of the land using the most complete water records available.) An official map of Management Area 2 will be maintained by the Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Management Area 3: Management Area 3 is defined as that land within the East Everglades area of Miami-Dade County described below as Management Areas 3A, 3B and 3C;
Management Area 3A is all land in the East Everglades which meets at least one (1) of the following three (3) criteria:
<section prefix = "a">
Has vegetation characterized by tree island and/or wet prairie communities; that is, the community mosaics characterized by (in order of abundance) sawgrass glades, spike rush-beak rush, and maidencane flats; by spike rush-beak rush, sawgrass glades and maidencane flats; and by the post-burn recovery vegetation of former bayhead, former cypress dome or hammock communities, and prairietree island communities, including narrow beard grass, three-awn grass, love grass prairies and wax myrtle-saltbush thickets, as depicted on the vegetation maps prepared as a part of the East Everglades Resources Planning Project.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Is flooded from three (3) to nine (9) months during a year when average rainfall occurs. (This boundary is calculated by the same method as that described above for Management Area 2.)
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Is flooded for less than three (3) months during a year when average rainfall occurs (calculated as described above), but is not contiguous with Management Area 1.
Management Area 3B is all land that is contiguous with Management Area 1 and is flooded less than three (3) months during a year in which average rainfall occurs.
Management Area 3C is all of the remaining land in the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern that is not within Management Areas 1, 2, 3A or 3B.
An official map of Management Areas 3A, 3B and 3C will be maintained by the Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Determination of management area boundaries: A person may file a request for a determination of management area boundaries with respect to a given parcel of land. Such request must be in writing and addressed to the Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management (DERM). The Director of DERM shall respond in a timely manner and shall specify why the parcel is in the assigned management area.
</section>
<section prefix = "C">
Revision of management area boundaries:
<section prefix = "1">
Revisions to the map of "Management Areas of the East Everglades" may be made by the Department of Environmental Resources Management from time to time as more scientific information becomes available. Any revisions to the boundaries of the Management Areas should be based entirely on the criteria listed in part (A) of this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Any individual may submit an application to revise the map of "Management Areas of the East Everglades" to the Director of the Department of Environmental Resources Management. Such application shall be in such form and contain sufficient information and documentation to allow an evaluation by the Department of Environmental Resources Management with respect to the criteria described in part (A) of this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Revision of the Management Area map boundary shall be by public hearing by the Board of County Commissioners in the manner specified below in subsection (D).
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "D">
Review of application:
<section prefix = "1">
Within fifteen (15) days after an application to revise the map of "Management Areas of the East Everglades" is submitted, the Director of Environmental Resources Management shall determine whether the application is complete. If the application is determined to be incomplete, a written statement specifying the deficiencies shall be sent to the applicant and no further action shall be taken on the application until the deficiencies are remedied.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Within forty-five (45) days after receipt of a complete application, the Director of the Department of Environmental Resources Management shall review the application to revise the map of "Management Areas of the East Everglades" and shall decide whether the proposed revision should be issued or denied and the grounds for such decision. Such review and decision shall be based on the comments and recommendations of all other relevant County departments and a determination of whether the applicant has demonstrated compliance with the criteria set forth in part (A) of this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
An applicant for revision to the map of "Management Areas of the East Everglades" under the provisions of this section may appeal the decision of the Director of the Department of Environmental Resources Management to the Board of County Commissioners of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Notice of appeal shall be filed with the Clerk of the County Commission within fifteen (15) days.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Upon receipt of a notice of appeal, the Clerk of the Commission shall place the application on the agenda of the next regular meeting of the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
The Board of County Commissioners of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County shall review the application, the decision of the Director of the Department of Environmental Resources Management and any additional information which may be submitted. The Commissioners may affirm, reverse or modify the decision of the Department of Environmental Resources Management. Such affirmance, reversal or modification shall be based on the extent to which the applicant has demonstrated compliance with the criteria set forth in part (A) of this section.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 81-121, § 10, 10-27-81; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 23, 9-3-98)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33B-31. Variances</catch_line>
<text>
Notwithstanding anything in Chapter 33 (Zoning Code) of the Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County to the contrary, applications for variances to the provisions of this division must comply with the provisions of Section 33B-28 (general standards for conditional use) of this division. The cumulative and/or secondary or induced impacts from a proliferation of the proposed development must also comply with the provisions of Section 33B-28 of this division.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 33B-32—33B-40. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (3) ---
Editor's note— Ord. No. 81-121, enacted Oct. 27, 1981, amended Ch. 33B, but did not specify the manner of disposition; therefore, inclusion of §§ 1—11 as Div. 2, §§ 33B-21—33B-31, has been at the discretion of the editor. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
