<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="3">ARTICLE III. UNIFORM TRADE STANDARDS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="4">DIVISION_7._MOTOR_VEHICLE_TITLE_LOANS</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-124.11. Title</catch_line>
<text>
This division shall be known and cited as the "Title Loan Ordinance of Miami-Dade County, Florida."
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-124.12. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
As used in this division:
<section prefix = "a">
Commission shall mean the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Department means the Miami-Dade County Consumer Services Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Motor vehicle means an automobile, motorcycle, truck, trailer, semitrailer, truck tractor and semitrailer combination, or any other vehicle operated on public highways and streets, used to transport persons or property, and propelled by power other than muscular power, but excluding vehicles which run only upon a track.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Person includes, but is not limited to, any individual, corporation, company, association, firm, partnership, society, or joint stock company.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Title loan means a loan of money secured by bailment of a certificate of title to a motor vehicle.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Title loan agreement means a written agreement whereby the title loan lender agrees to make a loan of a specific sum of money to a borrower, and the borrower agrees to give the title loan lender a security interest in an unencumbered motor vehicle certificate of title owned by the borrower.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Title loan lender means any person who is engaged in the business of making title loans or engaging in title loan agreements with borrowers, which includes, but is not limited to, secondhand dealers, as defined in Chapter 538, Florida Statutes, as may be amended.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Ultimate equitable owner means a natural person who, directly or indirectly, owns or controls an ownership interest in a corporation, a foreign corporation, an alien business organization, or any other form of business organization, regardless of whether such natural person owns or controls such ownership interest through one (1) or more natural persons or one (1) or more proxies, powers of attorney, nominees, corporations, associations, partnerships, trusts, joint stock companies, or other entities or devices, or any combination thereof.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-124.13. Motor vehicle title loan transactions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
A title loan lender may engage in a title loan transaction if the following conditions are met:
<section prefix = "1">
The title loan lender maintains physical possession of the motor vehicle certificate of title.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The borrower maintains possession of, or control over, the motor vehicle throughout the term of the loan.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The borrower is not required to pay rent or any other charge for the use of the motor vehicle.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The title loan lender holds a current active license issued by the Department pursuant to this division.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The title loan lender delivers to the borrower, at the time the loan is made, a written title loan agreement available in English, Spanish or Creole that contains the following information:
<section prefix = "a">
The make, model and year of the motor vehicle to which the loan relates.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The vehicle identification number, or other comparable identification number, along with the license plate number, if applicable, of the motor vehicle to which the loan relates.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The name, address, date of birth, physical description, and social security number of the borrower.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The date of the transaction.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The identification number and the type of identification, including the issuing agency, accepted from the borrower.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
The amount of money advanced, designated as the "amount financed."
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
The maturity date of the title loan agreement.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
The total title loan charge payable on the maturity date, designated as the "finance charge."
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
The total amount, amount financed plus finance charge, which must be paid to redeem the loan property on the maturity date, designated as the "total amount of all payments."
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
The annual percentage rate, computed in accordance with the regulations adopted by the Federal Reserve Board pursuant to the Federal Truth-in-Lending Act.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
The name and address of the title loan office.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
The name and address of the Department as well as a Department telephone number to which borrowers may address complaints.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
A statement printed in not less than fourteen (14) point, bold type that:
<section prefix = "1">
Your vehicle has been pledged as security for this loan and if you do not repay this loan in full, including the finance charge, YOU WILL LOSE YOUR VEHICLE. YOU ARE ENCOURAGED TO REPAY THIS LOAN AT THE END OF THE LOAN PERIOD. THE LENDER IS NOT REQUIRED TO EXTEND OR RENEW YOUR LOAN.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
THIS LOAN HAS A VERY HIGH INTEREST RATE. DO NOT COMPLETE THIS LOAN TRANSACTION IF YOU HAVE THE ABILITY TO BORROW FROM ANOTHER SOURCE AT A RATE LOWER THAN TWO AND ONE-HALF PERCENT (2½%) PER MONTH OR AN ANNUAL PERCENTAGE RATE OF THIRTY PERCENT (30%).
The contract shall contain a blank line below the statement for the initials of the borrower.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "n">
A statement that "The borrower represents and warrants that the motor vehicle and the certificate of title are not stolen, it has no liens or encumbrances against it, the borrower has the right to enter into this transaction, and the borrower will not attempt to sell the motor vehicle or apply for a duplicate certificate of title while the title loan agreement is in effect."
</section>
<section prefix = "o">
Immediately above the signature of the borrower, a statement that "I, the borrower, declare that the information I have provided is true and correct and I have read and understand the foregoing document."
</section>
<section prefix = "p">
A blank line for the signature of the borrower; and
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
The title loan lender displays, in a prominent place in the title loan premises, a sign no smaller than three (3) feet by five (5) feet with the following message in letters no less than one (1) inch high: IF YOU RECEIVE A TITLE LOAN, YOUR VEHICLE WILL BE PLEDGED AS SECURITY FOR THE LOAN. IF YOU DO NOT REPAY THIS LOAN IN FULL, INCLUDING ALL FINANCE CHARGES, YOU WILL LOSE YOUR VEHICLE. SHOULD THE VEHICLE BE SOLD, YOU ARE ENTITLED TO ANY PROCEEDS OF THE SALE IN EXCESS OF THE AMOUNT OWED ON THE TITLE LOAN AND THE REASONABLE EXPENSES OF REPOSSESSION AND SALE.
THIS LOAN HAS A VERY HIGH INTEREST RATE. DO NOT COMPLETE A TITLE LOAN TRANSACTION IF YOU HAVE THE ABILITY TO BORROW MONEY FROM ANOTHER SOURCE AT AN INTEREST RATE LOWER THAN TWO AND ONE-HALF PERCENT (2½%) PER MONTH OR AN ANNUAL PERCENTAGE RATE OF THIRTY PERCENT (30%). IF YOU HAVE A COMPLAINT, YOU MAY CALL THE MIAMI-DADE COUNTY CONSUMER SERVICES DEPARTMENT AT (CURRENT PHONE NUMBER).
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
No part of this division shall be construed to impair or affect the obligation of any title loan agreement or contract that was lawfully entered into prior to the effective date of this division. A title loan made before the effective date of Ordinance No. 99-36, which was May 7, 1999, may be renewed or extended after the effective date of Ordinance No. 99-36 at the interest rate agreed upon by the parties prior to May 7, 1999 provided:
<section prefix = "i">
The previously agreed upon interest rate does not violate chapter 538, Florida Statutes; and
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
The title loan agreement in question does not specifically state that the agreement is nonrenewable.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Any title loan made without benefit of a license is void, in which case the person making the title loan forfeits the right to collect any moneys, including principal and interest charged on the title loan, from the borrower in connection with such agreement. The person making the title loan shall return to the borrower the loan property, the titled personal property pledged or the fair market value of such titled personal property, and all principal and interest paid by the borrower. The borrower is entitled to receive reasonable attorney's fees and costs in any action brought by the borrower to recover from the person making the title loan the loan property, the titled personal property, or the principal and interest paid by the borrower.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-62, § 1, 6-8-99)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-124.14. Maximum interest rate and charges</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
A title loan lender may charge a maximum interest rate of two and one-half (2½) percent per thirty (30) day period the title loan agreement remains outstanding and unsatisfied provided, however, that said maximum interest rate shall not exceed a maximum annual interest rate of thirty (30) percent. The maximum interest rate provided for herein shall, upon the effective date of this section, supersede the maximum interest rate established by Ordinance No. 99-36. In determining compliance with the maximum interest and finance charges, the computation must be simple interest and not add-on interest or any other interest computation.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The annual percentage rate that may be charged in a title loan transaction may equal, but not exceed, the annual percentage rate that must be computed and disclosed as required by the Federal Truth in Lending Act and Regulation Z of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System. When the period for which the charge is computed is more or less than one (1) month, the maximum rate for the period must be computed on the basis of one-thirtieth (1/30) the applicable monthly interest rate, multiplied by the number of days of the period.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Any transaction involving a borrower's delivery of a motor vehicle certificate of title in exchange for the advancement of funds on the condition that the borrower shall or may redeem or repurchase the certificate of title upon the payment of a sum of money, whether the transaction be characterized as a "buy-sell agreement," "sale-leaseback agreement," or otherwise, shall be deemed a violation of this division if such sum exceeds the amount that a title loan lender may collect in a title loan agreement under this division or if the terms of the transaction otherwise conflict with the permitted terms and conditions of a title loan agreement under this division.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
No charges, including interest, in excess of the combined total of all charges permitted by this section shall be allowed. Notwithstanding the foregoing, a title loan lender may charge a one-time fee equivalent to the amount actually paid by the title loan lender to record a lien securing the title loan lender's interest in the motor vehicle certificate of title owned by the borrower.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
It shall be unlawful for secondhand dealers as defined in Section 538.03, Florida Statutes (1997), as same may be amended from time to time, to charge an interest rate on a motor vehicle title loan transaction entered into after the effective date of the ordinance from which this subsection derives greater than eighteen (18) percent, as provided in Section 687.03, Florida Statutes. Motor vehicle title loan transaction means a loan of money secured by bailment of a certificate of title to a motor vehicle where the borrower maintains possession of, or control over, the motor vehicle throughout the term of the loan, and the borrower is not required to pay rent or any other charge for the use of the motor vehicle.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-36, § 1, 4-27-99; Ord. No. 99-62, § 1, 6-8-99)</history>
<EditorsNote>
The maximum interest rate provided for in Ord. No. 99-36, § 1, adopted April 27, 1999, and codified in subsection 8A-124.14(e) has been superseded by Ord. No. 99-62, § 1, adopted June 8, 1999, codified in subsection 124.14(a).
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-124.15. Transaction satisfaction and default</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
When the title loan has been paid in full, the title loan lender must deliver to the borrower a certificate of title clear of all encumbrances placed upon the title by the title loan lender within thirty (30) days of such payment in full.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
If a borrower fails to repay all amounts legally due under the title loan agreement on or before the end of the title loan's maturity date or any extension thereof and fails to make a payment on the loan within thirty (30) days after the end of the loan's maturity date or any extension thereof, whichever is later, the title loan lender may take possession of the titled personal property. A lender may take possession of the titled personal property only through an agent who is licensed by the state to repossess motor vehicles.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Prior to engaging a repossession agent, the lender shall afford the debtor an opportunity to make the titled personal property available to the lender at a place, date, and time reasonably convenient to the lender and the borrower. Prior to taking possession of titled personal property, the lender shall afford the borrower a reasonable opportunity to remove from the titled personal property any personal belongings without charge or additional cost to the borrower. Once the lender takes possession of the titled personal property, the lender, at the lender's sole expense and risk, may authorize a third party to retain physical possession of the titled personal property.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Upon taking possession of titled personal property, the lender may dispose of the titled personal property by sale but may do so only through a motor vehicle dealer licensed under Section 320.27, Florida Statutes. At least 10 days prior to sale, the lender shall notify the borrower of the date, time, and place of the sale and provide the borrower with a written accounting of the principal amount due on the title loan, interest accrued through the date of the lender taking possession of the titled personal property, and any reasonable expenses incurred to date by the lender in taking possession of, preparing for sale, and selling the titled personal property. At any time prior to sale, the lender shall permit the borrower to redeem the titled personal property by tendering a money order or certified check for the principal amount of the title loan, interest accrued through the date of the lender taking possession, and any reasonable expenses incurred to date by the lender in taking possession of, preparing for sale, and selling the titled personal property. Nothing in this act nor in any title loan agreement shall preclude a borrower from purchasing the titled personal property at any sale.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Any such sale or disposal shall vest in the purchaser the right, title, and interest of the owner and the title loan lender.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Within thirty (30) days after the sale of the titled personal property, the borrower is entitled to receive all proceeds from the sale of the motor vehicle in excess of the principal amount due on the loan, interest on the loan up to the date of the lender taking possession, and the reasonable expenses incurred by the lender in taking possession of, preparing for sale, and selling the titled personal property. The borrower is entitled to reasonable attorneys' fees and costs incurred in any action brought to recover such proceeds that results in the title loan lender being ordered to return all or part of such amount.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
The borrower shall not be personally liable to the lender for any balance due on the title loan remaining after applying the proceeds of the sale of the titled personal property to the principal amount due on the title loan, interest accrued through the date of the lender taking possession, and any reasonable expenses incurred by the lender in taking possession of, preparing for sale, and selling the titled personal property unless such balance exceeds two thousand dollars ($2,000.00). If such balance exceeds two thousand dollars ($2,000), the lender shall be entitled to reasonable attorneys' fees and costs incurred in any action brought to recover such balance that results in a judgment in favor of the lender.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
The rights and remedies referred to in this section are cumulative. Except as otherwise provided in this section, the disposal of titled personal property is subject to the provisions of ch. 679, Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
In taking possession and disposing of titled personal property by sale or otherwise, the title loan lender shall at all times proceed in a commercially reasonable manner.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
For purposes of this division, nonpublic sales or disposal of a motor vehicle between licensees and business affiliates or family members are sales and disposal that are presumed not to be commercially reasonable.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-62, § 1, 6-8-99)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-124.16. Right to redeem; lost title loan agreements</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Any person presenting identification as the borrower and presenting the borrower's copy of the title loan agreement to the title loan lender is presumed to be entitled to redeem the certificate of title described in the title loan agreement; however, if the title loan lender determines that the person is not the borrower, the title loan lender is not required to allow the redemption of the certificate of title by such person. The person redeeming the certificate of title must sign the borrower's copy of the title loan agreement, which the title loan lender may retain to evidence such person's receipt of the certificate of title. The title loan lender shall provide the borrower with a copy of the signed title loan agreement. A person redeeming the certificate of title who is not the borrower must show identification to the title loan lender, together with written authorization from the borrower, and the title loan lender shall record that person's name and address on the title loan agreement retained by the title loan lender. In any such case, the person redeeming the certificate of title who is not the borrower shall be provided a copy of such signed form as evidence of such transaction.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
If the borrower's copy of the title loan agreement is lost, destroyed, or stolen, the borrower must notify the title loan lender, in writing by certified or registered mail, return receipt requested, or in person evidenced by a signed receipt, and receipt of such notice shall invalidate such title loan agreement if the certificate of title has not previously been redeemed. Before delivering the certificate of title or issuing a new title loan agreement, the title loan lender shall require the borrower to make a written statement of loss, destruction, or theft of the borrower's copy of the title loan agreement. The title loan lender shall record on the written statement the type of identification and the identification number accepted from the borrower, the date the statement is given, and the number or date of the title loan agreement lost, destroyed or stolen. The statement shall be signed by the title loan lender or the title loan office employee who accepts the statement from the borrower.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-62, § 1, 6-8-99)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-124.17. Licenses</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
No person may engage in business as a title loan lender or advertise to engage in business as a title loan lender unless the title loan lender has a valid license issued by the Department. A separate license shall be required for each physical location of title loan business. The Department shall issue more than one (1) license to an applicant if that applicant complies with the requirements of this section for each license.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
An application for a license pursuant to this section must be submitted to the Department on such form as the Department may prescribe. If the Department determines that a license should be granted, it shall issue the license for a period not to exceed two (2) years. A non-refundable application and license fee shall accompany an initial application for each title loan application.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
An application for license renewal pursuant to this section must be submitted to the Department on such form as the Department may prescribe. A title loan lender shall pay an annual license renewal fee. Renewal of registrations may be staggered over the annual period by the Director of the Department. A license that is not renewed at the end of each annual period shall automatically become inactive. An inactive license may be reactivated within ninety (90) days after the date it became inactive upon the submission of a completed reactivation form and payment of a reactivation fee. No inactive license may be reactivated after ninety (90) days.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
All fees required pursuant to this section, including the initial application and license fee, license renewal fee, replacement fee and reactivation fee shall be established by administrative order approved by the Commission.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Each license must specify the location for which it is issued and shall be conspicuously displayed at that location. If the address of the principal place of business of the title loan lender is different from the location for which the license is issued, the license must state the address of the principal place of business of the title loan lender. When a title loan lender wishes to move a title loan office to another location the title loan lender shall give thirty (30) days prior written notice to the Department by certified or registered mail return receipt requested, and the Department shall then amend the license accordingly after payment of a replacement fee. A license issued pursuant to this section is not transferable or assignable.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
A title loan lender licensed pursuant to this section shall designate and maintain an agent in this state for service of process.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
A title loan lender licensed pursuant to this section shall apply to the Department for a new license upon a change in ownership of twenty-five (25) percent or more of the licensed title loan lender at any title loan location or office.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
No license shall be issued or renewed unless the applicant has complied with the following:
<section prefix = "1">
Filed with the Department a bond in the amount of one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00) for each license with a surety company qualified to do business in this state. The bond shall be to the Department and in favor of any consumer who is injured in the context of a title loan transaction by the fraud, misrepresentation, breach of contract, financial failure or other failure of the business, unfair or deceptive trade practice, disclosure violation, or violation of any provision of this division by the title loan lender. The performance bond shall be maintained in the full amount specified herein throughout the term of the license and for one (1) year after the license expires or is terminated, without reduction or allowances for any amounts which are withdrawn or paid pursuant to this division. An injured consumer may bring an action in a court of competent jurisdiction against the surety bond. The court shall award to a prevailing consumer reasonable attorneys' fees and costs, including appellate attorneys' fees and costs. The surety bond shall require that any surety company canceling a bond provided to a title loan lender pursuant to this section shall notify the Department of such cancellation in writing at least forty-five (45) days before cancellation.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Not have pled nolo contendere to, or been convicted or found guilty of a felony within the last ten (10) years regardless of whether adjudication was withheld, or not be acting as an ultimate equitable owner for someone who has pled nolo contendere to, or been convicted or found guilty of a felony within the preceding ten (10) years, regardless of whether adjudication was withheld.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Not have pled nolo contendere to, or been convicted or found guilty of a crime involving fraud, dishonest dealing, or any act of moral turpitude regardless of whether adjudication was withheld, or not be acting as an ultimate equitable owner for someone who has pled nolo contendere to, or been convicted or found guilty of a crime involving fraud, dishonest dealing, or any act of moral turpitude, regardless of whether adjudication was withheld.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Not have pled nolo contendere to, or been convicted or found guilty of a crime directly related to the duties and responsibilities of a title loan lender within the preceding ten (10) years regardless of whether adjudication was withheld, or not be acting as an ultimate equitable owner for someone who has been convicted of a crime directly related to the duties and responsibilities of a title loan lender within the preceding ten (10) years, regardless of whether adjudication was withheld.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Filed with the Director a true, correct and complete application on the form prescribed by the Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Paid the initial, renewal or reactivation fee, as applicable.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Submitted to a background investigation resulting in a determination by the Director of the Department that:
<section prefix = "a">
Each corporate or partnership applicant is qualified under the laws of Florida to do business under the trade name or names under which it has applied for a license.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
No fraud or willful or knowing misrepresentation or false statement was made in the application.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
No judgment against the applicant arising out of the activity of title loan lending practices, unless a stay or reversal of the judgment is procured through the courts.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Complied with the provisions of this division.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
If an applicant for a title loan lending license is other than a corporation, the eligibility requirements of Subsections (h)(2), (3) and (4) apply to each direct or ultimate equitable owner.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
If an applicant for a title loan lending license is a corporation, the eligibility requirements of Subsections (h)(2), (3) and (4) apply to each direct or ultimate equitable owner of at least twenty-five (25) percent of the outstanding equity interest of such corporation and to each director and executive officer.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
The Department shall determine the form of the license and may perform criminal background checks as appropriate.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Licensees shall report changes in address, location of records, and any change of an executive officer within thirty (30) days of the change.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-62, § 1, 6-8-99)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-124.18. Record keeping</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Every title loan lender licensed by the Department shall maintain, at the principal place of business designated on the license, all books, accounts, records, and documents necessary to determine the title loan lender's compliance with this division.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Department may authorize maintenance of records at a location other than a principal place of business. The Department may require books and records to be produced and available at a reasonable and convenient location within Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
All books, accounts, records, documents and receipts for expenses paid by the title loan lender on behalf of the borrower, including each contract signed by the borrower and expenses incurred by the title loan lender in event of foreclosure and property recovery, shall be preserved by the title loan lender and shall be made available to the Department for examination for five (5) years after the date of original entry.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The Department may prescribe the minimum information to be shown in the books, accounts, records and documents of licensees.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Title loan lenders shall keep all certificates of title in fireproof or fire-resistant storage while the certificates are in the lender's possession.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-62, § 1, 6-8-99)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-124.19. Violations</catch_line>
<text>
The following acts shall constitute violations of this division and unfair and deceptive trade acts or practices:
<section prefix = "a">
Failing to comply with any provision of this division, any provision of resolutions adopted by the Commission pursuant to this division, or any written agreement entered into with the County.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Committing any act of fraud, misrepresentation, deceit, or gross negligence, regardless of reliance by or damage to a borrower, or any illegal activity in connection with a title loan transaction under this division.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Fraudulently misrepresenting, circumventing or concealing any matter required to be stated or furnished to a borrower pursuant to this division.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Imposition of illegal charges in any title loan transaction.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Engaging in false, deceptive, or misleading advertising.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Failing to maintain, preserve and keep available for examination, all books, accounts, or other documents required by this division, resolution of the Commission, state or federal law, or any agreement entered into with the Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Aiding, abetting, or conspiring with another person to circumvent or violate any of the requirements of this division, or the requirements of any state or federal law regulating title loan lenders.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Refusing to permit inspection of books or records in an investigation or examination by the Department or failure or refusal to comply with a subpoena or order issued by the Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Engaging in criminal conduct in the course of business as a title loan lender.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Knowingly entering into a title loan agreement with a person under the age of eighteen (18) years.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Making any agreement that requires or allows for the personal liability of the borrower or the waiver of any of the provisions of this division.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Knowingly entering into a title loan agreement with any person who is under the influence of drugs or alcohol when such condition is visible or apparent, or with any person using a name other than his or her own name or the registered name or his or her business.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
Entering into a title loan agreement in which the amount of money advanced in consideration for the loan secured by any single certificate of title exceeds one-third (1/3) of the value of the motor vehicle. The value of the motor vehicle shall be determined by reference to the loan value in the current Southeastern Edition of the National Automobile Dealer's Association Official Used Car Guide. The value may vary based upon documented unique characteristics of the motor vehicle.
</section>
<section prefix = "n">
Failing to exercise reasonable care in the safekeeping of a certificate of title or motor vehicle repossessed pursuant to this division.
</section>
<section prefix = "o">
Failing to return a certificate of title or repossessed motor vehicle to a borrower, with any and all of the title lender's liens on the property properly released, within thirty (30) days of the payment of the full amount due, unless the property has been seized or impounded by an authorized law enforcement agency, taken into custody by a court, or otherwise disposed of by court order.
</section>
<section prefix = "p">
Charging or receiving any finance charge, interest, cost, or fee which is not permitted by this division.
</section>
<section prefix = "q">
Engaging in business as a title loan lender without a current, active license issued by the Department pursuant to this division.
</section>
<section prefix = "r">
Refusing to accept partial repayment of the amount financed when all accrued finance charges have been paid.
</section>
<section prefix = "s">
Charging a prepayment penalty.
</section>
<section prefix = "t">
Capitalizing any unpaid finance charge as part of the amount financed in the renewal of a title loan agreement.
</section>
<section prefix = "u">
Failing to account for and remit to the borrower all surplus proceeds from the disposal of the borrower's motor vehicle, within thirty (30) days of disposal.
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
Advertising in any publication which is primarily circulated, displayed, distributed or marketed within Miami-Dade County, Florida, which advertisement identifies a motor vehicle title loan lender offering loans regulated by this article, unless the advertisement includes the license number issued by the Department and the name under which the business is licensed. For the purposes of this subsection, any advertisement shall be defined to include any announcement, listing, display, entry or other written or oral statement of whatever nature or kind, and specifically to include a name and address or telephone number placed under a heading, where the heading describes or encompasses any kind of repair work regulated under this article without a current valid license required by the Department.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-124.20. Enforcement and penalties</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It shall be the duty and responsibility of all law enforcement officials to assist in the enforcement of this division and the code to the extent that it is within their jurisdiction to do so.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The Department shall maintain a system by which licensees are given written notices of all violations. Department personnel shall be permitted to enter the business premises of a person who provides services pursuant to this division to ascertain whether the license is current, and to examine books and records as required by this division.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
In addition to all other penalties, remedies or other enforcement measures established within this division, or otherwise provided by law, violations of this division shall be subject to civil penalties as provided in Chapter 8CC of the Code, and penalties shall be imposed as set forth in the schedule of penalties therein. The Department is authorized to enforce the provisions of this division by, among other means, administrative fines as provided herein. Each day of a continuing violation shall be deemed a separate violation.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The Department may enter into written assurances of compliance pursuant to Sections 8A-82.1 and 8A-124.21 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, with respect to the matters regulated under this division.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
The Department is also authorized to enforce the provisions of this division by suspension or revocation of a license upon notice and hearing as provided in this section unless the licensee waives such notice and hearing. Licenses are subject to suspension or revocation when it shall appear that:
<section prefix = "1">
The licensee has failed to comply with or has violated any provision of this division; or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The license was obtained by an application in which any material fact was omitted or falsely stated.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Appeals from actions, decisions or determinations of the Director of the Department shall be governed by Section 8A-161.23 of the Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
In addition to any other judicial or administrative remedies provided by law, rule, regulation, ordinance or this division, the Director of the Department shall have the judicial remedies available to enforce the provisions of this division as provided in Section 8A-161.22 of the Code.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 99-62, § 1, 6-8-99)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-124.21. Assurances of compliance</catch_line>
<text>
Each violation of any of the terms and conditions of a verified, written assurance entered into pursuant to Section 8A-82.1 of the Code with respect to the matters regulated under this division shall constitute a separate offense under this division by the persons who executed the assurance, their respective officers, directors, agents, servants, employees and attorneys; and by those persons in active concert or participation with any of the foregoing persons and who receive actual notice of the assurance of compliance. Decisions, actions, and determinations of the Director, pursuant to Sections 8A-82.1 and 8A-124.20(d) or assurances of compliance executed thereunder, shall not be subject to review pursuant to Section 8A-124.20.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-124.22. Civil penalties</catch_line>
<text>
Any person who violates any of the provisions of this division or any cease and desist order of the Director or any written notice to correct a violation or any assurance of compliance entered into pursuant to Section 8A-82.1 of the Code and this division with respect to matters regulated under this division or any other lawful order of the Director or any condition, limitation, or restriction of a license, registration, certificate, or permit issued by the Director, shall be subject to the judicial imposition and recovery of a civil penalty in an amount of not more than ten thousand dollars ($10,000.00) per offense. Each day during any portion of which such violation occurs or continues to occur constitutes a separate offense. Such monies recovered by the Director shall be deposited in a separate county fund to be used exclusively for enforcement of this division.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-124.23. Criminal penalties</catch_line>
<text>
If any person violates or fails or refuses to obey or comply with any of the provisions of this division or any lawful order of the Director or any cease and desist order of the Director or any notice to correct a violation of the Director or any written assurance of compliance entered into pursuant to Section 8A-82.1 of the Code and this division, or any condition, limitation, or restriction of a license, registration, certificate, or permit issued by the Director, such person, upon conviction of any such offense, shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00), or by imprisonment not to exceed sixty (60) days in the county jail, or both, in the discretion of the court. Each day or portion thereof of continuing violation shall be deemed a separate offense.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-124.24. Additional remedy to borrower, private right of action</catch_line>
<text>
Any borrower injured by a violation of this part may bring an action for recovery of damages including twice the interest previously paid and the forfeiture of all interest charged, or contracted to be charged or reserved. Said borrower may recover reasonable attorney's fees and costs of such action. An award may be entered for punitive damages. The remedies provided for under this part are in addition to any other procedures or remedies for any violation provided in any other law or ordinance.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-124.25. Duties, functions, powers and responsibilities of Director</catch_line>
<text>
The duties, functions, powers and responsibilities of the Director of the Department shall include, among others, the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Enforce all of the provisions of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Upon receipt of complaints or upon the Director's initiative, investigate, inspect, sample, and test any matters regulated hereunder.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Institute civil actions or proceedings to enforce all the provisions of this article and subpoenae issued by the Director, including seeking mandatory and prohibitory injunctions, the imposition and recovery of civil penalties and such other remedies, recoveries, and attorneys fees as set forth in Section 8A-161.22. Such civil actions or proceedings may be instituted by the Director whether or not a cease and desist order or notice to correct the violation or other lawful order of the Director has been issued or other administrative proceeding is pending.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Prosecute through the State Attorney in the criminal courts for violations of this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Deny, revoke, suspend and issue licenses and impose conditions, limitations, and restrictions upon same in accordance with Section 8A-124.17 and 8A-124.2(e) of this Code. Notwithstanding the foregoing, no revocation or suspension of a license by the Director shall be effective until the rendition of the appeal, if any, of such revocation or suspension pursuant to Section 8A-161.23 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, or until the time period for filing such appeal has expired, whichever is later.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Issue subpoenae to compel the presence of any person or document or thing at any hearing, conference or proceeding authorized herein upon information or belief by the Director that a violation of any provision of this article has occurred or may occur.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Inquire into the practices, functions and policies of any and all motor vehicle title loan companies and make such recommendations to the Commission as the Director may deem necessary.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Administer oaths and certify official acts of the Director.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Investigate, upon the Director's initiative, the practices of any motor vehicle title loan company.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Apply to any judge of the circuit or county court, criminal or civil division, for the issuance of an administrative search warrant.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Conduct a program for monitoring consumer satisfaction levels in the field of motor vehicle title loan and make such monitoring information available to the Commission and the public.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Render, in the Director's discretion, assistance and technical advice to motor vehicle title loan companies.
</section>
<section prefix = "m">
Institute informal conferences for discussing and resolving any matter covered by this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "n">
Publish and disseminate information to the public concerning motor vehicle title loan.
</section>
<section prefix = "o">
Submit to the Commission proposed rules, regulations, and standards to effectuate the purposes of this article. No such proposed rules, regulations, and standards shall become effective until approved by the Commission by ordinance.
</section>
<section prefix = "p">
Provide motor vehicle title loan companies, at least annually, with information concerning the rules, regulations, and standards enacted during the immediate past year.
</section>
<section prefix = "q">
Issue cease and desist orders, notices to correct violations, and any other lawful orders of the Director which shall briefly set forth the general nature of the violation of this article and specify the time within which the violation shall be rectified or stopped. If an order to cease and desist or notice to correct violations or any other lawful order of the Director is not obeyed the Director shall have the power and authority to revoke or suspend the license, if any has been issued, or deny the issuance of a license, and take such other action authorized by this article. Notwithstanding the foregoing, no revocation or suspension of a registration by the Director shall be effective until the rendition of the appeal, if any, of such revocation or suspension pursuant to Section 8A-161.23 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, or until the time period for filing such appeal has expired, whichever is later. Orders to cease and desist, notices to correct violations, and any other lawful orders of the Director hereunder may be enforced by the institution by the Director of civil actions for mandatory and prohibitory injunctions, civil penalties and other remedies, recoveries, and attorneys fees as set forth in Section 8A-161.22 of the Code of Miami-Dade County in a court of competent jurisdiction.
</section>
<section prefix = "r">
Appoint and designate, in the Director's discretion, various technical advisory panels.
</section>
<section prefix = "s">
Enter into written assurances of compliance pursuant to Sections 8A-82.1 and 8A-124.21 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, with respect to the matters regulated under this article.
</section>
<section prefix = "t">
The powers of the Director enumerated in this article shall be in addition to and not a limitation of any other powers of the Director pursuant to any other provisions of this article or any other provisions of law or ordinance.

</section>
</text>
</law>
