<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="3">ARTICLE IV. PERSONNEL</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="4">DIVISION_1._PERSONNEL_DEPARTMENT</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-26. Established</catch_line>
<text>
A Personnel Department is hereby established, which shall be responsible for the administration of the County personnel program and the rules governing such program.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-27. Director—As head; appointment; term</catch_line>
<text>
The head of the Personnel Department is the Personnel Director who shall be appointed by the Manager and the Director shall serve at the Manager's will. The Personnel Director shall have had training and experience in personnel administration.
</text>
The head of the Personnel Department is the Personnel Director who shall be appointed by the Manager and the Director shall serve at the Manager's will. The Personnel Director shall have had training and experience in personnel administration.
<catch_line>Sec. 2-28. Same—Duties</catch_line>
<text>
The Director, as executive head of the Department, shall under the supervision of the Manager direct all its administrative and technical activities. In addition to the duties imposed upon the Director elsewhere in this law, it shall be the Director's duty:
<section prefix = "1">
To apply and carry out this law and the rules adopted thereunder.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
To attend meetings of the Board and act as its Secretary and keep minutes of its proceedings.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
To establish and maintain a roster of all employees in the County classified service, in which there shall be set forth, as to each employee, the class title, pay or status, and other pertinent data.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
To foster and develop, in cooperation with appointing authorities and others, programs for the improvement of employee effectiveness, including training, safety, health, counseling and welfare.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
To encourage and exercise leadership in the development of effective personnel administration within the several departments of the County service, and to make available the facilities of the Personnel Department to this end.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
To investigate from time to time the operation and effect of this law and of the rules made thereunder and to report the findings and recommendations to the Personnel Advisory Board and to the County Commission and other officials.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
To make an annual report regarding the work of the Department, and such special reports as the Director may consider desirable, to the Personnel Advisory Board, and to the County Commission and other officials.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
To perform any other lawful acts which the Director may consider necessary or desirable to carry out the purposes and provisions of this law.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
The Director may designate appropriate persons, including officers and employees in the County services, to assist in the preparation and rating of tests. An appointing authority shall excuse any employee from duty for the time required for this work as an examiner. Such officers and employees shall not be entitled to extra pay for their services as examiners but shall be entitled to reimbursement for necessary traveling and other expenses.

(Ch. 30255, § 7, Laws 1955; Ord. No. 57-16, § 1, 10-7-57; Ord. No. 88-1, § 1, 1-19-88)
</section>

Annotations—AO's 7-4, 7-8, 7-11.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-29. Organization; personnel; salaries</catch_line>
<text>
The organization and operating procedures of the Department shall be prescribed in administrative orders and regulations of the Manager. The Manager shall appoint such employees and other personnel as may be necessary to operate the Department. The salaries and compensation of all personnel, except employees within the classified service, shall be fixed by the County Commission upon recommendation of the Manager.
</text>
The organization and operating procedures of the Department shall be prescribed in administrative orders and regulations of the Manager. The Manager shall appoint such employees and other personnel as may be necessary to operate the Department. The salaries and compensation of all personnel, except employees within the classified service, shall be fixed by the County Commission upon recommendation of the Manager.
Charter reference— For authority of Manager to issue and place into effect administrative orders, rules and regulations and to prescribe the organization and operating procedure of departments of the County, § 4.02.
<catch_line>Secs. 2-30—2-36. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Ord. No. 93-104, § 3, adopted Oct. 19, 1993 and Ord. No. 93-114, § 3, adopted Oct. 21, 1993, abolished the personnel advisory board, and at the discretion of the editor, §§ 2-30—2-36, relative to such board, have been deleted from this Code. The provisions of former §§ 2-30—2-36 derived from Laws of Florida 1955, Ch. 30255, §§ 5, 6; Ord. No. 57-16, 10-7-57; Ord. No. 58-11, 4-16-58; Ord. No. 64-39, 9-1-64; Ord. No. 68-50, 9-19-68; Ord. No. 73-20, 3-8-73; Ord. No. 88-1, 1-19-88.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-37. Personnel departments in County hospitals</catch_line>
<text>
There may be established at any County hospital unit, a Personnel Department which shall work with and through the Director of the Personnel Department of the County.
(Ch. 30255, § 3, Laws 1955; Ord. No. 57-16, § 1, 10-7-57)
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-37.1. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<EditorsNote>
Section 2-37.1, pertaining to rules governing Transit Authority operating personnel, has been deleted as covered by §§ 2-39(h), 2-45. The section was derived from Ord. No. 64-51, § 1, adopted October 6, 1964.
</EditorsNote>
<catch_line>Sec. 2-38. Financing</catch_line>
<text>
The County Commission shall provide sufficient funds in its annual budget to carry out effectively the provisions of this article.
(Ch. 30255, § 3(c), Laws 1955)
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (10) ---
Annotations—AO's 3-5, 6-1, 6-3, 7-3, 7-6, 7-9, 7-19, 7-27, 9-1 (Back)
Charter reference— Charter provisions providing for department of personnel, § 4.05. (Back)

</text>
</law>
