<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="3">ARTICLE III. UNIFORM TRADE STANDARDS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="4">DIVISION_1._IN_GENERAL</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-65. Short title</catch_line>
<text>
This article shall be designated and cited as the Uniform Trade Standards Ordinance of Miami-Dade County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-66. Declaration of legislative intent</catch_line>
<text>
The provisions and penalties of this article are supplemental to all other laws and ordinances.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-67. Applicability</catch_line>
<text>
It is hereby provided that this article shall constitute a uniform law applicable in all the unincorporated and incorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-68. Repealing laws in conflict herewith</catch_line>
<text>
All municipal charters, municipal ordinances, municipal resolutions, special laws applying to and within this County and general laws applying only to this County, or any general laws applying only to this County, or any general law which this County Commission is specifically authorized by the Home Rule Amendment to the Florida Constitution (Article VIII, Section 11) to supersede, nullify, or amend, or any part of such charters, ordinances, resolutions or laws, in conflict with any provision of this article are hereby repealed.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-69. Superseding City ordinances and codes and certain County ordinances</catch_line>
<text>
It is further provided that this article shall pertain to all violations hereof within this County and supersedes and nullifies those provisions of any and all municipal ordinances and codes, including those adopted as a County ordinance, which define or penalize any act recognized and declared in this article to be a violation thereof. This article shall not be deemed to supersede or nullify any municipal ordinance imposing additional regulations upon the sale of or advertising of Kosher meats or meat products sanctioned in accordance with Orthodox Hebrew religious requirements.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-70. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
When used in this article:
<section prefix = "a">
Person. The word "person" shall be construed to mean both the plural and singular, as the case demands, and shall include individuals, partnerships, corporations, companies, societies and associations.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Weight(s) and (or) measure(s). The words "weight(s) and (or) measure(s)" shall be construed to mean all weights and measures of every kind, instruments and devices for weighing and measuring, and any appliances and accessories associated with any or all such instruments and devices, except that the term shall not be construed to include meters for the measurement of electricity, gas (natural or manufactured), or water when the same are operated in a public utility system. Such electricity, gas, and water meters are hereby specifically excluded from the purview of this article, and none of the provisions of this article shall be construed to apply to such meters or to any appliances or accessories associated therewith.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Sell; sale. The words "sell" and "sale" shall be construed to include barter and exchange.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Director; Inspector. The terms "Director" and "Inspector" shall be construed to mean, respectively, the County Manager or his delegate, as Director of Trade Standards and Inspectors of Trade Standards of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Intrastate commerce. The term "intrastate commerce" shall be construed to mean any and all commerce or trade that is begun, carried on, and completed wholly within the limits of the State of Florida, and the phrase "introduced into intrastate commerce" shall be construed to define the time and place at which the first sale and delivery of a commodity is made within the State, the delivery being made either directly to the purchaser or to a common carrier for shipment to the purchaser.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Commodity in package form. The term "commodity in package form" shall be construed to mean a commodity put up or packaged in any manner in advance of sale in units suitable for either wholesale or retail sale, exclusive, however, of an auxiliary shipping container enclosing packages that individually conform to the requirements of this article. An individual item or lot of any commodity not in package form as defined in this section, but on which there is marked a selling price based on an established price per unit of weight or measure, shall be construed to be a commodity in package form.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
[Complete purchase price.] The term "complete purchase price" shall mean the price paid by the purchaser to the seller at the time of the sale and shall include all charges except taxes levied at the retail level.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-71. Definitions of special units of measure</catch_line>
<text>
The term "barrel" when used in connection with fermented liquor, shall mean a unit of thirty-one (31) gallons. The term "ton" shall mean a unit of two thousand (2,000) pounds avoirdupois weight. The term "cord" when used in connection with wood intended for fuel purposes, shall mean the amount of wood that is contained in a space of one hundred twenty-eight (128) cubic feet when the wood is ranked and well stowed.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-72. Systems of weights and measures</catch_line>
<text>
The system of weights and measures in customary use in the United States and the metric system of weights and measures are jointly recognized, and one (1) or the other of these systems shall be used for all commercial purposes in Miami-Dade County. The definitions of basic units of weight and measure, the tables of weight and measure, and weights and measures equivalents, as published by the National Bureau of Standards, are recognized and shall govern weighing and measuring equipment and transactions in this County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-73. Construction of contracts</catch_line>
<text>
Fractional parts of any unit of weight or measure shall mean like fractional parts of the value of such unit as prescribed or defined in Sections 8A-71 and 8A-72 of this article, and all contracts concerning the sale of commodities and services shall be construed in accordance with this requirement.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-74. Field standards and equipment; verification</catch_line>
<text>
The field standards used by the County shall be verified by the State weights and measures office upon their initial receipt and at least once each two (2) years thereafter.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-75. Fair Packaging and Labeling Act, rules adopted</catch_line>
<text>
Rules having the force and effect of law as authorized under Sections 4, 5, and 6 of the Fair Packaging and Labeling Act (P.L. 89-755) that supersede State and local laws which are less stringent than or require information different from said act, are hereby adopted by reference as published in the Federal Register as part of this article. No person shall distribute or cause to be distributed, offer for sale or sell, in this County any packaged consumer commodity unless in conformity with the Fair Package and Labeling Act and/or the rules which shall be established by the promulgating authority.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-76. Notice of penalties for removal of shopping carts</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Shopping cart identification sign required for retail establishments. Every retail sales establishment which utilizes shopping carts, as defined by F.S. § 506.502(10), in the operation of its business shall affix an identification sign on the shopping cart providing the name, address and phone number of the retail establishment.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Every retail sales establishment which utilizes shopping carts, as defined by Florida Statutes, Section 506.501(10), in the operation of its business shall affix the following notice to all such carts which shall be clearly legible in the English, Spanish and Creole languages and shall state the following:
WARNING
Any person who removes a shopping cart from the premises of the owner, or is in the possession of any shopping cart, shall be presumed to be in possession of stolen property and is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable by a term of imprisonment of up to one (1) year as provided by Sections 506.509 and 506.513 of the Florida Statutes.

</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Every owner of a stand-alone retail sales establishment which utilizes shopping carts or owner of a shopping center in which one or more of the retail sales establishments utilizes shopping carts, as defined by Florida Statutes, Section 506.502(10), in the operation of its business shall post signs at the entrance(s) and exit(s) of its parking area(s) which shall be clearly legible in the English, Spanish and Creole languages and which shall provide, in substantial form, the information required in Section 8A-76(b). As an alternative, universal language signs designed to convey the warning required in Section 8A-76(b) may be used.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Any establishment desiring an exemption from Section 8A-76(a), (b) and (c) shall file a petition for exemption and enclose an appropriate application fee to be determined by the County Manager. A petition for an exemption from the requirements of this section may be granted by the Director of the Consumer Services Department to any retail establishment which:
<section prefix = "1">
Constructs barriers to prevent the removal of shopping carts, while permitting full wheelchair ingress and egress by disabled persons; or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Attaches alarm mechanisms or other security devices to shopping carts to prevent their removal from the property of the retail sales establishment or shopping center.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Failure to abide by Section 8A-76(a), (b) or (c) shall constitute a violation and result in a civil penalty as provided in chapter 8CC. Nothing herein shall make illegal the removal of a shopping cart with the consent or permission of the owner of the shopping cart.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 05-20, § 1, 1-27-05)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-76.1. Shopping carts</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Procedure for handling identifiable shopping carts found on public property.
<section prefix = "1">
Employees and officers of Miami-Dade County shall be deemed agents of Miami-Dade County and any identifiable shopping carts found by them on public property during the course of their official duties shall be reported to the Department of Solid Waste Management. The Department shall collect the shopping carts and place them in storage.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Director of the Department of Solid Waste Management or his designee shall provide reasonable notice to the owner of the shopping cart as designated on the shopping cart's identification sign to retrieve the property.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The owner of the shopping cart shall have ten (10) days from receipt of the notice to retrieve the property.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
If the shopping cart is not claimed by the owner within the time specified in this section or if the Department cannot contact the owner for failure to provide the identification information required under Section 8A-76 (a) of this Code, the title to such property shall vest in Miami-Dade County and shall be disposed of by the Department.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Procedure for handling unidentifiable shopping carts found on public property. All unidentifiable shopping carts found on public property shall be handled in accordance with F.S. ch. 705, as amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Department of Solid Waste Management is delegated the authority to enforce this section.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 97-213, § 1, 12-2-97; Ord. No. 05-20, § 2, 1-27-05)</history>
<catch_line>Secs. 8A-77—8A-79. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
</law>
