<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="3">ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="4">DIVISION_2._STATE_AND_FEDERAL_ADOPTIONS</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-25. Violations of rules and regulations of the State of Florida Department of Environmental Protection, Florida Department of Health, and the United States Environmental Protection Agency</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
All of the following rules and regulations are hereby adopted and are incorporated herein by reference hereto as same may be amended from time to time:
<section prefix = "a">
Chapter 62-160 of the Florida Administrative Code
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Chapter 62-550 of the Florida Administrative Code
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Chapter 62-713 of the Florida Administrative Code
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Chapter 62-761 of the Florida Administrative Code
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Chapter 64E-8 of the Florida Administrative Code
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Chapter 62-770 of the Florida Administrative Code
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Chapter 62-777 of the Florida Administrative Code
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Chapter 62-782 of the Florida Administrative Code
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Chapter 62-785 of the Florida Administrative Code
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The regulations of the United States Environmental Protection Agency as set forth in 40 C.F.R. Part 403, as of January 1, 2011, are hereby adopted and incorporated herein by reference hereto, with the exception of 40 C.F.R. § 403.6(c)(5), 40 C.F.R. § 403.8(f)(2)(v), and 40 C.F.R. § 403.12(e). The regulations of the United States Environmental Protection Agency set forth in 40 C.F.R. § 403.6(c)(5), 40 C.F.R. § 403.8(f)(2)(v), and 40 C.F.R. § 403.12(e) as published in 40 C.F.R. Part 403 as of July 1, 2005 are hereby adopted and incorporated herein by reference hereto.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
All rules and regulations promulgated by the State of Florida Department of Environmental Protection pursuant to provisions of Chapters 373, 403 and 253, Florida Statutes, as they may be amended from time to time, are hereby adopted and are made a part of this chapter by reference.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Any person who commits a violation of any rules and regulations adopted pursuant to this section shall be deemed guilty of committing a violation of this chapter. Violations of such rules and regulations shall constitute violations of this chapter triable in the court of appropriate jurisdiction.
Nothing herein shall be construed to prohibit Miami-Dade County from enacting ordinances stricter than the rules and regulations incorporated herein or to invalidate or supersede ordinances heretofore enacted by Miami-Dade County which are stricter than the rules and regulations incorporated herein. Notwithstanding the foregoing provision, nothing in Sections 24-42(2) and (4), 24-20(2), and 24-31(9) of this Code shall supersede Sections 24-25(1)(c), (f), (g), (h), and (i) with respect to cleanup target levels for contaminants found in groundwater, surface water, and soil for sites contaminated in whole or part with petroleum substances subject to Chapter 62-770, F.A.C., for sites contaminated in whole or in part with dry cleaning solvent substances subject to Chapter 62-782, F.A.C., and for sites governed in whole or in part by the terms of a brownfields site rehabilitation agreement pursuant to Chapter 62-785, F.A.C.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 11-91, § 1, 11-15-11)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-26. Brownfields Redevelopment Act; sections adopted</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Sections 376.77, 376.78, 376.79, 376.80, 376.81, 376.82 and 376.83(1), Florida Statutes, and any rules and regulations promulgated thereunder by the Florida Department of Environmental Protection, as all of the foregoing laws, rules, and regulations may be amended from time to time, are hereby adopted and made a part of this chapter by reference hereto.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Any person entitled to liability protection pursuant to Section 376.82, Florida Statutes, shall be relieved of further liability, to the same extent provided by Section 376.82, Florida Statutes, with respect to any enforcement action pursuant to Chapter 24 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Private Cause of Action for recovery of reasonable assessment or remediation costs pursuant to a Brownfields Site Rehabilitation Agreement.
<section prefix = "a">
A private cause of action is hereby created for any person who undertakes the assessment or remediation of a brownfields site pursuant to a Brownfields Site Rehabilitation Agreement authorized by Section 376.80, Florida Statutes, and Section 24-26 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. Said person may recover reasonable assessment or remediation costs or both. Nothing herein shall be construed to require the Director to bring any such action on behalf of a private person or entity other than Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The following persons, except for Miami-Dade County and any municipality in Miami-Dade County, shall be liable for all reasonable assessment and remediation costs incurred by any person at a brownfields site in accordance with a Brownfields Site Rehabilitation Agreement authorized by Section 376.80, Florida Statutes, and Section 24-26 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida and subject only to the defenses set forth in Sections 24-26(4):
<section prefix = "i">
The owner or operator of a brownfields site on the effective date of the Brownfields Site Rehabilitation Agreement;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Any person who, at the time of disposal of any hazardous substances or petroleum product, owned or operated a brownfields site at which such hazardous substance or petroleum product was disposed of;
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Any person who, by contract agreement, or otherwise, arranges for disposal or treatment, or arranges with a transporter for transportation or disposal or treatment, of a hazardous substance or petroleum product owned or possessed by such person or by any other party or entity at a brownfields site;
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
Any person who accepts or has accepted any hazardous substance or petroleum product for transportation or disposal or treatment at a brownfields site; or
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
Any person who has caused, let, suffered, permitted, or allowed to be caused, let, suffered, or permitted, any nuisance or sanitary nuisance at a brownfields site.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
In any private cause of action brought pursuant to this subsection to recover reasonable assessment or remediation costs or both, it shall not be necessary to plead and prove negligence. It shall only be necessary to plead and prove the existence of a Brownfields Site Rehabilitation Agreement, that a release or discharge of a hazardous substance or petroleum product has occurred at the brownfields site which is the subject of said Brownfields Site Rehabilitation Agreement, and that reasonable assessment or remediation costs, or both, have been incurred by the person filing the action in accordance with the Brownfields Site Rehabilitation Agreement. The only defenses to such a private cause of action shall be those specified in Sections 376.308, 376.3078, and 376.82(4), Florida Statutes.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
In any private cause of action brought pursuant to this subsection, the prevailing, party shall be entitled to recover reasonable attorney fees, expert witness fees and expenses, and costs.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
This subsection shall be liberally construed and shall be retroactively applied to protect the public health, safety, and welfare and to accomplish the purposes of this Section.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
For the purposes of this subsection the terms "disposal," "release," and "hazardous substance" shall have the same meaning as those terms are defined in the Comprehensive Response, Compensation, and Liability Act, 42 U.S.C. § 9601, et seq.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history>
</law>
