<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="3">ARTICLE II. EAST EVERGLADES</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="4">DIVISION_4._WETLANDS_DISCLOSURE</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 33B-51. Title</catch_line>
<text>
This division shall be known as the "East Everglades Wetlands Disclosure Law."
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33B-52. Purpose</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<history>In order to seek to ensure that the purchasers of land located in the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern are fully apprised of the character of the lands in the East Everglades, and in particular that such lands are subject to periodic flooding, it is necessary and appropriate that the seller of such lands disclose to all purchasers, or potential purchasers, the character of such lands prior to purchase or agreement to purchase. This division is adopted in order to seek to protect the potential purchasers of land from misrepresentations as to the suitability of land for residential use and is in furtherance of the goals and objectives of Article II, Divisions 1, 2 and 3. (Ord. No. 82-113, § 3, 12-21-82)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33B-53. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Interest in real property means a nonleasehold, legal or equitable estate in land or any severable part thereof created by deed, contract, mortgage, easement, covenant or other instrument.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Purchaser means a buyer, transferee, grantee, donee or other party acquiring an interest in real property.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Real property transaction means the sale, grant, conveyance, mortgage or transfer of an interest in real property.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern means that area legally described in Section 33B-13(a) of the Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, Florida, attached hereto as Exhibit A, but excluding those areas described in Section 33B-57
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 82-113, § 4, 12-21-82)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33B-54. Disclosure statement for land transactions in the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
All transactions involving the sale or transfer of real property or interest in real property located within the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern shall include in the documents of conveyance the following statement:
THE LAND WHICH IS THE SUBJECT OF THIS TRANSACTION IS LOCATED IN THE EAST EVERGLADES AREA OF CRITICAL ENVIRONMENTAL CONCERN. THE LAND IS SUBJECT TO PERIODIC, NATURAL FLOODING, WHICH POSES A SERIOUS RISK TO PERSONS AND PROPERTY IN THE AREA AND MAKES THE PROPERTY UNSUITABLE FOR RESIDENTIAL, COMMERCIAL, AND INDUSTRIAL DEVELOPMENT.
METROPOLITAN MIAMI-DADE COUNTY AND THE SOUTH FLORIDA WATER MANAGEMENT DISTRICT HAVE OFFICIALLY DETERMINED THAT FLOOD PROTECTION FOR THIS AREA WILL NOT BE PROVIDED WITH PUBLIC MONIES.
METROPOLITAN MIAMI-DADE COUNTY HAS ALSO DETERMINED THAT IT WILL NOT CONSTRUCT ANY NEW ROADS IN THE AREA OF CRITICAL ENVIRONMENTAL CONCERN AND WILL MAINTAIN ONLY THE FOLLOWING ROADS: SW 136 STREET FROM SW 187 AVENUE TO SW 209 AVENUE; SW 168 STREET FROM LEVEE L-31N TO SW 237 AVENUE; SW 237 AVENUE FROM SW 168 STREET TO SW 160 STREET; INGRAHAM HIGHWAY (FORMERLY SR 27).
I HEREBY CERTIFY THAT I HAVE READ AND UNDERSTAND THE FOREGOING STATEMENT.
<section prefix="1" type="table">
<table class="thead0 table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> _____</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> _____</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">   Signature</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">  Date</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 

</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The statement in subsection (a) of this section shall be set forth on a separate sheet of paper and shall be signed by the purchaser prior to the execution of any other instrument committing the purchaser to acquire said real property or to acquire any interest therein.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 82-113, § 5, 12-21-82)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33B-55. Acknowledgment of wetlands disclosure statement on instrument of conveyance</catch_line>
<text>
The following statement shall appear in a prominent location on the face of any instrument committing a purchaser to acquire real property or any interest therein in the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern:
I HEREBY CERTIFY THAT I HAVE READ AND SIGNED THE WETLANDS DISCLOSURE STATEMENT REQUIRED FOR THE SALE OF THIS PARCEL OF LAND.
<section prefix="2" type="table">
<table class="thead0 table" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0" width="100%" border="1" rules="all" style="text-align:left;"> 
 <colgroup class="std"> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
  <col width="50%" /> 
 </colgroup> 
 <tbody> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> _____</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class=""> _____</td> 
  </tr> 
  <tr> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">   Signature</td> 
   <td style="" valign="top" class="">  Date</td> 
  </tr> 
 </tbody> 
</table>
</section>
 


</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 33B-56. Failure to disclose</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
<history>Failure to substantially comply with the requirements of Sections 33B-54 and 33B-55 shall make the sale of the real property or interest therein voidable at the purchaser's option, for a period of seven (7) years from the date of the agreement. (Ord. No. 82-113, § 7, 12-21-82)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 33B-57. Exclusions to East Everglades Wetlands Disclosure Law</catch_line>
<text>
The provisions of the East Everglades Wetlands Disclosure Law do not apply to all of Sections 14, 21, 22, 23, 27, 28; the south half of Section 11 and the south half of the north half of Section 11; the east half of Section 15; the east half of Section 16; all land in Section 26 which lies northerly and westerly of Levee L-31-N; the east half of the east half of Section 29; all within Township 55 South, Range 38 East, Miami-Dade County, Florida; or to any other parcels of real property in the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern when the sale or transfer of the subject property is to the South Florida Water Management District.
</text>
<footnote>
FOOTNOTE(S):
--- (5) ---
Editor's note— At the editor's discretion, §§ 2—8 of Ord. No. 82-113, adopted Dec. 21, 1982, have been included as Div. 4, §§ 33B-51—33B-57 of Art. II, § 1, which incorporated the provisions of the preamble by reference, has not been included herein. (Back)

</footnote>
</law>
