<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="3">ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="4">DIVISION_1._GENERAL_PROVISIONS</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-1. Short title</catch_line>
<text>
This chapter enacted under and pursuant to the provisions of the Home Rule Charter of Government for Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall be known and may be cited as the "Miami-Dade County Environmental Protection Ordinance."
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-2. Declaration of legislative intent</catch_line>
<text>
The Board finds and determines that the reasonable control and regulation of activities which are causing or may cause pollution or contamination of air, water, soil and property is required for the protection and preservation of the public health, safety and welfare. It is the intent and purpose of this chapter to provide and maintain for the citizens and visitors of Miami-Dade County standards which will insure the purity of all waters consistent with public health and public enjoyment thereof, the propagation and protection of wildlife, birds, game, fish and other aquatic life, and atmospheric purity and freedom of the air from contaminants of synergistic agents injurious to human, plant or animal life, or property, or which unreasonably interfere with the comfortable enjoyment of life or property, or the conduct of business. The Board finds it necessary to establish, within the unincorporated and incorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, Countywide water control, coastal engineering, and coastal wetlands management programs for the purpose of maintaining adequate water levels, flood control, drainage, water conservation, and prevention of saltwater intrusion; for preserving beaches and shorelines; for managing coastal wetland resources; for acquisition of lands by gift, donation, purchase, condemnation or otherwise, as necessary for such programs; and providing for cooperation with federal, State and local agencies and authorities.
The Board further finds it necessary to maintain within Miami-Dade County a freshwater wetlands management program for the purposes of providing adequate water levels, flood control, water conservation, protection of water quality and recharge to the Biscayne Aquifer, and prevention of saltwater intrusion; for the maintenance of the biological integrity of freshwater wetlands in Miami-Dade County; for the protection of the interrelated natural functions between Miami-Dade County's wetlands and the natural systems in Everglades National Park; for managing freshwater wetland resources in accordance with environmental standards and management criteria as recommended by the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan and Chapter 33B of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, as amended from time to time; and providing for cooperation with federal, State, and local agencies and authorities.
The Board finds it necessary to establish for Miami-Dade County a Tree and Forest Resources Program for the purpose of protecting, preserving and replacing tree canopy, preserving natural forest communities including associated understory, providing protection for specimen-size trees and environmentally-sensitive tree resources, conserving rare, endangered, threatened and endemic species, protecting historically-significant tree resources, promoting the preservation of subtropical vegetation and unique or unusual species, providing for wildlife habitat, maintaining the natural character of neighborhoods, preserving the natural diversity of species, promoting environmentally-sound aesthetics, and providing for improved environmental quality by recognizing the numerous beneficial effects of trees (including improvements to air quality, maintenance of land areas essential to surface water management and aquifer recharge, reduction of heat and noise pollution, water and energy conservation and provision of shade and physical and psychological benefits to the people of Miami-Dade County by enhancing urban development). This program shall be a minimum standard and shall apply to both the incorporated and unincorporated areas, and in the unincorporated areas shall be enforced by the Department of Environmental Resources Management, and in the incorporated areas shall be enforced by the municipalities, unless the County is notified by a municipality, in the form of a letter from an official of the municipality or by resolution, that the municipality desires the County to enforce the Miami-Dade County Tree and Forest Program within the municipality. Any municipality may establish and enforce its own ordinance provided such ordinance is equivalent to or more stringent than the provisions of Ordinance Number 89-8.
The provisions of this chapter are not intended and shall not be construed as superseding or conflicting with any statutory provisions relating to, or rules and regulations promulgated by, the Florida State Department of Environmental Protection, but shall be construed as implementing and assisting the enforcement thereof. It is not the intent of this Board to hereby preempt the authority of any municipality in the exercise of its authority to issue coastal construction permits or to restrict it from adopting more stringent standards, the purpose of this chapter being to establish minimum standards for the issuance of coastal construction permits within all of Miami-Dade County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-3. Rules and regulations</catch_line>
<text>
The Board of County Commissioners shall adopt, revise, and amend from time to time appropriate rules and regulations reasonably necessary for the implementation and effective enforcement, administration and interpretation of the provisions of this chapter, and to provide for the effective and continuing control and regulation of air and water pollution in this County within the framework of this chapter. No such rules and regulations, including amendments thereto, shall be adopted or become effective until after a public hearing has been held by the Board of County Commissioners pursuant to notice published at least ten (10) days prior to the hearing. When adopted by the Board of County Commissioners and filed with the clerk, such rules and regulations shall have force and effect of law.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-4. Application of chapter and time for compliance</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
New facilities. On and after the effective date of this chapter, any person installing, constructing, or placing in operation for the first time any facility, equipment or process, the use of which will or may cause, or reasonably tend to cause, any air or water pollution as defined and controlled by this chapter, or who shall undertake the alterations, reconstruction or extension of existing facilities, equipment or processes in such a substantial manner as to materially increase the level or amount of air or water pollution, shall be subject to and required to comply with all the provisions of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Existing facilities. All facilities, equipment, plants and projects that are in actual use and operation on the effective date of this chapter shall have until and including January 1, 1968, to fully comply with and conform to the requirements of this chapter, provided that all existing facilities shall comply with, and shall not commit violations of, the following provisions of this chapter after January 1, 1964, namely: Section 24-5 (Nuisance); Section 24-42 (Toxic waste discharges); Section 24-41 (Black smoke emissions); Section 24-41.4 (Open burning); and Section 24-41.9 (Reduction of animal matter).
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Intent. It is intended that the provisions of this chapter shall be applicable to all new facilities and to any major or substantial addition, enlargement or extension of existing facilities; that existing facilities shall have until January 1, 1965, to comply with the specific sections of this chapter enumerated in subsection (2) hereinabove; and that existing facilities shall have until January 1, 1968, to comply with all other sections or provisions of this chapter (except those specifically designated in subsection (2) hereof), subject only to variances or extensions of time for compliance granted pursuant to the provisions of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Replacements. The replacement with identical or similar parts and minor changes that do not affect the character of the waste discharge or emission of air contaminants, or do not materially increase the existing amount of air or water pollution, shall not be considered as constituting the alteration, reconstruction or extension of an existing facility, but shall be considered as constituting an existing facility, for the purpose of this chapter.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-5. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
In construing the provisions of this chapter, where the context will permit and no definition is provided herein, the definitions provided in Chapter 403, Florida Statutes, as may be amended from time to time, and in rules and regulations promulgated thereunder, as may be amended from time to time, shall apply. The following words and phrases when used in this chapter shall have the meanings ascribed to them in this section:
1990 Urban Development Boundary shall mean the line established by the Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners on July 8, 1983 by Ordinance 83-58 delineating the approved urban development boundary for Miami-Dade County, as amended by ordinance from time to time.
Abandonment in place of an underground storage facility shall mean:
<section prefix = "1">
Installation and sampling of the monitoring wells and soil borings required for the TCAR, and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Emptying, inerting and cleaning the interior of the underground storage facility, and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Filling the underground storage facility with a non-shrinking, inert and solid material approved by the Department.

Aboveground storage facility shall mean a tank, pipe, vessel or other container, or any combination of the foregoing, used or designed to be used for the aboveground storage or aboveground transmission of hazardous materials including but not limited to line leak detectors, monitoring wells and secondary containment systems associated therewith.
<section prefix = "1">
Aboveground storage facilities have less than ten (10) percent of their total volume below the surface of the ground.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Facilities with ten (10) percent or more of their volume below the ground surface and which are contained within a vault or structure of sufficient size to allow human access and visual inspection of all components thereof are hereby determined to be aboveground storage facilities.

Adequate protection by natural means shall mean one (1) or more of the following processes of nature that produces water consistently meeting the requirements of the standards in this chapter: dilution, storage, sedimentation, sunlight, aeration, and the associated physical and biological processes which tend to accomplish natural purification in surface waters and, in the case of groundwaters, the natural purification of water by infiltration through soil and percolation through underlying material and storage below the ground water table, as may be approved by the Director.
Adequate protection by treatment shall mean complete or full treatment which is the combination of the controlled processes of coagulation, sedimentation, absorption, filtration, disinfection, or other processes which produce a water consistently meeting the potable water standards including processes which are appropriate to the quality of the raw water supply; works which are of adequate capacity to meet maximum demands without creating health hazards, and which are located, designed and constructed to eliminate or prevent pollution; and conscientious operation by well trained and competent personnel whose qualifications are commensurate with the responsibilities of the position and acceptable to the DERM.
Adequate transmission capacity shall mean that each pump station receiving sewage flow from the sewer service connection, the pump station immediately upstream from the pump station receiving sewage flow from the sewer service connection, and all pump stations through which sewage flow from the sewer service connection is transmitted to the wastewater treatment facility receiving such sewage flow, is operating (A) with fixed-speed pumps at a nominal daily average pump station operating time equal to or less than ten (10) hours per day, taking into account all existing sewage flow and loadings, including anticipated sewage flow resulting from all previously authorized sewer service connections or (B) with multiple-speed pumps at a nominal average power consumption that is equal to or less than forty-six (46) percent of the rated multiple-speed pump station motor horsepower or the equivalent thereof as approved by the Director or the Director's designee or (C) with variable-speed pumps at a nominal average power consumption that is equal to or less than a percentage of the rated variable-speed pump station motor horsepower as follows: (i) the percentage for all of the variable frequency driven pumps in the pump station shall be forty-nine (49) percent; (ii) the percentage for all of the magnetic-drive type variable speed pumps in the pump station shall be sixty-five (65) percent; and (iii) the percentage for all of the electrolyte rheostat or resistor bank type of variable speed drive pumps in the pump station shall be sixty-one (61) percent; or the equivalent of any of the foregoing, as applicable, as approved by the Director or the Director's designee, or (D) in such a manner that, upon completion of a rainfall-dependent peak flow management study approved by the Director or the Director's designee, the pump station is capable of managing peak flows (during a one (1) in two-year storm event as determined by the South Florida Water Management District) with a back-up pump out-of-service without causing or contributing to overflows in the collection and transmission system.
Adequate treatment capacity shall mean that the wastewater treatment plant which will receive flow from a sewer service connection shall not be in noncompliance as defined in 40 C.F.R. Part 123.45, Appendix A.
Adequate water depth shall mean the vertical extent of the water column above submerged bottom lands which is sufficient at all times to prevent any damage to the submerged bottom lands and to any natural resources in or upon the submerged bottom lands.
Adverse environmental impact shall mean any change in the physical or biological conditions of the natural environment within or adjacent to the area that results in a substantial detrimental effect upon flora, fauna, air, water, minerals or other natural characteristic(s) of the area.
Affected tree shall mean any tree which shall be, or already has been, removed, relocated, or effectively destroyed, thereby requiring a permit pursuant to Ordinance Number 89-8.
Agricultural fallowing period shall mean a period of inactivity, not to exceed five years, of a previously established, lawfully permitted agricultural operation prior to the resumption of an agricultural operation.
Agricultural operation shall mean the growing of crops, the raising of fowl, animals or bees, as a gainful occupation, but shall not include such activities engaged in as a hobby or truck farming in residential areas.
Agricultural site alteration shall mean preparation of a site for commercial or noncommercial horticultural or floricultural uses including, but not limited to: row crops, farms, groves, nurseries, horticultural farming, truck farming, barns, sheds or other structures not habitable by human beings which are used for the storage of farm machinery, fertilizer, seed or other items or equipment ancillary to an on-site agricultural use; and the maintenance and raising of animals for commercial purposes.
Agricultural vehicle or agricultural equipment maintenance facility shall mean a facility which repairs or maintains vehicles or equipment ancillary to and directly supportive of a bona fide agricultural purpose and which vehicle or equipment are owned or operated by the owner or leasee of the agricultural vehicle or agricultural equipment maintenance facility.
Air contaminants shall mean a particulate, gas or odor, including, but not limited to, smoke, charred paper, dust, soot, grime, carbon or any particulate matter, or irritating, malodorous or noxious acids, fumes or gases, or any combination thereof, but shall not include uncombined water vapor.
Air pollution shall mean the presence in the outdoor atmosphere of one (1) or more air contaminants or the combination thereof in such quantities and of such duration which are injurious to human, plant or animal life, or property, or which unreasonably interfere with the comfortable enjoyment of life or property, or the conduct of business.
Alter or altering a mangrove tree shall mean removing, poisoning, defoliating, or destroying a mangrove tree, either partially or entirely.
Ambient (natural) temperature shall mean the existing temperature of the receiving water at a location which is unaffected by man-made thermal discharges and a location which is also of a depth and exposure to winds and currents which typify the most environmentally stable portions of the receiving bodies of water.
Annular space shall mean the space between two (2) casings or between the outer casing and the wall of the well hole.
Approved recycling or recovery equipment shall mean any device designed to recapture or reuse ozone-depleting compounds which has the written approval of the Director or the Director's designee.
Asbestos shall mean a fibrous, rock-forming material, including, but not limited to, such amphibole varieties as tremilite, actinolite, anthophyllite, grunerite, richterite, edenite, amosite, crocilolite, and such serpentine varieties as amianthus and chrysotile, as well as synthetic asbestos fibers, including, but not limited to, fluor-tremilite, fluor-richterite, and fluor-edenite.
Association of primary and secondary wetland plant species shall mean an assemblage of primary and secondary wetland species within a defined area. In order for said assemblage to be classified as an association, it must be composed of at least twenty-five (25) percent primary wetland species.
Average day pumpage wellfield protection area shall mean the area within the cone of influence of a public utility potable water supply well based upon average day pumpage.
Average shall mean the arithmetic average of the results of at least three (3) separate samples collected within a referenced specific time period. At least one (1) of these samples shall be taken at peak flow conditions, where applicable, and a minimum of twenty-five (25) percent of the referenced time period shall serve as an interval between successive samples.
Back-up pump shall mean the highest capacity pump installed in a pump station.
Balanced system shall mean a gasoline or gasohol vapor recovery system that draws such vapor through a nozzle boot to an underground storage tank by means of the pressure differential created as the volume of gasoline or gasohol in the underground storage tank is reduced and the volume of gasoline or gasohol in the motor vehicle fuel tank is increased during motor vehicle refueling.
Basic wellfield protection area shall mean the area within two hundred ten (210) days travel time from a public utility potable water supply well based upon maximum day pumpage.
Basin B shall mean those lands within the following geographical boundary:
Section 13, 14, and 24, Township 52 South, Range 39 East, less those portions thereof lying southwesterly of the southwesterly right-of-way of Okeechobee Road, and
Sections 16, 17, 18 and 20, Township 52 South, Range 40 East, and
Section 19, Township 52 South, Range 40 East, less that portion thereof lying southwesterly of the northeasterly right-of-way of the Miami Canal and northwesterly of the northwesterly right-of-way of the Florida Turnpike, and
that portion of Section 21, Township 52 South, Range 40 East, lying westerly of the westerly right-of-way of Interstate I-75, and
Section 30, Township 52 South, Range 40 East, less that portion thereof lying northwesterly of the northwesterly right-of-way of the Florida Turnpike, and less those portions included within the right-of-way of the Miami River, and
Section 31, Township 52 South, Range 40 East, and
Sections 6, 7, 8, 17, 18 and 19, Township 53 South, Range 40 East, and
Section 30, Township 53 South, Range 40 East, less the southeast one quarter thereof.

All lying in Miami-Dade County, Florida.
Bird Drive Everglades Wetland Basin shall mean the wetlands described below:
That portion of Section 3, Township 54 South, Range 39 East lying south of U.S. Highway 41 (Tamiami Trail) and lying west of S.W. 143 Avenue north of S.W. 9th Terrace and lying west of S.W. 144 Avenue south of S.W. 9th Terrace; those portions of Sections 4, 5, and 6, Township 54 South, Range 39 East lying south of U.S. Highway 41 (Tamiami Trail); that portion of Section 10, Township 54 South, Range 39 East lying west of S.W. 144 Avenue; that portion of Section 31, Township 54 South, Range 39 East, lying north of S.W. 88th Street (North Kendall Drive); and Sections 7, 8, 9, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 29, 30, and 32, Township 54 South, Range 39 East.

Blackwater shall mean that portion of domestic sewage not emanating from residential showers, residential baths, residential bathroom washbasins, or residential clothes washing machines.
Boat docking facility shall mean a place where vessels may be secured to a fixed or floating structure or to the shoreline.
Boat slip shall mean a berthing space for a vessel which has been created or authorized pursuant to a permit or permits issued by the Department.
Boat storage facility shall mean a facility where recreational vessels are stored on uplands by one (1) or more of the following methods:
<section prefix = "1">
On boat trailers on a paved or unpaved surface; or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
On individual boat racks; or
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
On multi-story boat racks.

Bona fide agricultural purposes shall mean good faith commercial or domestic agricultural use of the land. In determining whether the use of the land for agricultural purposes is bona fide, the following factors as set forth in Section 193.461, Florida Statutes (and as amended from time to time), though nonexclusive, shall be taken into consideration:
<section prefix = "1">
The length of time the land has been so utilized;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Whether the use has been continuous;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The purchase price paid;
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Size, as it relates to specific agricultural use;
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Whether an indicated effort has been made to care sufficiently and adequately for the land in accordance with accepted commercial agricultural practices, including, without limitation, fertilizing, liming, tilling, mowing, reforesting, and other accepted agricultural practices;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Whether such land is under lease and, if so, the effective date, length, terms and conditions of the lease; and
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Such other factors as may from time to time become applicable.

Bona fide fruit grove shall mean a grove of fruit trees specifically planted to produce edible fruit for commercial purposes or for personal consumption by the owner.
Botanical garden shall mean any publicly-owned real property used for the cultivation of plants for display or scientific research.
C-9 Wetland Basin shall mean the wetlands within the following geographic boundaries:
Beginning at the intersection of U.S. Highway 27 (Okeechobee Road) and the south right-of-way of the C-9 Canal; thence run easterly to the west right-of-way of Interstate Highway 75; thence run southerly to the west right-of-way line of the Homestead Extension of Florida's Turnpike; thence run southwesterly and southerly to the north right-of-way of U.S. Highway 27 (Okeechobee Road); thence run northwesterly to the point of beginning.

Canopy coverage shall mean the areal extent of ground within the drip line of a tree.
Canopy shall mean those trees which constitute the tallest layer within a forest.
Casing shall mean the tubular material utilized to shut off or exclude a stratum or strata other than the source bed and conduct water from only the source bed to the surface.
Clean fill shall mean material consisting of soil, rock, sand, earth, marl, clay, stone and/or concrete rubble.
Closure shall mean cessation of operation of a County solid waste management system facility and the act of securing such a facility, in accordance with applicable regulatory requirements, so that it will pose no significant threat to human health or the environment. This includes closing, long term monitoring, maintenance and financial responsibility.
Coastal band community shall mean a mangrove community which borders Biscayne Bay or one (1) of the tributaries of Biscayne Bay and which receives frequent tidal inundation and whose dominant floral constituent is mature Rhizophora mangle. The boundary of a coastal band community shall not be limited or affected by artificial boundaries such as, but not limited to, property lines.
Coastal resources management line shall mean the landward extent of the areas where detrital cycles contribute to the ecological productivity of coastal waters.
Coastal waters shall mean all waters in the State which are not classified as fresh waters.
Coliform group shall include all organisms considered in the coliform group as set forth in Standard Methods for the Examination of Water and Waste Water, sixteenth edition.
Combustible refuse shall mean any combustible waste material containing carbon in a free or combined state.
Combustion contaminants shall mean particulate matter discharged into the atmosphere from the burning of any kind of material containing carbon in a free or combined state.
Commercial boat docking facility shall mean a boat docking facility which has boat slips, moorings, davit spaces, or vessel tieup spaces of which more than fifty (50) percent are designated for or contain commercial vessels.
Commercial vessel shall mean any vessel engaged in any activity wherein a consideration is paid by the user either directly or indirectly to the owner, operator or custodian of the vessel; or any vessel engaged in the taking of saltwater fish or saltwater products for sale either to the consumer, retail dealer or wholesale dealer.
Community water system shall mean a public water system which serves at least fifteen (15) service connections used by year-round residents or which regularly serves at least twenty-five (25) year-round residents.
Comprehensive environmental impact statement ("CEIS") shall mean a detailed report, based upon current data obtainable at the time of permit application submittal, which describes the proposed work and its purposes and which addresses one (1) or more of the following assessment points so as to permit assessment of the probable environmental impacts, benefits and detriments of the proposed work:
<section prefix = "1">
An analysis of the probable impact of the proposed work in the wetland environment, including impact on ecological systems such as floral, faunal, marine and freshwater communities. Both direct and indirect potential adverse environmental impacts shall be included in the analysis. The statement shall include the effect, if any, of the proposed work upon the ability of the wetland to:
<section prefix = "a">
Receive and store surface waters and to recharge groundwater.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Contribute to quantity and quality of the water supply and protect against saltwater intrusion.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Protect adjacent uplands from hurricane and tidal storm surges.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Provide filtration and uptake of nutrients and pollutants from surface waters.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Contribute sheet flow of surface waters to adjacent areas.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Provide habitat for indigenous floral and faunal species, and rare, threatened and endangered species, as defined in this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Provide protection for the recharge area of a wellfield.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
An analysis of other adverse environmental impacts which cannot be avoided should the proposal be implemented, such as water or air pollution, undesirable land use patterns, urban congestion, threats to health or other consequences adverse to the County's environmental goals, as set forth in this Code and the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
A description and analysis of alternatives to the proposed work which avoid or mitigate some or all of the probable adverse environmental impacts of the proposed work or which increase the beneficial environmental effects of the proposed work. An economic cost-benefit analysis may be submitted by the applicant for the proposed work and each such alternative.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
An analysis of the cumulative and long-term effects of the proposed work. The analysis shall compare the proposed work's short-term use of the environment with long-term environmental parameters including, but not limited to, biological productivity, habitat quality, protection of hydrological resources, and nutrient and pollution attenuation capacity.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
An analysis of all irreversible commitments of natural resources which would occur if the proposed work is implemented. This analysis shall include the extent to which the proposed work would curtail the range of beneficial uses of the environment.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
A summary of the problems and objections raised by any federal, State or local entities and by the public in the review process, the disposition of the issues involved, and the reasons therefor.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
A description and analysis of the socioeconomic benefits that may be derived from implementation of the proposed work as well as the potential negative impacts to the public resulting from denial of or modifications to the proposed work.

Condensed fumes shall mean minute solid particles generated by the condensation of vapors from solid matter volatilization from the molten state, or may be generated by chemical processes, operations or reactions, when these processes create air-borne particles.
Cone of influence means a localized depression or draw-down of the groundwater due to water supply well pumpage.
Construction and demolition debris shall mean solid waste comprised exclusively of materials which are not hazardous materials and which are not water soluble, including steel, concrete, glass, brick, soils not containing any hazardous materials, asphalt roofing and paving material, and lumber from a construction or demolition project.
Contaminant shall mean any substance present in any medium which may cause an adverse effect upon public health, public safety, public welfare or the environment, or causes a nuisance as defined in Section 24-5, Section 24-27 or Section 24-28.
Cooling pond shall mean a body of water enclosed by natural or constructed restraints which has been approved by the State of Florida Department of Environmental Protection for purposes of controlling heat dissipation from thermal discharges.
Cross-connection shall mean any physical connection or arrangement whereby contamination may enter a water supply system; such as two (2) otherwise separate piping systems, one (1) of which contains or is designed to contain potable water and the other waste water or other fluids or material of unknown or questionable safety, where intermixing may occur depending on the pressure or temperature differential between the two (2) systems.
CTLs shall mean Clean-up Target Levels as set forth in Section 24-44.
Cumulative adverse environmental impact shall mean adverse environmental impact, as defined in this chapter, resulting from a proliferation of a particular proposed work or land use within a wetland area.
Daily average pump station operating time shall mean the total of the number of operating hours for all nonvariable speed and non-multiple-speed pumps in the pump station for the month divided by the number of days in the month which is then divided by the total number of the same type of pumps in the pump station less one (1) pump of the same type, or the equivalent thereof as approved by the Director or the Director's designee.
Davit space shall mean an area along a bulkhead or pier where a vessel may be suspended over tidal waters by a mechanical device.
Department shall mean the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management.
Detention of stormwater shall mean the collection and temporary storage of stormwater in a manner that will provide treatment through physical, chemical or biological processes, with subsequent gradual release of the stormwater in a manner not to exceed the design limitations of the temporary storage area.
Detention pond shall mean an open basin which intercepts the groundwater table and is used for the temporary storage of stormwater runoff.
Developed land shall mean land upon which structures or facilities have been constructed.
Developed property shall mean any parcel of land which contains an impervious area.
Development shall mean any proposed activity or material change in the use or character of land, including, but not limited to, the placement of any structure, utility, fill, or site improvement on land, and any act which requires a building permit.
Dewater shall mean to discharge off-site or on-site water from an excavation, underground structure, or depressed land.
Diameter breast height (DBH) shall mean the diameter of a tree's trunk measured at a point four and one-half (4½) feet from where the tree emerges from the ground at natural grade. In the case of multiple-trunked trees, the DBH shall mean the sum of each trunk's diameter measured at the point four and one-half (4½) feet from where the tree emerges from the ground at natural grade.
Director shall mean the Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management, with duties created pursuant to Section 24-6 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
Dissolved hydrocarbon shall mean any substance soluble in fluorocarbon-113 and dispersed, emulsified, or otherwise dissolved throughout a sample.
Domestic sewage shall mean waste water from toilets, showers, sinks, baths, and other facilities designed for human sanitation whether located within residential or nonresidential land uses.
Dominance shall mean the species or group of species having the largest total number of individuals in the canopy and/or understory within a defined area.
Dominant plant community shall mean a minimum of fifty-one (51) percent of the plant cover within an area based on the following formula: Dominance equals one hundred (100) multiplied by the total estimated basal area of wetland plant species divided by the total estimated basal area of all plant species.
Drainage area shall mean a geographically defined land surface having topographical features such that stormwater runoff will be directed towards a drainage structure or natural waterway.
Drainage well shall mean any excavation that is drilled, cored, bored, washed, driven, dug, jetted or otherwise constructed when the intended use of such excavation is for the artificial recharge of groundwater, or the intentional introduction of water into any underground formation.
Dredging shall mean the removal of soil (i.e., rock, clay, peat, sand, marl, sediments or other naturally occurring soil material) from the surface of submerged or unsubmerged coastal or freshwater wetlands, tidal waters or submerged bay-bottom lands. Dredging shall include, but not be limited to, the removal of soils by use of clamshells, suction lines, draglines, dredges or backhoes.
Drip line shall mean an imaginary vertical line extending from the outermost horizontal circumference of a tree's branches to the ground.
Dry exfiltration shall mean an underground stormwater disposal system where the invert of a perforated conveyance pipe is placed at or above the average October groundwater level as set forth in the Miami-Dade County Public Works Manual, Part II, Section D4, dated September 1, 1974, as may be amended from time to time.
Dry infiltration or dry retention shall mean the process which occurs when stormwater is conveyed to a grassed swale or open basin for disposal into the ground where the bottom of the grassed swale or open basin is at least one (1.0) foot above the average October groundwater level as set forth in the Miami-Dade County Public Works Manual, Part II, Section D4, dated September 1, 1974, as may be amended from time to time.
Dry storage space shall mean a designated place where a recreational vessel is stored on uplands by one (1) of the following methods:
<section prefix = "1">
On a boat trailer on a paved or unpaved surface; or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
On an individual boat rack; or
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
On a multi-story boat rack.

Dust shall mean minute solid particles released into the air by natural forces or by mechanical processes such as crushing, grinding, milling, drilling, demolishing, shoveling, conveying, covering, bagging, sweeping, etc.
Dwelling shall mean any building which is wholly or partly used or intended to be used for living, sleeping, cooking and eating.
Dwelling unit shall mean any room or group of rooms located within a dwelling and forming a single habitable unit with facilities used or intended to be used for living, sleeping, cooking and eating. This term shall include, for the purposes of this ordinance, rooming units.
East Turnpike Wetland Basin shall mean the wetlands described below:
Those portions of Sections 18 and 19, Township 52 South, Range 40 East, lying east of the Homestead Extension of Florida's Turnpike; and Sections 6, 7, 8, 17 and 18, Township 53 South, Range 40 East, Miami-Dade County, Florida.

Effectively destroy shall mean the girdling, or damaging of a tree's trunk, branch or root system or cutting, pruning or trimming not done in accordance with the most recent American National Standards (ANSI) A-300 Standard Practices for Tree Care Operations.
Emission shall mean the act of passing into the atmosphere an air contaminant or gas stream which contains or may contain an air contaminant; or the material so passed to the atmosphere.
Engineering control shall mean a process or structure which eliminates or reduces the migration of contaminants or eliminates or reduces the exposure of human and environmental receptors to contaminants.
Environment shall mean the complex of climatic, edaphic and biotic factors that act upon an organism or an ecological community and ultimately determine its form and survival and which will be affected by the proposed work.
Environmental remediation shall mean clean-up of, or mitigation for, air, soil or water contamination from the County solid waste management system and those facilities for which the County is legally responsible for environmental clean-up or mitigation.
Environmentally-sensitive tree resources shall mean a specimen tree, natural forest community, or any other tree or trees that substantially contribute(s) to the aesthetics of an area, and which are not exempted from permit requirements under Section 24-49(4)(f).
Equivalent residential unit (sometimes hereinafter referred to as "ERU") shall mean the statistically estimated average horizontal impervious area of residential developed property per dwelling unit. This estimated average is calculated by dividing the total estimated impervious area of four (4) residential categories, to wit, single family, mobile home, multifamily and condominium, by the estimated total number of residential dwelling units. For the purposes of this ordinance each dwelling unit, to wit, single family residence, mobile home, multifamily, or condominium, is assigned one (1) ERU.
Excavation shall mean the action or process of creating any lake, rockmining (excluding ancillary property uses necessary for extracting and processing subsurface materials), reservoir, pond or other surface water.
Exfiltration of stormwater shall mean the process by which stormwater flows out of a trench or a buried perforated pipe into the surrounding ground.
Existing heat source shall mean any thermal discharge:
<section prefix = "1">
Which is presently taking place, or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
For which a construction or operating permit has been issued prior to the effective date of these rules.

Facility shall mean anything that is built or purchased to make an action or operation easier or to serve a special purpose.
Feasible distance for public water mains shall mean the distance between the closest point of the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public water main is not excessive as determined by the Director or the Director's designee in accordance with the following:
<section prefix = "1">
Residential uses. If the distance between the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public water main is less than the distance derived by dividing the sum of the existing and proposed gross floor area by a factor of twelve (12) square feet per linear foot of public water main, extension of public water mains to serve the property is required, or
Notwithstanding the above, if the nearest available point of connection to an available public water main is located within two hundred (200) feet of the closest point of the property, extension of public water mains to serve the property is required.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Office building uses. If the distance between the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public water main is less than the distance derived by dividing the sum of the existing and proposed gross floor area by a factor of ten (10) square feet per linear foot of public water main, extension of public water mains to serve the property is required, or
Notwithstanding the above, if the nearest available point of connection to an available public water main is located within four hundred (400) feet of the closest point of the property, extension of public water mains to serve the property is required.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Business district uses. If the distance between the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public water main is less than the distance derived by dividing the sum of the existing and proposed gross floor area by a factor of ten (10) square feet per linear foot of public water main, extension of public water mains to serve the property is required, or
Notwithstanding the above, if the nearest available point of connection to an available public water main is located within six hundred (600) feet of the closest point of the property, extension of public water mains to serve the property is required.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Industrial uses. If the distance between the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public water main is less than the distance derived by dividing the sum of the existing and proposed gross floor area by a factor of ten (10) square feet per linear foot of public water main, extension of public water mains to serve the property is required, or
Notwithstanding the above, if the nearest available point of connection to an available public water main is located within seven hundred fifty (750) feet of the closest point of the property, extension of public water mains to serve the property is required.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
In determining whether or not the distance between the closest point of the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public water main is excessive, the Director or the Director's designee shall follow the principles set forth below:
<section prefix = "a">
The nearest available point of connection to an available public water main shall be determined by the Director or the Director's designee in accordance with good engineering practices.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Notwithstanding any of the provisions of this definition, additions, modifications, or remodelings of existing improvements on the property shall not require extension of public water mains to serve the property from the nearest available point of connection to an available public water main, if the gross floor area of the new construction and new improvements is less than twenty-five (25) percent of the existing gross floor area.

Feasible distance for public sanitary sewers shall mean that distance between the closest point of the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer is not excessive as determined by the Director or the Director's designee in accordance with the following:
<section prefix = "1">
Residential uses.
<section prefix = "a">
Development requiring gravity sewer line extensions: If the distance between the closest point of the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer is less than that distance derived by dividing the sum of the existing and proposed gross floor area by a factor of twenty (20) square feet of gross floor area per linear foot of public sanitary sewer, extension of public sanitary sewers to serve the property is required, or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Development requiring the installation of a sanitary sewer lift station for eleven (11) residential units or more: If the distance between the closest point of the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer is less than that distance derived by subtracting one thousand (1,000) linear feet of public sanitary sewer from that distance derived by dividing the sum of the existing and proposed gross floor area by a factor of seventeen (17) square feet of gross floor area per linear foot of public sanitary sewer, extension of public sanitary sewers to serve the property is required, or
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Notwithstanding subsections (1)(a) or (1)(b) above, if the nearest available point of connection to an available public gravity sanitary sewer is located within one hundred (100) feet of the closest point of the property, extension of public sanitary sewers to serve the property is required.
<section prefix = "2">
Office building uses.
<section prefix = "a">
If the distance between the closest point of the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer is less than that distance derived by dividing the sum of the existing and proposed gross floor area by a factor of fifteen (15) square feet gross floor area per linear foot of public sanitary sewer, extension of public sanitary sewers to serve the property is required, or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Notwithstanding subsection (2)(a) above, if the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer is located within three hundred (300) feet of the closest point of the property, extension of public sanitary sewers to serve the property is required.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Business district uses.
<section prefix = "a">
If the distance between the closest point of the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer is less than that distance derived by dividing the sum of the existing and proposed gross floor area by a factor of fifteen (15) square feet gross floor area per linear foot of public sanitary sewer, extension of public sanitary sewers to serve the property is required, or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Notwithstanding subsection (3)(a) above, if the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer is located within five hundred (500) feet of the closest point of the property, extension of public sanitary sewers to serve the property is required.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Industrial uses.
<section prefix = "a">
If the distance between the closest point of the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer is less than that distance derived by dividing the sum of the existing and proposed gross floor area by a factor of fifteen (15) square feet gross floor area per linear foot of public sanitary sewer, extension of public sanitary sewers to serve the property is required, or
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Notwithstanding subsection (4)(a) above, if the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer is located within seven hundred (700) feet of the closest point of the property, extension of public sanitary sewers to serve the property is required.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
In determining whether or not the distance between the closest point of the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer is excessive, the Director or the Director's designee shall follow the principles set forth below:
The nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer shall be determined by the Director or the Director's designee in accordance with good engineering practices.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Notwithstanding any of the provisions of this definition, additions, modifications, or remodelings of existing improvements on the property shall not require extension of public sanitary sewers to serve the property from the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer, if the gross floor area of the new construction and new improvements is less than twenty-five (25) percent of the existing gross floor area.

Filling shall mean the alteration of wetlands, tidal waters or bay-bottom lands, by adding material or soil to obtain higher elevations or better compaction of existing elevations.
Firebreak shall mean an area of bare ground no more than ten (10) feet in width in a forest which has been created to prevent the spreading of wild fires.
First inch of retention shall mean the disposal by on-site retention of the volume of stormwater generated by the first inch of runoff from a defined drainage area.
First inch of runoff shall mean the volume of stormwater runoff generated during the initial stages of a rainfall event and is calculated as the volume of stormwater runoff generated during the time required to supply and transport to the emergency overflow outfall, one (1) inch of stormwater runoff from the farthest point in the basin, as set forth in "DESIGN OF DRAINAGE STRUCTURE, AN UPDATED POLICY FOR THE DESIGN OF STORM RUNOFF DRAINAGE STRUCTURES, DECEMBER 1980," a document prepared by and on file in the offices of the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management.
Fixed structure shall mean anything of a permanent or temporary nature which is built, constructed, placed or installed in, on, over or upon tidal waters. Fixed structures shall not include vessels or floating structures.
Floating hydrocarbon shall mean any substance soluble in fluorocarbon-113 as set forth in EPA Method 413.1 and floating or otherwise forming a visible layer upon any aqueous surface.
Floating structure shall mean a barge-like entity, with or without accommodations, which is not used as a means of transportation on water but which serves purposes or provides services typically associated with a structure upon or improvements to real property. A floating structure includes, but is not limited to, a residence, place of business, office, hotel, motel, restaurant, lounge, retail or wholesale store, clubhouse, helicopter pad, meeting facility, or a storage or parking facility. Incidental movement or the capability of movement upon water shall not preclude an entity from classification as a floating structure. Registration of the entity as a vessel in accordance with Chapter 327, Florida Statutes, shall not preclude an entity from classification as a floating structure.
Flooding shall mean the accumulation of stormwater on the ground surface which occurs as a result of excessive rainfall precipitation which has saturated the soil and filled the canals, lakes, ditches and drainage structures beyond their storage and transmission capacities.
Florida No. 1 grade or equivalent shall mean the classification of the quality of a nursery plant as published in Grades and Standards for Nursery Plants, Part II, Florida Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, Division of Plant Industry.
Flue shall mean any duct or passage for air, gases, or airborne materials, such as a stack or chimney.
Forest management plan shall mean a document which specifies the techniques that will be implemented to maintain and preserve an individual natural forest community.
Free chlorine shall mean chlorine existing in water as hypochlorous acid, hypochlorite ions, and molecular chlorine.
Free product shall mean any non-aqueous liquid.
French drain shall mean a structure consisting of a perforated, slotted or open joint pipe buried in a trench and surrounded by ballast rock and used for the underground disposal of stormwater runoff into groundwater or the unsaturated zone.
Fresh waters shall mean all waters of the state which are contained in lakes and ponds, or are in flowing streams above the zone in which tidal actions influence the salinity of the water and where the concentration of chloride ions is normally less than five hundred (500) milligrams per liter.
Fully loaded vessel shall mean:
<section prefix = "1">
All of the vessel's fuel tanks, water tanks and other tanks are full, and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The vessel has the maximum allowable number of crew, passengers, equipment and provisions pursuant to the manufacturer's specifications and, where applicable, the United States Coast Guard certification, and
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The vessel has all safety and rescue equipment required pursuant to state, federal and, if applicable, international law, and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
The vessel contains the maximum authorized amount (by weight) of cargo pursuant to state, federal and, if applicable, international law.

Garbage shall mean every refuse accumulation of animal, fruit or vegetable matter that attends the preparation, use, cooking and dealing in, or storage of edibles, and any other matter, of any nature whatsoever, which is subject to decay, putrefaction and the generation of noxious or offensive gases or odors, or which, during or after decay, may serve as breeding or feeding material for flies or other germ-carrying insects.
Gas shall mean a formless fluid which occupies space and which can be changed to a liquid or solid state only by increasing pressure with decreased or controlled temperature, or by decreased temperature with increased or controlled pressure.
Grassed swale shall mean a depression on the ground surface which is covered by vegetation and is located entirely within the unsaturated zone.
Gravity injection means the introduction of water into a well from which the water enters the groundwater without any force other than the force of gravity. Said well shall be in excess of two (2) feet below the average yearly highest groundwater elevation as specified in the Miami-Dade County Public Works Manual as same may be amended from time to time.
Graywater shall mean that portion of domestic sewage emanating from residential showers, residential baths, residential bathroom washbasins, or residential clothes washing machines.
Ground cover shall mean plants, other than turf grass, normally reaching an average maximum height of not more than twenty-four (24) inches at maturity.
Ground pollution shall mean the introduction into or upon any ground of any organic or inorganic matter or deleterious substances in such quantities, proportions or accumulations which are injurious to human, plant, animal, fish and other aquatic life, or property, or which unreasonably interfere with the comfortable enjoyment of life or property, or the conduct of business. It shall be a rebuttable presumption that the introduction of any hazardous waste as defined in Section 24-5 or hazardous materials as defined in Section 24-5 into or upon the ground, which exceeds any of the clean-up target levels (CTLs) set forth in Section 24-44, shall constitute and shall be deemed to be ground pollution.
Halophytic vegetation shall mean the following species:
Aizoaceae (carpetweed family)—Sesuvium portulacastrum (sea purslane)
Amaranthaceae (amaranth family)—Philoxerus vermicularis (marsh samphire)
Amaryllidaceae (amaryllis family)—Hymenocallis latifolia (spider lily)
Apocynaceae (oleander family)—Rhabdadenia biflora (mangrove rubber vine)
Asteraceae (aster family)—Aster tenuifolius var. aphyllus (salt-marsh aster)
Baccharis angustifolia (false willow)
Baccharis halimifolia (groundsel tree)
Borrichia arborescens (oxeye daisy)
Borrichia frutescens (oxeye daisy)
Iva frutescens (marsh elder)
Avicenniaceae (black mangrove family—Avicennia germinans (black mangrove)
Batidaceae (saltwort family)—Batis maritima (saltwort)
Chenopodiaceae (goosefoot family)—Salicornia virginica (perennial glasswort)
Salicornia bigelovii (annual glasswort)
Suaeda linearis (sea blite)
Salsola kali (saltwort)
Combretaceae (white mangrove family)—Conocarpus erecta (buttonwood)
Laguncularia racemosa (white mangrove)
Cymodoceaceae (manatee grass family)—Halodule wrightii (Cuban shoal weed)
Syringodium filiforme (manatee grass)
Cyperaceae (sedge family)—Cyperus odoratus (sedge)
Cyperus ligularis (sedge)
Cyperus planifolius (sedge)
Fimbristylis castanea
Fimbristylis spathacea
Hydrocharitaceae (frog's bit family)—Thalassia testudinum (turtle grass)
Juncaceae (rush family)
Juncus roemerianus (rush)
Juncaginaceae (arrow grass family)—Triglochin striata
Plumbaginaceae (leadwort family)—Limonium carolinianum var. carolinianum (sea lavender)
Limonium carolinianum var. angustatum (sea lavender)
Poaceae (grass family)—Distichlis spicata (seashore salt grass)
Monanthochloe littoralis (Key grass)
Paspalum vaginatum (salt joint grass)
Spartina alterniflora (smooth cord grass)
Spartina patens (salt-meadow cord grass)
Spartina spartinae (gulf cord grass)
Sporobolus virginicus (Virginia dropseed)
Primulaceae (primrose family)—Samolus ebracteatus (water pimpernel)
Pteridaceae (bracken family)—Acrostichum aureum (coastal leather fern)
Rhizophoraceae (red mangrove family)—Rhizophora mangle (red mangrove)
Ruppiaceae (widgeon grass family)—Ruppia maritima (widgeon grass)
Solanaceae (nightshade family)—Lycium carolinanum (Christmasberry)
Surianaccac (bay-cedar family)—Suriana maritima (bay cedar)

Harmful obstruction or undesirable alteration of the natural flow of surface water shall mean any substantial diversion, obstruction, creation of backwater conditions, interruption, adverse change in velocity, volume, or depth of the natural flow of surface water. Natural flow need not be uniform or uninterrupted and may be seasonal or periodic.
Hazard index shall mean the sum of more than one (1) hazard quotient for multiple contaminants or for multiple exposure pathways.
Hazard quotient shall mean the ratio of a single contaminant exposure level over a specified time period to a reference dose for that contaminant derived from a similar exposure period.
Hazardous materials shall mean any waste, product, substance, or combination or breakdown product thereof which, because of its biological or chemical characteristics, if introduced into a potable public water supply well, will impair the potability of the water withdrawn by the potable public water supply well or which will be harmful or potentially harmful to human, plant or animal life or property or the conduct of business or which will increase the cost of operation of public water supply treatment facilities or which will increase the reliance by consumers of potable water from such potable public water supply wells on the operation of public water supply treatment facilities to provide potable water which is not harmful or potentially harmful to human, plant or animal life or property or the conduct of business.
Within ninety (90) days from the effective date of Ord. No. 83-96 and at least annually thereafter, the Director or the Director's designee shall submit to the Board of County Commissioners a list of wastes, products, substances or combination or breakdown products thereof which the Director or the Director's designee has determined to be hazardous materials as hereinabove defined. The Board of County Commissioners shall designate, by resolution, which of the wastes, products, substances or combination or breakdown products thereof so listed by the Director or the Director's designee shall be legally presumed to be hazardous materials as defined hereinabove. Such designation by the Board of County Commissioners shall create a rebuttable presumption that the wastes, products, substances or combination or breakdown products thereof so designated are hazardous materials as hereinabove defined. Such designations shall be deemed nonexclusive. Nondesignation by the Board of County Commissioners shall not create any presumption that the nondesignated wastes, products, substances or combination or breakdown products thereof are not hazardous materials. Nothing herein shall be construed to limit in any way the power of the Director or the Director's designee in the performance of his duties and responsibilities to determine that a waste, product, substance or combination or breakdown product thereof is a hazardous material as defined hereinabove.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
Hazardous waste shall mean:
<section prefix = "1">
A waste defined as a hazardous waste in 40 C.F.R. Part 261, or
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Used radiator fluid,
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Used lubricating oil,
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Used transmission fluid,
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Used brake fluid, or
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Used power steering fluid.

Health care facilities shall mean hospitals, skilled nursing facilities, clinics, intermediate care facilities, ambulatory surgical centers, health maintenance organizations, doctor's offices, dentist's offices or free standing hemodialysis centers.
Health hazards shall mean any conditions, devices, or practices in a water supply system or its operation which create a possible danger to the health and well-being of the water consumer. (An example of a health hazard is a structural defect in the water supply system, whether of location, design or construction, which may regularly or occasionally prevent satisfactory purification of water supply or cause it to be polluted from extraneous sources.)
Heated-water discharges shall mean the effluents from commercial or industrial activities or processes in which water is used for the purpose of transporting waste heat.
Highway shall mean any public thoroughfare, including streets, designed for motor vehicles.
Impervious area shall mean a division of the horizontal ground surface which is incapable of being penetrated by rainwater. This shall include, but not be limited to, all structures, roof extensions, slabs, patios, porches, driveways, sidewalks, parking areas, swimming pools, athletic courts, and decks.
Individual water supply shall mean a well or wells or other source of water, and pump and piping if any, located on the premises served for supplying twenty-five (25) persons or less.
Industrial liquid waste facility shall mean any facility engaged in the manufacture, production, fabrication, packaging, repackaging, repair, processing or sale of goods or services, and which produces or generates or may reasonably be expected to produce or generate liquid waste.
Industrial waste shall mean discharges, effluents, spills, or leaks of any hazardous wastes, hazardous materials, process wastewater, or wastes other than domestic sewage, from an industrial liquid waste facility.
Infiltration means the distribution of water on the surface of land to permit the water to soak through the vegetation and soil into the groundwater.
Infiltration of stormwater shall mean the process by which stormwater flows vertically downward through the ground into the Biscayne Aquifer.
Inflow shall mean any water, other than domestic sewage or other wastewater approved by the Director or the Director's designee to be discharged into a sanitary sewer system, introduced into any publicly or privately owned or operated gravity sanitary sewer or pump station wet well which is not sewer system infiltration.
Institutional control shall mean a restriction on the use of, or access to, a site to eliminate or minimize exposure to contaminants. Examples include, but are not limited to, deed restrictions, restrictive covenants, or conservation easements.
Interim sewage treatment plant shall mean any sewage treatment plant, public or private, including but not limited to interim package sewage treatment plants, that discharges its effluent directly into the Biscayne Aquifer or inland surface waters of Miami-Dade County.
Intermediate care facilities shall mean day care centers, day nurseries, convalescent homes, adult congregate living facilities, rooming houses, boarding homes, homes for the elderly, homes for dependent children or retirement villages or any other facility providing shelter and supervision for dependent individuals who because of their mental or physical condition require health related care and services above the level of room and board.
Key manhole shall mean the sanitary sewer manhole into which the entire sewage flow from a sewer subsystem is discharged.
Landclearing shall mean the removal of vegetation or soils from submerged or unsubmerged wetlands. Landclearing shall not mean the removal of the following undesirable exotic vegetation: Melaleuca, Australian pine, or Brazilian pepper trees.
Landscape replacement plan shall mean a drawing containing proposed tree removal, tree replacement planting, tree relocation and preservation areas.
Liquid waste generator shall mean any person or entity whose act or process produces liquid waste, or who by the nature of its operations uses materials in a process which would subsequently require disposal as a liquid waste as defined in this chapter.
Liquid waste shall mean sludge resulting from, but not limited to, a waste treatment works, air pollution control facility, domestic, commercial, mining, institutional, agricultural, or governmental operations; or other waste materials, including materials to be recycled or otherwise beneficially reused; or septic tank, grease trap, sediment trap, portable toilet, or oil and grease separator pump-outs; or solvents, sewage, industrial waste, hazardous waste, semisolid waste, or potentially infectious waste; or any similar materials which would cause a nuisance or would otherwise cause a violation of this chapter if discharged to the ground or waters of Miami-Dade County. However, sewage and industrial wastes which have been permitted by the Department to be discharged and which are discharged through a lateral connection to the sewerage system or on-site treatment facility are not included in this definition. Furthermore, subsurface materials extracted as a result of rock mining which are not discharged to canals or other water bodies are not included in this definition.
Liquid waste transporter shall mean any person or entity which carries, conveys, bears or transports any liquid waste in any moving vehicle including but not limited to a car, truck, tank car, railroad car or other vehicle.
Loading facility shall mean a gasoline, gasohol or petroleum distillates storage and distribution facility with an average daily throughput (calculated over a thirty-day period) equal to or greater than twenty thousand (20,000) gallons of gasoline, gasohol or petroleum distillates.
Local agencies shall mean any county or municipal government or agency thereof.
Mangrove tree shall mean any of the following species, regardless of size, including mangrove trees as small as rooted seedlings: Avicennia germinans (black mangrove), Rhizophora mangle (red mangrove), Laguncularia racemosa (white mangrove). Notwithstanding the foregoing, mangrove tree shall not include seedlings smaller than 3—5 leaf stage rooted seedlings.
Maximum contaminant level shall mean the maximum permissible level of a contaminant in water which is delivered to any user of a public water system.
Maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area shall mean the area within the cone of influence of a public utility potable water supply well based upon maximum day pumpage.
Metal recycling facility shall mean a facility using equipment to crush, shred, cut or otherwise process ferrous scrap metal into prepared ferrous scrap for resale or reuse. For the purpose of this definition, facilities limited to dealing in non-ferrous metals are not included.
Miami-Dade County Nursery Report shall mean a monthly, published bulletin listing availability of trees, prices of trees, and stock of many major nurseries in Miami-Dade County which is prepared by the Florida Nurserymen and Grower Association.
Minimum flow shall mean the rate of sewage flow, expressed in gallons per day per inch diameter per mile, measured at a pump station wet well or a key manhole of a sewer subsystem from 1:00 a.m. to 5:00 a.m. or at such other time when the rate of sewage flow transmitted through the pump station or key manhole is at the lowest rate during any one (1) twenty-four-hour period exclusive of known or estimated sewage flows from commercial and industrial sources of wastewater.
Mist shall mean a suspension of any finely divided liquid in any gas.
Mobile home shall mean the same term as defined by Section 320.01(2), Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time.
Monitoring well or test well shall mean a well constructed with a surface seal and a sand filter pack in accordance with accepted technical design practices to provide for the collection of representative groundwater samples for laboratory analyses. Such wells may also be used to detect the presence of free product or collect water-level elevation data to aid in determining the direction of groundwater flow.
Mooring shall mean a temporary or permanent piling or floating device anchored in tidal waters for the purpose of securing a vessel.
Motor vehicle fuel delivery vessel shall mean a tank truck or trailer equipped with a storage tank used for the transportation of gasoline or gasohol from sources of supply to stationary storage tanks at motor vehicle fuel service stations.
Motor vehicle fuel service station shall mean any location which has underground storage facilities or aboveground storage facilities or both and which location has a total storage capacity of gasoline or gasohol of ten thousand (10,000) gallons or more, or which dispenses ten thousand (10,000) gallons or more per month of gasoline or gasohol to motor vehicle fuel tanks from such location.
Motor vehicle shall mean any car, truck, bus or other self-propelled wheeled conveyance that does not run on rails.
Multiple and variable-speed daily average pump station operating time shall mean the equivalent of the daily average pump station operating time, computed as follows: The average daily kilowatt-hours of consumption of all pumps of the same type in a pump station divided by the average daily kilowatt criteria in kilowatt hours multiplied by ten (10). The average daily kilowatt criteria in kilowatt hours ("A") is computed as follows: A = M × 24 hrs. × .746 KW/HP multiplied by P/100 where M is the Maximum Station HP. The applicable pump control factor ("P") is expressed as a percentage in parts (B) and (C) of the definition of adequate transmission capacity in this chapter. M is computed as follows: The rated horsepower of each pump at high speed multiplied by the number of pumps of the same type in the pump station less one (1) pump of the same type having the greatest rated horsepower, or the equivalent thereof as approved by the Director or the Director's designee.
Multiple-chamber incinerator shall mean any article, machine, equipment, contrivance, structure or part of a structure, used to dispose of combustible refuse by burning, consisting of three (3) or more refractory-lined combustion chambers in a series, physically separated by refractory walls, interconnected by gas passage ports or ducts and employing adequate design parameters necessary for maximum combustion of the material to be burned.
The refractories shall have a pyrometric cone equivalent of at least seventeen (17), tested according to the method described in the American Society for Testing [and] Materials, Method C-24.
Native plant species shall mean a plant species with a geographic distribution indigenous to all or part of Miami-Dade County. Plants which are described as being native to Miami-Dade County in botanical manuals such as, but not limited to, "A Flora of Tropical Florida" by Long and Lakela and "The Biology of Trees Native to Tropical Florida" by P.B. Tomlinson, are native plant species within the meaning of this definition. Plant species which have been introduced into Miami-Dade County by man are not native plant species.
Natural attenuation shall mean a method of site rehabilitation action which allows natural processes to contain the spread of contaminants and to reduce the concentration of contaminants in groundwater and soil. Natural attenuation processes include, but are not limited to, diffusion and dispersion in conjunction with the following: sorption, biodegradation, chemical reactions, or volatilization.
Natural forest community shall mean all stands of trees (including their associated understory) which were designated as Natural Forest Communities on the Miami-Dade County Natural Forest Community Maps and approved by the Board of County Commissioners, pursuant to Resolution No. R-1764-84. These maps may be revised from time to time by resolution in order to reflect current conditions and to insure that, at a minimum, the canopy and understory of designated natural forest communities are dominated by native plant species, as defined herein. The Department shall evaluate the following additional factors when reviewing existing and proposed natural forest community sites:
<section prefix = "1">
The presence of endangered, threatened, rare or endemic species included on the Federal List of Endangered and Threatened Species, the Florida Game and Fresh Water Fish Commission List of Endangered and Potentially Endangered Fauna and Flora in Florida, or the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan List of Endangered, Threatened, Rare and Endemic Plants in Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Overall plant species diversity of the site.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Size of the trees.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Size of the site.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Wildlife habitat value of the site.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Geological features of the site.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Percentage of the site covered by exotic (non-native) species.

Within one hundred twenty (120) days of the effective date of Ordinance Number 89-8, the Department shall develop a quantitative evaluation form incorporating the above factors to be used in evaluating natural forest community sites, and shall include a minimum quantitative threshold standard for inclusion on the revised natural forest community maps. Said evaluation form may be revised from time to time as appropriate, and shall be reviewed and approved by the Tree and Forest Resources Committee prior to its utilization.
Upon completion of the review of the existing natural forest community maps, the Director shall recommend to the Board of County Commissioners that only those sites which meet the minimum quantitative threshold standard established in the above-described evaluation form be maintained on the list and that all other sites be deleted. This shall not preclude the further addition of sites to the maps. The Director shall also recommend to the Board of County Commissioners that all applicable boundary changes be made to all remaining sites.
Natural grade shall mean the ground elevation of a property prior to the placement of any fill on the site.
Naturally occurring background concentrations shall mean concentrations of contaminants which are naturally occurring in the groundwater, surface water, soil or sediment in the vicinity of a site.
Nominal average power consumption shall mean the total power consumption for the month of all of the pumps of the same type in the pump station divided by the number of days in the month and which is then divided by the total number of the same type of pumps in the pump station less one (1) of the same type of pumps, or the equivalent thereof as approved by the Director or the Director's designee, which is then averaged with the same computations performed for the previous eleven (11) months.
Nominal daily average pump station operating time shall mean the total of the number of operating hours for all nonvariable speed and non-multiple-speed pumps in the pump station for the month divided by the number of days in the month and which is then divided by the total number of nonvariable speed and non-multiple speed pumps in the pump station less one (1) of the same type of pumps, or the equivalent thereof as approved by the Director or the Director's designee, which is then averaged with the same computations performed for the previous eleven (11) months.
Nonresidential development property shall mean any parcel of land which contains an impervious area and which is classified by the Miami-Dade County Property Appraiser as land use types 10 through and including 49 and 70 through and including 99 as set forth in the Florida Administrative Code Rule 12D-8.008(2)(c), as same may be amended from time to time.
Nonstructural controls of stormwater shall mean any activity designed to reduce pollutant loading of stormwater including, but not limited to, pollution prevention management policies and public education programs.
Nonviable shall mean not capable of existing and continuing to provide the biological or aesthetic qualities associated with a healthy, functioning tree resource.
North Trail Basin shall mean a basin located in western Miami-Dade County comprising the following lands:
Sections 33, 34, 35 and 36, Township 53 South, Range 39 East and, Government Lots 1, 2, 3 and 4, Townships 53-54 South and, those portions of Sections 1, 2, 3 and 4, Township 54 South, Range 39 East, which lie north of the north right-of-way line of the Tamiami Canal.

North Trail Wetland Basin shall mean the wetlands described below:
That portion of Section 3, Township 54 South, Range 39 East, lying north of U.S. Highway 41 (Tamiami Trail); that portion of Section 4, Township 54 South, Range 39 East, lying north of U.S. Highway 41 (Tamiami Trail); Government Lot 2, located between Townships 53 and 54 South, Range 39 East; Government Lot 3, located between Townships 53 and 54 South, Range 39 East and Government Lot 4, located between Townships 53 and 54 South, Range 39 East, Miami-Dade County, Florida.

Nuisance shall mean and include the use of any property, facilities, equipment, processes, products or compounds, or the commission of any acts or any work that causes or materially contributes to:
<section prefix = "1">
The emission into the outdoor air of dust, fume, gas, mist, odor, smoke or vapor, or any combination thereof, of a character and in a quantity as to be detectable by a considerable number of persons or the public so as to interfere with their health, repose or safety, or cause severe annoyance or discomfort, or which tends to lessen normal food and water intake, or produces irritation of the upper respiratory tract, or produces symptoms of nausea, or is offensive or objectionable to normal persons because of inherent chemical or physical properties, or causes injury or damage to real property, personal property or human, animal or plant life of any kind, or which interferes with normal conduct of business, or is detrimental or harmful to the health, comfort, living conditions, welfare and safety of the inhabitants of this County.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The discharge into any of the waters of this County of any organic or inorganic matter or deleterious substance or chemical compounds, or any effluent containing the foregoing, in such quantities, proportions or accumulations so as to interfere with the health, repose or safety of any considerable number of persons or the public, or to cause severe annoyance or discomfort, or which tends to lessen normal food and water intake, or produces symptoms of nausea, or is offensive or objectionable to normal persons because of inherent chemical or physical properties, or causes injury or damage to real property, personal property, human, plant or animal life of any kind, or which interferes with normal conduct of business, or is detrimental or harmful to the health, comfort, living conditions, welfare and safety of the inhabitants of this County.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Any violation of provisions of this chapter which becomes detrimental to health or threatens danger to the safety of persons or property, or gives offense to, is injurious to, or endangers the public health and welfare, or prevents the reasonable and comfortable use and enjoyment of property by any considerable number of the public.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Adverse environmental impact to a coastal or freshwater wetlands.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Cumulative adverse environmental impact to a coastal or freshwater wetlands.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Adverse environmental impact to environmentally-sensitive tree resources.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Cumulative adverse environmental impact to environmentally-sensitive tree resources.

Odor shall mean that property of a substance which materially offends the sense of smell.
Oil-effluent water separator shall mean any tank, box, sump or other container in which any petroleum or product thereof, floating on or entrained or contained in water entering such tank, box, sump or other container, is physically separated and removed from such water prior to outfall, drainage, or recovery of such water.
On-site domestic well system shall mean any water supply system using a well and piping to provide potable water for human consumption.
On-site shall mean within the boundaries of a facility location, property or site including those sites spatially separated by public or private rights-of-way.
On-site retention shall mean the containment and disposal of stormwater runoff by means other than positive drainage within the limits of the project site.
Open outdoor fire shall mean any combustion of combustible material of any type outdoors, in the open, not in any approved enclosure or device, where the products of combustion are not directed through a flue.
Out of service shall mean an underground storage facility which is empty, does not have hazardous materials transferred into or withdrawn from the underground storage facility, is not in active use and is in compliance with the requirements set forth in Chapter 62-761.800, Florida Administrative Code.
Outer wellfield protection zone shall mean the maximum extent of area protected by the wellfield protection provisions set forth in Chapter 24 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, for one wellfield or if a wellfield complex exists, the maximum extent of area protected by the wellfield protection provisions set forth in Chapter 24 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, as set forth in the wellfield protection maps adopted by the Board of County Commissioners.
Overflow outfall shall mean a drainage structure designed to discharge to an on-site or off-site location any excess stormwater runoff after an initial runoff volume has been retained on-site.
Overflow shall mean the discharge of sewage from any publicly or privately-owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system or wastewater treatment facility to the surface of the ground or to a surface water.
Overland sheet flow shall mean stormwater runoff flowing over an unrestricted ground surface area.
Owner-builder shall mean (an) owner(s) in fee who construct(s) no more than one (1) single-family or duplex residence per year for personal use and occupancy by said owner(s), and not intended for sale.
Ozone-depleting compound shall mean any of the substances identified in Section 602(a) and Section 602(b) of Title VI of the Clean Air Act Amendments of 1990 by the United States Environmental Protection Agency as contributing to the depletion or destruction of the stratospheric ozone layer of the Earth.
Particulate matter shall mean any material which at standard conditions, is emitted into the atmosphere in a finely divided form as liquid or solid or both, but shall not include uncombined water vapor.
Party or parties responsible for site rehabilitation actions shall mean the discharger or, if the discharger is unknown or the contamination was the result of a previously unreported discharge, the property owner or operator who is subject to the provisions of Section 24-44(2).
Permeability shall mean the ability of an aquifer, soil, rock or other geological formation to transmit water.
Person shall be construed to include any natural person, individual, public or private corporation, firm, association, joint venture, partnership, municipality, governmental agency, political subdivision, public officer or any other entity whatsoever, or any combination of such, jointly or severally.
Point of discharge (POD) for a heated-water discharge shall mean either that point at which the effluent physically leaves its carrying conduit (open or closed) and discharges into the waters of the State, or a specific point designated by the Florida Department of Environmental Protection for that particular thermal discharge.
Pollution prevention shall mean the use of materials processes, or practices that reduce or eliminate the creation of, or toxicity of, pollutants or wastes at the source.
Pollution shall mean the presence of any foreign substance (organic, inorganic, radiological, biological or thermal) in water which tends to degrade its quality so as to constitute a hazard or impair the usefulness of the water.
Positive drainage shall mean the direct disposal of stormwater runoff by overland sheet flow or through a channel ditch, or closed pipe system into an on-site or off-site surface water body such as, but not limited to, a lake, lagoon, river, canal, bay or the ocean.
Potable water shall mean water that is satisfactory for drinking, culinary and domestic purposes meeting the quality standards defined in this chapter.
ppm (vol.) shall mean parts per million by volume.
ppm (wt.) shall mean parts per million by weight and is equivalent to milligrams per liter.
Prepared ferrous scrap shall mean any scrap iron or steel which has been mechanically or otherwise processed into a raw material meeting any of the specifications contained in the Scrap Specifications Circular 1993, published by the Institute of Scrap Recycling Industries, Inc., Washington, D.C. Guidelines for Ferrous Scrap.
Prescribed burning shall mean the process of periodic deliberate burning of a pineland in a controlled manner taking into consideration weather and understory moisture conditions, for the purposes of maintaining the pineland in a natural condition and for the promotion of pine regeneration.
Preservation area shall mean portions of a site that are to be protected from any tree or understory removal (except as required by the Department) and maintained without any development.
Primary pump station shall mean any pump station in a publicly or privately owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system which directly receives sewage flow from gravity sanitary sewers.
Privately owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system shall mean any sanitary sewer collection and transmission facilities, including that located both on private property and within a public right-of-way or easement, which is owned or operated by any person other than Miami-Dade County, the state, the United States of America, or any municipality in Miami-Dade County.
Process weight per hour shall mean the total weight of all materials, except uncombined water, introduced into any unit process, which process may cause any discharge into the atmosphere. Solid fuels charged will be considered as part of the process weight, but liquid and gaseous fuels, combustion air, excess air, infiltrated and other air added to the process, will not be so considered. The process weight per hour will be derived by dividing the total process weight by the number of hours in one (1) complete operation from the beginning of any given process to the completion thereof, excluding any time during which the equipment is idle.
Protective barrier shall mean a temporary fence or other structure built to restrict passage into an area surrounding a tree or stand of trees for the purpose of preventing any disturbance to the roots, trunk or branches of the tree or trees.
Public water system shall mean plumbing for the provision to the public of water for human consumption, such plumbing has at least fifteen (15) service connections or regularly serves an averages of at least twenty-five (25) individuals daily at least three (3) months out of the year or serves at least five (5) individuals and is not a single-family residence or a duplex residence. Such term includes:
<section prefix = "1">
Any collection, treatment, storage and distribution facilities under control of the operator of such system and used primarily in connection with such system, and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Any collection or pretreatment storage facilities not under such control which are used primarily in connection with such system.

Public water main shall mean any water main in a public water system owned and operated by a public utility.
Publicly owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system shall mean any sanitary sewer collection and transmission facilities, including that portion of the sewage lateral connection located within a public right-of-way or easement, which is owned or operated by Miami-Dade County, the state, the United States of America, or any municipality in Miami-Dade County.
Publicly owned treatment works (POTW) shall mean any device or system that is used in the treatment (including recycling and reclamation) of sewage and that is owned by a state, county, or municipality. Sewers, pipes, or other conveyances are included only if they convey sewage to a POTW.
Rare, threatened and endangered species shall include all species classified as endangered, threatened or rare by Sections 581.185—581.187 and Chapter 372 of the Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time; or by Appendix A or B of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan for Miami-Dade County, Florida, as amended from time to time.
Rated multiple-speed pump station motor horsepower shall mean the sum of the rated horsepower for the same type of pumps in the pump station less the rated horsepower of the one (1) pump of the same type having the greatest rated horsepower, or the equivalent thereof as approved by the Director or the Director's designee.
Rated variable-speed pump station motor horsepower shall mean the sum of the rated horsepowers for the same type of pumps in the pump station less the rated horsepower of the one (1) pump of the same type having the greatest rated horsepower, or the equivalent thereof as approved by the Director or the Director's designee.
Recreational boat docking facility shall mean a boat docking facility which has boat slips, moorings, vessel tieup spaces, or davit spaces of which fifty (50) percent or more are designated for or contain recreational vessels.
Recreational vessel shall mean any vessel used by its owner or operator for noncommercial purposes.
Refrigerant shall mean any substance containing any ozone-depleting compound which is utilized in any refrigeration system.
Refrigeration system shall mean any refrigerator, freezer, chiller, cold storage warehouse, refrigeration unit, or any kind of air conditioner (mobile, portable, stationary, motor vehicle).
Relocated tree shall mean a tree which has been transplanted pursuant to Ordinance Number 89-8 and which continues to be viable at least one (1) year after transplanting.
Replacement tree shall mean a shade tree, small tree, or palm tree required to be planted pursuant to the provisions of Ordinance Number 89-8.
Residential developed property shall mean any parcel of land which contains an impervious area and which is classified by the Miami-Dade County Property Appraiser as land use types 00 through and including 09 and land use types 50 through and including 69 if said land use contains a single-family or multifamily residence, as set forth in Florida Administrative Code Rule 12D-8.008(2)(c), as same may be amended from time to time.
Resource recovery and management facility shall mean any facility the purpose of which is disposal, recycling, incineration, processing, storage, transfer, or treatment of solid or liquid waste; but for the purpose of permitting does not include sewage treatment, industrial waste treatment, or facilities exclusively within State or federal jurisdiction.
Retention pond shall mean an open basin which intercepts the groundwater table and is used for the storage and ultimate disposal of stormwater runoff by evaporation and seepage.
Right-of-way shall mean a strip of ground dedicated by the subdivider, or deeded by the owner, for public use.
Ringelmann Chart shall mean the method of estimating smoke density described in U.S. Bureau of Mines Information Circular 7718.
Risk Reduction shall mean the lowering or elimination of the level of risk posed to human health or the environment through interim remedial actions, remedial action, or institutional, and, if applicable, engineering controls.
Road shall mean any cleared, plowed, bulldozed, filled, graded, excavated or paved area, elevated boardwalk or roadway used or capable of being used for the passage of vehicles or persons. Roads shall not mean tracks used or capable of being used solely by off-road vehicles such as airboats, swamp buggies and all-terrain vehicles.
Rockmining shall mean the dredging or excavation of an area for the purpose of extracting subsurface materials. Rockmining shall also include ancillary property uses necessary for extracting and processing subsurface materials.
Rockplowing shall mean the alteration of wetlands by breaking up the limestone surface of a wetland in preparation for agriculture. Rockplowing may include the regrading of surface materials into planting beds at elevations sufficiently high to protect crops from flooding.
Rooming unit shall mean any room or group of rooms, forming a single habitable unit, used or intended to be used for living and sleeping but not for cooking or eating purposes.
Root ball shall mean a group of roots extending from the base of a tree trunk that must be intact when relocating a tree in order to promote survival of the tree.
Sanitary nuisance shall mean the commission of any action, by an individual, municipality, organization or corporation, or the keeping, maintaining, propagation, existence or permission of anything, by an individual, municipality, organization or corporation, by which the health or life of an individual or the health or life of individuals, may be threatened or impaired or by which or through which, directly or indirectly, disease may be caused.
Sanitary sewer shall mean a conduit which is a part of a gravity or pressurized force main system which receives and transports waste water for treatment and disposal.
Secondary containment system shall mean an impervious layer of materials which is installed so that any volume of hazardous materials which may be discharged from an underground storage facility will be prevented from contacting the environment outside said impervious layer for the period of time necessary to detect and recover all the discharged hazardous materials. Materials or devices used to provide a secondary containment system may include concrete, impervious liners, slurry walls, double-walled tanks, double-walled piping or other devices or materials approved by the Director or the Director's designee.
Seepage shall mean the introduction of water into a subsurface excavation from which the water enters the groundwater. Said excavation shall not exceed a depth of two (2) feet below the average yearly highest groundwater elevation described in the Miami-Dade County Public Works Manual as same may be amended from time to time.
Seepage trench or slab covered trench shall mean a trench cut into a rock strata supporting a reinforced concrete slab and providing the necessary wall and bottom areas required for exfiltration of stormwater.
Septic tank shall mean any settling tank in which the settled sludge is in immediate contact with sewage flowing through the tank thereby allowing the organic solids to be partially decomposed by putrefaction, i.e., anaerobic bacterial action.
Sewage lateral connection shall mean the pipe(s) which transmits wastewater from a building, residence or facility to a publicly or privately-owned or operated gravity sanitary sewer collection system.
Sewage loading shall mean the estimated average amount of waste water generated by the actual and projected use of a property as a function of the unsubmerged area of said property. Abutting easements and rights-of-way shall be included to the center lines thereof in calculating the unsubmerged area of the property.
Sewer service area shall mean that portion of a publicly or privately owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system which contributes sewage flow to a particular primary pump station.
Sewer subsystem shall mean a portion of a publicly or privately owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system which discharges sewage to a particular key manhole.
Sewer system infiltration shall mean the introduction of groundwater into any publicly or privately owned or operated gravity sanitary sewer or pump station wet well.
Shredder residue shall mean the predominantly non-metallic solid material including, without limitation, plastic, broken glass, rubber, foam rubber, soil and fabric, resulting from the shredding of ferrous metals such as, but not limited to, scrap automobiles and appliances.
Shrub shall mean a self-supporting woody perennial plant of low to medium height characterized by multiple stems and branches continuous from the base.
Site plan shall mean a drawing having a scale sufficient to provide the following information: Location of all proposed or existing buildings, septic tanks, utility easements, fences, walls, parking areas, driveways, access roads, setbacks, and any other site development.
Site rehabilitation action or SRA shall mean source removal, if applicable, site assessment and, if required, one or more of the following: risk assessment, monitoring or remediation. These site rehabilitation actions serve to characterize the nature and extent of contamination and to reduce the levels of contaminants through applicable treatment methods to comply with the clean-up target levels (CTLs) set forth in this chapter.
Small quantity generator of hazardous waste shall mean any person who brings into existence a quantity of fifty-five (55) gallons or less of hazardous waste during any one (1) period of three hundred sixty-five (365) consecutive days. However, within the average day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, Hialeah Wellfield and John E. Preston Wellfield, a small quantity generator of hazardous waste shall mean any person who brings into existence a quantity of fifty-five (55) gallons or less of hazardous waste during any one (1) period of one hundred twenty (120) consecutive days.
Smoke shall mean the solid particles produced by incomplete combustion or organic substances, including, but not limited to, particles, fly ash, cinders, tarry matter, soot and carbon.
Solid waste shall mean garbage, rubbish, refuse, trash, yard trash, construction and demolition debris, or other discarded material, including solids or contained gaseous material resulting from domestic, industrial, commercial, mining, agricultural, or governmental operations. However, subsurface materials which do not contain hazardous materials and which are extracted as a result of rockmining are not included in this definition.
Source bed shall mean the stratum or strata from which water is drawn in the well.
Source gas volume shall mean the volume, in standard cubic feet, of all gases leaving a source operation; and the boundary of a source operation is that point or surface at which the separation of the air contaminants from the process materials, or the conversion of the process materials into air contaminants, is essentially complete.
Source operation shall mean the last operation preceding the emission of an air contaminant, which operation:
<section prefix = "1">
Results in the separation of the air contaminant from the process material or in the conversion of the process materials and air contaminants, as in the case of combustion fuel; and
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Is not an air pollution abatement operation.

South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex shall mean the following wellfields: South Miami Heights, Roberta Hunter Park, Caribbean Park and Rockpit 77 Park wellfields.
Specimen tree shall mean a tree with any individual trunk which has a DBH of eighteen (18) inches or greater, provided, however, that the following trees are not specimen trees:
<section prefix = "1">
All trees listed in Section 24-49(4)(f).
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Non-native fruit trees that are cultivated or grown for the specific purpose of producing edible fruit, including, but not limited to, mangos, avocados, or species of citrus.
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Non-native species of the genus Ficus.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
All multitrunk trees in the palm family, except Acoelorrhaphe wrightii and Phoenix reclinata which have a minimum overall height of fifteen (15) feet.

SRA (see Site rehabilitation action)
Standard conditions shall mean a pressure of fourteen and seven-tenths (14.7) pounds per square inch, absolute, and a temperature of sixty (60) degrees Fahrenheit. Results of all analyses and tests shall be calculated or reported at this gas temperature and pressure.
Standard sample is taken to mean that for the bacteriological test it shall consist of:
<section prefix = "1">
For the bacteriological fermentation tube test, five (5) standard portions of either:
<section prefix = "a">
Ten milliliters (10 ml).
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
One hundred milliliters (100 ml).
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
For the membrane filter technique, not less than fifty milliliters (50 ml).

State of Florida Conservation and Recreation Lands Trust Fund shall mean a fund established under Florida Statutes Chapter 375 (as amended from time to time) for the purposes of purchasing environmentally-sensitive land.
State-approved plant nursery shall mean a business actively engaged in propagating, growing, maintaining and selling tree species that has been licensed to conduct such business by the State of Florida or Miami-Dade County.
Storm sewer shall mean any conduit which is designed to carry stormwater runoff.
Stormwater infrastructure shall mean the structural, nonstructural or natural features of a parcel of land or watershed which collect, convey, store, absorb, inhibit, treat, use, reuse, or otherwise affect the quantity or quality of stormwater.
Stormwater management area shall mean that portion of a tract of land which shall be left at natural grade (unfilled), filled to an elevation no less than four (4) inches above the seasonal high water table, or excavated below natural grade for the purposes of: managing water which results from rainfall, storing water in the Biscayne Aquifer and recharging the Biscayne Aquifer.
Stormwater management program shall mean the same term as defined by Section 403.031(14), Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time.
Stormwater management system shall mean the same term as defined by Section 403.031(15), Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time.
Stormwater runoff shall mean the excess rainfall precipitation which runs over the ground surface when the rate of rainfall precipitation exceeds the rate of infiltration of stormwater into the ground.
Stormwater shall mean the water which results from rainfall.
Stormwater utility shall mean the same term as defined by Section 403.031(16), Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time.
Structural controls of stormwater shall mean physical devices used to control stormwater including, but not limited to, levees, dikes, pump stations, spillways, locks, embankments, roadways, lakes, retention ponds, and detention ponds.
Substantial reduction in recharge of water to the Biscayne Aquifer shall mean a reduction in natural infiltration rates or reduction of volume of surface water from a defined area; or transportation of surface waters off-site to the extent that a site's natural hydrological regimen is changed.
Surcharged gravity sanitary sewer shall mean a condition during which a gravity sanitary sewer contains sewerage flows above the crown of the pipe.
Test well (see Monitoring well)
Top pruning shall mean the removal of any distal branches or limbs of a mangrove tree which will result in the reduction in the overall height of the mangrove tree.
Total hazardous organic materials (THOM) shall mean the sum of all quantifiable concentration values of organics presumed to be hazardous materials by the designation of the Board of County Commissioners pursuant to Section 24-5 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
Total metals shall mean the sum of the concentration of copper, nickel, total chromium, and zinc.
Total toxic organics (TTO) shall mean the sum of all quantifiable concentration values of those organics set forth in 40 CFR 413 and 40 CFR 433 of the Code of Federal Regulations, and Xylene.
Transitional Northeast Everglades shall mean the wetlands within the following geographic boundaries:
Beginning at a point on the north right-of-way line of theoretical N.W. 12th Street as it intersects the east side of the Miami-Dade-Broward levee, thence run northerly along the east side of the Miami-Dade-Broward levee for approximately 10 miles to its point of intersection with the eastern right-of-way line of the State Road 997 (Krome Avenue); thence, run northeasterly along the eastern right-of-way line of said State Road 997 (Krome Avenue); to its intersection with the west right-of-way line of U.S. Highway 27 (Okeechobee Road); thence run southeasterly along said west right-of-way line of U.S. Highway 27 (Okeechobee Road); to its intersection with the western right-of-way line of the Homestead Extension of Flordia's Turnpike; thence run southerly along said western right-of-way line of the Homestead Extension of Florida's Turnpike; for approximately 8 miles to theoretical N.W. 12th Street; thence run westerly along theoretical N.W. 12th Street to the point of beginning.
Beginning at a point on the south right-of-way line of U.S. Highway 41 as it intersects the west right-of-way line of State Road 997; thence run southerly along the west right-of-way line of State Road 997 for approximately 4 miles to the southeast corner of Section 25, Township 54 South, Range 38 East; thence run westerly for approximately 1 mile along the south section line of said Section 25 to its intersection with the east right-of-way line of Levee 31N; thence run northerly for approximately 4 miles along the east right-of-way line of Levee 31N to its intersection with the south right-of-way line of U.S. Highway 41; thence run easterly for approximately 1 mile to the point of beginning.

Transmissivity shall mean the rate at which groundwater is transmitted through a unit width of aquifer under a unit hydraulic gradient.
Trash shall mean solid waste comprised of yard trash or construction and demolition debris, and shall include but not be limited to paper, cardboard, cloth, glass, plastics, street sweepings, and vehicle tires.
Travel time shall mean the period of time in days or equivalent distance in feet for groundwater to travel from one (1) point in an aquifer to another point in the aquifer.
Tree island shall mean a vegetative community located within freshwater wetlands whose dominant vegetative components consist of native hardwood trees and shrubs.
Tree removal shall mean directly or indirectly cutting down, destroying, removing or relocating, or effectively destroying (through damaging, trimming, authorizing or allowing the cutting down, destroying, removing, moving or damaging of) any tree.
Tree shall mean a woody or fibrous perennial plant with a trunk having a minimum DBH of three (3) inches or with an overall height of twelve (12) or more feet. Tree shall not include any mangrove tree as defined in Section 24-5.
Tree survey shall mean a drawing overlaid directly upon the site plan sufficient to provide the following information:
<section prefix = "1">
The location, plotted by accurate techniques, in relation to all proposed development, of all existing trees which are proposed to be destroyed, relocated or preserved,
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The common and scientific name of each tree,
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The DBH of each tree, or if a multiple trunk tree, the sum DBH for all trunks, and
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
An estimate of the height of the canopy.

Tree well shall mean a soil retaining structure designed to maintain the existing natural ground elevation beneath a tree to preserve the tree when the surrounding area is filled to raise the ground elevation. Tree wells shall have a minimum radius of three (3) feet from the trunk of the tree and a maximum radius of ten (10) feet from the trunk of the tree.
Underground storage facility shall mean a tank, pipe, vessel or other container, or any combination of the foregoing, used or designed to be used for the underground storage or underground transmission of hazardous materials, including but not limited to line leak detectors, monitoring wells, continuous automatic leak detection systems and secondary containment system associated therewith, excluding hydraulic lift systems, excluding sanitary sewers, septic tanks, septic tank drainfields, the primary pipeline transmitting jet fuel from Port Everglades to Homestead Air Base, and any other primary pipeline transmitting hazardous materials from one (1) county to another county. Underground storage facilities have ten (10) percent or more of their total volume below the surface of the ground.
Understory shall mean the complex of woody, fibrous, herbaceous, and graminoid plant species that are typically associated with a natural forest community.
Unmaintained underground storage facility shall mean an underground storage facility which was not or is not properly closed or placed out of service in accordance with the rules and regulations of the State of Florida and Section 24-45(6) of this Code and for which there is neither a valid operating permit issued pursuant to Section 24-18(2) of this Code nor, a valid registration placard issued by the State of Florida Department of Environmental Protection.
Unsubmerged land shall mean any land which meets or exceeds the minimum elevation required by Miami-Dade County flood criteria.
Vacuum assist system shall mean a gasoline or gasohol vapor recovery system that uses a vacuum generating device to create a vacuum in the vapor return line from the nozzle boot to the underground storage tank during motor vehicle refueling.
Vapor shall mean any mixed material in a gaseous state which is deformed from a substance usually a liquid, by increased temperature.
Vessel shall mean a watercraft, boat, ship, yacht, barge, canoe, or kayak, used or capable of being used as a means of transportation on water. Vessel shall not mean a floating structure as defined in Section 24-5. Notwithstanding that the floating structure has previously been used as a means of transportation on water or is capable of being used as a means of transportation on water, vessel shall not mean a floating structure as defined in Section 24-5.
Vessel tieup space shall mean an area abutting a bulkhead or shoreline where a vessel may be secured.
Waste discharge shall mean any outfall, ditch, pipe, soakage pit, drainage well, drainfield, or any other method or device by which treated or untreated sewage, industrial waste, or other wastes can enter the surface waters, tidal salt water, or groundwaters, so as to cause water pollution as herein defined.
Water dependent use shall mean a use which cannot exist or occur without association with marine, freshwater or estuarine water masses.
Water pollution shall mean the introduction in, on or upon any surface water or ground water, or tidal water, of any organic or inorganic matter or deleterious substances in such quantities, proportions, accumulations or levels which exceed any of the clean-up target levels (CTLs) set forth in Section 24-44, or which are injurious to human, plant, animal, fish and other aquatic life, or property, or which unreasonably interfere with the comfortable enjoyment of life or property, or the conduct of business.
Water system shall mean a system which supplies water for drinking, culinary, fire, industrial, commercial, or domestic purposes.
Watershed shall mean the same term as defined by Section 403.031(17), Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time.
Wellfield complex shall mean two or more wellfields which: a.) provide raw water to the same water treatment facility or provide raw water to interconnected water treatment facilities for treatment of raw water from the same wellfield and, b.) which wellfields are within the same outer wellfield protection zone.
Wet retention shall mean the disposal of stormwater runoff to a storage basin having a bottom elevation lower than one (1) foot below the average October groundwater level as set forth in the Miami-Dade County Public Works Manual, Part II, Section D4, dated September 1, 1974, as may be amended from time to time.
Wetlands shall mean those areas as defined in Chapter 373, Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time.
Work shall mean any project, activity, or any artificial or man-made alteration of the environment, including, but not limited to, the construction or maintenance of roads; landclearing; trimming or cutting of a mangrove tree(s); dredging; filling; construction or placement of structures, floating structures, fixed structures, facilities or dwellings; excavations; or rockplowing.
Yard trash shall mean solid waste comprised of vegetative matter resulting from landscaping maintenance or land clearing operations and shall include, but not be limited to, Melaleuca, Australian pine, Brazilian pepper and other tree and shrub trimmings, grass clippings, palm fronds, trees and tree stumps, and soils not containing any hazardous materials.
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-6. Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management—Office created; appointment; term; exempt from classified service and merit system; compensation; assistants; operating procedures</catch_line>
<text>
The office and position of Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management, is hereby created and established. The Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management, shall be appointed by and serve at the will of the County Manager. Such Director shall be chosen by the Manager on the basis of his qualifications and experience in the field of air and water pollution controls, and the Director shall be a professional engineer registered to practice in the State of Florida under the provisions of Chapter 471, Florida Statutes, or he shall become registered within eighteen (18) months after the date of appointment, or he shall have at least a bachelor's degree from an accredited university in a field which will, in the Manager's judgment, technically qualify him to discharge the duties imposed by this chapter. The Office of Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management, shall constitute a position exempted from the classified service of Miami-Dade County and the State merit system. The salary for such position shall be fixed by the Board of County Commissioners. The Director shall serve under the administrative jurisdiction of the County Manager and subject to the direct supervision of the County Manager. The County Manager shall appoint such assistants to the Director as may be necessary in order that the duties of the Director may be performed properly. The organization and administrative operating procedures of such County office and its relationship and coordination with other County departments shall be established and placed in effect, from time to time, by administrative order of the County Manager, but the Manager shall not have any power to modify the duties imposed upon the Director by this chapter or the procedures prescribed herein for the performance of such duties.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-7. Same—Duties and powers</catch_line>
<text>
The duties, functions, powers and responsibilities of the Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management, shall include the following:
<section prefix = "1">
The enforcement of the provisions of this chapter and the rules and regulations promulgated hereunder, all rules and regulations of the Florida Department of Environmental Protection pertaining to air and water pollution and the Federal Pretreatment Standards, promulgated under the authority of Section 307 of the Federal Clean Water Act, as incorporated in this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Investigate complaints, study and observe air and water pollution conditions, institute actions necessary to abate nuisances caused by air and water pollution, and prosecute proceedings for violations of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Make appropriate surveys, tests and inspections to determine whether the provisions of this chapter are being complied with, and whether air and water pollution is being effectively controlled throughout this County.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Make inspections of property, facilities, equipment and processes operating under the provisions of this chapter to determine whether the provisions of this chapter are being complied with, and make recommendations for methods by which air and water pollution may be reduced or eliminated.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Maintain and review all operating records required to be filed by persons operating facilities and equipment subject to the provisions of this chapter and as required by 40 CFR 403.8 and 40 CFR 403.12, Federal Pretreatment Regulations.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Render all possible assistance and technical advice to persons operating equipment, facilities and processes, the use of which may cause air or water pollution, provided that the Director or the Director's designee shall not design equipment or facilities for any person.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Establish, operate and maintain a continuous program for monitoring air and water pollution by means of countywide air and water quality surveillance networks designed to provide accurate data and information as to whether the requirements of this chapter are being complied with and whether the level of air and water pollution is increasing or decreasing throughout this County.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Publish and disseminate information to the public concerning air and water pollution and recommended methods for decreasing and eliminating pollution. Additionally, publish annually a list of industrial users in significant noncompliance in accordance with the requirements of 40 CFR 403.8(f)(2)(vii), Federal Pretreatment Regulations.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Render assistance to the State of Florida Department of Environmental Protection in connection with the review of plans, specifications and processes filed in accordance with the requirements of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
Render all possible cooperation and assistance to federal, State and local agencies in the accomplishment of the effective control of air and water pollution.
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
Enlist and encourage public support, and the assistance of civic, technical, scientific and educational organizations, and the cooperation of industrial and business enterprises and organizations.
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Make periodic reports concerning the status of air and water pollution in this County and the enforcement of the provisions of this chapter, and recommendations concerning the improvement of pollution requirements. Such reports shall be filed with the County Manager and made available to the County Commission, the State of Florida Department of Environmental Protection, and other cognizant agencies.
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Make continuing studies and periodic reports and recommendations for the improvement of air and water pollution controls in the County, and work in cooperation with the State of Florida Department of Environmental Protection, the United States Public Health Service and other appropriate agencies and groups interested in the field of air and water pollution.
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
Investigate air and water pollution control programs and activities in operation in other areas and to make recommendations for the improvement of the regulation, administration and enforcement of pollution controls in this County. Publicize the importance of adequate pollution controls, to hold public hearings, discussions, forums and institutes, and arrange programs for the presentation of information by experts in the field of air and water pollution, and visit and study pollution control programs conducted in other metropolitan areas, subject to budget limitations.
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
<section prefix = "a">
Whenever evidence has been obtained or received establishing that a violation of this chapter has been committed, the Director or the Director's designee, shall issue a notice to correct the violation or a citation to cease the violation and cause the same to be served upon the violator by personal service or certified mail or by posting a copy in a conspicuous place on the premises of the facility causing the violation. Such notice or citation shall briefly set forth the general nature of the violation and specify a reasonable time within which the violation shall be rectified or stopped, commensurate with the circumstances. Reasonable time herein means the shortest practicable time to rectify or stop the violation. If notice to correct the violation or citation to cease the violation is not obeyed within the time set forth therein, the Director or the Director's designee, shall have the power and authority to issue an order requiring the violator to restrict, cease or suspend operation of the facility causing the violation until the violation is corrected. Any orders issued by the Director or the Director's designee, hereunder may be enforced by suit brought by the Director in the appropriate court of competent jurisdiction.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Whenever a violation of this chapter has been committed, the Director may initiate proceedings against the violator in the appropriate court for such violation, whether or not a notice to correct the violation or citation to cease the violation has been issued by the Director or the Director's designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The Director or the Director's designee, may, in the Director's or the Director's designee's discretion, terminate an investigation or an action commenced under the provisions of this chapter upon execution of a written consent agreement between the Director, or the Director's designee, and the persons who are the subjects of the investigation or action. The consent agreement shall provide written assurance of voluntary compliance with all the applicable provisions of this chapter by said persons. The consent agreement may, in the discretion of the Director, or the Director's designee, provide the following: environmental mitigation; compensatory damages; punitive damages; civil penalties; costs and expenses of the County in tracing the source of any discharge, in controlling and abating the source of the pollutants and the pollutants themselves, and in restoring the air, waters, ground and property, including animal, plant and aquatic life, of the County in accordance with the provisions of this chapter; costs of the County for investigation, enforcement, testing, monitoring, and litigation, including attorneys' fees; and remedial or corrective action. An executed written consent agreement shall neither be evidence of a prior violation of this chapter nor shall such agreement be deemed to impose any limitation upon any investigation or action by the Director, or the Director's designee, in the enforcement of this chapter. The consent agreement shall not constitute a waiver of or limitation upon the enforcement of any federal, State or local laws and ordinances. Executed written consent agreements are hereby deemed to be lawful orders of the Director, or the Director's designee. Each violation of any of the terms and conditions of an executed written consent agreement shall constitute a separate offense under this chapter by the person who executed the consent agreement, their respective officers, directors, agents, servants, employees and attorneys; and by those persons in active concert or participation with any of the foregoing persons and who receive actual notice of the consent agreement. Each day during any portion of which each such violation occurs constitutes a separate offense under this chapter. Decisions and actions of the Director or the Director's designee, pursuant to Section 24-7(15)(c) of this Code and written consent agreements executed thereunder, shall not be subject to review pursuant to Section 24-11 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
In the event a violation of this chapter creates a health hazard or threatens serious damage to the public health, aquatic life or property, or creates a nuisance as herein defined, the Director or the Director's designee shall have the power and authority to order immediate cessation of the operations causing such conditions. Any person receiving such an emergency order for cessation of operation shall immediately comply with the requirements thereof. It shall be unlawful for any person to fail or refuse to comply with an emergency order issued and served under the provisions of this section. Any person who is convicted of willfully failing or refusing to comply with such an emergency order shall be punished by a fine not exceeding five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for not more than sixty (60) days, or both, in the discretion of the appropriate court. Each day during which the willful failure or refusal to comply with such an emergency order continues shall constitute a separate offense.
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
In addition to and not limited by any other provision or remedy of this chapter, the Director shall have the power and authority to order a moratorium on the issuance of building permits by any County or municipal agency should it be determined:
<section prefix = "a">
That violations of this chapter have occurred or may be reasonably anticipated to occur, or that the physical limitations of the public or private water or sewage system have or will be met so as to endanger or threaten the public health, aquatic life or property or creates a nuisance; and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
That such a situation can reasonably be anticipated to deteriorate by the issuance of additional building permits that require added or new demands being made on the water or sewage system involved.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
Perform such other administrative duties as may be assigned by the County Manager.
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
To appoint with the approval of the County Manager, deputies who are hereby empowered to perform the duties of the Director, as provided by this chapter, subject to the Director's control.
</section>
<section prefix = "20">
Where necessary the Director and duly authorized deputies of the Director are hereby empowered to seek all search warrants reasonable and necessary to carry out their powers and duties as established by this chapter, in accordance with the requirements of the Constitutions of the United States and the State of Florida, the Laws of Florida, and in accordance with the procedures established by the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "21">
The powers and duties enumerated in this section shall be in addition to and not a limitation of any other power or duty specifically granted to the Director by any other provision of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "22">
Whenever this chapter specifies the need for approval, a determination, permits, review or the promulgation of standards or criteria by an undisclosed entity, said approval, review, permitting, or promulgation shall be the duty and responsibility of the Director, unless otherwise specifically provided, subject to the manner and mode of review set in Section 24-11 of the Code. Said approvals, determinations, decisions to permit, and the promulgation of standards and criteria shall be based upon generally accepted concepts and standards of the particular professional discipline concerned.
</section>
<section prefix = "23">
The Board of County Commissioners hereby authorizes the establishment of Countywide water control, coastal engineering and wetlands management programs, and vests in the Director the administration of said programs. A plat showing existing and proposed water-control facilities and their general locations is hereby adopted and made a part of this chapter, said plat being identified as amended plat of Miami-Dade County Water Control Plan recorded in August, 1972, in plat book 94, page 4. The amended water control plan may be further revised at any time by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners. Authority for administering said program includes, but is not limited to, the power to:
<section prefix = "a">
Establish, adopt, and implement water control, coastal engineering and wetlands management programs, as may be necessary or appropriate for prevention and control of floods, drainage, water conservation, prevention of saltwater encroachment, protection against pollution, safeguard of water supplies, protection of beaches, shorelines, and wetlands areas and the best use of all the water, shoreline and wetland resources of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Administer the processing of property right exchanges and advise the Board of County Commissioners on the acquisition by gift, donation, dedication, purchase, condemnation or otherwise of such lands as may be necessary for aforesaid purposes of water control, beach and wetlands management, all acquisitions to be in accord with such State and local laws as may be applicable.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Defray costs and expenses of said water control, coastal engineering and wetlands management programs, including, but not limited to, the costs of engineering, construction, operation, maintenance, lands, rights-of-way, alterations, cooperation with other agencies and authorities, all as authorized herein, subject to County budgetary procedures and limitations.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Determine, establish, and regulate water levels in all parts of Miami-Dade County, including, but not limited to, levels of bays, streams, canals, ditches, lakes, borrow ditches, and the underground water table, by dams with or without locks or boat lifts, by gates, levees, or other facilities; providing, however, that said authority and powers are not to encroach upon, be inconsistent with, and are in conjunction with the statutes, rules and regulations of appropriate State and federal agencies as they exist now and in the future.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Administer programs for the preservation of beaches and shorelines, including cooperative federal, State, and local programs and projects; establish standards and permitting procedures for the control of excavation in water areas, dredging and filling and performing work in all saltwater and wetland areas.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Cooperate with appropriate federal, State, municipal and other local agencies. Any action(s) taken by the Department shall be taken only after the affected municipality(ies) has been notified of the proposed action(s).
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
Make and adopt reasonable rules and regulations, subject to approval of the Board of County Commissioners by ordinance, for the administration of said water control, coastal engineering and wetlands management programs, all such rules and regulations (within declared policies, powers, and authorities granted by the Board of County Commissioners) having the force and effect of law and being enforceable under Section 24-29 of this Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
Require permits and set permit fees for connecting any private or public drain, ditch, canal, storm sewer, outfall, inlet, intake, outlet or irrigation pipe with, into, through, or across any ditch, canal, waterway, culvert or other water-control facility under the jurisdiction of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
Require permits and set permit fees for any type of public or private crossing over, under or within any ditch, canal, waterway, culvert or other such facility under the jurisdiction of Miami-Dade County, including, but not limited to, bridges, footbridges, culverts, earthfills, pipelines and other obstructions of any kind, such as fences, barricades, dams, and the like.
</section>
<section prefix = "j">
Require permits and set permit fees for excavating, filling and performing work in coastal areas and wetland areas of Miami-Dade County, including, but not limited to, beach and shoreline alteration, beach nourishment, and construction, installation, alteration or repairs of marinas, docks, piers, seawalls, fixed structures, or floating structures, and construction of roads, fill pads, rockplowing and rockmining within the incorporated or unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "k">
Provide for permits and fees for accomplishing, through contractors, land developers and others, the excavation of ditches, canals, and installation of water-control facilities, within the general limits of said programs of water control, coastal engineering and wetlands management.
</section>
<section prefix = "l">
Limit and control excavation or filling of wetlands, channels, ditches, canals, or lakes in wetlands by individuals, firms, corporations, miners, partnerships, joint ventures, estates, trusts, syndicates, fiduciaries, and all other associations and combinations whether public or private, including governmental agencies, to the extent necessary for the prevention of pollution or further saltwater encroachment and for the protection of water recharge areas and wetland and tidal habitats in Miami-Dade County.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "24">
To require and issue Florida Department of Environmental Protection and South Florida Water Management District permits as provided by law.
</section>
<section prefix = "25">
Require that a comprehensive environmental impact statement be submitted for any work or activity requiring a permit or permits issued by the Department or for any work or activity defined as a nuisance in Chapter 24 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, if, in the opinion of the Director, the work or activity may result in adverse environmental impact. The Director shall only require a comprehensive environmental impact statement if a comprehensive environmental impact statement, as defined in this chapter, has not already been submitted as part of a federal, State or regional permit application.
</section>
<section prefix = "26">
Order testing by any person who is or may be responsible for a violation of this chapter, or who installs, modifies, repairs, expands, replaces or operates any facility under the provisions of this chapter. The design and nature of such testing shall be approved by the Department prior to implementation of testing. Said testing shall be accomplished and the results thereof submitted to the Department for review no later than such time as determined by the Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "27">
When a violation of this chapter has occurred or continues to exist or when there may be an imminent endangerment to the public health or welfare or the environment because of a threatened release or discharge of a hazardous material, the Director or the Director's designee may:
<section prefix = "a">
Take action necessary to prevent such violation, and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Restore the air, water, and property, including but not limited to animal, plant, and aquatic life affected by said violation.
This provision shall not be construed to provide a defense to or otherwise relieve or limit the liability or responsibility of any person violating the provisions of this chapter. Furthermore, the Director may institute suit in a court of competent jurisdiction to recover the sums expended by the County for the investigation and the aforesaid restoration and prevention from the persons responsible. All sums received by the Director pursuant to this provision shall be deposited by the Director into the fund from which said sums were expended.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "28">
The Board of County Commissioners hereby authorizes the establishment of a Countywide Tree and Forest Resources Program, and vests in the Director the administration of said program. Authority for administering said program includes, but is not limited to, the power to:
<section prefix = "a">
Make and adopt reasonable rules and regulations subject to approval of the Board of County Commissioners by ordinance for the administration of said Tree and Forest Resources Program, all such rules and regulations (within declared policies, powers, and authorities granted by the Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners) having the force and effect of law and being enforceable under Section 24-29 with penalties and liabilities set forth under Sections 24-30 and 24-31 of this Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Require permits under the provisions of Section 24-49, and set permit fees for the removal of trees, and understory where applicable, in unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County and municipalities in which this chapter is enforced by the Department.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Limit and control the removal of trees and understory in unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County and municipalities in which Ordinance Number 89-8 is enforced by the Department under the provisions of Section 24-49 in order to preserve as many native trees and their understory and desirable non-native trees as possible.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
If the provisions of Section 24-49 or the provisions of a tree ordinance passed by a municipality are not adequately enforced by a municipality, or if the municipal ordinance does not meet the minimum standards of Ordinance Number 89-8, and it is the Department's intent to administer Section 24-49 in said municipality, then the Director shall notify the municipality by certified letter of the Department's intent and, following the municipality's receipt of the letter, the Department shall enforce Ordinance Number 89-8 within the municipality.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Require preparation and implementation of management plans for natural forest communities presently owned or managed by Miami-Dade County or those which are acquired by Miami-Dade County in the future. All said management plans shall be submitted to the Department for approval within two (2) years of the effective date of Ordinance Number 89-8 or within one (1) year after acquisition.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
Review the existing Miami-Dade County Natural Forest Community Maps and make recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners concerning the addition to or deletion of specific sites from said maps. Modify the boundaries of existing natural forest communities, as indicated on the aforementioned maps, when it is determined that the approved boundaries no longer accurately reflect the boundaries of a natural forest community as defined herein.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "29">
Enlist or encourage cooperation by the general public and public utilities owning or operating public water systems to implement voluntary water conservation measures for prevention of contamination of the Northwest Wellfield.
</section>
<section prefix = "30">
Order public utilities owning or operating public water systems to reduce public water system pressure for the purpose of conserving water to prevent contamination of the Northwest Wellfield.
</section>
<section prefix = "31">
Impose mandatory water conservation restrictions in the unincorporated and incorporated areas of Miami-Dade County to prevent contamination of the Northwest Wellfield.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-8. Environmental Quality Control Board</catch_line>
<text>
A Miami-Dade County Environmental Quality Control Board is hereby created and established, consisting of five (5) members appointed by the County Commission.
<section prefix = "1">
Qualifications of members. Members of the Board shall be residents of Miami-Dade County who possess outstanding reputations for civic pride, interest, integrity, responsibility and business or professional ability. Appointments shall be made by the Board of County Commissioners on the basis of experience or interest in the field of air and water pollution. The composition and representative membership of the Board shall be as follows:
<section prefix = "a">
Two (2) members shall be scientists possessing Ph.D. degrees in biology.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
One member shall be a scientist possessing a Ph.D. degree in biochemistry.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Two (2) members shall be professional engineers with experience in the field of sanitary engineering, who may be recommended by the Miami Chapter of the Florida Engineering Society.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Terms of office. In order that the terms of office of all members of the Board shall not expire at the same time, the initial appointments to the Board shall be as follows: Two (2) members shall be appointed for the term of one (1) year, two (2) members shall be appointed for the term of two (2) years, and one (1) member shall be appointed for the term of three (3) years. Thereafter all appointments shall be made for the term of three (3) years. Appointments to fill any vacancy on the Board shall be for the remainder of the unexpired term of office. A member may be removed with or without cause by the affirmative vote of not less than a majority of the entire County Commission. Should any member of the Board fail to attend three (3) consecutive meetings without due cause, the Chairman shall certify the same to the County Commission. Upon such certification, the member shall be deemed to have been removed and the County Commission shall fill the vacancy by appointment.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Organization of the Board; quorum; Secretary; compensation of members; meetings; personnel. The members of the Board shall elect a Chairperson and such other officers as may be deemed necessary or desirable, who shall serve at the will of the Board. A majority vote of the entire membership of the Board shall be necessary to take any action. Three (3) members of the Board shall constitute a quorum necessary to hold a meeting and take any action, except that the affirmative vote of four (4) members of the Board shall be required to grant variances and extensions of time for compliance with the requirements of this chapter for new or existing facilities, equipment, and processes or classes thereof, within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area. The Director shall be secretary of the Board and shall be responsible for the custody of all minutes and records of the Board, but shall not be entitled to vote on any matter before the Board. Members shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties, upon approval by the Board of County Commissioners. The Chairperson may call meetings of the Board, and the Board at any meeting may fix and call a meeting on a future date. Minutes shall be kept of all meetings of the Board. All meetings shall be public. The County Manager shall provide adequate and competent clerical administrative personnel as may be reasonably required by the Board for the proper performance of its duties, subject to budget limitations.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Technical advisory panel. The Board may designate from time to time one (1) or more citizens of the community to sit as one (1) or more technical advisory panels. The members of such panels shall be persons technically skilled and qualified to render advice on particular matters of pollution control then before the Board. The members shall serve at the will of the Board and shall furnish advice and information of a technical nature to the Board for so long a period of time as the Board may request it. All such advice and information given by the panel or any member thereof shall be in the form of testimony before the Board at a regularly scheduled meeting and subject to cross examination by any interested party. The members of the panels shall not be deemed County officers or employees within the purview of Sections 2-10.2, 2-11.1, or otherwise.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Duties and powers of the Environmental Quality Control Board. The Environmental Quality Control Board shall have the following duties, functions, powers and responsibilities:
<section prefix = "a">
To hear appeals by any person aggrieved by any action or decision of the Director as provided in Section 24-11
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
To hear and pass upon all applications for variances and extensions of time in the manner provided by Sections 24-13 and 24-14, except for compliance with Federal Pretreatment Regulations set forth in 40 CFR 403 as incorporated in this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
To hear and pass upon all applications for extension of time for compliance with the provisions of this chapter. All such applications shall be filed in accordance with the provisions of this chapter and shall be heard and considered by the Environmental Quality Control Board at a public hearing pursuant to notice. In considering such applications, the Board shall take into account such factors as practicability, availability of equipment, and relative benefits to the community. The Board shall not have the power and authority to grant any application for extension of time to comply with the prohibitions against open burning (Section 24-41.4), or the prohibitions against reduction of animal matter (Section 24-41.8), or the prohibitions against a nuisance (Section 24-27), or the prohibitions against the discharge of cyanides or other toxic chemicals into the waters in excess of the standards set forth in Section 24-42(3). Applications for extension of time for compliance shall be considered on the basis of public interest and not merely on economic benefit to the applicant; applications shall be granted only when it is established that the requested extension of time for compliance will not be detrimental to the public health, welfare and safety, and will not create or permit the continuation of a nuisance, or that no technically feasible, economically reasonable means of compliance are readily available to the applicant. The Board shall not have the power and authority to grant extensions of time for compliance with the Federal Pretreatment Regulations set forth in 40 CFR 403 as incorporated in this chapter. Any person aggrieved by any decision of the Environmental Quality Control Board shall be entitled to judicial review in accordance with the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
To hear and pass upon all applications pursuant to Section 24-15 for approval of interim package sewage treatment plants. In considering such applications the Board shall take into account such factors as the public interest, compliance with the technical requirements of this chapter, factors of practicability and availability of equipment, alternative methods of sewage disposal and the likelihood of creating a present or future nuisance. If the Board approves such application it shall direct the Director to issue the Director's approval subject to any reasonable conditions that the Board finds to be in the public interest. Provided, however, that no action on the application shall be taken by the Board until a public hearing has been held upon at least ten (10) days notice of the time and place of such hearing published in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
To provide additional notice to the public, property that may be affected by the application shall be posted in a manner as shall provide notice of the purpose, time and place of such hearing. Failure to post such property shall not affect any action taken by the Board. Provided, however, that the Board may, upon application of any city or any governmental water and sewer authority existing on the effective date of this subsection and chartered pursuant to State law, waive the requirement for a public hearing on interim package sewage treatment plant applications where such proposed plant is to be located within a city that requires by law a public hearing before granting approval of such a plant where such applications are considered under standards equal to or stricter than those provided by Chapter 24 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, as amended from time to time.
</section>
<section prefix = "f">
To hear and pass upon applications by private and/or public water or sewer utilities for a statement of approved water quality or approved sewage service filed pursuant to the requirements of Section 24-15 of the Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "g">
To issue subpoena to compel the presence of a witness or documents at any hearing authorized above, such subpoenas to be issued by the Chairman of the Board and enforced pursuant to the provisions of Section 24-9 of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "h">
To review decisions of the Miami-Dade County Fire Department or other Fire Department having jurisdiction, pursuant to Section 2-103.23 of the Code.
</section>
<section prefix = "i">
The powers enumerated in this section shall be an addition to and not a limitation of any other power specifically granted to the Environmental Quality Control Board by any other provision of this chapter.

</section>
</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-9. Contempt powers</catch_line>
<text>
The Board is empowered and authorized to hold any individual, corporation, or public utility which refuses to obey any legal order, mandate, decree or instruction issued by the Board during any proceeding before the Board, in contempt of the Board. The Board, through two-thirds of those members who are present, may fine any individual, corporation, or public utility which is in contempt of the Board a sum of up to one hundred dollars ($100.00) for each contemptuous act, payable to the Miami-Dade County Finance Director within fifteen (15) days of the Board's ruling.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-10. Issuance of stop orders; injunctions; standards of service</catch_line>
<text>
Whenever any public utility as herein defined engages or is about to engage in the construction, operation or extension of a water system or sewer system in violation of the provisions of this chapter, the Director, on the Director's own initiative or upon complaint, shall forthwith make such preliminary investigation as he may deem appropriate and may, either with or without notice, enter an order requiring such public utility to cease and desist from such construction, operation or extension until further order of the Board. A public hearing on such violation shall be held by the Board within thirty (30) days after the entry of the order to cease and desist. Reasonable written notice of the public hearing shall be given by mail to the public utility involved. Within fifteen (15) days after the hearing the Board shall enter an order either requiring the permanent cessation of construction, operation or extension, or authorizing continuation thereof under such terms and conditions as may be commensurate with the public interest and welfare. Any failure to comply with the stop orders of the Board may be enjoined and restrained by injunctive order of the Circuit Court in appropriate proceedings instituted for such purpose.
The Environmental Quality Control Board shall have the power, and it shall be its duty, to establish reasonable standards of service for each class of public utilities as defined in Section 32-4(c) of the Code, after notice and public hearing, and thereafter to enforce such standards. In performing this duty, the Board shall exercise its powers to conduct investigations and inspections, to make examinations and tests, to prescribe standards of measurement for testing the quality, pressure, or other conditions pertaining to the supply or quality of the product furnished or adequacy of the service rendered by any such utility, and to fix fees for the examination and testing of meters and other measuring devices, as provided by law in establishing the general regulatory powers of the Board, and as directed herein. Standards previously adopted by the Water and Sewer Board pursuant to Section 32-51 remain in full force and effect under the jurisdiction of the Environmental Quality Control Board until modified as provided above.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-11. Appeals from actions or decision of the Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management</catch_line>
<text>
Any person aggrieved by any action or decision of the Director, may appeal to the Environmental Quality Control Board by filing within fifteen (15) days after the date of the action or decision complained of, a written notice of appeal which shall set forth concisely the action or decision appealed from and the reasons or grounds for the appeal. The Environmental Quality Control Board shall set such appeal for hearing at the earliest possible date, and cause notice thereof to be served upon the appellant and the Director. The Environmental Quality Control Board shall hear and consider all facts material to the appeal, and render a decision promptly. The Environmental Quality Control Board may affirm, reverse or modify the action or decision appealed from provided that the Environmental Quality Control Board shall not take any action which conflicts with or nullifies any of the provisions of this chapter. The decision of the Environmental Quality Control Board shall constitute final administrative review and no hearing or reconsideration shall be considered. Any person aggrieved by any decision of the Environmental Quality Control Board on an appeal shall be entitled to judicial review in accordance with the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure. The words "action" and "decision" as used herein shall not include the filing of any action by the Director, in any court. The Board shall not have jurisdiction to reconsider the subject matter of any appeal after its final administrative determination for a period of six (6) months from the date of the Board's final action, unless the Board determines that there has been a material and substantial change in the circumstances; provided, however, any action taken or decision made by the Director at any time may be reconsidered by the Director and the Director may therefore modify any such action or decision.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-12. Variances and extensions of time for compliance</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
The Environmental Quality Control Board shall have the power and authority to grant or extend from time to time variances and extensions of time for compliance with the requirements of this chapter to new or existing facilities, equipment and processes. Such variances or extensions may be granted to specific facilities, equipment or processes or to a class. The Environmental Quality Control Board may grant such variances or extensions only if it is affirmatively established by competent factual data and information that strict compliance with the requirements of this chapter is impossible or inappropriate because of conditions beyond the control of the person or persons involved, or that strict compliance would result in substantial curtailment or closing down of a plant, project or operation which would be detrimental to the public interest, or that the particular operation is essential for the public health or the national security, or that no technically feasible, economically reasonable means of compliance are available to the person or persons involved, or that the variance or extension will not be detrimental to the public health, welfare and safety and will not create a nuisance and will not materially increase the level of pollution in this County, or that a more unhealthy condition will occur if a variance or extension is not granted. Variances and extensions of time shall be considered and acted upon in accordance with the provisions of Section 24-4, Section 24-12, Section 24-13 and the provisions of Section 24-8(5)(b).
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The above provisions for obtaining a variance shall not apply to applications for variances from the regulations of Section 24-49, which are provided for as follows. Any person desiring to do tree or understory removal work which is not in accordance with the regulations of Section 24-49 may apply to the Environmental Quality Control Board for a variance from such regulations in accordance with the provisions of Section 24-13. The Environmental Quality Control Board shall have the power and authority to grant such variances on a case-by-case basis only where it is affirmatively established by competent factual data and information that a literal application or enforcement of the regulations would result in unnecessary hardship (other than economical) and the relief granted would not be contrary to the public interest but will do substantial justice.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
The board shall not have the power and authority to grant variances and extensions of time to comply with the Federal Pretreatment Regulations set forth in 40 CFR 403 as incorporated in this chapter.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-13. Procedure governing variances and extensions of time</catch_line>
<text>
Applications for variances or extensions of time for compliance with this chapter shall be filed with the Director in substantially the form prescribed therefor. The Director shall make written recommendations concerning such applications and promptly file the records with the Environmental Quality Control Board. Upon request by any applicant for a variance from the regulations of Section 24-49, the Tree and Forest Resources Advisory Committee shall also make written recommendations concerning such applications and promptly file the recommendations with the Environmental Quality Control Board. The Director may initiate and file with the Board an application for variance or extension. Upon receipt of an application and the recommendations of the Director and upon receipt of the recommendations of the Tree and Forest Resources Advisory Committee, where applicable, the Board shall promptly hold a public hearing upon the application, after publication of notice of the hearing. All interested persons shall be entitled to be heard before the Board. The Board shall promptly hear and pass upon all such applications, and shall set forth the grounds and reasons for granting or denying the application. Any person aggrieved by any decision of the Environmental Quality Control Board shall be entitled to judicial review in accordance with the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure. The Board shall prescribe rules of procedure governing applications for variances or extensions of time, which shall conform to and be commensurate with the applicable and controlling provisions of this chapter. For purposes of this section, the County Manager may constitute a person aggrieved whenever the Environmental Quality Control Board renders a decision adverse to the recommendation of the Director.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-14. Statements of approved water or sewer service; Emergency water and/or sewer rate requests</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Any public utility holding a valid certificate pursuant to Sections 32-33 and 32-39 of the Code that desires to apply for a change of rate or to change any rule or regulation as provided by Section 32-64 shall file with the Board or the Department a request for a statement of approved water quality or approved sewage service.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
The Department shall within ten (10) days from the date of such request set a hearing date for consideration by the Board of such request in all cases not exempted under subsection (3), below.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
A municipal public utility is exempted from the herein described public hearing process before the Board if both of the following conditions are met:
<section prefix = "a">
The utility holds a valid County operating permit pursuant to Section 24-18, and
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Not more than twenty (20) percent of the utility's gross revenues are generated from customers located outside of the municipality.
If the utility obtains an exemption by having met the above two (2) conditions, said utility must obtain a statement of approval from the Department.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
In determining whether or not a public utility is entitled to a statement of approved water quality or approved sewer service, the Board shall consider the water and effluent quality requirements of Chapter 24 and other evidence including public comments regarding the overall quality of service. If the Board finds that the utility has provided reasonable and satisfactory water quality and sewage service to the public, it shall issue its statement of approved water quality or approved sewage service which shall be valid for one (1) year from the date of issuance. The validity of the statement may be extended by the Board for a period not to exceed six (6) months beyond the original expiration date. Such a statement shall also indicate "excellent," "good" or "fair" quality of service depending on which, in the opinion of the Board, is most appropriate.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
The public utility shall send a written notice to each customer informing:
<section prefix = "a">
That the utility plans to file for a rate increase;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
The date, time and place of public hearing as set by the Department;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
The name, address and phone number of the Department; and
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The name, address and phone number of the consumer advocate.
The notice shall be reviewed and approved by the Department and shall be mailed at least twenty (20) days prior to the hearing. In the event that the hearing on the matter is continued, mailed notices of the continuation may be disposed with by the Board.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
The Board may issue a conditional certificate pursuant to this section if it determines that certain improvements of said water and/or sewer utility are necessary or desirable to increase the quality of service provided to the consumers, and said conditions and improvements shall be specifically set out within said Board order granting the conditional certificate. In no event, however, shall the Water and Sewer Board grant any rate increase to said utility without requiring that the amounts collected from such rate increase be placed in escrow account under Water and Sewer Board control and not released until the conditions set forth in said conditional approval have been complied with by the utility. However, the Board or the Department may not issue its approval of the water or sewer service provided by a water and/or sewer utility if it does not meet the minimum requirements of Chapter 24
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Notwithstanding the requirements of this Section the Board may grant a qualified statement of approval of water or sewer service which shall be sufficient to permit the utility to apply to the Water and Sewer Board for an emergency rate increase solely for the purpose of permitting immediate repairs and improvements necessary to bring water or sewer service and quality to minimum standards. Said qualified approval will authorize the filing of an application for a change in rates as required by Section 32-64 of the Code, but qualified approvals received pursuant to this section will only support a temporary rate increase for such time as is necessary to finance the approved or authorized improvements required to achieve minimum water and/or sewage service quality, as noted above. In no event, however, shall the rate increase be imposed in excess of the life expectancy of the particular improvement or improvements so constructed. In addition, any rate increase granted pursuant to a statement issued under this section shall be used solely and exclusively by the utility for the purpose of improving its water or sewer service to the minimum standards required under the Miami-Dade County Code. Said repairs and improvements shall be specifically set out within said order granting the qualified statement of approval. Any approved rate increase pursuant to this section shall terminate when sufficient funds to finance the repairs and improvements have been collected from the rate increase. Statements of qualified approval may be granted by the Board only when the Board finds that:
<section prefix = "a">
Water service and/or sewage service is below minimum acceptable standards either as to the quality of water and/or sewage treatment or the quality of service for same.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
That an emergency exists as to the quality of water or water service available to the public or quality of sewage treatment or sewer service available to the public.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
That a temporary rate increase may be required to remedy the immediate problem of inadequate quality or service or treatment.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
That no other reasonable adequate means exists for improving the quality of service or the quality of water and/or sewage treatment.
The provisions of this Section requiring notice of hearing shall also be required for any utility applying under this emergency section.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-15. Plan approval required</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Intent. It is the intent and purpose of this section to require that all new facilities, equipment and processes constructed or operated after the effective date of this chapter shall comply with the requirements herein contained, and that any major or substantial enlargement, expansion or addition to existing facilities also shall comply with the requirements herein contained. Any building permit issued by the County or a municipality in violation of the provisions of this chapter is hereby determined to be void.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Waste water facilities. It shall be unlawful for any person to enter into or let a contract for or to commence the installation, extension, or operation of any sewerage system or waste treatment facility or any industrial waste disposal facility without first obtaining the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee. It shall be unlawful for any person to make any enlargement, alteration or addition to any facility, or commence the construction of any facility, that will reasonably be expected to be a source of water pollution without first obtaining the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee. No building permit involving the generation or discharge of effluents shall be issued by the County or any municipality unless the application for a building permit has been approved by the Director or the Director's designee.
The provisions of this section shall not apply to facilities discharging only domestic wastes to a public sewer system approved by the Director or the Director's designee. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the provisions of this section shall apply to facilities discharging only domestic wastes to a public sewer system approved by the Director or the Director's designee if the facilities provide any form of pretreatment in conjunction with a grease trap.
Provided that after January 25, 1974, the Director shall not approve an application for an interim package sewage treatment plant unless directed to do so by the Environmental Quality Control Board after a public hearing pursuant to notice.
For the purpose of this subsection, an interim package sewage treatment plant shall include all domestic waste water treatment facilities that are not included in the regional treatment system as described in the approved 1973 Water Quality Management Plan.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Air facilities. It shall be unlawful for any person to make any major or substantial alteration, enlargement or addition to any existing facility, equipment or operation, or to commence the construction or operation of any new facility, that may be a source of air pollution as herein defined, without first obtaining the prior written approval of the plans, equipment or processes thereof by the Director or the Director's designee. No building permit shall be issued by the County or any municipality unless the application therefor or the plans for construction of the proposed facility have been approved by the Director or the Director's designee. The provisions of this chapter shall not apply to individual family dwellings or multiple-family dwellings of not more than four (4) units in respect to heating equipment or comfort space heating.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Potable water facilities. It shall be unlawful for any person to enter into or let a contract for or to commence the installation, extension, alteration or operation of any public water supply facility without first obtaining the prior written approval of the Director. No building permit involving a demand on a public water supply shall be issued by the County or any municipality unless the application for a building permit or plans for construction thereof have been approved by the Director or the Director's designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Aboveground storage facilities. It shall be unlawful for any person to install, repair, modify, expand, replace or permit, cause, allow, let or suffer the installation, repair, modification, expansion or replacement of any aboveground storage facility, without first obtaining the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee. No building permit shall be issued by the County or any municipality unless the application therefor or the plans for construction of the proposed aboveground storage facility show the approval of the Director or the Director's designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Underground storage facilities. It shall be unlawful for any person to install, repair, modify, expand, replace or permit, cause, allow, let or suffer the installation, repair, modification, expansion or replacement of any underground storage facility, without first obtaining the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee. No building permit shall be issued by the County or any municipality unless the application or the plans for construction of the proposed underground storage facility have been approved in writing by the Director or the Director's designee. The Director, or the Director's designee, shall issue such written approval only upon receipt of formal engineering plans, which are signed and sealed by a professional engineer registered in the State of Florida and which plans detail that the underground storage facilities specified in said plans shall be constructed in compliance with the requirements of this Chapter, Chapter 62-761 of the Florida Administrative Code and the referenced standards contained therein. After receipt of written approval from the Director, or the Director's designee, the owner or operator of the underground storage facility shall notify the Department a minimum of two (2) working days prior to the commencement of installation, repair, modification, expansion or replacement of any underground storage facility. The installation, repair, modification, expansion or replacement shall be subject to inspection by the Department to determine compliance with the approved plans and applicable laws and ordinances.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 05-196, § 2, 11-3-05; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-15.1. Procedure for approval of plans</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
APPLICATION FOR APPROVAL. Application for approval of plans required hereunder shall be made on forms prescribed for such purpose and filed with the Director. Such application shall be signed by the person seeking to install, extend or alter the facility involved or a duly authorized representative vested with lawful power to bind the applicant. Upon receipt of such application and supporting data, the Director shall review all data and render a decision on the acceptability of the facility.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
REQUIRED INFORMATION. Each such application shall be accompanied by the following data and information:
<section prefix = "a">
Report of engineer. A comprehensive engineer's report describing the project, the basis of design including design data, and all other pertinent data necessary to give an accurate understanding of the work to be undertaken and the reason therefor. Such report shall contain a certificate of a registered engineer certifying that in the professional opinion of such registered engineer the facility or project will fully comply with the requirements of this chapter and the rules and regulations promulgated hereunder, and will not cause or tend to cause any pollution as herein defined.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Blueprints. Blueprints or white prints of the drawings of the work to be done in sufficient detail necessary to make it clear to the contractor constructing the facility or project exactly what work is to be accomplished.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Specifications. Complete specifications in sufficient detail necessary to supplement the drawings and specify the work and the methods by which it is to be accomplished.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Processes. A description of all processes proposed to be utilized in connection with the operation of the facility or project sufficient to indicate whether or not such processes will reasonably comply with the requirements of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Additional data. Such additional data and information as may be reasonably required by the Director or the Director's designee, including, but not limited to, Baseline Monitoring Reports, Compliance Reports, or any report required for compliance pursuant to the Federal Pretreatment Regulations.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-15.2. Registered engineer required</catch_line>
<text>
The drawings, specifications and other data submitted with the application filed hereunder shall be prepared by a competent professional engineer or engineers registered under the provisions of Chapter 471, Florida Statutes. The plans and other data required to be submitted with the application shall have affixed thereto the names and certificate and registration number of the engineer preparing the same. The Director shall not accept or receive any application that does not comply with the requirements of this section.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-15.3. Standards for preparation of plans</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Waste treatment works shall be designed in accordance with the sewerage guide promulgated by the Florida State Board of Health, or similar professional publication, recommended standards for sewage works and water pollution control federation manuals of practice numbered eight (8) and nine (9), as applicable to conditions prevailing within Miami-Dade County, and in accordance with good engineering practices.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Outfalls shall be extended or carried to the channel of a stream or to deep water where outlet is submerged at all times. The extent and length of the outfall shall conform to the requirements of the Director or the Director's designee. No outfall shall be approved unless satisfactory evidence is presented to establish that solids or other objectionable pollutants will not be deposited on the shore, and that other forms of pollution will not be caused.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Grease traps shall be provided and installed in accordance with the rules and regulations promulgated under the provisions of this chapter. At a minimum, all grease traps discharging to publicly or privately-owned or operated sanitary sewer collection systems shall be provided with a sampling point on the effluent discharge side of the grease trap. Wastes containing sizable quantities of grease such as those produced by restaurants shall not be deemed suitable for disposal into tile drainfields.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Drainage or disposal wells shall not be used for disposal of treated or untreated wastes except as approved by the Director or the Director's designee.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Air pollution facilities designed to control the emission of air contaminants to the atmosphere in accordance with the provisions of this chapter shall be designed in accordance with good engineering practice taking into consideration the meteorological conditions prevailing within this County. Such facilities shall comply with the requirements of this chapter and rules and regulations promulgated under and pursuant to the provisions of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Approval of plans for potable water supply facilities shall be dependent, in part, upon:
<section prefix = "a">
Owner's program for protective measures to protect and prevent development of health hazards to the water supply.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Protective measures for water quality throughout all parts of the system by frequent surveys, proper operation by personnel certified by the State of Florida.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Adequate system capacity to meet peak demands without development of low pressures or other health hazards.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Records of laboratory examinations showing consistent compliance with the water quality requirements of this chapter.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-15.4. Technical Reports/Professional Engineer/Professional Geologist required</catch_line>
<text>
All applicable portions of the technical plans, reports, proposals or studies required as set forth in Section 24-44(2) shall be signed and sealed by a licensed professional engineer registered in the State of Florida or licensed professional geologist registered in the State of Florida.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-16. Construction of waste water facility or air pollution abatement facility, or potable water facility</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
After approval of an application, the person causing the installation or construction of the project or facility shall furnish the Director or the Director's designee with monthly reports of a registered engineer certifying that the work to date has been accomplished in strict compliance with the approved plans, drawings and specifications and that there has been no major or substantial deviation therefrom. If during construction, changes are proposed which would materially alter the quality characteristics of the effluent of a waste water facility, or which would materially alter the emission of air pollutants of an air pollution abatement facility or would materially alter the quality characteristics of the effluent of a potable water facility, then plans and specifications for such changes prepared by a registered engineer shall be submitted to the Director or the Director's designee for approval before making such changes. The Director shall have the right at any reasonable time to enter upon the project for the purpose of making inspections of the work, and may require reports and additional information at any stage of construction.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
It shall be unlawful for any person causing the installation or construction of the project or facility to deviate from the conditions of the approval of the Director or the Director's designee without the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-17. Certificate of occupancy</catch_line>
<text>
No certificate of occupancy shall be issued by the County or any municipality for any facility or project subject to the provisions of this chapter, and no such facility or project shall commence operations, until the Director or the Director's designee certifies that the work has been completed in strict compliance with the approved plans and specifications, and that there is good cause to believe that the facility or project will operate in accordance with the provisions of this chapter and an operating permit has been obtained from the Director.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-18. Operating permits</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "A">
Permit Required No person shall operate, maintain or permit, cause, allow, let or suffer the operation or maintenance of a public water system, public sewerage system, location at which a site rehabilitation action has been completed in accordance with the provisions set forth in Section 24-44(2)(k)(ii) or any of the following facilities, all of which will reasonably be expected to be a source of air pollution, ground pollution or water pollution, without a valid operating permit issued by the Director or the Director's designee or in violation of any condition, limitation or restriction which is part of an operating permit:
<section prefix = "1">
Interim package sewage treatment plants;
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Interim package water treatment plants;
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Private sewage pumping station;
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Facilities which generate, dispose of, store, use, discharge, handle or reclaim any liquid waste other than domestic sewage, any hazardous waste or any hazardous material (except factory prepackaged products intended primarily for domestic use or consumption), including, but not limited to, the following:
<section prefix = "a">
Industrial and agricultural waste reclaim systems; waste or product holding tanks; or waste or product spill prevention control systems;
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Industrial and agricultural waste pretreatment facilities;
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Industrial and agricultural waste treatment facilities;
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
The following industrial and agricultural liquid waste facilities:
<section prefix = "i">
Aircraft, vehicle, construction equipment, and boat mechanical maintenance or repair facilities including, but not limited to, engine and electric motor maintenance and repair, and facilities which perform maintenance or repair of any component parts of aircraft, vehicles, boats, or construction equipment;
</section>
<section prefix = "ii">
Chemical manufacturing, packaging, repackaging, storage, or distribution facilities;
</section>
<section prefix = "iii">
Pest control facilities;
</section>
<section prefix = "iv">
Photographic processing facilities or laboratories;
</section>
<section prefix = "v">
Printing facilities;
</section>
<section prefix = "vi">
Paint manufacturing, distribution, and product testing; paint research laboratory facilities;
</section>
<section prefix = "vii">
Battery manufacturing; battery reclaiming facilities; battery refurbishing facilities;
</section>
<section prefix = "viii">
Hospitals;
</section>
<section prefix = "ix">
Medical, research or chemical laboratories;
</section>
<section prefix = "x">
Animal hospitals; animal clinics, and animal grooming facilities;
</section>
<section prefix = "xi">
Plastics manufacturing facilities;
</section>
<section prefix = "xii">
Anodizing facilities;
</section>
<section prefix = "xiii">
Silk screening and silk printing facilities;
</section>
<section prefix = "xiv">
Junk yards;
</section>
<section prefix = "xv">
Jewelry manufacturing and repair facilities;
</section>
<section prefix = "xvi">
Machine shops;
</section>
<section prefix = "xvii">
Construction contractor's facilities handling hazardous materials;
</section>
<section prefix = "xviii">
Funeral homes;
</section>
<section prefix = "xix">
Agricultural field packing facilities;
</section>
<section prefix = "xx">
Stationary agricultural packinghouses;
</section>
<section prefix = "xxi">
Aerial pesticide applicators (crop-dusters);
</section>
<section prefix = "xxii">
Dry cleaning facilities;
</section>
<section prefix = "xxiii">
Textile dyeing facilities;
</section>
<section prefix = "xxiv">
Vehicle paint and body shops;
</section>
<section prefix = "xxv">
Metal recycling facilities;
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, nonresidential land uses which are served or will be served by a liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment method or those nonresidential land uses which use, generate, handle, dispose of, discharge or store hazardous materials, on any portion of the property within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area;
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, nonresidential land uses which are served or will be served by any liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment method (other than public sanitary sewers) or those nonresidential land uses which use, generate, handle, dispose of, discharge or store hazardous materials, on any portion of the property within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, Hialeah Wellfield or within the outer protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex;
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Resource recovery and management facilities;
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Facilities that will reasonably be expected to be a source of air pollution; provided, however, the operation of heating equipment or comfort space heating within individual facility dwellings or multiple family dwellings of not more than four (4) units is exempt from the requirement of obtaining a permit pursuant to this section;
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
All commercial boat docking facilities. Operating permits shall be required for all such facilities no later than May 17, 1990;
</section>
<section prefix = "10">
All boat storage facilities contiguous to the tidal waters of Miami-Dade County with a total of ten (10) or more dry storage spaces. Operating permits shall be required for all such facilities no later than May 17, 1990;
</section>
<section prefix = "11">
All recreational boat docking facilities with a total of ten (10) or more boat slips, moorings, davit spaces, and vessel tieup spaces. Operating permits shall be required for all such facilities no later than May 17, 1990;
</section>
<section prefix = "12">
Underground storage facilities;
</section>
<section prefix = "13">
Aboveground storage facilities;
</section>
<section prefix = "14">
Loading facilities;
</section>
<section prefix = "15">
Balanced systems utilized by motor vehicle fuel service stations;
</section>
<section prefix = "16">
Vacuum assist systems utilized by motor vehicle fuel service stations;
</section>
<section prefix = "17">
Any facility which sells or distributes or which offers to sell or distribute any refrigerant or which recharges or causes, lets, allows, permits, or suffers the recharging of refrigerant into any refrigeration system;
</section>
<section prefix = "18">
Any nonresidential facility, including, but not limited to, restaurants, bakeries, hotel and cafeteria kitchens, processing plants or such other nonresidential facilities discharging into a publicly or privately-owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system, if oil and grease can be introduced into a sewer by such nonresidential facility in quantities which have the potential to affect or hinder the operation of sewage collecting, transmission or treatment facilities.
</section>
<section prefix = "19">
Privately owned or operated sanitary sewer collection systems, except sanitary sewers which are less than six (6) inches in diameter.
</section>
<section prefix = "20">
Locations at which a site rehabilitation action has been completed in accordance with the provisions set forth in Section 24-44 (2)(k)(ii).
The criterion for issuance of an operating permit pursuant to this section is compliance with Chapter 24, Miami-Dade County Code. Additionally, no resource recovery and management facility permit shall be granted without the written recommendation of approval of the Director of the Department of Solid Waste Management issued pursuant to the provisions of Chapter 15, Miami-Dade County Code. At the discretion of the Director or the Director's designee, conditions, limitations or restrictions may be required as part of the operating permit if said conditions, limitations and restrictions are consistent with the requirements of this chapter.
The Director or the Director's designee may deny the issuance of an operating permit if the public water system, public sewerage system or pollution source does not comply with the provisions of this chapter.
The Director or the Director's designee may suspend or revoke an operating permit if the public water system, public sewerage system or pollution source does not comply with the provisions of this chapter.
Such operating permits shall not be required for the aforesaid facilities, systems, and plants existing on the effective date of this section until one hundred twenty (120) days from the effective date of this section.
This section shall not be immediately applicable to air pollution sources with valid air pollution control operating permits on the effective date of this section. However, said air pollution sources shall comply with this section by obtaining the operating permit required by this section no later than one hundred eighty (180) days from the effective date of this section.
Notwithstanding anything in this chapter to the contrary, such operating permits shall not be required for underground storage facilities until ninety (90) days from the effective date of this paragraph.
All applications for permits issued pursuant to this section shall be on a form prescribed by the Director and accompanied by a fee which shall be established by administrative order of the County Manager and approved by the Board of County Commissioners.
</section>
</section>
<section prefix = "B">
Disposition of Fees The permit fee payable hereunder shall be deposited in a separate County fund and shall be used exclusively by the Department to pay for the costs of the following environmental services to, and environmental regulation of, the aforesaid facilities, systems and plants:
<section prefix = "1">
Monitoring and evaluating purification and disposal systems of said sources.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Responding to and attempting to resolve citizen complaints against said sources.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Investigation, preparation, and prosecution of enforcement actions, pursuant to Chapter 24 of this Code, to protect the groundwater, surface water, drinking water, and air quality.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Ambient monitoring of groundwater, surface water, and air quality.
</section>
<section prefix = "5">
Special studies of groundwater, drinking water, surface water, and air quality when deemed necessary by the Director to protect the groundwater, surface water, drinking water, and air quality.
</section>
<section prefix = "6">
Air quality and water supply protection, planning, and programming.
</section>
<section prefix = "7">
Laboratory analyses of groundwater, surface water, drinking water, waste water, ambient air, air emissions, and other effluents affecting air or water quality.
</section>
<section prefix = "8">
Restoration of the air, water, property, animal life, aquatic life, and plant life to their condition prior to any violation of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "9">
Prevention of any imminent threat of any violation of this chapter.
No part of said fund shall be used for purposes other than the aforesaid.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 06-125, § 2, 9-12-06; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-19. Operation of facility; competent supervision</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
The owners or operators of each facility or project installed or constructed under the provisions of this chapter shall provide competent and responsible personnel for the operation thereof in order that the requirements of this chapter shall be observed and complied with in respect to the operation of such facility or project. Competent personnel shall be construed to mean a person or persons who have experience or knowledge concerning the proper operation of the particular facility involved, and a knowledge of the basic scientific principles relating to the proper operation of waste treatment plants and collection systems, or a knowledge of the basic scientific principles relating to the proper operation of facilities causing emissions of air contaminants from incineration, salvage, heat transfer, general combustion, or other operations of a similar nature, as the case may be. The names and qualifications of the supervisory personnel responsible for the proper operation of such facilities shall be furnished to the Director or the Director's designee upon request.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
All sewage treatment plants shall be operated under the direct supervision of a qualified sewage treatment plant operator who must hold a minimum of a class "C" operator's license issued by the State of Florida and/or any higher level of certification as required by the State of Florida Department of Environmental Protection. All operation reports submitted pursuant to this chapter shall be signed by the licensed operator, which signature shall be a verification by said operator of the authenticity of said report.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
All potable water treatment plants shall be operated under the direct supervision of a qualified water treatment plant operator who must hold a minimum of a class "C" operator's license issued by the State of Florida. In addition, all public water supplies which provide adequate protection by treatment for an effluent which exceeds ten (10) MGD shall be operated under the direct supervision of a qualified water treatment plant operator who must hold a minimum of a class "A" operator's license issued by the State of Florida. All operation reports submitted pursuant to this chapter shall be signed by the licensed operator, which signature shall be a verification by said operator of the authenticity of said report.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-20. Abnormal occurrences</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "1">
Reports required. In the event of any breakdown or lack of proper functioning of any facility installed or operating under the provisions of this chapter, which causes or may cause improperly treated or untreated potable water or sewage or hazardous materials or industrial wastes to be discharged from the plant or facility, or which causes or may cause a nuisance or sanitary nuisance or the emission of air contaminants in excess of the quantity permitted by the provisions of this chapter, it shall be the duty of the owner or operator thereof to immediately notify the Director or the Director's designee and to take all actions necessary to prevent or minimize air, water or ground pollution. It shall be unlawful to fail to notify the Director or the Director's designee as required herein and said notification shall not be a defense to any civil liability imposed under the provisions of this chapter.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Power to stop operation of facility. If in the judgment of the Director or the Director's designee, the abnormal operation of any facility, equipment, process, or plant is causing or will cause air, water or ground pollution to such extent as to be or become dangerous to the public health, safety or welfare, the Director or the Director's designee may require such corrective measures as may be necessary for the protection of the public on an emergency basis, and the Director or the Director's designee shall have the power and authority to cause all operation(s) of the facility, equipment, process or plant to cease until appropriate corrective measures have been taken by issuing an order to the owner or operator thereof directing the cessation of the operation(s) or by ordering the utility providing water service to the facility or plant to cease providing such service. If the cessation of the operation(s) of any sewage treatment plant would cause greater danger to the public than that caused by the continued operation(s) thereof, the Director or the Director's designee, shall not order such cessation, but shall order that steps be taken immediately to rectify the dangerous condition. Any person polluting the ground or waters of the County shall, within the earliest practicable time, correct the violations caused by the pollution and restore said ground or waters in accordance with the provisions of this chapter. If such person fails to make said restoration, the Director may seek an injunction in a court having jurisdiction to compel said person to perform such restoration. In the alternative and at his election, if restoration is not effected, the Director may restore the ground or waters and shall be reimbursed by the persons causing the pollution for the actual costs of investigation, restoration and prevention. The Director shall institute suit to enforce such reimbursement if it is not made within ten (10) days from demand therefor.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Permissible operations. Discharges or emissions exceeding any of the limits established in this chapter as a direct result of upset conditions in or breakdown of any pollution control equipment or related operating equipment, or as a direct result of the shutdown of such equipment for scheduled maintenance, shall not be deemed to be in violation of the rules establishing such limits, provided that such occurrence shall have been reported to the Director or the Director's designee, as soon as reasonably possible; for scheduled maintenance such report shall be submitted at least twenty-four (24) hours prior to shutdown, and for upset conditions or breakdown such report shall in any case be made within four (4) hours of the occurrence; and provided that the person responsible for such discharge or emission shall, with all practicable speed, initiate and complete appropriate reasonable action to correct the conditions causing such discharge or emission to exceed said limits; to reduce the frequency of occurrence of such conditions; to minimize the amount by which said limits are exceeded; and to reduce the length of time for which said limits are exceeded; and shall, upon request of the Director or the Director's designee, submit a full report of such occurrence, including a statement of all known causes and of the scheduling and nature of the actions taken; provided that the provisions of this subsection shall not be construed to permit any nuisance, sanitary nuisance, or any other conditions dangerous to the public health, safety, or welfare, or as imposing any limitation upon the powers of the Director prescribed in subsection (2) hereof.
</section>
<section prefix = "4">
Emergencies. Classification and procedure [for emergencies] are as follows:
<section prefix = "a">
Class A—those emergencies resulting from or due to natural calamitous occurrences such as, but not limited to, hurricanes, tornadoes, fires, floods, or high winds which involve: (i) the loss of human life or limb, (ii) the loss or damage to property, or (iii) the breaks of dams, levees, or water control structures. No permit shall be required for temporary measures taken to correct or give relief from class A emergencies. Immediately after the occurrence of a class A emergency, the Department shall be notified of the emergency. Within fourteen (14) calendar days after the correction of the emergency a report to the Department shall be made setting forth the details of the emergency, the steps taken for its temporary relief, and any pollution control measures which were utilized or are being utilized to prevent pollution of waters over submerged lands or coastal wetlands. A permit is required for any permanent measures subject to the requirements of Division I of Article IV of the Code of Miami-Dade County, and for any permanent measures in relief of class A emergencies.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Class B—those emergencies resulting from non-natural disasters such as, but not limited to, bridge collapses, sudden and unpredictable structural collapses and failures, and sudden and unpredictable hazards to navigation which do not threaten the immediate loss of life or property but which will require immediate action for relief. No permit shall be required for temporary measures needed to correct or provide relief for class B emergencies. Temporary measures shall be limited to only those minimum activities required to protect against loss of life, limb, health or property or which immediately threaten plant and animal life. The Department shall be notified in writing within fourteen (14) calendar days after completion of the temporary measures which have been taken. The written notification shall include a description of all activities which have occurred as well as any pollution control measures which were utilized to prevent pollution of waters of the County or wetlands. A permit is required for any permanent measures subject to the requirements of Division I of Article IV of the Code of Miami-Dade County and for any permanent measures taken for relief of class B emergencies.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Upon applying for a permit for permanent measures in relief of a Class A or a Class B emergency, the Director or the Director's designee may issue an emergency authorization to proceed with construction, repair, or stabilization activities, subject to conditions, limitations or restrictions. Prior to the issuance of an emergency authorization, the Director or the Director's designee may require the posting of a performance bond to ensure compliance with the conditions of the emergency authorization, the submittal of plans or sketches of the proposed work, and a plan which details the measures to be taken to prevent or minimize pollution impacts to the work area. If the Director or the Director's designee determines that work allowed by an emergency authorization issued pursuant to Section 24-20(4) has not been performed in accordance with the approved plans upon which the emergency authorization was issued or has not complied with all of the conditions or special conditions of the emergency authorization, the Director or the Director's designee shall notify the permit applicant of such noncompliance and specify a period of time in which the permit applicant shall correct or otherwise bring the work into compliance with the emergency authorization. In the event that the permit applicant fails or is unable to comply with the requirements of the notice, the Director or the Director's designee may, in addition to available enforcement remedies, call the performance bonds for the project.
Emergency authorizations issued pursuant to Section 24-20(4) are temporary in nature and may be suspended or revoked by the Director or the Director's designee in the event of noncompliance with the conditions, limitations, or restrictions of the emergency authorization or non-compliance with the provisions of this chapter. The issuance of an emergency authorization, the decision of the Director or the Director's designee to issue an emergency authorization, the suspension or revocation of an emergency authorization, or the decision of the Director to suspend or revoke an emergency authorization, is not subject to review pursuant to Section 24-11 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08; Ord. No. 12-58, § 2, 7-3-12)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-21. Operating records</catch_line>
<text>
The owner or operator of any facility installed or operating under the provisions of this chapter shall cause to be maintained and kept such records of the operation data and control tests as may be required by the Director to indicate the operating efficiency of such facility, and to show whether or not such facility is causing pollution as herein defined, and to furnish all such information and data concerning the operation of the facility as the Director may require from time to time.
In addition to the above, any industrial user, as defined in section 24-42.4(1)(c) of this Code, shall comply with the reporting and record keeping requirements set forth in 40 CFR 403.12, Federal Pretreatment Regulations.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-22. Circumvention unlawful</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful for any person to build, erect, construct, install, design, or use any article, device, machine, equipment, process, or other contrivance, the use of which, without resulting in a reduction in the total discharge of contaminants in the water, or the total release or emission of air contaminants to the atmosphere, conceals a discharge or an emission which would otherwise constitute a violation of the provisions of this chapter.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-23. Information concerning processes shall be confidential</catch_line>
<text>
Confidentiality of all submittals shall be in accordance with all applicable federal and state laws.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 24-24. Waiver of performance bonds</catch_line>
<text>
Waiver of performance bonds. The Director of the Department may waive all requirements concerning posting of a performance bond by any governmental agency whenever the work is to be performed by employees of said agency, provided that, in lieu of the posting of a performance bond, said agency shall furnish the Department satisfactory written assurances that the work performed by its employees will comply fully with all requirements of the permit, and provided, further, that the Director of the Department may waive the posting of a performance bond by any private firm or corporation under contract with any governmental agency when said firm or corporation shall have posted a satisfactory and acceptable bond with the said governmental agency, proof of such bond having been furnished by said agency to the Department.
</text>
</law>
