<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="3">ARTICLE III. WEAPONS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="4">DIVISION_3._ELECTRONIC_CONTROL_DEVICES</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-20.20. Definitions</catch_line>
<text>
For purposes of this division, the following terms shall be defined as follows:
<section prefix = "a">
The word "Electronic Control Device" as used in this division shall be construed to mean any portable device which is designed or intended by the manufacturer to be used, offensively or defensively, which fires one or more barbs attached to a length of wire and which, upon hitting a person, can send out an electric pulse or current capable of temporarily immobilizing or incapacitating a person by disrupting that person's nervous system.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
"Any part of the transaction" means any part of the sales transaction, including but not limited to, the offer of sale, negotiations, the agreement to sell, the transfer of consideration, or the transfer of the electronic control device.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
"Property to which the public has the right of access" means any real or personal property to which the public has a right of access, including property owned by either public or private individuals, firms and entities and expressly includes, but is not limited to, flea markets, gun shows and firearm exhibitions.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
"Sale" means the transfer of money or other valuable consideration.

</section>
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-20.21. Five-day Waiting Period and Criminal History Records Check on Electronic Control Device Sales</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Application and enforcement of section. Law enforcement officers shall have the right to enforce the provisions of this section against any person found violating these provisions within their jurisdiction.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Sale and delivery of electronic control devices; mandatory five-day waiting period. There shall be a mandatory five-day waiting period, which shall be five full days, excluding weekends and legal holidays, between the hour of the sale and the hour of the delivery of any electronic control device when any part of the transaction is conducted within Miami-Dade County on property to which the public has the right of access.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
Sale and delivery of electronic control devices; mandatory criminal records check. No person, whether licensed or unlicensed, shall sell, offer for sale, transfer or deliver any electronic control device to another person when any part of the transaction is conducted on property to which the public has the right of access within Miami-Dade County unless the buyer or the transferee has undergone the criminal history and background check procedures specified under section 790.065, Florida Statutes (2005) and has been provided with a unique approval number.
In the case of a seller who is not a licensed importer, licensed manufacturer or licensed dealer, compliance with section 790.065 or its state or federal successor shall be achieved by the seller requesting that a licensed importer, licensed manufacturer or licensed dealer complete all the requirements of section 790.065 or its state or federal successor. Licensed importers, manufacturers and dealers may charge a reasonable fee of an unlicensed seller to cover costs associated with completing the requirements of section 790.065.
</section>
<section prefix = "d">
Records available for inspection. Records of electronic control device sales must be available for inspection by any law enforcement officer as defined in section 934.02(6), Florida Statutes (2005).
</section>
<section prefix = "e">
Exemptions. Holders of a concealed weapons permit as prescribed by state law and holders of an active certification from the Criminal Justice Standards and Training officer, or a correctional probation officer as set forth in state law shall not be subject to the provisions of this section.
Sales to a licensed importer, licensed manufacturer or licensed dealer shall not be subject to the provisions of this section.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 05-201, ยง 1, 11-3-05)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-20.22. Unlawful to sell electronic control devices to persons who have not had mandatory training on the proper use of electronic control devices</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
It shall be unlawful for any person to acquire an electronic control device in Miami-Dade County unless such person has received safety instruction and is otherwise qualified, pursuant to this section, or unless he is specifically exempted from the operation of this section.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
In order to qualify under this section the purchaser must complete the training course offered by the manufacturer of the electronic control device or any other instructor certified by the manufacturer. Persons who have successfully completed the training course offered by the manufacturer in the course of purchasing an electronic control device shall not be required to repeat the training in any given year in order to purchase another electronic control device.
</section>
<section prefix = "c">
This section shall not apply to:
<section prefix = "1">
Law enforcement officers or agents of any state of the United States, or any political subdivision, municipal corporation, department or agency of either, members of the organized militia of any state for the armed forces of the United States, or law enforcement officers of any political subdivision, municipal corporation, department or agency of either, while engaged in the discharge of their official duties.
</section>
<section prefix = "2">
Wholesale dealers in their business intercourse with retail dealers or retail dealers in their business intercourse with other retail dealers or to wholesale or retail dealers in the regular or ordinary transportation of electronic control devices by mail, express or other mode of shipment to points outside the country.
</section>
<section prefix = "3">
Nonresidents of the United States having proper authorization from his or her consulate, acting consulate, commercial attache, or such other authorized representative.
</section>
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 05-201, ยง 1, 11-3-05)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-20.23. Sale or delivery of electronic control devices to certain classes of persons is prohibited</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful to sell or deliver any electronic control device to any person who the seller has reasonable grounds to believe is under the age of eighteen (18); is under the influence of intoxicating liquor, narcotic drugs, barbiturates, hallucinogens, other controlled substance; is addicted to the use of any narcotic drug, barbiturate, hallucinogens, or other controlled substance; is a habitual alcoholic; is of unsound mind; has been convicted of a felony; or is a fugitive from justice.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-20.24. Possession of electronic control device</catch_line>
<text>
It shall be unlawful to possess an electronic control device in Miami-Dade County unless the person possessing the electronic control device has undergone the criminal history and background check procedures specified under section 790.065, Florida Statutes, and the mandatory training requirements specified in section 21-20.22 of this division. Upon request, a person possessing an electronic control device in Miami-Dade County must be able to provide proof of having undergone the criminal history and background check procedures specified under section 790.065, Florida Statutes, and the mandatory training requirements specified in section 21-20.22 of this division.
It shall be unlawful for a person who has been convicted of a felony to possess an electronic control device in Miami-Dade County.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-20.25. Electronic control device must be kept secure</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
If a person stores or leaves a firearm at any location where the person knows or reasonably should know that a minor might gain access to the electronic control device, the person shall secure the electronic control device in a securely locked box or container except when it is carried on his or her body or is located within such close proximity that the person can retrieve the electronic control device and prevent access to it by a minor.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
A violation of this section is a breach of a duty of safety owed by the person who owns or possesses the electronic control device to all minors who might gain access to it and to the general public.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 05-201, ยง 1, 11-3-05)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 21-20.26. Penalties</catch_line>
<text>
Any person violating any section of this division shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for not more than sixty (60) days, or by both such fine and imprisonment. Nothing contained herein shall be construed to preempt the imposition of higher penalties imposed by state or federal law.
</text>
</law>
