<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
	<structure>
		<unit label="chapter" level="3">ARTICLE III. UNIFORM TRADE STANDARDS</unit>
		<unit label="title" level="4">DIVISION_2._DIRECTOR_AND_INSPECTORS</unit>
	</structure>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-80. Director of Trade Standards; inspectors</catch_line>
<text>
The County Manager is authorized to establish a division or Office of Trade Standards, which shall be operated under his administrative direction, supervision and control. The office may be called the Trade Standards Office or other suitable title, as the Manager may determine. The County Manager shall have power to appoint a Director of Trade Standards and such inspectors and other personnel as necessary to perform the duties prescribed by this article and administrative orders. The Director and his Secretary shall be in the exempt service.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-81. General powers and duties of Director</catch_line>
<text>
The Director shall have the custody of the County standards of weight and measure and of the other standards and equipment provided for by this article, and shall keep accurate records of the same. The Director shall enforce the provisions of this article. The specifications, tolerances, and other technical requirements for commercial weighing and measuring devices, together with amendments thereto, as recommended by the National Bureau of Standards and published in National Bureau of Standards Handbook 44 and supplements thereto or any publication revising or superseding Handbook 44 not in conflict with state regulations, shall be the specifications, tolerances, and other technical requirements for commercial weighing and measuring devices in this County, and are hereby adopted by reference as part of this article in the same manner and to the same effect as if said specifications, tolerances and other technical requirements were set out in full herein. For the purposes of this article, apparatus shall be deemed to be "correct" when it conforms to all applicable requirements promulgated as specified in this section; other apparatus shall be deemed to be "incorrect." He shall have and keep a general supervision over weights and measures offered for sale, sold, or in use in the County. He shall annually make to the County Manager a report of all the activities of his office.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-82. Specific powers and duties of Director—Issuance of regulations; testing at County-supported institutions</catch_line>
<text>
<section prefix = "a">
Regulations. The Director shall issue from time to time reasonable regulations for the enforcement of this article, which regulations shall have the force and effect of law.
</section>
<section prefix = "b">
Testing at County-supported institutions. The Director shall from time to time test all weights and measures used in checking the receipt and disbursement of supplies in every institution for the maintenance of which monies are appropriated by the County Commission, reporting his findings in writing, to the executive officer of the institution concerned.
</section>
</text>
<history>(Ord. No. 68-52, § 7, 9-19-68)</history>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-82.1. Same—Acceptance of assurances of compliance</catch_line>
<text>
The Director of the Miami-Dade County Consumer Protection Division may terminate an investigation or an action commenced under any provision of this chapter upon acceptance by the Director of a verified, written assurance, executed by the person or persons who are the subject of the investigation or action, of voluntary compliance with the provisions of this chapter. Acceptance of an assurance by the Director may be conditioned, in the discretion of the Director, upon a verified, written commitment by said person or persons to reimburse consumers, to take other corrective action deemed appropriate by the Director, and to reimburse Miami-Dade County for the costs of investigation, enforcement and litigation. An executed assurance shall not be evidence of a prior violation of this chapter. No such assurance shall act as a limitation upon any action or investigation by the Director of the Miami-Dade County Consumer Protection Division in the enforcement of this chapter, nor shall such assurance act as a limitation upon any action or remedy available to a person aggrieved by a violation of the provisions of this chapter. Each violation of any of the terms and conditions of a verified, written assurance by the person or persons who executed the assurance shall constitute a separate offense under this chapter.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-83. Same—General testing</catch_line>
<text>
When not otherwise provided by law, the Director shall have the power to inspect and test, and ascertain if they are correct, all weights and measures kept, offered, or exposed for sale. It shall be the duty of the Director, within a twelve-month period, or less frequently if in accordance with a schedule issued by him, and as much oftener as he may deem necessary, to inspect and test, to ascertain if they are correct, all weights and measures commercially used (1) in determining the weight, measurement, or count of commodities or things sold, or offered or exposed for sale, on the basis of weight, measure, or count, or (2) in computing the basic charge or payment for services rendered on the basis of weight, measure, or count; provided, however, that with respect to single-service devices, that is, devices designed to be used commercially only once and to be then discarded, and with respect to devices uniformly mass-produced, as by means of a mold or die, and are not susceptible of individual adjustment tests may be made on representative samples of such devices; and the lots of which such samples are representative shall be held to be correct or incorrect upon the basis of the results of the inspections of and tests on such samples.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-84. Same—Investigations</catch_line>
<text>
The Director shall investigate complaints made to him concerning violations of the provisions of this article and shall, upon his own initiative, conduct such investigations as he deems appropriate and advisable to develop information on prevailing procedures in commercial quantity determination and on possible violations of the provisions of this article and to promote the general objective of accuracy in the determination and representation of quantity in commercial transactions.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-85. Same—Inspection of packages</catch_line>
<text>
The Director shall, from time to time, weigh or measure and inspect packages or amounts of commodities kept, offered, or exposed for sale, sold or in the process of delivery, to determine whether the same contain the amounts represented and whether they are kept, offered, or exposed for sale or sold, in accordance with law; and when such packages or amounts of commodities are found not to contain the amounts represented, or are found to be kept, offered, or exposed for sale in violation of law, the Director may order them off sale and may so mark or tag them as to show them to be illegal. In carrying out the provisions of this section, the Director may employ recognized sampling procedures under which the compliance of a given lot of packages will be determined on the basis of the result obtained on a sample selected from the representative of such lot. No person shall (1) sell, or keep, or offer, or expose for sale in intrastate commerce any package or amount of commodity that has been ordered off sale or marked or tagged as provided in this section unless and until such package or amount of commodity has been brought into full compliance with all legal requirements, or (2) dispose of any package or amount of commodity that has been ordered off sale or marked or tagged as provided in this section and that has not been brought into compliance with legal requirements, in any manner except with the specific approval of the Director.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-86. Same—Stop-use, stop-removal, and removal orders</catch_line>
<text>
The Director shall have the power to issue stop-use orders, stop-removal orders, and removal orders with respect to weights and measures being, or susceptible of being, commercially used, and to issue stop-removal orders and removal orders with respect to packages or amounts of commodities kept, offered, or exposed for sale, sold, or in process of delivery, whenever in the course of his enforcement of the provisions of this article he deems it necessary or expedient to issue such orders, and no person shall use, remove from the premises specified, or fail to remove from the premises specified any weight, measure, or package or amount of commodity contrary to the terms of a stop-use order, stop-removal order, or removal order issued under the authority of this section.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-87. Same—Disposition of correct and incorrect apparatus</catch_line>
<text>
The Director shall approve for use and seal or mark with appropriate devices such weights and measures as he finds upon inspection and test to be correct, and shall reject and mark or tag as "rejected" such weights and measures as he finds, upon inspection or test, to be incorrect, but which in his best judgment are susceptible of satisfactory repair. The Director shall condemn, and may seize and may destroy, weights and measures found to be incorrect that, in his best judgment, are not susceptible of satisfactory repair. Weights and measures that have been rejected may be confiscated and may be destroyed by the Director if not corrected as required by Section 8A-90 of this article or if used or disposed of contrary to the requirements of Section 8A-90 of this article.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-88. Same—Police powers; right of entry and stoppage</catch_line>
<text>
With respect to the enforcement of this article and any other ordinance or State statute dealing with false advertising, consumer protection, trade standards and weights and measures that he is, or may be, empowered to enforce, the Director of the Miami-Dade Police Department may deputize the Director of the Trade Standards Department and his inspectors. When so deputized the Director is vested with special police powers, and is authorized to arrest any violator of the said ordinances or statutes, and to seize and impound as material evidence, any incorrect or unsealed weights and measures or amounts or packages of commodity used, retained, offered or exposed for sale, or sold in violation of law. In the performance of his official duties, the Director is authorized upon probable cause to enter and go into or upon, any structure or premises, and to stop any violating person and require him to proceed, to such place within the County as the Director or his authorized inspector may specify.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-89. Powers and duties of inspectors</catch_line>
<text>
The powers and duties given to and imposed upon the Director by Sections 8A-82 through 8A-88 and 8A-122 of this article are hereby given to and imposed upon the inspectors also, when acting under the instructions and at the direction of the Director.
</text>
<catch_line>Sec. 8A-90. Duty of owners of incorrect apparatus</catch_line>
<text>
Weights and measures that have been rejected under the authority of the Director shall remain subject to the control of the rejecting authority until such time as suitable repair or disposition thereof has been made as required by this section. The owners of such rejected weights and measures shall cause the same to be made correct within thirty (30) days or such longer period as may be authorized by the rejecting authority; or, in lieu of this, may dispose of the same, but only in such manner as is specifically authorized by the rejecting authority. Weights and measures that have been rejected shall not again be used commercially until they have been officially re-examined and found to be correct or until specific written permission for such use is issued by the rejecting authority.
</text>
<catch_line>Secs. 8A-91, 8A-92. Reserved</catch_line>
<text>
</text>
</law>
